<bill session="111" type="h" number="1756" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Microloan Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the Microloan program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Tax.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSM19" subcommittee="Finance and Tax" name="House Small Business"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Microloan Modernization Act of 2009 - Amends provisions of the Small Business Act regarding the Microloan program (a program administered by the Small Business Administration [SBA] to provide small-scale loans to startup, newly established or growing small businesses for working capital or the acquisition of materials, supplies, or equipment) to: (1) require the SBA Administrator to establish a process under which a lender provides to the major credit reporting agencies information about the borrower that is relevant to credit reporting (such as loan payment activity); (2) remove the requirement that Microloan loans be short-term only; (3) revise Microloan intermediary eligibility requirements; (4) increase from $7,500 to $10,000 the limit for loans made to intermediaries that will receive a reduced interest rate; (5) increase from 25% to 35% of grant funds received by Microloan intermediaries the amount that may be used to provide information and technical assistance to small businesses that are prospective borrowers; and (6) include disabled entrepreneurs and small business owners under the Microloan program.</summary>
</bill>
