<bill session="112" type="h" number="3361" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Utilizing DNA Technology to Solve Cold Cases Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Attorney General to design and implement a procedure to permit enhanced searches of the National DNA Index System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Utilizing DNA Technology to Solve Cold Cases Act of 2011 - Requires the Attorney General to adopt policies and procedures to ensure that: (1) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) may conduct familial searches for DNA samples collected from crime scenes in federal investigations, (2) a CODIS (Combined DNA Index System) state administrator or a state attorney general may request that the FBI conduct such searches in state investigations, and (3) the privacy interests of persons identified in familial searches are protected. Defines "familial search" as a search of the offender index in the National DNA Index System in which a DNA sample from an unknown source collected from a crime scene is compared to such index to determine if a familial match exists between the DNA profile contained in such index and the DNA sample collected from the crime scene. Allows FBI familial searches to be conducted only if: (1) no identical match for a DNA sample collected from a crime scene can be identified in the offender index; and (2) the investigation for which DNA samples are collected involves murder, voluntary manslaughter, kidnapping, a sex offense against a minor, or an offense for which an offender would be required to register as a tier III sex offender. Sets forth requirements for state requests for such searches, including assurances that the requesting state will: (1) take steps to facilitate the investigation of familial matches from other states, and (2) investigate possible familial matches in that state before requesting assistance from other states.</summary>
</bill>
