<bill session="110" type="sc" number="97" updated="2013-07-19T22:20:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress regarding sexual assaults and rape in the military.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8280" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hc" number="397"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women soldiers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2008--Introduced.
Calls for the Secretary of Defense to develop a comprehensive strategy to increase and encourage investigation and prosecution of sexual assault and rape cases in the military. Sets forth elements to be included in such strategy, including: (1) requiring commanders to be held accountable for sexual assaults and rapes in their units and for disposition of such cases; (2) developing prevention and response programs to create a culture that prevents sexual assault and rape in the military and encourages more reporting by victims; (3) reviewing the capacity of the legal infrastructure in the Armed Forces to investigate and prosecute effectively sexual assault cases; (4) examining any barriers on military facilities to conducting effective investigations of sexual assault and rape cases; and (5) ensuring that the command affords an alleged sexual assault victim an opportunity for a transfer if a military protection order is issued.</summary>
</bill>
