<bill session="111" type="s" number="3498" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support the establishment and operation of Teachers Professional Development Institutes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4991-4992"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4992-4993" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5556"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to: (1) award grants to encourage the establishment and operation of Teachers Institutes; and (2) provide technical assistance, all or some of which may be provided through the Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute, to assist local educational agencies (LEAs) and institutions of higher education (IHEs) in establishing and operating Teachers Institutes. Sets forth selection criteria, including consideration of the extent to which the proposed Institute will serve schools that have a significant low-income population. Defines a Teachers Institute as a partnership or joint venture between one or more IHEs and one or more LEAs serving one or more schools with significant low-income populations that is established to improve the quality of teaching and learning through collaborative seminars.</summary>
</bill>
