<bill session="113" type="s" number="1144" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Telephone Billing Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit unauthorized third-party charges on wireline telephone bills, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4407-4408"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4408-4409" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2013--Introduced.
Fair Telephone Billing Act of 2013 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit local exchange carriers or providers of interconnected VoIP (Voice over Internet Protocol) service from placing, or causing to be placed, a third-party charge that is not directly related to the provision of telephone services on the bill of a customer, unless: (1) the third-party charge is from a contracted third-party vendor and for a product or service that the carrier or provider markets or sells jointly with its own service, (2) the customer provided affirmative consent for the charge, (3) the customer was provided with a disclosure of material terms and conditions prior to such consent, and (4) the charge is implemented with reasonable procedures to ensure that the customer has requested the product or service. Defines: (1) a "third-party charge" as a charge for a product or service not provided by a local exchange carrier or a provider of interconnected VoIP service, and (2) a "contracted third-party vendor" as a person with a contractual right to receive billing and collection services from such a carrier or provider for a product or service the person provides directly to a customer. Subjects violators to civil forfeiture and specified penalties and refund requirements. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promulgate rules to: (1) define how local exchange carriers and providers of interconnected VoIP service will obtain affirmative consent from a consumer for a third-party charge, (2) ensure that consumers are fully aware of the charges to which they are consenting, and (3) impose recordkeeping requirements on such carriers and providers related to any grants of affirmative consent by consumers.</summary>
</bill>
