<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1197" updated="2013-07-19T23:06:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for democracy in Honduras and restoring normal relations between Honduras and the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2010-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2010--Introduced.
Requests the Department of State to take actions to assure that the government of Honduras settles in good faith and within a reasonable time all unresolved expropriation claims of U.S. citizens against the government of Honduras or its agencies. Recognizes Honduras as a democratic country and calls on responsible nations to restore normal relations with the government of Honduras. Urges Department of State consular officials to review new visa applications submitted by members of the former government of Honduras under President Micheletti, without prejudice of an applicant's previously revoked visa. Supports Secretary of State Clinton's announcement that the United States will be restoring aid to Honduras.</summary>
</bill>
