<bill session="113" type="s" number="1460" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISA Judge Selection Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create two additional judge positions on the court established by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 and modify the procedures for the appointment of judges to that court, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
FISA Judge Selection Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, with respect to the appointment of judges to the court established by such Act (FISA Court), to: (1) increase from 11 to 13 the number of FISA Court judges, with one judge designated from each judicial circuit; (2) authorize a chief judge of a judicial circuit to submit to the Chief Justice of the United States the name of a district judge within such circuit to fill a FISA Court vacancy; (3) allow the Chief Justice to accept the proposed replacement judge or reject such replacement and request two additional names; (4) require the Chief Justice to fill the vacancy with one of the two additional named judges; and (5) require any judge appointed to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review by the Chief Justice to be confirmed by five Associate Justices. Directs the Committee on Intercircuit Assignments of the Judicial Conference of the United States to study and report on how to ensure that judges appointed to the FISA Court and the FISA Court of Review are diverse and representative.</summary>
</bill>
