<bill session="109" type="s" number="388" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Climate Change Technology Deployment and Infrastructure Credit Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to direct the Secretary of Energy to carry out activities that promote the adoption of technologies that reduce greenhouse gas intensity and to provide credit-based financial assistance and investment protection for projects that employ advanced climate technologies or systems, to provide for the establishment of a national greenhouse gas registry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2005-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1426-1428"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2005--Introduced.
Climate Change Technology Deployment and Infrastructure Credit Act of 2005 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to instruct the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to develop a national strategy to promote greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices through research and development programs conducted by National Laboratories, other Federal research facilities, universities, and the private sector. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish: (1) an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Climate Change Technology to coordinate Federal climate change activities and programs to promote such strategy; and (2) a permanent Climate Change Technology Program to assist the Committee in the interagency coordination of climate change technology research, development, and demonstration, and deployment to reduce greenhouse gas intensity. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish the Climate Change Science Program to assist the Committee in the interagency coordination of climate change science research. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) conduct an inventory and evaluation of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies to determine suitable commercialization and deployment technologies; (2) use inventory results for guidance in such commercialization; (3) establish a Climate Change Technology Working Group to identify major statutory, regulatory, and economic barriers to such commercialization; and (4) establish within the Department of Energy a Climate Credit Board to implement the greenhouse gas intensity reducing technology deployment program, using energy credit financial support for eligible projects. Requires the President to establish a national greenhouse gas registry to serve as the depository for data on greenhouse gas emissions and emission reductions.</summary>
</bill>
