<bill session="109" type="s" number="567" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nonprofit Athletic Organization Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide immunity for nonprofit athletic organizations in lawsuits arising from claims of ordinary negligence relating to the passage, adoption, or failure to adopt rules of play for athletic competitions and practices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2272-2273"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1176"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Athletics"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2005--Introduced.
Nonprofit Athletic Organization Protection Act of 2005 - Exempts a nonprofit athletic organization from liability for harm caused by an act or omission in the adoption of rules of play for sanctioned or approved athletic competitions or practices if: (1) the organization was acting within the scope of its duties; (2) the organization was properly licensed, certified, or authorized for the competition or practice; and (3) the harm was not caused by the organization's willful or criminal misconduct, gross negligence, or reckless misconduct. Makes exceptions where State law: (1) requires such an organization to adhere to risk management procedures, including mandatory training; (2) makes the organization liable for the acts or omissions of its employees, agents, and volunteers to the same extent as an employer is liable for its employees; and (3) makes a limitation of liability inapplicable if the civil action was brought by an officer of a State or local government .</summary>
</bill>
