<bill session="112" type="h" number="1325" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">AMERICA Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Achievement Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that certain Federal job training and career education programs give a priority to programs that provide an industry recognized and nationally portable credential.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2012-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412386" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412447" joined="2012-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412497" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2011-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412423" joined="2012-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2011-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1243"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2011--Introduced.
American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Achievement Works Act or AMERICA Works Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, with respect to statewide and local adult and youth workforce investment employment and training programs, to require a one-stop delivery system, in selecting and approving training services, or programs of training services, to give priority consideration to state- and local board-approved services and programs that lead to an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential that is in high demand in the local area served and listed in the skill credential registry created under this Act. Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 and the Trade Act of 1974 to require the same priority consideration in the state and local plans for career and technical education programs as well as in tech prep programs and trade adjustment assistance (TAA) programs. Requires that funds allocated for local area youth activities be used, in part, for training programs, giving priority consideration to those that lead to a registry-listed credential in high demand in the local area served. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) create a registry of skill credentials; and (2) list in the registry credentials that are required by federal or state law for an occupation, are from the Manufacturing Institute-Endorsed Manufacturing Skills Certification System, and are industry-recognized and nationally portable credentials consistent with established industry competency models as well as consistently updated through third party validation to reflect changing industry competencies.</summary>
</bill>
