<bill session="110" type="h" number="4290" updated="2013-07-19T21:41:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Technology Advancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for additional availability of testing facilities and equipment and to extend the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out certain research and development projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400654"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-26">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated into H.R. 2764.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2007--Introduced.
Homeland Security Technology Advancement Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to extend (for five additional years) specified authority of the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out certain basic, applied, and advanced research and development projects and prototype projects.Directs the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to: (1) make available to any person or entity, for an appropriate fee, the services of any DHS owned and operated center or other facility for the testing of materials, equipment, models, computer software, and other items designed to advance the homeland security mission; and (2) ensure that the testing of materiel not owned by the government shall not cause government resources to be diverted from scheduled tests of government materiel or otherwise interfere with government mission requirements. Prohibits: (1) the disclosure outside the federal government of the test results and associated data that are trade secrets or privileged or confidential commercial or financial information without the consent of the person or entity for whom the tests are performed; and (2) fees from exceeding the amount necessary to recoup the costs involved. Directs the Under Secretary to submit to Congress: (1) a report detailing a plan for operating such program; and (2) an annual report on the facilities that have collected fees, the partnerships formed, and the testing conducted.Directs the Comptroller General to submit to Congress an assessment of such program.</summary>
</bill>
