<bill session="112" type="h" number="3257" updated="2013-07-20T01:38:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Time-Out Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a time-out on certain regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2011-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2011-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Affairs, Stimulus Oversight and Government Spending     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO28" subcommittee="Regulatory Affairs, Stimulus Oversight and Government Spending" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3194"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1538"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1786"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2011--Introduced.
Regulatory Time-Out Act of 2011 -&#160;Prohibits covered regulations from being in effect or from taking effect during the period beginning on the enactment of this Act and ending on January 21, 2013 (time-out period).&#160;Prohibits publication of any general notice of a proposed rulemaking for what would be a covered regulation, and nullifies a rulemaking that was published but for which the comment period did not expire before enactment of this Act, during such period. Defines a "covered regulation" as a final regulation that did not take effect before September 1, 2011, that increases costs on businesses in a manner that will have an adverse effect on job creation, job retention, productivity, competitiveness, or the efficient functioning of the economy and that is likely to: (1) have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; (2) adversely affect in a material way the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or state, local, or tribal governments or communities; (3) create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action by another agency; (4) materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients; or (5) raise novel legal or policy issues. Exempts regulations that are required by law. Allows agency heads to exempt covered regulations that: (1) are necessary due to an imminent threat to human health or safety or any other emergency; (2) are necessary to enforce criminal laws,&#160;(3) foster private sector job creation; (4) encourage economic growth; (5) reduce regulatory burdens; (6) pertain to a military or foreign affairs function; or (7) are limited to interpreting, implementing, or administering the Internal Revenue Code.</summary>
</bill>
