<bill session="109" type="s" number="2655" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit Card Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act, to prohibit universal default practices by credit card issuers, to limit fees that may be imposed on credit card accounts, and to require credit card issuers to verify a prospective consumer's ability to pay before extending credit to the consumer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3592-3593"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2006--Introduced.
Credit Card Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit a credit card issuer from using any adverse information concerning any consumer (including information contained in any consumer report, or any change in the consumer's credit score) as the basis for increasing any annual percentage rate of interest (APR) applicable to a credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan, or from removing or increasing any introductory APR. Prohibits a credit card issuer, also, from changing the terms of a credit card contract or agreement under an open end consumer credit plan without written consumer consent. Prohibits a credit card issuer from imposing adverse consequences for late payment if the cardholder's payment is postmarked or initiated by electronic funds transfer on or before the required postmark date in accordance with this Act. Limits late payment and related fees to an amount reasonably related to the cost to the card issuer of consumer default, omission, or violation of the credit plan agreement. Requires a credit card issuer to verify, when the account is opened or the credit limit increased, that the consumer will be able to make the scheduled payments based on a consideration of current and expected income, current obligations, and employment status.</summary>
</bill>
