<bill session="110" type="h" number="7086" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pathway to Nuclear Power Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">United States High Level Nuclear Waste Management Corporation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To help our Nation meet our growing energy needs and strengthen our energy security through the development of nuclear power in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Rules, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
Pathway to Nuclear Power Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) revise terms and conditions governing federal loan guarantees for innovative technology projects; (2) modify the contract authority of the Secretary of Energy; (3) convert the Nuclear Energy Research Initiative into the Nuclear Power 2010 Program; and (4) instruct the Secretary of Labor to promulgate regulations to implement workforce training programs for the nuclear industries. Creates an interagency working group to make recommendations to coordinate federal actions and programs to promote domestic manufacture and export of nuclear energy products and services. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe: (1) a qualifying nuclear power manufacturing credit; (2) a nuclear power facility construction credit; (3) a five-year accelerated depreciation for new nuclear power facilities; and (4) a special rule for the allocation of credit among public-private partnerships that own an advanced nuclear power facility. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 revise administrative procedures for licensing new nuclear power plants. Establishes a Joint Committee on Nuclear Energy to make recommendations to promote domestic nuclear energy. States that, for the period following the licensed operation of any facility for the treatment or storage of spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste, no consideration of the public health and safety, common defense and security, or environmental impacts of such storage is required regarding the development, construction, and operation of, or any permit, license, or siting approval for, a civilian nuclear power reactor or any facility for nuclear fuel or waste treatment or storage. United States High Level Nuclear Waste Management Corporation Act - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to establish the United States High Level Nuclear Waste Management Corporation.Terminates the Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. Requires the Secretary of Energy, in specified circumstances, to propose an adjustment to the fee for electricity generated from civilian nuclear power reactors. Replaces the Nuclear Waste Fund with a Nuclear Waste Revolving Fund and a Nuclear Waste Legacy Fund. Revises contract requirements with respect to such Funds following issuance of a license to construct and operate facilities to receive and store spent nuclear fuel at the Yucca Mountain site, Nevada.</summary>
</bill>
