<bill session="112" type="s" number="1314" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Labor to establish minimum funding levels for States for the support of disabled veterans' outreach program specialists and local veterans' employment representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2011-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6563"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3429"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish minimum funding levels for specified veterans' benefits contracts and grants to ensure that each state receives sufficient funding to support at least one disabled veterans' outreach program specialist and one local veterans' employment representative per 5,000 square miles of service delivery area within the state. Allows the Secretary, in establishing such minimum levels, to establish hold-harmless criteria for states and exclude consideration of counties with a population density of less than one person per square mile. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the needs of veterans residing in an area consisting of a county or counties with fewer than seven persons per square mile.</summary>
</bill>
