<bill session="112" type="sr" number="529" updated="2013-07-20T02:15:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-26">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing that the occurrence of prostate cancer in African-American men has reached epidemic proportions and urging Federal agencies to address that health crisis by supporting education, awareness outreach, and research specifically focused on how prostate cancer affects African-American men.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5626-5627" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5626" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5493" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="313"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="hr" number="753"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="493"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Recognizes: (1) that prostate cancer has created a health crisis for African-American men; and (2) the importance of health coverage and access to care, as well as promoting informed decisionmaking between men and their doctors, taking into consideration the known risks and potential benefits of screening and treatment options for prostate cancer. Urges federal agencies to support: (1) research to address and attempt to end that crisis; (2) efforts relating to education, awareness, and early detection at the grassroots level; and (3) the Office of Minority Health of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) in focusing on improving health and health care outcomes for African Americans at an elevated risk. Urges investment by federal agencies in research focusing on the improvement of early detection and treatment, such as the use of: (1) biomarkers to distinguish indolent forms of prostate cancer from lethal forms, and (2) advanced imaging tools.</summary>
</bill>
