<bill session="111" type="h" number="5506" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Pollution Environmental Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">OPERA</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require that treatment of the issuance of any exploration plans, development production plans, development operation coordination documents, and lease sales required under Federal law for offshore drilling activity on the outer Continental Shelf as a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for the purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2010-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2010--Introduced.
Oil Pollution Environmental Review Act or OPERA - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require the head of any federal agency to treat the issuance of any exploration plans, development production plans, development operation coordination documents, and lease sales required under federal law for offshore drilling activity on the outer Continental Shelf as a major federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for the purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and requiring detailed environmental analysis of proposed actions and reasonably foreseeable subsequent actions. Defines "offshore drilling activity" as drilling for oil or gas under a lease, or conducting a major geophysical seismic survey, under such Act, including for exploration, development, or production of oil or gas. Repeals a provision requiring the Secretary of the Interior to approve a plan for geological and geophysical exploration in the outer Continental Shelf within 30 days of its submission.</summary>
</bill>
