<bill session="111" type="h" number="6219" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Jobs Amendments Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010 to enhance the provisions of the Small Business Lending Fund Program, to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to create a Small Business Early-Stage Investment Program, and to create the Small Business Borrower Assistance Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Introduced.
Small Business Jobs Amendments Act of 2010 - Amends the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010 with respect to the Small Business Lending Fund Program (Program) to: (1) remove the requirement that a community development loan fund (CDLF) be a tax-exempt entity; (2) include as an eligible institution under the Program any small business lending company that has total assets equal to or less than $10 billion; and (3) include as authorized small business lending nonowner-occupied commercial real estate loans. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to develop eligibility criteria to determine the financial ability of a CDLF to participate in the Program. Allows CDLFs to apply to receive from the Small Business Lending Fund up to 10% (current law allows up to 5%) of the total assets of the CDLF for investment in small businesses. Provides: (1) dividend and interest incentives for participating loan institutions based on increases in small business lending; and (2) an authorized alternative computation of small business lending by such institutions. Requires eligible institutions to: (1) provide Program outreach to Indian tribes; and (2) include on its Internet website a statement that the institution is seeking to make small business loans and may not discriminate on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, marital status, or age. Requires the Secretary, in exercising loan authorities, to consider increasing the availability of credit for small businesses operating on tribal trust lands or other Indian areas. Authorizes an eligible institution to temporarily amortize, for up to a 10-year period, any loan loss or write-down in order to increase the availability of credit for small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
