<bill session="111" type="h" number="2645" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">For the relief of Elvira Arellano, Juan Carlos Arreguin, Maria I. Benitez, Francisco J. Castro, Jaime Cruz, Martha Davalos, Maria A. Martin, Juan Jose Mesa, Domenico Papaianni, Juan Manuel Castellanos, Juan Jose Rangel Sr, Dayron S. Rios Arenas, Araceli Contreras-Del Toro, Doris Oneida Ulloa, Bladimir I. Caballero, Arnulfo Alfaro, Consuelo Castellanos, Eliseo Pulido, Gilberto Romero, Maria Liliana Rua-Saenz, Aurelia Martinez-Garcia, Tomas F. Martinez-Garcia, Flor Crisostomo, Gloria M. Alcantara, Roberto Barrera - lopez, Toribio Barrera-Vieyra, Carolina Carrillo de Uribe, Adan Rosales Del Valle, Marie Teresa Herenandez, Consualo Constella, Lucia Larios Arreola, Maria Guadalupe Lopez, Jose Martinez de la Cerde, Ruben Mendoza Lagunas, Jesus de Parafox, German Raminez, Josefina Santoyo, Noelia Corona, Teresa Figueroa-Villasenoe, and Fatima Karuma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Private legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Provides for the relief of Elvira Arellano, Juan Carlos Arreguin, Maria I. Benitez, Francisco J. Castro, Jaime Cruz, Martha Davalos, Maria A. Martin, Juan Jose Mesa, Domenico Papaianni, Juan Manuel Castellanos, Juan Jose Rangel Sr, Dayron S. Rios Arenas, Araceli Contreras-Del Toro, Doris Oneida Ulloa, Bladimir I. Caballero, Arnulfo Alfaro, Consuelo Castellanos, Eliseo Pulido, Gilberto Romero, Maria Liliana Rua-Saenz, Aurelia Martinez-Garcia, Tomas F. Martinez-Garcia, Flor Crisostomo, Gloria M. Alcantara, Roberto Barrera - lopez, Toribio Barrera-Vieyra, Carolina Carrillo de Uribe, Adan Rosales Del Valle, Marie Teresa Herenandez, Consualo Constella, Lucia Larios Arreola, Maria Guadalupe Lopez, Jose Martinez de la Cerde, Ruben Mendoza Lagunas, Jesus de Parafox, German Raminez, Josefina Santoyo, Noelia Corona, Teresa Figueroa-Villasenoe, and Fatima Karuma.</summary>
</bill>
