<bill session="113" type="h" number="2178" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIT Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fitness Integrated with Teaching Kids Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize a grant program to promote physical education, activity, and fitness and nutrition, and to ensure healthy students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2013-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1033"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Fitness Integrated with Teaching Kids Act or FIT Kids Act - Requires the Secretary of Education to award grants to states to implement comprehensive programs to promote physical activity, education, and fitness and nutrition that are based on scientifically valid research, and an analysis of need that considers, at a minimum, physical education indicators. Limits a grant award to a maximum of five years. Prescribes certain activities under a grant, including that states must: (1) develop and implement a physical education indicators measurement system; (2) collect and publish information on physical activity, education, and fitness and nutrition at the school level; (3) use indicators to identify and address student needs; (4) encourage local education agencies to integrate physical activity, education, and fitness into a range of subjects throughout the school day and locations within schools; and (5) award sub-grants based on identified needs. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, to establish program performance metrics to measure the effectiveness of the grant program's activities. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the compact with parents under the school-level parental involvement policy to include a description of the school's responsibility to support their children in leading a healthy and active life, such as by providing health meals and snacks, encouraging participation in physical education, and sharing in physical activity outside the school day to support successful academic achievement. Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to require the Secretary to promote equal opportunities for students with disabilities to be included and participate in physical education and extracurricular athletics implemented in, or in conjunction with, elementary schools, secondary schools, and institutions of higher education, by ensuring the provision of appropriate technical assistance and guidance for schools and institutions and their personnel.</summary>
</bill>
