<bill session="112" type="s" number="2049" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Currency Optimization, Innovation, and National Savings Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the circulation of $1 coins, to remove barrier to the circulation of such coins, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2012-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2977"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2012--Introduced.
Currency Optimization, Innovation, and National Savings Act - Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Federal Reserve Board) to sequester all $1 coins bearing the design common to those $1 coins minted and issued from 1979-1981 and again in 1999. Allows the release of such sequestered coins to collectible coin dealers and countries that have adopted the U.S. dollar as their base unit of exchange. Directs the Federal Reserve Board to: (1) undertake efforts to improve, and remove barriers to, the circulation of all other $1 coins; and (2) work with the U.S. Mint, consumer groups, media outlets, and schools to publicize the Presidential $1 Coin Program. Declares it is U.S. policy that after consumers and retailers are comfortable using and able to obtain adequate supplies of $1 coins, such $1 coins should replace $1 Federal Reserve notes as the only $1 monetary unit issued and circulated by the Federal Reserve System.</summary>
</bill>
