<bill session="109" type="s" number="1810" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Outer Continental Shelf Revenue Sharing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to allow certain coastal States to share in qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300099"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10824-10825"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10825-10826" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2005--Introduced.
Outer Continental Shelf Revenue Sharing Act of 2005 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) regarding the coastal impact assistance program to: (1) repeal references to leasing moratoria; (2) redefine a "producing state" as one that begins production on a leased tract on or after the date of enactment of this Act, regardless of whether the leased tract was on any date subject to a leasing moratorium; (3) repeal the exclusion of certain revenues from "qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues;" and (4) repeal the exclusion of certain leased tracts from the statutory formula for payments to coastal political subdivisions. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to delineate the lateral boundaries between coastal states in areas of the Outer Continental Shelf under exclusive federal jurisdiction. Prescribes guidelines for petitions to lease within the seaward lateral boundaries of coastal states. Includes guidelines under which a state shall share in qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues as of the date production begins under this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to issue implementing regulations, including procedures for entering into gas-only leases.</summary>
</bill>
