<bill session="110" type="h" number="2070" updated="2013-07-19T21:21:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Learning Assessment for Students and Schools (CLASS) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding adequate yearly progress and assessments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-07-17" withdrawn="2007-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E879"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2007--Introduced.
Comprehensive Learning Assessment for Students and Schools (CLASS) Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to revise requirements affecting adequate yearly progress (AYP) assessments of students against state academic performance standards. Allows AYP longitudinal growth calculations and the averaging of school data in a manner designed to stabilize school-building results from year to year. Identifies a school as needing improvement, corrective action, or restructuring only on the basis of the unsatisfactory AYP of a particular group of students in the same academic subject for the requisite period of time. Requires multiple measures of student academic achievement. Requires academic achievement standards to calculate AYP within a continuum of achievement by children within advanced, proficient, and basic achievement levels. Allows states to use the results of subsequent assessments of students who take more than one assessment for the same grade and subject. Limits the provision of supplemental services and transfers to those students who fall within a group whose underperformance results in the school's failure to make AYP. Requires state assessments to be aligned with curriculum and instruction so their effectiveness may be assessed. Requires alternate standards and assessments for disabled children aligned with the child's individualized education program. Allows states to measure the AYP of limited English proficient (LEP) children by including children that have attained English proficiency and excluding LEP children who have resided in the country for less than three years. Allows states to set separate starting points for measuring the AYP of each student group.</summary>
</bill>
