<bill session="112" type="s" number="751" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to develop a comprehensive national manufacturing strategy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Commerce to assess the U.S. economy to determine what goods the United States currently produces, where such goods are produced, which U.S. manufacturing sector is the most competitive in the global economy, and what policies are necessary to maintain or increase the competitiveness of U.S. manufacturing in the global economy. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop and submit to Congress a comprehensive national manufacturing strategy; (2) establish and submit to Congress targets for the growth of U.S. manufacturing for each of FY2012-FY2016; (3) survey all federal agencies that provide support to U.S. manufacturers, and report survey results to Congress; (4) report to Congress on progress and trends in U.S. manufacturing since a specified 2004 report by the Secretary concerning manufacturing in America; and (5) biennially survey U.S. entities that maintain manufacturing facilities outside the United States, maintain a database on information collected through each survey, and submit each survey's results to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
