<bill session="111" type="s" number="819" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Autism Treatment Acceleration Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for enhanced treatment, support, services, and research for individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412381" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4379-4385" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Autism Treatment Acceleration Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to implement an Autism Care Center Program to provide grants and other assistance to improve the effectiveness and efficiency in providing comprehensive care to individuals diagnosed with autism spectrum disorders and their families. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide grants for services to enable adults with autism spectrum disorders to be as independent as possible; (2) establish the National Registry for Autism Spectrum Disorders; and (3) award grants for multimedia campaigns to increase public education and awareness and reduce stigma concerning such disorders. Establishes the Interdepartmental Autism Coordinating Committee to coordinate all federal efforts concerning autism spectrum disorders. Repeals provisions establishing the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee to coordinate all efforts within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) concerning autism spectrum disorders. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) the National Network for Autism Spectrum Disorders Research and Services to provide resources for, and facilitate communication between, autism spectrum disorder researchers and service providers; and (2) a National Data Repository for Autism Spectrum Disorders Research and Services to facilitate the development and rapid dissemination of research into best practices that improve care. Requires the Secretary to award national training initiative supplemental grants to address the unmet needs of individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Public Health Service Act to require group health plans to provide coverage for the diagnosis and treatment of autism spectrum disorders. Applies such requirement to coverage offered in the individual market.</summary>
</bill>
