<bill session="112" type="hr" number="266" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should, without any further delay, submit the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement to Congress for its consideration and immediate approval under fast track procedures pursuant to the Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority of 2002.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412465"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2011-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="86"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="20"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2011--Introduced.
Recognizes that the implementation of the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement will create jobs in the United States, increase export opportunities for U.S. businesses and agricultural producers, and further develop cross-cultural business relationships between the United States and South Korea. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) it is in the security, economic, and diplomatic interests of the United States to enhance relationships with South Korea by approving such trade agreement immediately; (2) the President should submit implementing legislation to Congress immediately; and (3) Congress should consider promptly and enact this implementing legislation under congressional "fast track" procedures.</summary>
</bill>
