<bill session="113" type="sr" number="16" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-24">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution amending the Standing Rules of the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2013-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S293-294" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S270-274" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="2" datetime="2013-01-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 86 - 9. Record Vote Number: 2.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S274" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2013--Passed Senate without amendment.
Amends Rule XXII (Precedence of Motions) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to prescribe a procedure for a bipartisan cloture motion on a motion to proceed to a measure or matter. Requires the motion to be signed by 16 Senators, including the Majority Leader, the Minority Leader, 7 additional Senators not affiliated with the majority, and 7 additional Senators not affiliated with the minority. Requires: (1) the Presiding Officer, or the clerk at the Presiding Officer's direction, to lay the motion before the Senate one hour after the Senate meets on the following calendar day; and (2) a vote on the motion, without further debate, if cloture is invoked. Amends Rule XXVIII (Conference Committees; Reports; Open Meetings) to make it in order, when a message from the House of Representatives is laid before the Senate, for a single, non-divisible motion to be made that includes motions to: (1) disagree to a House amendment or to insist upon a Senate amendment, (2) request a committee of conference with the House or to agree to a request by the House for a committee of conference, and (3) authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees (or a motion to appoint conferees). Limits to two hours any debate, equally divided in the usual form, on a cloture motion presented on such motions. Requires: (1) the Presiding Officer, or the clerk at the Presiding Officer's direction, to lay the motion before the Senate; and (2) a vote on the motion, without further debate, if cloture is invoked.</summary>
</bill>
