<bill session="111" type="h" number="5694" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">One Global Internet Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To combat trade barriers that threaten the maintenance of a single, open, global Internet, that mandate unique technology standards as a condition of market access and related measures, and to promote the free flow of information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
One Global Internet Act of 2010 - Establishes a Task Force on the Global Internet. Requires the Task Force to implement strategies in response to foreign government policies that unjustifiably or unreasonably burden or restrict international trade in Internet-related goods, services, and content, mandate or otherwise preference Internet-related technology standards and related measures, impede the free flow of information on the Internet, or otherwise threaten U.S. interests in Internet-related international trade and the open, global nature of the Internet. Requires the Task Force to transmit to Congress specified annual reports and action plans and to hold a public hearing in the preparation of each report and plan. Instructs the U.S. Trade Representative to initiate an investigation of any acts, policies, or practices of a foreign government that are identified in such reports and plans as priority concerns in accordance with specified provisions of the Trade Act of 1974. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and the Attorney General to investigate whether each act, policy, or practice identified in such a report or plan (or any related action by a nongovernmental entity) violates any antitrust laws. Requires the Task Force to report to Congress on the sufficiency of existing multilateral and bilateral trade agreements in advancing specified objectives that support the goal of a single open, global Internet. Instructs the Task Force to organize specified standards related training.</summary>
</bill>
