<bill session="109" type="s" number="3828" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Language Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 4, United States Code, to declare English as the official language of the Government of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2006-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8845-8846"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="4408"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Allegiance"/>
    <term name="Bilingualism"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Loyalty oaths"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
National Language Act of 2006 - Makes English the official language of the U.S. government. Requires the government to: (1) conduct its official business in English, including publications, income tax forms, and informational materials; and (2) preserve and enhance the role of English as the official language of the United States of America. Provides that no person has a right, entitlement, or claim to have the government act, communicate, perform, or provide services or materials in any other language, unless specifically stated in applicable law. Provides that this Act shall not apply to the use of a language other than English for religious purposes, for training in foreign languages for international communication, or in school programs designed to encourage students to learn foreign languages. States that this does not prevent the U.S. government from providing interpreters for persons over age 62. Repeals provisions of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 regarding bilingual election requirements and regarding congressional findings of voting discrimination against language minorities, prohibition of English-only elections, and other remedial measures. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that all public ceremonies in which the oath of allegiance is administered pursuant to such Act be conducted solely in English. Specifies that this Act shall not preempt any state law.</summary>
</bill>
