<bill session="112" type="s" number="1051" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vietnam Human Rights Sanctions Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to impose sanctions on individuals who are complicit in human rights abuses committed against nationals of Vietnam or their family members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2011--Introduced.
Vietnam Human Rights Sanctions Act - Directs the President to: (1) impose financial and immigration/entry sanctions on listed nationals of Vietnam who are complicit in human rights abuses committed against nationals of Vietnam or their family members, regardless of whether such abuses occurred in Vietnam; and (2) submit to Congress a publicly available list of individuals determined to be complicit in such human rights abuses. Authorizes the President to waive sanctions to comply with international agreements or if in the U.S. national interest. Terminates sanctions if the President certifies to Congress that the government of Vietnam has: (1) released all political prisoners; (2) ceased its practices of violence, detention, and abuse of citizens of Vietnam engaging in peaceful political activity; and (3) conducted a transparent investigation into the killings, arrest, and abuse of such political activists and prosecuted those responsible. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S.-Vietnam relationship cannot progress while the government of Vietnam's human rights record continues to deteriorate, and (2) the Secretary of State should designate Vietnam as a country of particular concern with respect to religious freedom.</summary>
</bill>
