<bill session="110" type="s" number="2497" updated="2013-07-19T22:42:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that families of members of the National Guard and Reserve have full access to mental health care during the mobilization, deployment, and demobilization of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/2007--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Department of Defense (DOD) should undertake actions to ensure that family members of National Guard and Reserve personnel who are deployed have full access to mental health care during the periods of mobilization, deployment, and demobilization.Requires the Secretary of Defense to undertake an initiative to increase access to mental health care, including education concerning mental health challenges and information on available resources, for family members of such personnel who are mobilized.Requires reimbursement under the TRICARE program for certain mental health care services, including chemical dependency treatment, provided to a family member of a covered Guard or Reserve member during a period of deployment on active duty for more than 30 days in connection with Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom who, while on such duty, is covered by the TRICARE program on a for self and family basis.Requires regular reports from the Secretary assessing the access and quality of such family mental health care services and recommendations for legislative and administrative action.</summary>
</bill>
