<bill session="112" type="s" number="1058" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pharmacy Competition and Consumer Choice Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure transparency and proper operation of pharmacy benefit managers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1971"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2011--Introduced.
Pharmacy Competition and Consumer Choice Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirements Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), the Internal Revenue Code, and part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prohibit a group or individual health plan from entering into a contract with any pharmacy benefits manager (PBM) to manage the prescription drug coverage provided under such plan or to control the costs of such coverage, unless the PBM satisfies the requirements of this Act. Directs a PBM to provide at least annually a report to each plan sponsor that includes information on the number and total costs of prescriptions under the contract, payments to pharmacies, payments from pharmaceutical manufacturers, and generic drugs and brand name drugs dispensed. Sets forth provisions governing the interaction between a PBM and pharmacies that contract with the PBM, including requiring a PBM to: (1) include in contracts drug pricing information and agree to provide timely updates on pricing, (2) agree to pay pharmacies promptly for clean claims, (3) not exclude qualifying pharmacies willing to accept terms and conditions of PBM, and (4) require each pharmacy to sign a contract before assuming responsibility to fill prescriptions for a PBM. Prohibits a PBM from mandating or providing incentives to beneficiaries for use of a pharmacy in which the PBM has an ownership interest. Sets forth limits on audits of pharmacy providers by PBM, including with respect to record keeping, appeals, and recoupment. Establishes limits and notice requirements related to PBM's selling claims or utilization data.</summary>
</bill>
