<bill session="112" type="s" number="278" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the exchange of certain land located in the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S547"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S547-548" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-39.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-08-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/02/2011 without amendment. With written report No. 112-51.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-08-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="131">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 131.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2011-11-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7089-7090" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7090" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14T19:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14T19:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8950-8952" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14T19:14:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 278.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14T19:19:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Hastings (WA) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16T11:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9822-9823" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE" datetime="2011-12-16T11:48:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="940" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 413 - 0 (Roll no. 940).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/14/2011 H8950-8952" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-17">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8780" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8780" label="text of measure as agreed to in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-12-23">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-12-23" type="public" number="112-79">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-79.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="643"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/23/2011--Public Law.
Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), if the Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District of Boulder, Colorado, offers to convey non-federal land in unincorporated Boulder County and the offer is acceptable to the Secretary, to accept the offer and to convey federal land in the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests in Colorado. Applies provisions of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 relating to the exchange of public lands and interests within the National Forest System to the land exchange authorized under this Act, except that: (1) the Secretary may accept a cash equalization payment in excess of 25% of the value of the federal land, and (2) the District shall pay costs relating to any land surveys and appraisals of the federal and non-federal lands and enter into an agreement that allocates any other administrative costs between the Secretary and the District. Expresses the intent of Congress that such land exchange be completed within one year of enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to offer to sell the federal land to the District if the exchange is not completed by such deadline. Permits the Secretary to offer to sell such land to the District for its fair market value. Sets forth requirements for the disposition and use of the proceeds received as the result of any cash equalization payment or any sale specified above. Requires the acquired non-federal land to become part of the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests. Revokes any public orders withdrawing the federal land from entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws to the extent necessary to permit the conveyance of the federal land to the District. Withdraws such land on the date of enactment, if it is not already withdrawn or segregated from entry and appropriation under the public land laws and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, until it is conveyed to the District.</summary>
</bill>
