<bill session="113" type="s" number="814" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Communities from Chemical Explosions Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide stronger penalties for violations of the Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Communities from Chemical Explosions Act of 2013 - Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 to make any owner or operator of a chemical facility that holds a quantity of a chemical of interest that is at or above the screening threshold quantity established under interim final regulations establishing security performance standards and requiring site security plans for chemical facilities, and that does not file a Chemical Security Assessment Tool Top-Screen with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), liable for a civil penalty. Subjects an officer of an entity that owns or operates, or an owner or operator of, a chemical facility that holds a quantity of a chemical of interest that is at or above the screening threshold quantity, who intentionally fails to file a Chemical Security Assessment Tool Top-Screen with DHS, to a fine, up to six years' imprisonment, or both.</summary>
</bill>
