<bill session="109" type="s" number="1116" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Positive Aging Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to provide for mental health screening and treatment services, to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for integration of mental health services and mental health treatment outreach teams, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5923-5924"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5924-5926" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Anxiety"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medication abuse"/>
    <term name="Mental depression"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prejudice"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychiatrists"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Retirement communities"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senior centers"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2005--Introduced.
Positive Aging Act of 2005 - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to direct the Assistant Secretary for Aging to establish the Office of Older Adult Mental Health Services within the Administration on Aging to develop and implement initiatives to address the mental health needs of older individuals. Directs the Assistant Secretary to make grants to: (1) states for systems to deliver mental health screening and treatment services to older individuals lacking access to such services and for programs to increase public awareness of the benefits of preventing and treating mental disorders in older individuals; and (2) public and nonprofit private entities for demonstration projects providing mental health screening and treatment services to older individuals residing in rural areas or in naturally occurring retirement communities in urban areas. Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services, to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities for: (1) demonstration projects integrating mental health services for older patients into primary care settings; and (2) multidisciplinary geriatric mental health outreach teams in community settings where older adults reside or receive social services. Requires the Director to designate a Deputy Director for Older Adult Mental Health Services. Requires membership of the advisory council for the Center for Mental Health Services to include representatives of older Americans, their families, and geriatric mental health specialists. Includes among projects of national significance the targeting of substance abuse by older individuals. Includes services for older individuals under community mental health services block grant state plan criteria.</summary>
</bill>
