<bill session="110" type="s" number="3584" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Obesity Prevention, Treatment, and Research Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to comprehensively prevent, treat, and decrease overweight and obesity in our Nation's populations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9498-9499"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9499-9502" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Eating disorders"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Obesity"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Weight loss"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
Obesity Prevention, Treatment, and Research Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to convene a United States Council on Overweight-Obesity Prevention with duties to include developing strategies to comprehensively prevent, treat, and reduce overweight and obesity. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to establish a grant demonstration and pilot program to address overweight and obesity issues, including through promoting increased physical activity and healthier lifestyles.Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, to award grants to promote health behaviors for women and children in target populations.Provides for the collection and analysis of data on fitness levels, health, and nutrition. Includes community education programs designed to address and prevent overweight, obesity, and eating disorders as activities states may carry out under preventive health services and health services block grants.Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture to update and reform federal oversight of food and beverage labeling.Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to provide for additional funding for a program to make free fresh fruits and vegetables available in elementary schools.Amends the Medicare, Medicaid, State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP), and Maternal and Child Health Services Block Grant titles of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of certain services related to overweight and obesity, including diet and exercise counseling, medical nutrition therapy services, and weight and body mass index (BMI) measurement and monitoring.</summary>
</bill>
