<bill session="113" type="h" number="1385" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Cosmetics and Personal Care Products Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VI of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure the safe use of cosmetics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Safe Cosmetics and Personal Care Products Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for the regulation of cosmetics by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS). Requires any brand owner engaged in bringing a cosmetic to market for use in the United States to register annually and pay a fee for oversight and enforcement of this Act. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish labeling requirements, (2) establish a safety standard that provides a reasonable certainty of no harm from exposure to a cosmetic or an ingredient in a cosmetic and that protects the public from any known or anticipated adverse health effects associated with the cosmetic or ingredient, and (3) issue guidance prescribing good manufacturing practices for cosmetics and ingredients. Requires brand owners to submit to the Secretary safety data for the ingredients listed on the cosmetic label and the cosmetic itself, which shall be published in a database. Requires the Secretary to review and evaluate the safety of cosmetics and ingredients of cosmetics that are marketed in interstate commerce, including nanotechnology and contaminants of concern linked to severe acute reactions or long-term adverse health effects. Requires the Secretary, based on an initial review and evaluation, to establish three lists for ingredients: (1) a prohibited and restricted list, (2) a safe without limits list, and (3) a priority assessment list. Authorizes the Secretary to order a recall or cease of distribution for a cosmetic that is adulterated, misbranded, or otherwise in violation of the FFDCA. Requires reporting of any serious adverse event associated with cosmetics. Requires the Secretary to take action to minimize the use of animal testing of ingredients and cosmetics. Establishes an Interagency Council on Cosmetic Safety. Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate an occupational safety and health standard relating to cosmetics for professional use.</summary>
</bill>
