<bill session="112" type="h" number="6296" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-19T18:17:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-19T18:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Loan Fairness Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Disaster Loan Fairness Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to provide the interest rate for certain disaster related loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barletta moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6115-6118" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6296.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-09-19T18:17:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6115-6116" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Passed House amended.
Disaster Loan Fairness Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to provide the interest rate to be charged by the Small Business Administration (SBA) for loans made to small businesses beginning on January 1, 2011, and ending four years after the date of enactment of this Act in major disaster areas. Requires such rate to be the lesser of 4% or one-half the prevailing rate for similar loans in the area for those unable to attain credit elsewhere, or three-fourths the prevailing rate for those able to attain credit elsewhere. Requires the SBA Administrator to refund excess interest payments made by qualifying borrowers before the enactment of this Act. Directs the Administrator to report to Congress on whether the reduced rate has resulted in: (1) a greater number of applications for disaster-related loans, (2) a greater number of approvals for such loans, or (3) a decreased default rate. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury, with respect to any presidential election held after 2012, from making any payments from the Presidential Election Campaign Fund (Fund) to any national committee of a political party for political nominating conventions.</summary>
</bill>
