<bill session="112" type="h" number="3550" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring Ethical Standards, Transparency, and Responsibility in Congressional Trading Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">RESTRICT Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require certain individuals subject to that Act to either place their securities in a blind trust or to report the sale, purchase, or exchange of securities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2011-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3549"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2011--Introduced.
Restoring Ethical Standards, Transparency, and Responsibility in Congressional Trading Act or RESTRICT Act - Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require the President, the Vice President, Members of Congress, and certain federal officers and employees to: (1) place all of his or her stocks, bonds, commodities futures, and other forms of securities, including securities held jointly with a spouse or dependent child, in a qualified blind trust; or (2) file a report with the appropriate ethics officer, within three business days after a transaction is settled, on any purchase, sale, or exchange in stocks, bonds, commodities futures, and other forms of securities, including those jointly held with the individual's spouse or dependent child. Exempts from this requirement any financial interests in or income derived from: (1) the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), including the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP); (2) any other federal retirement system for U.S. officers and employees, including the President, or for members of the uniformed services; or (3) benefits received under the Social Security Act. Subjects violators of this Act to specified civil and criminal penalties.</summary>
</bill>
