<bill session="111" type="h" number="4512" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Country-of-Origin Labeling for Fuels Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Energy to implement country-of-origin disclosure requirements with respect to motor vehicle fuels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2010-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2010--Introduced.
Country-of-Origin Labeling for Fuels Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy to study and report to Congress with recommendations for appropriate methods and standards for requiring: (1) motor vehicle fuel suppliers to disclose to the next person in the motor vehicle fuel supply chain information regarding each country in which the fuel or any of its components were extracted, refined, or otherwise processed; and (2) motor vehicle retailers to disclose this information to consumers. Requires the Secretary to prescribe regulations requiring disclosure of country-of-origin information by motor vehicle fuel suppliers and retailers in accordance with such recommendations. Prohibits such regulations, however, from requiring the listing of more than one country-of-origin for a fuel blend containing fuel 70% or more of which originated in a single country. Authorizes the Secretary to impose a civil penalty of up to $10,000 on any person that knowingly violates such regulations.</summary>
</bill>
