<bill session="112" type="sc" number="47" updated="2013-07-20T02:16:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress on the sovereignty of the Republic of Cyprus over all of the territory of the island of Cyprus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2012-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3784" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="676"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Cyprus"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2012--Introduced.
Respects the sovereignty of the Republic of Cyprus over all of the territory on the island of Cyprus. Urges Turkey to recognize the sovereignty of the Republic of Cyprus over all of the territory of the island of Cyprus, end its illegal military occupation of Cyprus, and implement all U.N. Security Council resolutions on Cyprus. Supports the Republic of Cyprus in its plans to explore and exploit energy reserves within its Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ) and praises Cyprus and Israel for working cooperatively to develop the energy holdings in the region. Opposes Turkey's threatening statements and naval movements designed to keep Cyprus from exploiting its energy resources. Expresses concern about Turkey's efforts to colonize the area of northern Cyprus, and considers Turkey in violation of Article 49 of the 4th Geneva Convention of 1949 by transferring parts of its own civilian population into occupied northern Cyprus. Urges the President to call on Turkey to end its illegal colonization of Cyprus, terminate its occupation of northern Cyprus, and cease illegal interference with Cyprus' exploitation of its energy resources.</summary>
</bill>
