<bill session="110" type="h" number="6683" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western Alaska Community Development Quota Program Technical Corrections Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the provisions of the Western Alaska Community Development Quota Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2008--Introduced.
Western Alaska Community Development Quota Program Technical Corrections Act of 2008 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act with respect to the Western Alaska Community Development Quota Program to revise the investment components of the eligibility requirements for participating entities. Requires an entity to make investments that have a fisheries-related purpose or a purpose for which the entity made an investment before March 1, 2006. Limits non-fisheries-related investments to the property or other assets located within the Community Development Quota (CDQ) region in which the entity's eligible villages are located, or within the CDQ region in which another entity's eligible villages are located if an investment is made jointly with, or with the approval of, the other entity.</summary>
</bill>
