<bill session="111" type="s" number="4036" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to clarify the National Credit Union Administration authority to make stabilization fund expenditures without borrowing from the Treasury.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-12-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10364-10365" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10364-10365" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17T09:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Klein (FL) asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Financial Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8975-8976" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-12-22T17:41:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8975-8976" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22T17:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-01-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-01-04" type="public" number="111-382">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-382.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2011--Public Law.
Amends the Federal Credit Union Act regarding repayment to the Treasury of advances to the Temporary Corporate Credit Union Stabilization Fund (Stabilization Fund) for payments connected to the conservatorship, liquidation, or threatened conservatorship or liquidation, of a corporate credit union. Revises requirements for assessments on federally insured credit unions by the National Credit Union Administration Board to ensure that the Stabilization Fund will have sufficient funds to make scheduled repayments to the Treasury. Authorizes the Board to assess a special premium on each insured credit union in an aggregate amount reasonably calculated to make any pending or future expenditure from the Stabilization Fund. Makes the premium due and payable by 60 days after the assessment date. Requires the Board, in setting the amount of any such assessment, to take into consideration any potential impact on credit union earnings that such an assessment may have. Requires calculation of the equity ratio of the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund (Insurance Fund), for timing and assessment of premium charges, to use the financial statements of the Insurance Fund alone, without any consolidation or combination with the financial statements of any other fund or entity. Revises the definition of net worth with respect to any insured credit union to include, at Board discretion, and subject to Board rules and regulations, special assistance to an insured credit union to avoid liquidation that is provided to facilitate a least-cost resolution consistent with the best interests of the credit union system. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress and the Financial Stability Oversight Council on the supervision of corporate credit unions and implementation of prompt corrective action by the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA). Requires the Council to report to Congress within six months after receiving the Comptroller General's report on any actions taken in response to it, including any recommendations issued to NCUA under the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to apply new or heightened standards and safeguards to insured credit unions for financial stability purposes.</summary>
</bill>
