<bill session="112" type="s" number="3082" updated="2013-07-20T02:43:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nationwide Network of Support for Veterans and Military Families Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the National Veterans Support Network to carry out activities to support and supplement the mission of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2012-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1846"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2012--Introduced.
Nationwide Network of Support for Veterans and Military Families Act of 2012 - Establishes the National Veterans Support Network to, among other things: (1) carry out national activities to raise awareness of the challenges facing military families and veterans, with related media campaigns; (2) provide support to communities that include veterans or members of the Armed Forces; and (3) encourage and promote participation by private organizations in activities that serve and support veterans. Requires the Network to establish a community support grant program to award grants to create or expand community-based veterans readjustment and support programs. Prohibits the Network from accepting any federal funds. Requires annual Network audits and reports to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
