<bill session="109" type="h" number="4570" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Security Letter Judicial and Congressional Oversight Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the approval of a Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court judge or designated United States Magistrate Judge for the issuance of a national security letter, to require the Attorney General to submit semiannual reports on national security letters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2005-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2005-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2005--Introduced.
National Security Letter Judicial and Congressional Oversight Act - Prohibits a national security letter from issuing unless a Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or a designated U.S. Magistrate Judge finds that: (1) the information sought is relevant to an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities; (2) such an investigation of a U.S. person is not conducted soley upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution; and (3) there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the information sought pertains to a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power. Requires the court established under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to establish an electronic system for the submission of documents and other information relating to such proceedings, and for the issuance of orders relating to national security letters. Expresses the sense of Congress that, in the case of a challenge to a nondisclosure requirement of a national security letter, a certification by the Attorney General or other appropriate head or deputy head of a federal department, agency, or instrumentality that disclosure of such a letter may endanger U.S. national security or interfere with diplomatic relations should not be considered conclusive evidence but only a rebuttable presumption that such disclosure would do so. Directs the Attorney General to establish minimization and destruction procedures to ensure that information obtained pursuant to a national security letter regarding persons no longer of interest in an authorized investigation is destroyed.</summary>
</bill>
