<bill session="112" type="h" number="2264" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Tunnel Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the trafficking of drugs and to prevent human smuggling across the Southwest Border by deterring the construction and use of border tunnels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400337"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2011-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2011-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4119"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1236"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2011--Introduced.
Border Tunnel Prevention Act of 2011 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) subject anyone who attempts or conspires to construct or finance construction of an unauthorized tunnel or subterranean passage that crosses the international border between the United States and another country, to use such a tunnel for smuggling, or to disregard such construction or use, to the penalties prescribed for someone who commits such an offense; (2) make such a border tunnel offense a predicate offense for a money laundering violation and for authorization for interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications; and (3) provide for the criminal forfeiture of proceeds of such an offense and the seizure and forfeiture of merchandise introduced into the United States through such a tunnel. Encourages the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to annually provide each known nongovernmental owner and tenant of land located in a national security zone with a written notification that describes federal laws related to the construction of illegal border tunnels and the procedures for reporting violations of such laws to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE). Defines: (1) "national security zone" as any Southwest Border land designated by the Secretary as being at a high risk for border tunnel activity; and (2) "Southwest Border land" as all parcels of real property in the United States that are located within one mile of the U.S.-Mexico international border and that are not owned by a federal, state, tribal, or local government entity. Requires the Secretary to submit an annual report describing: (1) cross border tunnels discovered in Southwest Border land; and (2) DHS needs to effectively prevent, investigate, and prosecute border tunnel construction on such land.</summary>
</bill>
