<bill session="111" type="s" number="1180" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for greater diversity within, and to improve policy direction and oversight of, the Senior Executive Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6187-6188"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6188-6189" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2009--Introduced.
Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act of 2009 - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish within OPM the Senior Executive Service Resource Office (SES Resource Office). Makes it the mission of the SES Resource Office to: (1) improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and productivity of the Senior Executive Service (SES) through policy formulation and oversight; (2) advance the professionalism of the SES; and (3) recruit qualified individuals from appropriate sources to ensure that the SES is reflective of the nation's diversity. Sets forth the functions of the SES Resource Office with respect to the management, training, oversight, and recruitment activities of the SES. Revises the career appointments recruiting process to require agency heads to ensure diversity of executive resources boards and any subgroup or other evaluation panel related to the merit staffing process for career appointees by including members of racial and ethnic minority groups, women, and individuals with disabilities. Requires each federal agency to submit to OPM a plan to enhance and maximize opportunities for the advancement and appointment of minorities, women, and individuals with disabilities to the SES.</summary>
</bill>
