<bill session="109" type="h" number="3896" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06T20:59:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-06T20:59:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Relief CDBG Flexibility Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Relief CDBG Flexibility Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To temporarily suspend, for communities affected by Hurricane Katrina, certain requirements under the community development block grant program.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To temporarily suspend, for communities affected by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, certain requirements under the community development block grant program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2005-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Baker moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8670-8674" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3896.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8707" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-10-06T20:59:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="514" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 514).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8670-8671" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Passed House amended.
Hurricane Katrina Emergency Relief CDBG Flexibility Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to: (1) suspend the community development block grant public services cap for FY2005-FY2008 for communities directly or indirectly affected by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita; (2) consider the specific economic circumstances of each indirectly affected community in determining the length of such suspension; and (3) waive or find alternative specified public hearing requirements in FY2006 for a directly affected community. Authorizes similar fund use in directly affected nonentitlement areas, and provides that such amounts shall not be considered for statewide limitation purposes. Defines: (1) "directly affected community" as a unit of general local government or area that is located in an area for which the President has declared a major disaster as a result of Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita; and (2) "indirectly affected community" as a unit of general local government or area that is a metropolitan city, urban county, or Indian tribe that is not a directly affected community and is determined by the Secretary to have been significantly affected economically by the occurrence of Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita (including from the presence of Katrina- or Rita-evacuated persons).</summary>
</bill>
