<bill session="111" type="h" number="260" updated="2013-07-19T23:14:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Energy Independence Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Energy to make loan guarantees for cellulosic ethanol production technology development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2009--Introduced.
21st Century Energy Independence Act of 2009 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to seek to ensure: (1) the availability of 200% of the volume of renewable fuels required to be available in the United States by 2013 under the Energy Policy Act of 2005; and (2) the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions from the production and use of renewable fuels by 25%.Directs the Secretary to establish a loan guarantee program for up to 80% of the cost of a project for: (1) the harvesting, storing, and delivery of agriculture residues for use in cellulosic or traditional ethanol production plants; (2) cellulosic ethanol production technologies that will reduce the initial capital cost to $2.50 per annual gallon, and operation and maintenance costs to 125% of those at traditional corn ethanol plants; (3) advanced biomass gasifiers that can provide specified thermal input requirements for traditional ethanol plants to produce syngas; and (4) scaled catalytic conversion projects to convert syngas to liquid fuels.Permits such loan guarantees for: (1) a traditional ethanol plant only if the agriculture residue products are used as feedstock to replace thermal input requirements otherwise provided by fossil fuels; and (2) an existing ethanol plant only if the applicant demonstrates the potential to reduce carbon dioxide emissions related to ethanol production by at least 75%.Authorizes the Secretary to provide grants for up to 50% of the capital costs of the initial commercialization for certain cellulosic ethanol production technologies.</summary>
</bill>
