<bill session="111" type="h" number="766" updated="2013-07-19T23:18:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Assistance Act for Persons with Mental Illness</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage States and units of general local government to use amounts received under the community development block grant program and the community mental health services and substance abuse block grant programs to provide housing counseling and financial counseling for individuals before their release from inpatient or residential institutions for individuals with mental illness and periodic evaluation of the appropriateness of such counseling after such release.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2009--Introduced.
Community Assistance Act for Persons with Mental Illness - Authorizes the use of specified funds, by state and local governments under the community development, mental health services, and substance abuse prevention and treatment block grant programs of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 and the Public Health Service Act, to provide housing counseling and financial counseling for individuals before their release from institutions for individuals with mental illness. Amends the Public Health Service Act to include in a state plan for comprehensive community-based mental health systems: (1) housing counseling; (2) financial counseling; and (3) support services for individuals released from inpatient or residential institutions.</summary>
</bill>
