<bill session="109" type="s" number="1000" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Palliative Care Training Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to increase the number of permanent faculty in palliative care medicine at accredited allopathic and osteopathic medical schools and to promote the development of faculty careers as academic palliative specialists who emphasize teaching.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4940-4941"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4944" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Osteopathy and osteopaths"/>
    <term name="Pain"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2005--Introduced.
Palliative Care Training Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program to provide Hospice and Palliative Care Academic Career Awards to individuals that: (1) are board certified or board eligible in internal medicine, family practice, or pediatrics and their subspecialties; (2) have completed an approved fellowship program or demonstrated specialized experience in palliative medicine; and (3) have a junior faculty appointment at an accredited school of medicine within an approved internship or residency program. Provides that the amount of such an Award shall be $75,000 for FY2006 (to be adjusted for subsequent fiscal years to reflect increases in the Consumer Price Index) and the term shall not exceed five years. Requires an individual who receives an Award to provide training in hospice care and palliative medicine, which shall constitute at least 75 percent of the obligations of such individual under the terms of the Award.</summary>
</bill>
