<bill session="110" type="h" number="301" updated="2013-07-19T21:06:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voter Bounty Registration Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish standards for the distribution of voter registration application forms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2007--Introduced.
Voter Bounty Registration Act of 2007 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prescribe standards for paid distribution of voter registration application forms.Prohibits any individual from distributing a voter registration application form for federal elections in a state if the individual: (1) is not registered to vote in such elections; (2) has been convicted of a felony under any state or federal law; (3) does not sign and print legibly the individual's name on the form; or (4) does not provide identifying information to the election official to whom the form will be submitted.Excepts from this prohibition the distribution of a voter registration application form by an individual who is not compensated directly or indirectly for it.Establishes criminal penalties for: (1) individuals not meeting such standards; and (2) anyone who employs such an individual knowingly, or who should reasonably be expected to know the individual is ineligible.</summary>
</bill>
