<bill session="112" type="h" number="3241" updated="2013-07-20T01:38:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Travelers Bill of Rights Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require operators of Internet websites that provide access to international travel services and market overseas vacation destinations to provide on such websites information to consumers regarding the potential health and safety risks associated with traveling to such vacation destinations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412421"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2011-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1120"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1753"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2011--Introduced.
International Travelers Bill of Rights Act of 2011 - Requires an individual or entity that operates a website that provides access to international travel services to provide to consumers information regarding the health and safety risks associated with overseas vacation destinations marketed on such website, including: (1) information compiled by the Department of State that includes country-specific travel warnings and alerts; and (2) information on the availability of on site health and safety services at a destination, including the hours and days such services are available, or a disclaimer that such destination does not provide certain health and safety services or that information regarding such services is not available. Requires a website operator that does not possess information on a destination's health and safety services to request it from that destination. Grants the website operator immunity from liability relating to inaccurate or incomplete information if such information was provided by the destination and the operator published it without knowledge that it was inaccurate or incomplete. Treats a violation as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to require the Secretary of State to: (1) collect and include in the database on overseas deaths of U.S. citizens from non-natural causes information on the name and address of the property where a death occurred, and (2) update the database not less frequently than once each month (currently, every six months) and to report such updated information to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
