<bill session="110" type="h" number="1165" updated="2013-07-19T21:13:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Drug Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Swift Approval, Full Evaluation Drug Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish additional authorities to ensure the safe and effective use of drugs, to establish whistleblower protections for certain individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E390-391"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Censorship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2007--Introduced.
Swift Approval, Full Evaluation Drug Act or the SAFE Drug Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) order postmarket studies of approved drugs upon receiving evidence of a significant issue regarding the safety or lack of effectiveness of such a drug; and (2) establish restrictions on the distribution or use of the drug during the period in which the study is conducted.Directs the Secretary to amend regulations to require postmarket studies of drugs approved under an accelerated approval process for new drugs for serious or life-threatening illnesses. Deems a drug or device to be misbranded if there is a failure to comply with requirements under this Act.Prohibits discrimination against individuals who provide information in an investigation or proceeding regarding a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, censorship, distortion, or suppression of scientific information, research, or analysis, or the willful disclosure of false, misleading, or incomplete scientific information.Authorizes Food and Drug Administration (FDA) officers, employees, and sponsored individuals to publish in peer-reviewed journals and other scientific publications and make oral presentations at professional society meetings and other meetings of their peers, with certain exceptions.Prohibits an FDA officer or employee from directing any other FDA officer or employee to: (1) censor, distort, or suppress any scientific research, analysis, opinion, or recommendation; or (2) willfully disclose scientific information that is false, misleading, or incomplete.Requires the Secretary to publish a summary statement of the scientific basis for approval of any new drug and how the final decision balanced the risk and benefits within 48 hours after approval of an application.</summary>
</bill>
