<bill session="111" type="h" number="5346" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">America's Waterway Watch Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance homeland security in the ports and waterways of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3619"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2010--Introduced.
America's Waterway Watch Act - Establishes within the Coast Guard the America's Waterway Watch Program to promote voluntary reporting of activities indicating a threat or act of terrorism against a vessel, facility, port, or waterway. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) report to specified congressional committees and to the Comptroller General on the pilot program to test the business processes, technology, and operational impacts required to deploy transportation security card readers at secure areas of the marine transportation system; (2) report to specified congressional committees on the establishment of Interagency Operational Centers for Port Security and on the threat, vulnerability, and consequence of a terrorist attack on gasoline and chemical cargo shipments in port activity areas; (3) establish no less than two maritime security response teams to act as the Coast Guard's counterterrorism and law enforcement response units; (4) increase the number of detection canine teams certified by the Coast Guard for maritime-related security; (5) conduct a program for the mobile biometric identification of suspected individuals, including terrorists, to enhance border security; (6) establish a pilot program to test and deploy preventive radiological or nuclear detection equipment on Coast Guard vessels to enhance border security; (7) establish procedures for fingerprinting applicants for transportation security cards and prepare an assessment of the enrollment sites for such cards; and (8) initiate a national study to identify measures for improving the security of maritime transportation of certain dangerous cargo and coordinate an evaluation of the waterside security of vessels carrying, and waterfront facilities handling, certain dangerous cargo. Directs the Comptroller General to: (1) study the effects that the Transportation Worker Identification Credential (TWIC) has on companies that employ seasonal employees; (2) study methods to conduct a background security investigation of an individual who possesses a biometric identification card that complies with International Labor Convention number 185; and (3) report to specified congressional committees regarding background checks and forms of identification required under state and local transportation security programs. Requires the Commandant of the Coast Guard to promote maritime security and ensure appropriate coverage of maritime security missions within the workforce. Authorizes the Commandant to establish and operate one or more centers of expertise for maritime security.</summary>
</bill>
