<bill session="110" type="s" number="1503" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gas Petroleum Refiner Improvement and Community Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gas PRICE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve domestic fuels security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6866-6867"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Aircraft engines"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Gas Petroleum Refiner Improvement and Community Empowerment Act or the Gas PRICE Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to enter into a domestic fuels facility permitting agreement with a requesting state or Indian tribe under which the process for obtaining all permits necessary for construction and operation of a domestic fuels facility shall use a prescribed interdisciplinary multimedia approach.Requires the Administrator to: (1) conduct a research and demonstration program to evaluate the air quality benefits of ultra-clean Fischer-Tropsch transportation fuel, including diesel and jet fuel; (2) evaluate the use of such fuel for reducing engine exhaust emissions; and (3) submit recommendations and reports to Congress. Directs the Secretary of Energy and the Economic Development Administration to give priority to projects supportting commercial-scale cellulosic biomass ethanol projects and coal-to-liquids facilities. Directs the Secretary to make an additional award in connection with a grant made to a recipient (including any Indian tribe for use on Indian land) for a project to support a commercial-scale biomass ethanol facility or coal-to-liquid facility.Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to appoint a task force to report to Congress on: (1) modernization of the hydrocarbon reserves disclosures classification system of the SEC to reflect advances in reserves recovery from nontraditional sources; and (2) creation of a renewable reserves classification system for cellulosic biofuels feedstocks.</summary>
</bill>
