<bill session="111" type="h" number="1842" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-18T11:07:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-18T11:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanding Entrepreneurship Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Expanding Entrepreneurship Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the Small Business Administration's entrepreneurial development programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rural Development, Entrepreneurship and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Provisions of Measure incorporated into H.R. 2352.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Velazquez moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13079-13081" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T10:59:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1842.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-11-18T11:07:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13079-13080" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM21" subcommittee="Rural Development, Entrepreneurship and Trade" name="House Small Business"/>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2009--Passed House amended.
Expanding Entrepreneurship Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Act relating to small business entrepreneurial development programs (programs) to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to: (1) develop and submit to Congress a plan for using the programs as a catalyst for job creation for FY2010-FY2011; (2) promulgate a rule to develop and implement a data collection process covering all programs; (3) report to Congress on opportunities to foster coordination, limit duplication, and improve delivery under the programs; (3) after public comment, establish and make available a database of providers of entrepreneurial development services; (4) designate at least one staff member in each SBA district office as a community specialist with full-time responsibility working with such providers to increase coordination with federal resources; and (5) publish a design for a Web-based portal that provides comprehensive information on the programs and, after public comment, establish such portal. Prohibits the Administrator from conducting any pilot program for a period of more than three years if the pilot program conflicts with or uses the resources of any of the entrepreneurial development programs.</summary>
</bill>
