<bill session="112" type="h" number="6082" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-25T14:43:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-07-25T14:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Replacement of President Obama's Energy-Restricting and Job-Limiting Offshore Drilling Plan</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Congressional Replacement of President Obama's Energy-Restricting and Job-Limiting Offshore Drilling Plan</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Congressional Replacement of President Obama's Energy-Restricting and Job-Limiting Offshore Drilling Plan</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To officially replace, within the 60-day Congressional review period under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, President Obama's Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil &amp; Gas Leasing Program (2012-2017) with a congressional plan that will conduct additional oil and natural gas lease sales to promote offshore energy development, job creation, and increased domestic energy production to ensure a more secure energy future in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2012-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 17.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-20T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-615.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-20T16:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="447">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 447.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 738.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H51467-5182" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4078 and H.R. 6082. H.R. 4078 is accorded 2 hours of general debate and H.R. 6082 is accorded 1 hour of general debate. For H.R. 4078, specified amendments printed in Part B of the report are in order and for H.R. 6082, specified amendments printed in Part C are in order. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 738 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Robert J. Dold to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 6082.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt (NJ) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Richardson amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holt amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Holt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings (FL) amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hastings (FL) amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (FL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 738, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings (FL) amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hastings (FL) amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (FL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 6082 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5217-5224" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 6082.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5222" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 07/24/2012 H5174" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Slaughter moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5222-5223" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5222" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Slaughter motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment prohibiting the issuance of leases for drilling to any person that is in violation of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010, or the Syria Accountability and Lebanese Sovereignty Restoration Act of 2003.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5222" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 179 - 240 (Roll no. 510).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-07-25T14:43:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="511" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 253 - 170 (Roll no. 511).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="474">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 474.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="738"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6168"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3438"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1439"/>
    <amendment number="h1440"/>
    <amendment number="h1441"/>
    <amendment number="h1442"/>
    <amendment number="h1443"/>
    <amendment number="h1444"/>
    <amendment number="h1445"/>
    <amendment number="h1446"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/25/2012--Passed House amended.
Congressional Replacement of President Obama's Energy-Restricting and Job-Limiting Offshore Drilling Plan - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to implement the Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil &amp; Gas Leasing Program (2012-2017) in accordance with the schedule for conducting oil and gas lease sales set forth in it and in the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. Instructs the Secretary to conduct each of specified oil and gas lease sales in the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Planning Areas, including certain ones in the Draft Proposed Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Oil and Gas Leasing Program (2010-2015), during its specified year. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to offer for sale, by December 31, 2013, leases of tracts in the Santa Maria and Santa Barbara/Ventura Basins of the Southern California OCS Planning Area. Requires the Secretary to include in such leases any terms and conditions necessary to require that development and production may occur only from offshore infrastructure in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act or from onshore-based drilling. (Sec. 5) Retains the authority of the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to designate national defense areas on the OCS. Prohibits exploration, development, or production of oil or natural gas on the OCS under a lease issued under this Act that would conflict with any military operation determined in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement between the Department of Defense and the Department of the Interior on Mutual Concerns on the Outer Continental Shelf signed July 20, 1983, including any revision or replacement for that agreement agreed to after that date but before the issuance of the lease under which such exploration, development, or production is conducted. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to prepare a multisale environmental impact statement pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for lease sales required under this Act that are not included in the Proposed Final Leasing Program (2012-2017). States that the Secretary is not required to identify nonleasing alternative courses of action or to analyze the environmental effects of such alternative courses of action. Requires the Secretary only to: (1) identify a preferred action for leasing and not more than one alternative leasing proposal, and (2) analyze the environmental effects and potential mitigation measures for such preferred action and such alternative leasing proposal. (Sec. 7) Declares that nothing in this Act affects restrictions on oil and gas leasing under the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary, in determining the areas off the coasts of South Carolina and California to be made available for leasing under this Act, to: (1) consult with the governor and legislature of each state; and (2) focus on areas considered to have the most geologically promising energy resources.</summary>
</bill>
