<bill session="109" type="s" number="1003" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-02">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Act of December 22, 1974, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4950"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4950-4956" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-183.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator McCain with amendments. With written report No. 109-206.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="324">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 324.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3918-3930" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3918-3924" label="text of measure as reported"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-05-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3924-3930" label="text of measure as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02T21:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02T22:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-20">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3858"/>
    <amendment number="s3859"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/2/2006--Passed Senate amended.
Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Amendments of 2005 - Title I: Amendments to the Act of December 22, 1974 - (Sec. 101) Amends the Act of December 22, 1974, to repeal authority and requirements for appointment of Navajo and Hopi relocation negotiating teams, a Mediator, and related matters (because all such requirements have been fulfilled). Renames the Act, as revised, the Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Act. (Sec. 106) Revises requirements for the partition of the Navajo and Hopi Joint Use Area of the 1882 Reservation established by Executive Order on December 16, 1882. (Sec. 107) Revises requirements for the exchange of land, at the discretion of the Secretary of the Interior, between the United States (under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management in Arizona and New Mexico) and the Navajo Tribe. (Currently, the Secretary is required to make such a land exchange.) Terminates on September 30, 2008, the authority of the Commissioner of the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation (ONHIR) to select lands to be transferred to or acquired by the Navajo Tribe.Authorizes the Commissioner, in order to facilitate relocation of a member of a Tribe, to grant a homesite lease on land acquired under such Act to a member of the extended family of a Navajo Indian eligible to receive benefits under such Act. Prohibits the Commissioner, however, from using any available funds to provide housing to such an extended family member. (Sec. 108) Terminates ONHIR on September 30, 2008, and transfers all remaining duties to the Secretary. Allows the Secretary: (1) to consult with the Commissioner regarding the transfer of the responsibilities of the ONHIR to the Department of the Interior; and (2) take any action the Secretary determines to be necessary to assume the responsibilities of the Office on September 30, 2008. (Sec. 110) Prohibits any payment of benefits under the Act to any head of household not certified eligible to receive payments by September 30, 2008. (Sec. 111) Directs the Commissioner to notify the Secretary by September 30, 2008, of any head of household who: (1) is certified eligible to receive benefits; (2) does not reside on land partitioned to the Tribe of which the head of household is a member; and (3) has not received a replacement home. Directs the Commissioner also, by September 30, 2008, to transfer to the Secretary any funds not used to make payments to eligible heads of households. Requires the Secretary to hold such funds, for the benefit of each eligible head of household who has not received a replacement home, until receiving a request for them, at which time payments shall be made for such a home. Requires the Commissioner to notify each eligible head of household who has not entered into a lease with the Hopi Tribe to reside on land partitioned to the Tribe. Requires the Commissioner, before July 1, 2008, but within 90 days after receiving notice of the imminent removal of a relocatee from land provided to the Navajo Tribe or the Hopi Tribe under this Act, to: (1) determine the relocatee's eligibility for a replacement home; and (2) begin construction of such a home for an eligible relocatee on any acquired land. Requires the Commissioner to establish an expedited procedure for reaching a final determination on appeals of eligibility denials. Authorizes appeal of an eligibility denial to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit. (Sec. 121) Authorizes appropriations to a discretionary fund of the Commissioner to carry out the relocation program for FY2006-FY2008 and beyond. Title II: Transfer of Functions and Savings Provisions - (Sec. 202) Transfers to the Secretary any ONHIR function that has not been carried out in accordance with the Act of December 22, 1974, as amended by this Act. Prescribes related administrative requirements. (Sec. 212) Requires the Commissioner to report annually to Congress and authorizes appropriations for such reports. Title III: Personnel of the Office of Navajo and Hopi Relocation - (Sec. 301) Allows ONHIR to request funding for and offer voluntary separation incentive payments and voluntary early retirement to any ONHIR employee.</summary>
</bill>
