<bill session="110" type="s" number="701" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strategic Energy Fund Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a temporary oil profit fee and to use the proceeds of the fee collected to provide a Strategic Energy Fund and expand certain energy tax incentives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Geophysical prediction"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2007--Introduced.
Strategic Energy Fund Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish in the Treasury the Strategic Energy Fund to finance the energy conservation and research initiatives set forth by this Act. Increases the tax credits for: (1) investment in alternative fuel vehicle refueling property; (2) small ethanol producers of sucrose or cellulosic ethanol; and (3) investment in advanced coal projects.Extends tax credits for: (1) alcohol used as fuel through 2012; (2) electricity produced from certain renewable resources through 2013; and (3) solar energy property through 2014. Increases the number of hybrid and advanced lean burn technology vehicles eligible for the full amount of the tax credit for alternative motor vehicles.Extends through 2015: (1) the tax credits for biodiesel used as fuel, investment in fuel cell property, new energy efficient home expenditures; and (2) the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial property expenditures.Allows new tax credits for the manufacture of advanced technology motor vehicles, including plug-in hybrid vehicles and investment in small wind energy property.Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a grant program for geological disposal deployment projects.Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish the position of Assistant Secretary for Advanced Energy Research, Technology Development, and Deployment to implement innovative programs for energy conservation.Imposes for taxable years beginning during 2007 or 2008 a 50% excise fee on the excess profit of certain integrated oil companies and producers or refiners of crude oil with gross receipts exceeding $100 million. Provides for the transfer of excise fees to the Strategic Energy Fund. Eliminates certain tax benefits for major oil companies, producers, or refiners, including: (1) the tax deductions for intangible drilling and development costs and for income attributable to domestic production of oil, natural gas, or related products; (2) accelerated amortization of geological and geophysical expenditures; and (3) the tax credit for enhanced oil recovery expenditures and certain foreign tax credits and deferrals.Grants the Secretary of the Interior authority to suspend royalty relief for lessees of federal oil-producing properties and to renegotiate leases based upon price thresholds for oil and natural gas. Places limits on depreciation of certain non-farm heavy passenger motor vehicles.</summary>
</bill>
