<bill session="112" type="s" number="425" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Neurological Diseases Surveillance System Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of permanent national surveillance systems for multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's disease, and other neurological diseases and disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2595"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2011--Introduced.
National Neurological Diseases Surveillance System Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) enhance and expand infrastructure and activities to track the epidemiology of neurological diseases, including multiple sclerosis and Parkinson's disease; and (2) incorporate information obtained through such activities into a National Neurological Diseases Surveillance System. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the System is designed in a manner that facilitates further research on neurological diseases. Requires the Secretary to provide for the collection and storage of information on the incidence and prevalence of neurological diseases in the United States and other information on neurological diseases, such as demographics information, risk factors, or diagnosis and progression markers. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide for the collection and storage of information relevant to analysis on neurological diseases, such as information concerning the epidemiology, natural history, prevention, detection, management, and treatment of the diseases and the development of outcomes measures; and (2) address issues identified through consultations with individuals with appropriate expertise. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, public or private nonprofit entities to carry out activities under this Act. Requires the Secretary to: (1) make information and analysis in the System available to federal agencies and to the public, including researchers; and (2) ensure that privacy and security protections applicable to the System are at least as stringent as federal privacy and security law under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).</summary>
</bill>
