<bill session="109" type="hr" number="248" updated="2013-07-19T18:56:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28T18:22:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-28T18:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 95) establishing the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2006, revising appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal year 2005, and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2007 through 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400328"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-63, by Mr. Putnam.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read and shall be debatable for one hour, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-04-28T16:51:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2693-2702" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 248.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 196 (Roll no. 147).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2701" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2701" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-04-28T18:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2693" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="109" type="hc" number="95"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hc" number="95"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.Con.Res. 95 (establishing the congressional budget for FY 2006). Makes it out of order for a motion that the Committee of the Whole rise and report a bill to the House of Representatives if the bill, as amended, exceeds an applicable allocation of new budget authority under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as estimated by the Committee on the Budget. Requires the Chair of the Committee to put the question regarding the motion if a point of order is sustained. Excludes from such prohibition a motion offered under rule XXI (Restrictions on Certain Bills) or after disposition of the question on a given bill. Makes it out or order, if a question is decided in the negative, for a further amendment except: (1) one proper amendment, under specified conditions; and (2) pro forma amendments, if offered by the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their designees, for debate purposes.</summary>
</bill>
