<bill session="111" type="sj" number="14" updated="2013-07-20T00:16:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A joint resolution to acknowledge a long history of official depredations and ill-conceived policies by the Federal Government regarding Indian tribes and offer an apology to all Native Peoples on behalf of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4976-4977"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4977" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hj" number="46"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Recognizes the special legal and political relationship the Indian tribes have with the United States and the solemn covenant with the land we share. Commends and honors the Native Peoples for the thousands of years that they have stewarded and protected this land. Recognizes that there have been years of official depredations, ill-conceived policies, and the breaking of covenants by the federal government regarding Indian tribes. Apologizes on behalf of the people of the United States to all Native Peoples for the many instances of violence, maltreatment, and neglect inflicted on them by U.S. citizens. Expresses the regret of the United States for the ramifications of former wrongs and its commitment to build on the positive relationships of the past and present to move toward reconciliation. Urges the President to acknowledge the wrongs of the United States against Indian tribes in U.S. history.Commends the state governments that have begun reconciliation efforts with recognized Indian tribes located in their boundaries, and encourages all state governments to do the same. Prohibits anything in this Joint Resolution from authorizing or supporting any claim against the United States or serving as a settlement of any claim against the United States.</summary>
</bill>
