<bill session="111" type="s" number="1346" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crimes Against Humanity Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Crimes Against Humanity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to penalize crimes against humanity and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7010-7011, S7012"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7011-7012" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="474">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 474.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Crimes Against Humanity Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 20 years (or any term of years or for life if death results from a violation of the prohibitions of this Act) on any person who commits or engages in conduct that would violate specified federal criminal laws (including murder, kidnapping, peonage, involuntary servitude, forced labor or trafficking in persons, sex trafficking of children, sexual abuse, hostage taking, torture, extermination, national, ethnic, racial, or religious cleansing, or measures intended to prevent births) as part of a widespread (not less than 50 victims) and systematic attack against any civilian population, with knowledge of the attack. Provides for jurisdiction to prosecute a violation of this Act if: (1) the alleged offender is a U.S. national, an alien residing in the United States, or a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States; or (2) the offense is committed in whole or in part within the United States. Exempts prosecutions under this Act from any statute of limitations. Prohibits a prosecution for a violation of this Act in the United States unless the Attorney General certifies in writing that: (1) there is no foreign jurisdiction prepared to prosecute a violation of this Act and a prosecution by the United States is in the public interest and necessary to secure substantial justice; and (2) the Secretaries of State and Defense and the Director of National Intelligence do not object to a prosecution. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) make unlawful conduct pursuant to the laws of war; (2) limit or extinguish any otherwise available defense or immunity; (3) support ratification of, or participation by the United States in, the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court; or (4) repeal or limit the applicability of the American Servcemembers' Protection Act of 2002.</summary>
</bill>
