<bill session="111" type="h" number="5221" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require air carriers and foreign air carriers to transmit a passenger and crew manifest for a flight in foreign air transportation to or from the United States to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection at least 24 hours before the departure of the flight, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2010-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2010--Introduced.
Requires domestic and foreign air carriers operating a passenger flight in foreign air transportation to or from the United States to provide to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) by electronic transmission a passenger and crew manifest at least 24 hours in advance of the departure of the aircraft to or from the United States. (Currently, such manifests must be provided to the Commissioner of CBP only in advance of a flight landing in the United States.) Requires transmittal to the Commissioner of CBP of supplemental passenger and crew manifests in instances when a passenger acquires a flight ticket or a flight crewmember is assigned to a flight after transmittal of the original manifest. Allows late ticket purchases or crewmember assignments within two hours before depature of a flight only if the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) issues procedures permitting such ticketing and assignments. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to require those air carriers that transmit a passenger and crew manifest to conduct a final comparison of passenger information on the manifest to the no fly list of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) within 60 minutes of a flight's departure.</summary>
</bill>
