<bill session="110" type="h" number="4194" updated="2013-07-19T21:40:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Underage Drinking Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a grant to increase enforcement of laws to prohibit underage drinking through social sources, to improve reporting of Federal underage drinking data, to establish grants to increase parental involvement in school-based efforts to reduce underage drinking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="4453"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2007--Introduced.
Underage Drinking Prevention Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) understanding which programs are effective in reducing underage drinking will maximize scarce federal resources and help confront underage drinking in a more effective, cost-efficient manner; (2) the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration should explore ways to expand and improve evaluation efforts; and (3) federal agencies should strive to evaluate all federally funded underage drinking programs and modify programs as needed to reach maximum effectiveness.Requires the Director of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Programs to award grants to states and local governments to implement and evaluate enforcement and public education programs aimed at reducing the provision of alcohol by social sources to underage drinkers as part of the Enforcing Underage Drinking Laws Program.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as Chair of the Interagency Coordinating Committee on the Prevention of Underage Drinking, to: (1) work with members of that Committee to improve federal data collection by ensuring that federally funded surveys related to underage drinking collect and report data in a consistent manner; and (2) establish a federal data improvement committee.Requires the Secretary of Education to: (1) award grants on a competitive basis to local educational agencies to develop and implement innovative and effective programs to increase parental awareness and involvement in reducing underage drinking in elementary and secondary schools; and (2) identify existing, effective, national programs that increase parent-child interaction to prevent underage drinking and disseminate that information to such agencies for replication at the local level.</summary>
</bill>
