<bill session="109" type="s" number="721" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Army to carry out a program for ecosystem restoration for the Louisiana Coastal Area, Louisiana.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3288-3290"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3288-3289" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Barrier islands"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2005--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to carry out a program for ecosystem restoration, Louisiana Coastal Area, Louisiana, substantially in accordance with the report of the Chief of Engineers, dated January 31, 2005. Directs the Secretary to give priority to any: (1) portion of the program identified in that report as a critical restoration feature; (2) Mississippi River diversion project that protects a major population area of the Pontchartain, Pearl, Breton Sound, Barataria, or Terrebonne Basin and that produces an environmental benefit to the coastal area of Louisiana or Mississippi; and (3) barrier island or shoreline project that is carried out in conjunction with a Mississippi River diversion project and that protects a major population area. Directs the Secretary, in coordination with the Governor of Louisiana, to develop a plan for protecting, preserving, and restoring the coastal Louisiana ecosystem. Establishes the Coastal Louisiana Ecosystem Protection and Restoration Task Force. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop a plan for modifying the Mississippi River Gulf Outlet that addresses wetland losses attributable to the Outlet, channel bank erosion, hurricane storm surges, saltwater intrusion, navigation interests, and environmental restoration; (2) establish a coastal Louisiana ecosystem science and technology program; (3) contract with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to conduct a study to identify causes of degradation of the Area ecosystem attributable to an action by the Secretary; and (4) review each federally-authorized water resources project in the Area to determine whether each project could contribute to ecosystem restoration through modification of the project's operations or features.</summary>
</bill>
