<bill session="111" type="s" number="1564" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arctic Oil Spill Research and Prevention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the readiness of the United States to deal with increased maritime and development activity in the Arctic as a result of climate change, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8685-8687"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2009--Introduced.
Arctic Oil Spill Research and Prevention Act of 2009 - Directs the Commandant of the Coast Guard to assess and take action to reduce the risk of, and improve the U.S. capability to respond to, a maritime disaster in the United States Beaufort and Chukchi Sea, including the prioritization of resources to address such issues as: (1) oil spill response capabilities and infrastructure; (2) coordinating contingency plans and agreements with U.S. agencies, industry, and foreign governments to respond to an Arctic oil spill; and (3) expansion of search and rescue capabilities, infrastructure, and logistics. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and in collaboration with other agencies with appropriate Arctic science expertise, to direct research and take action to improve the U.S. ability to conduct oil spill prevention, response, and recovery in Arctic waters. Requires the Secretary to request that the National Research Council conduct a risk assessment to identify and evaluate existing spill prevention and response standards and develop recommendations that will enhance safety and lessen the potential adverse environmental impacts of industrial activities in Arctic waters. Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to make specified sums in the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund available annually to the Coast Guard, NOAA, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and the Minerals Management Service for Arctic oil spill research and development for FY2010-FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
