<bill session="109" type="h" number="5527" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the authority of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to restructure mortgages and rental assistance for certain assisted multifamily housing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2006-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2006-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2006-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 109-572.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-17T19:26:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="327">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 327.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6115"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3511"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2006--Reported to House amended.
Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997 to reauthorize to October 1, 2011: (1) the Mark-to-Market program; and (2) provisions of the FHA-insured Multifamily Housing Mortgage and Housing Assistance Restructuring program regarding projects and programs for which binding commitments have been entered into under such Act. (Sec. 3) Permits the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to waive rent level limits for up to 9% (currently 5%) of all units subject to restructured mortgages in any fiscal year, based on certain findings of special need. (Sec. 4) Revises requirements for an approved mortgage restructuring and rental assistance sufficiency plan with respect to modification or forgiveness of all or part of a second mortgage held by the Secretary (debt relief) if the project concerned is acquired by a tenant organization or tenant-endorsed community-based nonprofit or public agency. Sets forth requirements for alternative periods of eligibility for such nonprofit debt relief if the purchaser acquires the project subsequent to the date of recordation of the related affordability agreement, and two years after the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 5) Declares disaster-damaged eligible projects eligible without regard to the relationship between rent level for the assisted units and comparable market rents. (Sec. 6) Requires each mortgage restructuring and rental assistance sufficiency plan to determine for units assisted with project-based assistance in eligible multifamily housing projects, if rents cannot be determined, adjusted rent levels: (1) for disaster-damaged eligible projects equal to 100% of the fair market rents for the relevant market area; and (2) for other eligible multifamily housing projects equal to 90% of the fair market rents for the relevant market area. States that, with respect to a disaster-damaged eligible project, the owner contribution toward rehabilitation needs shall be determined in accordance with specified requirements.</summary>
</bill>
