<bill session="109" type="h" number="6070" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance Federal efforts focused on increasing public awareness of the risks and dangers associated with Shaken Baby Syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2006-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Special weeks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2006--Introduced.
Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and implement a public information and educational campaign to inform the public, new parents, child care providers, and other care givers of young children about: (1) brain injuries and other harmful effects that may result from shaking infants and children under five years of age; and (2) healthy strategies to cope with a crying baby and related frustrations. Directs that such campaign include dissemination of effective prevention practices and techniques to parents, care givers, maternity hospitals, child care centers, organizations providing prenatal and postnatal care, and organizations providing parenting education and support services. Requires the Secretary to establish biannual meetings with Shaken Baby Syndrome advocacy groups, parenting support communities, organizations involved in child protection and child maltreatment prevention, and other federal and state agencies involved in prevention activities. Directs the Secretary and such entities to provide support for the parents of surviving children who suffer serious brain injuries as the result of shaking.</summary>
</bill>
