<bill session="112" type="s" number="1515" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permit certain members of the United States Secret Service and certain members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division who were appointed in 1984, 1985, or 1986 to elect to be covered under the District of Columbia Police and Firefighter Retirement and Disability System in the same manner as members appointed prior to 1984.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-08-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/02/2012 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-205.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-08-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="496">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 496.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2532"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/28/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2102 - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of the Senate that members of the U.S. Secret Service Division and the U.S. Secret Service Uniformed Division hired between January 1, 1984, and December 31, 1986, were promised that they would be eligible to participate in the District of Columbia Police and Firefighters Retirement System (DCPFRS). (Sec. 3) Amends the Policemen and Fireman's Retirement and Disability Act of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow certain covered employees of the U.S. Secret Service to elect participation in DCPFRS after notifying the Director of the Secret Service and providing certain information and assurances required by the Director. Requires covered employees to make a lump sum payment into a specified appropriations account of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) equal to the cost of transition into DCPFRS. Defines "covered employee" for purposes of this Act as an individual who: (1) was appointed during 1984, 1985, or 1986 as a member of the Secret Service Uniformed Division or as a criminal investigator; (2) has actively performed duties other than clerical for 10 or more years directly related to the protection mission of the Secret Service; (3) is serving as an officer or member of the Uniformed Division or is employed by the Secret Service as a criminal investigator, and (4) is covered under the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) as of the enactment of this Act. Requires the Director of the Secret Service to notify each covered employee of eligibility for coverage under the D.C. Fireman's Retirement and Disability Act. Requires notification to such covered employees of the cost of transition from FERS to DCPFRS. Requires the Office of Pay and Retirement Services of the District of Columbia to determine the cost of transition to DCPFRS for each covered employee and authorizes such Office to enter into contracts for carrying out activities under this Act. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 4) Requires a covered employee to forfeit all contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund made by an employing agency prior to the effective date of such employee's election under this Act. (Sec. 5) Makes covered employees who accept employment with another federal agency subject to the same pension offset rules that are applicable to reemployed annuitants under FERS and the Civil Service Retirement System. (Sec. 6) Provides for compliance of the budgetary effects of this Act with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
