<bill session="109" type="h" number="5854" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Partnership for Academic Success in the States Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PASS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a pilot program under which the Secretary of Education allows selected States to combine certain funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve the academic achievement of its students.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400020"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Introduced.
Partnership for Academic Success in the States Act, or the PASS Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to implement a competitive pilot program, in up to 10 states, under which, pursuant to a performance agreement with each state, the Secretary: (1) directly provides the grant amount that such state would otherwise receive under one or more specified elementary and secondary education grant programs; and (2) waives the applicability of one or more of the requirements of such programs. Allows the Secretary to terminate a state's participation in the pilot program if it fails for three consecutive years to demonstrate adequate yearly progress toward achieving challenging academic performance standards. Requires the equitable participation of private schools in the use of such grants. Provides for awards to states for reducing achievement gaps.</summary>
</bill>
