<bill session="113" type="s" number="909" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Student Loan Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Direct Loan Program under the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for student loan affordability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3260-3261"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1946"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Responsible Student Loan Solutions Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to limit the unpaid amount of Direct Stafford loans that students may amass before completing their undergraduate education. Varies that limit on the basis of whether a student is a dependent student, independent student, or dependent student whose parents are unable to borrow a Direct PLUS loan. Limits the amount of Direct Stafford loans that students may borrow in any academic year before the completion of their undergraduate studies. Varies that limit on the basis of whether a student: (1) is a dependent student, independent student, or dependent student whose parents are unable to borrow a Direct PLUS loan; and (2) has or has not successfully completed the first year or first and second years of their undergraduate studies. Sets the annual interest rate on Direct loans at the bond equivalent rate on 91-day Treasury bills plus a percentage that: (1) represents the total cost of administering the Direct Loan program and borrower benefits, and (2) results in the program being revenue neutral for the applicable 12-month period. Allows the Secretary of Education to use different percentages under that formula for the Direct Stafford Loan, Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, PLUS Loan, and Consolidation Loan programs. Caps the annual interest rate for Direct Stafford loans at 6.8%, and for Direct Unsubsidized Stafford loans and Direct PLUS and Consolidation loans at 8.25% Directs the Secretary to charge the borrower of a Direct PLUS loan an origination fee of up to 3% of the loan principal. Limits the applicability of the preceding provisions to loans first disbursed on or after July 1, 2013. Authorizes the Secretary to refinance federal PLUS and Stafford loans to permit borrowers to obtain an interest rate determined pursuant to this Act's provisions. Allows the Secretary to charge borrowers an administrative fee for refinancing such loans that does not exceed 0.5% of the loan principal.</summary>
</bill>
