<bill session="109" type="h" number="5491" updated="2013-07-19T19:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securities Litigation Attorney Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect investors by fostering transparency and accountability of attorneys in private securities litigation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2006-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
Securities Litigation Attorney Accountability and Transparency Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Securities Act of 1933 to require, in any private action in which the court enters a final judgment, that the court award the defendant reasonable fees and expenses, and impose such fees and expenses on the plaintiff's attorney, if the plaintiff's position was not substantially justified. Requires each plaintiff and plaintiff's attorney in a private action to provide sworn certifications, filed with the complaint, that identify any conflict of interest, including any direct or indirect payment, between the attorney and the plaintiff. Authorizes the court, in exercising its discretion over the approval of lead counsel, to employ alternative means in the selection and retention of counsel for the most adequate plaintiff, including a competitive bidding process.</summary>
</bill>
