<bill session="111" type="h" number="6510" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Administrator of General Services to convey a parcel of real property in Houston, Texas, to the Military Museum of Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2010-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Norton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8326-8328" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6510.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H.R. 6510.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:57:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T18:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8330-8331" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-12-14T18:48:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="630" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 363 - 0 (Roll no. 630).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8326" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T18:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10695-10696" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-12-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-18">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-01-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-01-04" type="public" number="111-370">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-370.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2011--Public Law.
Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to convey, at a specified market value, to the Military Museum of Texas all U.S. right, title, and interest in and to a certain parcel of real property located at 8611 Wallisville Road in Houston, Texas. Requires an independent appraisal of the market value of the real property, to be paid for by the Military Museum. Requires the conveyance to include improvements, structures, and fixtures located on the conveyed real property and related personal property. Directs the Military Museum to use and maintain the conveyed property, for a minimum period of 30 years, in a manner consistent with the use of it at the time it is conveyed. Reverts, at the option of the Administrator, all or any portion of the conveyed property in its then existing condition to the United States if it ceases to be used or maintained as described above. Permits the Military Museum to seek abrogation of such use restriction by obtaining advance written consent of the Administrator and by payment of the fair market value of the property to be released. Requires the Military Museum to submit annual reports, for a period of 30 years, on the Military Museum's use and maintenance of the conveyed property and any other reports required by the Administrator to evidence the Museum's continuous use of such property. Requires the Administrator to conduct inspections on the conveyed property to confirm the information provided in such reports every 5 years for a period of 30 years. Makes the Military Museum responsible for all reasonable and necessary costs associated with the conveyance, including real estate transaction and environmental documentation costs. Bars anything in this Act being construed to affect or limit the application of or obligation to comply with any environmental law, including requirements under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) with regard to the sale or other transfer of U.S. owned real property on which any hazardous substance was stored for one year or more, known to have been released, or disposed of.</summary>
</bill>
