<bill session="113" type="h" number="1219" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Fisheries Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to provide that each of the States of Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Florida have exclusive fishery management authority over reef fish in the Gulf of Mexico in waters that, on average, are 20 fathoms or less in depth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412394" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2013-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2013--Introduced.
Gulf Fisheries Fairness Act - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to provide each of the states of Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Florida with exclusive fishery management authority over reef fish: (1) within the exclusive economic zone in the Gulf of Mexico in waters of a specified average depth on a continuous line within a minimum distance of nine nautical miles from the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured, and (2) between projected jurisdictional lines determined by the President under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to publish a description and map of the applicable line along the coasts of such states. Prohibits the Secretary from suspending, revoking, terminating, or otherwise limiting the authority of any person under federal law to engage in fishing based on the person fishing for Gulf reef fish in waters subject to the exclusive authority of such states. Exempts such waters from specified federal regulatory requirements addressing fishery permits.</summary>
</bill>
