<bill session="110" type="h" number="885" updated="2013-07-19T21:11:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-18T15:58:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-18T15:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Nuclear Fuel for Peace and Nonproliferation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">International Nuclear Fuel for Peace and Nonproliferation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support the establishment of an international regime for the assured supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means and to authorize voluntary contributions to the International Atomic Energy Agency to support the establishment of an international nuclear fuel bank.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-196.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-18T14:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="117">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 117.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lantos moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6597-6600" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 885.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-06-18T15:58:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6597-6598" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1700"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Netherlands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2007--Passed House amended.
International Nuclear Fuel for Peace and Nonproliferation Act of 2007 - Title I: International Regime for the Assured Supply of Nuclear Fuel for Peaceful Means - (Sec. 103) States that it is U.S. policy to: (1) support the establishment of an international regime for the assured supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means under multilateral authority, such as the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA); (2) oppose the development of a capability to produce nuclear weapons by any non-nuclear weapon state; (3) encourage Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT) states to interpret the right to "develop research, production and use of nuclear energy for peaceful purposes" as a qualified right conditioned by the overall purpose of the NPT to prevent the spread of nuclear weapons and nuclear weapons capability; and (4) strengthen the Nuclear Suppliers Group guidelines concerning consultation by members regarding violations of supplier and recipient understandings by instituting the practice of a timely and coordinated response to such violations, including termination of nuclear transfers to an involved recipient. (Sec. 104) Directs the President to report to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations on U.S. activities to support the establishment of an international regime for the assured supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means at current market prices under multilateral authority, including an assessment of the feasibility of establishing an international fuel services center within the United States. Title II: International Fuel Bank - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the President to make voluntary grant basis contributions to the IAEA for an international nuclear fuel bank to maintain a low-enriched uranium reserve of reactor fuel for eligible countries. Requires the President, prior to making such contributions, to certify to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations that: (1) the IAEA has received specified monetary pledges for the international nuclear fuel bank; (2) the bank will be established in a nonnuclear weapon state under IAEA oversight; (3) the bank will provide nuclear reactor fuel only to a country that is in full compliance with IAEA and other safeguards, agrees to use the nuclear reactor fuel in accordance with IAEA safeguards, does not operate uranium enrichment or spent-fuel reprocessing facilities, and is not a state sponsor of terrorism (which may be waived by the President for national security reasons); (4) the bank will not contain uranium enrichment or spent-fuel reprocessing facilities; and (5) the nuclear reactor fuel will be provided at current market prices. Authorizes FY2008 appropriations, which shall remain available until September 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
