<bill session="110" type="s" number="2806" updated="2013-07-19T22:45:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Greenhouse Gas Endangerment Finding Deadline and California Waiver Reconsideration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to reconsider the decision of the Administrator to deny the request of the State of California to regulate greenhouse gas emissions from new motor vehicles, and to complete further proceedings in accordance with the decision of the Supreme Court in Massachusetts v. Environmental Protection Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2361"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2362" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2008--Introduced.
Greenhouse Gas Endangerment Finding Deadline and California Waiver Reconsideration Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), not later than June 30, 2009, to reconsider, and confirm or reverse, the decision to deny California's request to regulate greenhouse gas emissions from new motor vehicles.Requires the Administrator, not later than 60 days after this Act's enactment, to issue a finding in accordance with: (1) the Clean Air Act with respect to whether such emissions from one or more classes of new motor vehicles or engines causes or contributes to air pollution that may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or welfare; and (2) the decision of the U.S. Supreme Court in Massachusetts v. Environmental Protection Agency.</summary>
</bill>
