<bill session="112" type="h" number="108" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voting Opportunity and Technology Enhancement Rights Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect voting rights and to improve the administration of Federal elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E4"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2212"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Voting Opportunity and Technology Enhancement Rights Act of 2011 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 with respect to: (1) use of a national federal write-in absentee ballot; (2) verified ballots; (3) preservation of voting records; (4) requirements for counting provisional ballots; (5) minimum required voting systems and poll workers in polling places; (6) standards for establishing the minimum required voting systems and poll workers; (7) election day registration; (8) removal from voter registration list; (9) early voting; (10) voting systems and voter registration; (11) Internet registration; (12) voter identification; (13) election administration requirements; (14) required use of publicly available open source software in voting machines; (15) standards for conducting recounts; and (16) standards for prohibiting conflicts of interest of entities involved in manufacture, distribution, or other activities relating to voting machines. Amends the Revised Statutes to prohibit false statements, including those about public endorsements, intended to mislead voters in federal elections. Creates a private right of action for preventive relief against such false statements. Authorizes the Attorney General to communicate to the public corrections to materially false information if state or local election officials have not taken prompt and adequate steps to do so. Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) increase the penalty for voter intimidation; and (2) prohibit voter caging and challenges based on certain evidence. Defines "voter caging document" as: (1) a nonforwardable document that is returned to the sender or a third party as undelivered or undeliverable despite an attempt to deliver it to the address of a registered voter or applicant; or (2) any document with instructions to an addressee that the document be returned to a sender or third party but is not so returned, despite an attempt to deliver it to the address of a registered voter, unless at least two federal election cycles have passed since the date of the attempted delivery. States that the right of a U.S. citizen to vote in any election for federal office shall not be denied or abridged because that individual has been convicted of a criminal offense, unless such individual is serving a felony sentence in a correctional institution or facility at the time of the election. Treats election day in the same manner as a legal public holiday for purposes of federal employment. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress and the President on the impact of such treatment on voter participation. Expresses the sense of Congress that private employers in the United States should give their employees a day off on the Tuesday after the first Monday in November 2012 and each even-numbered year thereafter to enable them to cast votes in the elections held on that day.</summary>
</bill>
