<bill session="109" type="h" number="3060" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Terrorist Death Penalty Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide the death penalty for certain terrorism related crimes and make other modifications of law relating to the penalty of death.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2005-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1763"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Antiaircraft missiles"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Virus diseases"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2005--Introduced.
Terrorist Death Penalty Enhancement Act of 2005 - Amends the federal criminal code to apply the death penalty or life imprisonment for a terrorist offense that results in the death of a person. Makes an individual or corporation convicted of a terrorist offense ineligible for federal benefits for any term of years or for life. Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to make the death penalty available in certain air piracy cases occurring before enactment of the Federal Death Penalty Act of 1994 but after enactment of the Antihijacking Act of 1974. Narrows the language of "especially heinous, cruel, or depraved" by requiring that the act involved torture or serious physical abuse to the victim. Includes among aggravating factors for espionage, treason, and terrorism for which the death penalty may be imposed that the defendant committed the offense after substantial planning. Authorizes imposition of the death penalty for specified terrorism-related offenses, including an offense involving the use of a radiological dispersal device or the variola virus. Modifies death penalty procedures, including by adding as an aggravating factor for homicide for which the death penalty may be imposed that the defendant engaged in any conduct resulting in the death of another person in order to obstruct the investigation or prosecution of any offense. Authorizes impaneling a new jury when a unanimous recommendation cannot be reached. Permits four additional peremptory challenges when seven, eight, or nine alternates are impaneled.</summary>
</bill>
