<bill session="110" type="s" number="1609" updated="2013-07-19T22:34:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Offshore Aquaculture Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide the necessary authority to the Secretary of Commerce for the establishment and implementation of a regulatory system for offshore aquaculture in the United States Exclusive Economic Zone, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7645"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7646-7650" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2010"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1552"/>
    <amendment number="s1553"/>
    <amendment number="s1554"/>
    <amendment number="s1555"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/13/2007--Introduced.
National Offshore Aquaculture Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish an operating permit process for the development and operation of offshore aquaculture facilities in areas of the U.S. Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ). Requires the Secretary to prepare an analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 with respect to the process for issuing permits. Authorizes the Secretary to issue such permits. Prohibits considering offshore aquaculture "fishing" under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act. Prohibits permits for facilities within 12 miles of a coastal state if the state opposes the activities. Authorizes the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to designate a zone around a facility in which incompatible installations, structures, or uses are prohibited. Requires the Secretary of Commerce, for permits for facilities in certain areas subject to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, to obtain the concurrence of the Secretary of the Interior and the consent of lessees, operators, and owners. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish and conduct an integrated, multidisciplinary, scientific research and development program to further marine aquaculture technologies that are compatible with the protection of marine ecosystems; and (2) conduct research and development in partnership with permit holders. Directs the Secretary to conduct research to reduce the use of wild fish in aquaculture feeds.</summary>
</bill>
