<bill session="112" type="hr" number="276" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-25T15:01:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-25T15:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 1540) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2012 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-88, by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Armed Services now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-24T21:31:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="40">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 40.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3423-3430" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3423-3424" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order raised by Mr. Garamendi on the content of the measure. Mr. Garamendi made point of order against the measure and the Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration on H.Res. 276. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order, and if necessary, the Chair will put the question on consideration. Point of order overruled by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 276.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and on ordering the previous question on the resolution, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment and order the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3434-3436" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 181 (Roll no. 341).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3430, H3435" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-05-25T15:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="342" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote: 243 - 170 (Roll no. 342).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="1540"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h300"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/25/2011--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1540 (National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012).</summary>
</bill>
