<bill session="111" type="s" number="1693" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Food for Schools Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to ensure the safety of school meals by enhancing coordination with States and schools operating school meal programs in the case of a recall of contaminated food.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4590"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2009--Introduced.
Safe Food for Schools Act of 2009 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) develop guidelines for determining when it is appropriate to institute an administrative hold on suspect commodities and products being used in school meal programs; (2) work with states to increase their timeliness in notifying schools of food recalls; (3) improve the timeliness and completeness of direct communication with schools about holds and recalls; (4) establish a timeframe for improving commodity hold and recall procedures so that they address the role of processors and distributors, thereby facilitating the provision of more timely and complete information to schools; (5) revise procedures to provide states with more specific instructions for schools about how to dispose of recalled commodities and products and obtain timely reimbursement; and (6) institute a systematic quality check procedure to ensure that holds on commodities and products used by schools are carried out effectively. Directs the Secretary, within one year of this Act's enactment, to revise the procedures of the Food Safety and Inspection Service to ensure that schools are included in recall effectiveness checks.</summary>
</bill>
