<bill session="109" type="s" number="1535" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-07">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to provide compensation to members of the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for damage resulting from the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-572.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator McCain with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-343.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="623">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 623.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-12-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11546-11548" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11546-11548" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08T10:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2006--Passed Senate amended.
Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2006 - Amends the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to make member landowners eligible for the additional financial compensation provided to the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for the acquisition by the federal government of 104,492 acres of land of the Tribe and member landowners for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir project. Defines member landowner as a member of the Tribe (or an heir of such a member) that owned land on the Cheyenne River Sioux Reservation that was acquired by the United States for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin program. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make five annual deposits into the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribal Recovery Trust Fund of: (1) $58,144,591.60; and (2) an additional amount equal to the interest that would have accrued under certain circumstances. Directs the Secretary to invest the Fund only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States according to specified requirements, including separate investments of principal and interest from two separate accounts within the Tribal Recovery Trust Fund. Authorizes the plan prepared for the use of payments to the Tribe to provide for payment of additional compensation to member landowners; except that payments of additional compensation shall not be deposited or transferred into any member landowner's Individual Indian Money account, and shall not exceed an amount equal to 44.3% of the amount transferred by the Secretary of the Interior to the Tribe. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to assist the Tribe in claims processing by providing any record requested to identify the heirs of member landowners within 90 days after receiving a request. Declares that, upon deposit of the final payment into the Fund, all claims that the Tribe has or may have against the United States for the taking of tribal land or property for the Project shall be extinguished.</summary>
</bill>
