<bill session="111" type="h" number="941" updated="2013-07-19T23:20:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Low-Income Rate Payer Disaster Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for disaster assistance for electric utility companies serving low-income households, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400006"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2009--Introduced.
Low-Income Rate Payer Disaster Recovery Act of 2009 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to make contributions to the owner or operator of a private or investor-owned electric utility company serving low-income households for facilities damaged or destroyed by a major disaster only if the costs of repairing, restoring, reconstructing, or replacing such facilities exceed 10% of the facilities' total transmission and distribution rate base minus: (1) accumulated depreciation on the date of the disaster in the case of a single major disaster; or (2) accumulated depreciation on the date of the first major disaster in the case of an aggregation of major disasters during the preceding 12 months. Sets forth application deadlines.Prohibits the total amount of contributions made to an owner or operator from exceeding $50 million in any 12-month period. Authorizes the President, for any major disaster occurring after enactment of this Act, to waive the limit upon determining that the event is of an extraordinary nature. Requires the President to approve or disapprove applications within 30 days after receipt.Allows an owner or operator who determines that the public welfare would not best be served by repairing, restoring, reconstructing, or replacing a facility to elect to receive, in lieu of the cost-based contribution, 75% of the funding that would have been available.</summary>
</bill>
