<bill session="112" type="s" number="1885" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible Unemployment Extension Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a temporary extension of unemployment insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="584"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="734"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3346"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="18"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="164"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="262"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1726"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1804"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Responsible Unemployment Extension Act - Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 with respect to the state-established individual emergency unemployment compensation account (EUCA). Extends the final date for entering a federal-state agreement under the Emergency Unemployment Compensation (EUC) program through January 3, 2013. Postpones the termination of the program until June 8, 2013. Amends the Assistance for Unemployed Workers and Struggling Families Act to extend until January 4, 2013, requirements that federal payments to states cover 100% of EUC. Amends the Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008 to exempt weeks of unemployment between enactment of this Act and June 9, 2013, from the prohibition in the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 against federal matching payments to a state for the first week in an individual's eligibility period for which extended compensation or sharable regular compensation is paid if the state law provides for payment of regular compensation to an individual for his or her first week of otherwise compensable unemployment. (Thus allows temporary federal matching for the first week of extended benefits for states with no waiting period.) Rescinds specified unobligated discretionary funds. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to determine and identify from which appropriation accounts such rescissions shall apply, including their amounts. Exempts from rescission any unobligated funds of the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), or the Army Corps of Engineers.</summary>
</bill>
