<bill session="113" type="h" number="2750" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Design-Build Efficiency and Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 41, United States Code, to require the use of two-phase selection procedures when design-build contracts are suitable for award to small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2013--Introduced.
Design-Build Efficiency and Jobs Act of 2013 - Modifies the procedure for awarding design and construction contracts for federal buildings and facilities to require: (1) a contracting officer to provide a written justification to the head of an agency for requiring more than five finalists in the bidding process for such contracts and agency approval of such justification; and (2) the use of the two-phase selection process (i.e., submission of qualifications and then the submission of price and technical proposals in response to a request for proposal) for contracts having a value of $750,000 or greater. Requires each agency that awards design and construction contracts to submit to the Comptroller General (GAO) and publish in the Federal Register an annual report on: (1) all contracts for which more than five finalists were selected for phase-two requests for competitive proposals, and (2) contracts having a value of $750,000 or greater for which the two-phase selection process was not used. Requires the Comptroller General to publish a report that analyzes the compliance of federal agencies with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
