<bill session="112" type="h" number="2150" updated="2013-07-20T01:28:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Petroleum Reserve Alaska Access Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Petroleum Reserve Alaska Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Naval Petroleum Reserves Production Act of 1976 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct an expeditious program of competitive leasing of oil and gas in the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska, including at least one lease sale in the Reserve each year in the period 2011 through 2021, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412476" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412415" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2011-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 14.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T14:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-249.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-14T14:54:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="165">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 165.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4480"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/2011--Reported to House without amendment.
National Petroleum Reserve Alaska Access Act - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the National Petroleum Reserve (NPR) in Alaska remains explicitly designated to provide oil and natural gas resources to the United States, and (2) it is national policy to actively advance oil and gas development within the NPR. (Sec. 3) Amends the Naval Petroleum Reserves Production Act of 1976 to require the mandatory program of competitive leasing of oil and gas in the NPR to include at least one lease sale annually in those areas of the NPR most likely to produce commercial quantities of oil and natural gas each year in the period 2011-2021. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to ensure permits, according to a specified timeline, for all surface development activities, including pipelines and roads construction to: (1) develop and bring into production any areas within the NPR that are subject to oil and gas leases; and (2) transport oil and gas from and through the NPR to existing transportation or processing infrastructure on the North Slope of Alaska. (Sec. 5) Instructs the Secretary to issue regulations establishing clear requirements to ensure that the Department of the Interior is supporting development of oil and gas leases in the NPR. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to assess all technically recoverable fossil fuel resources within the NPR, including all conventional and unconventional oil and natural gas. Requires the resource assessment to be implemented by the U.S. Geological Survey, which is authorized to use resources and funds provided by the state of Alaska.</summary>
</bill>
