<bill session="112" type="h" number="967" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bed Bug Management, Prevention, and Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 and the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to support efforts to control and eradicate bed bugs with respect to public health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2011-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Horticulture .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Nutrition and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2011--Introduced.
Bed Bug Management, Prevention, and Research Act - Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to: (1) award grants for bed bug management and eradication, (2) appoint a bed bug task force, and (3) award grants for related research projects. Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to include bed bugs in the definition of "vector." Requires the submission and evaluation of efficacy data if a pesticide is labeled for or proposed to be labeled for the control of a public health pest. Prohibits the sale or distribution of any product that is marketed, distributed, or sold with a claim that such product will control a public health pest if the submitted data does not support such claim. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to award grants through September 30, 2017, to three state agencies for a pilot program under which state subdivisions and housing authorities use such funds to supplement ongoing bed bug prevention and mitigation activities. (Requires at least one of the three grants to be awarded to a state agency that before November 1, 2009, submitted a public health exemption request which proposed a pesticide use to control bed bugs but which was voluntarily canceled.)</summary>
</bill>
