<bill session="112" type="h" number="3856" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Waters Partnership Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the authority of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency with respect to certain numeric nutrient criteria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412408"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412414" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412415" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412410" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2012-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2012--Introduced.
State Waters Partnership Act of 2012 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA): (1) should take into account the effect of numeric nutrient criteria for nitrogen or phosphorus developed to meet the water quality requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) on the economy, job creation, consumers, municipalities, agriculture, small business, and other affected sectors; and (2) should not promulgate or enforce any nutrient criteria that would result in a negative economic impact of at least 15% on any such sector. Prohibits the Administrator from proposing, promulgating, or enforcing numeric nutrient criteria for streams, lakes, springs, canals, estuaries, or marine waters of Florida until the Administrator makes a final determination in accordance with such Act regarding the Florida amended rule approved for adoption by the Environmental Regulation Commission on December 8, 2011. Provides that if the Administrator determines that such rule meets the requirements of such Act: (1) the Administrator shall withdraw specified regulations concerning site-specific alternative criteria; and (2) the Administrator shall be prohibited from proposing or promulgating numeric nutrient criteria for streams, lakes, springs, canals, estuaries, or marine waters of Florida based on EPA's January 14, 2009, determination regarding numeric nutrient criteria.</summary>
</bill>
