<bill session="109" type="h" number="5852" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-25T13:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-25T13:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Emergency Communications Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">21st Century Emergency Communications Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance emergency communications at the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5696-5705" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5852.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T11:40:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5742-5743" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-07-25T13:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="397" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 2 (Roll no. 397).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5696-5698" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2006--Passed House without amendment.
21st Century Emergency Communications Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) an Office of Emergency Communications, to be headed by the Assistant Secretary for Emergency Communications. Includes among the Assistant Secretary's responsibilities: (1) assisting the Secretary of DHS in developing and implementing the program to enhance public safety interoperable communications at all levels of government; (2) administering DHS authorities for the SAFECOM Program, the Integrated Wireless Network program, and the Interoperable Communications Technical Assistance Program; (3) coordinating administration of the National Communications System; (4) facilitating creation of Regional Emergency Communications Coordination Working Groups; (5) establishing requirements for total and nonproprietary interoperable emergency communications capabilities for all public safety radio and data communications systems and equipment purchased using DHS assistance; and (6) coordinating with the Director of the Office for Interoperability and Compatibility. Directs the Secretary, through the Assistant Secretary, to: (1) assess the range of emergency communications capabilities needed, the current capabilities, and the gap between the two; (2) develop a National Emergency Communications Report to provide recommendations regarding how the United States can accelerate the deployment of interoperable emergency communications nationwide; (3) report annually on the degree to which such communications have been achieved and on the feasibility of developing a mobile communications capability; and (4) ensure that grant guidelines for the use of DHS assistance relating to interoperable emergency communications are coordinated and consistent with Report goals and recommendations. Requires the Secretary to: (1) support the development of national voluntary consensus standards for interoperable emergency communications; and (2) prohibit a governmental jurisdiction from using DHS assistance for new equipment or systems that do not meet such standards. Establishes the Emergency Communications Preparedness Center to serve as the focal point for interagency efforts to address operable and interoperable communications. Directs the Secretary to provide technical guidance, training, and other assistance to support the rapid establishment of effective interoperable emergency communications capabilities in emergencies in areas determined to be at consistently high risk from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other emergencies. Requires that such capabilities ensure the ability of all levels of government, emergency response and support providers, the private sector, and other organizations with emergency response capabilities to: (1) communicate with each other; (2) have timely access to the Information Sharing Environment described in the National Security Intelligence Reform Act of 2004; and (3) be consistent with any applicable state or urban area homeland strategy or plan. (Sec. 3) Requires the Director of the Office of Interoperability and Compatibility to: (1) assist the Secretary in developing and implementing the science and technology aspects of public safety interoperable communications programs of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act; (2) support the creation of national voluntary consensus standards for interoperable emergency communications; (3) establish a comprehensive research, development, testing, and evaluation program for improving interoperable emergency communications; (4) evaluate and assess new technology in real-world environments to achieve interoperable emergency communications capabilities; and (5) coordinate with the private sector to develop solutions to improve and achieve such capabilities. (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress that in carrying out DHS responsibilities relating to the SAFECOM Program, the Assistant Secretary and the Director should work with the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to implement the Project 25 Compliance Assessment Program.</summary>
</bill>
