<bill session="111" type="h" number="1318" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Afghanistan-Pakistan Security and Prosperity Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide duty-free treatment for certain goods from designated Reconstruction Opportunity Zones in Afghanistan and Pakistan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400415"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412296" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2009-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E556"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2009--Introduced.
Afghanistan-Pakistan Security and Prosperity Enhancement Act - Authorizes the President to designate Reconstruction Opportunity Zones within Afghanistan or Pakistan, provided certain eligibility criteria are met, including that: (1) such countries establish, or make progress toward establishing, a market-based economy, instituting rule of law, protecting core labor standards, and eliminating barriers to trade and investment; (2) such countries can be designated as a beneficiary developing country; and (3) the designation of a Reconstruction Opportunity Zone is appropriate taking into account certain qualifying factors. Provides for the duty-free treatment of certain textile and apparel products, as well as nontextile and nonapparel products, from a Reconstruction Opportunity Zone through September 30, 2024. Sets forth requirements to prevent the unlawful transshipment of such products. Continues the duty-free treatment of such products from a Reconstruction Opportunity Zone in Afghanistan or Pakistan only if the President certifies to Congress that such countries have met certain requirements, including: (1) designation of a labor official; and (2) have agreed to require textile or apparel exporting enterprises to participate in a technical assistance, capacity building, compliance assessment, and remediation program. Authorizes the President to withdraw, suspend, or limit the application of duty-free treatment under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
