<bill session="111" type="s" number="1426" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Guard and Reserve Soft Landing Reintegration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the retention on active duty after demobilization of members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces following extended deployments in contingency operations or homeland defense mission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3358"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6279"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3748"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2009--Introduced.
National Guard and Reserve Soft Landing Reintegration Act - Requires that a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who was deployed for more than 179 days for a contingency operation or a homeland defense mission be: (1) retained on active duty in the Armed Forces for 90 days after the end of the member's demobilization from a deployment; (2) allowed to use accrued leave; and (3) paid specified pay and allowances. Allows a member to be released from such retention if the member requests release after the first 15 days of the retention. Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide each member so retained (and, as practicable, appropriate family members) reintegration counseling and services.</summary>
</bill>
