<bill session="113" type="h" number="1928" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proprietary Institution of Higher Education Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the calculation of cohort default rates for proprietary institutions of higher education under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Proprietary Institution of Higher Education Accountability Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education, in calculating the cohort default rate for a proprietary institution of higher education, to treat its current and former students who have received a specified forbearance or deferment of over six months on direct loans before the end of the second fiscal year after they enter repayment on such loans, as students who have defaulted on such loans before the end of such second fiscal year. Applies that calculation to forbearances: (1) that have been agreed to by the parties to an insured loan and approved by the insurer, or (2) for borrowers whose educational debt burden equals or exceeds 20% of their income. Applies that calculation to deferments for borrowers who: (1) are seeking and unable to find full-time employment, or (2) have or will experience an economic hardship.</summary>
</bill>
