<bill session="111" type="s" number="1050" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Informed Consumer Choices in Health Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to establish Federal standards for health insurance forms, quality, fair marketing, and honesty in out-of-network coverage in the group and individual health insurance markets, to improve transparency and accountability in those markets, and to establish a Federal Office of Health Insurance Oversight to monitor performance in those markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-06-04" withdrawn="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5523-5524, S5528"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5524-5527" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2427"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
Informed Consumer Choices in Health Care Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) develop standards for health insurance issuers in providing information to group health plans, for forms used in connection with group health insurance coverage, for quality assurance, for marketing of group health insurance coverage, and for the accuracy and clarity of coverage for out-of-network providers; (2) undertake activities to promote accountability of health insurance issuers in meeting federal health insurance requirements; (3) provide grants to Departments of Insurance in states to assist in enforcement of federal health insurance requirements governing health insurance issuers operating in such states; (4) undertake activities to promote transparency in costs, market practices, and other factors for health insurance coverage; and (5) establish within HHS an Office of Health Insurance Oversight to promote accountability and transparency in health insurance and provide for assistance to consumers in selecting health care coverage. Directs the Secretaries of Labor and the Treasury to establish standards and accountability and transparency initiatives for group health plans comparable to the standards established by the HHS Secretary under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
