<bill session="109" type="h" number="3901" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International U.S. Seniors Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide certain Medicare beneficiaries living abroad a special Medicare part B enrollment period during which the late enrollment penalty is waived and a special Medigap open enrollment period during which no underwriting is permitted.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3654"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2005--Introduced.
International U.S. Seniors Act of 2005 - Provides for a Medicare part B (Supplementary Medicare Insurance) special enrollment period, waiver of the late enrollment penalty, and a Medigap special open enrollment period for certain individuals 65 years or older who live abroad. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should enter into an international convention with respect to individuals 65 or older who live abroad under which the nation of which the individual is a citizen agrees to reimburse another nation in which the individual lawfully resides for the costs of health care furnished to the individual while residing in that nation.</summary>
</bill>
