<bill session="110" type="h" number="7267" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mortgage Credit Repair Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to requirements relating to information contained in consumer reports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400270"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2008--Introduced.
Mortgage Credit Repair Act of 2008 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to define "front end ratio" as a ratio that indicates what portion of an individual's income is used to make mortgage payments, calculated by dividing an individual's gross monthly income by their housing expenses, particularly the mortgage principal, interest, taxes, and insurance (PITI). Prohibits a consumer reporting agency from making a consumer report containing cases under title 11 or under the Bankruptcy Act that antedate the report by more than three years when certain criteria are met. Includes among such criteria that a consumer's front-end debt ratio on a mortgage instrument originated or refinanced on or after January 1, 2003, was 37% or higher for at least six months before and continuing through the time that the bankruptcy is filed. Prohibits a consumer reporting agency from making a consumer report containing any adverse information excluding bankruptcy, but including closed accounts, amounts in collections, accounts charged to profit or loss, repossessions, and foreclosures, if certain circumstances have occurred.</summary>
</bill>
