<bill session="111" type="h" number="1156" updated="2013-07-19T23:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Parents' Right to Know Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies to provide to parents, on request, information regarding the professional qualifications of their child's pupil services instructors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2009--Introduced.
Parents&#146; Right to Know Improvement Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies (LEAs) to notify the parents of each student at the beginning of each school year that they will provide the parents, upon request, with timely information regarding the professional qualifications of their child's specialized pupil services instructors. (This is in addition to the current requirement that LEAs provide parents, upon request, with information regarding the professional qualifications of their child's classroom teachers.) Defines "pupil services instructors" as qualified professionals who provide ongoing, direct instruction to disabled children with individualized education programs.</summary>
</bill>
