<bill session="110" type="h" number="3411" updated="2013-07-19T21:33:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Juvenile Crime Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the treatment of juveniles with mental health or substance abuse disorders by establishing new grant programs for increased training, technical assistance, and coordination of service providers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Introduced.
Juvenile Crime Reduction Act - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to allow the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to award grants to public agencies to: (1) provide training to individuals involved in making decisions regarding the disposition of cases involving youth who enter the juvenile justice system; and (2) develop a plan to address the service needs of juveniles with mental health or substance abuse disorders who come into contact with, or are at risk of coming into contact with, the justice system. Requires the Administrator to award matching grants to public agencies to implement such plan.Authorizes the Administrator to award grants for the establishment of four regional research, training, and technical assistance centers.Requires the Administrator to award grants to public agencies to reform their mental health and substance abuse policies with respect to juveniles who come into contact with the juvenile justice system.Requires states receiving juvenile justice grants to include in their state plan information regarding screening, assessment, and treatment of juveniles with mental health and substance abuse disorders. Requires the Administrator to: (1) distribute evidence-based practice bonuses to grant recipients if certain requirements are met; and (2) include in the Office's annual report to Congress information regarding the prevalence of mental health disorders among juveniles.Requires the Coordinating Council on Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to examine and report on evidence-based practices for decreasing delinquency and recidivism among juveniles with mental health or substance abuse disorders.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that a portion of grants awarded under programs to divert individuals with a mental illness from the criminal justice system specifically target juveniles if appropriations for such grants exceed a specified amount.</summary>
</bill>
