<bill session="109" type="h" number="4476" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Network for Avian Influenza Surveillance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a global network for avian influenza surveillance among wild birds nationally and internationally to combat the growing threat of bird flu, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2005-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2005-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Horticulture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1912"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2005--Introduced.
Global Network for Avian Influenza Surveillance Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Influenza Branch of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to offer to enter into a contract with one or more eligible organizations to establish a Global Network for Avian Influenza Surveillance (GNAIS). Requires the eligible organization to manage an international surveillance program under which federal GNAIS partners: (1) monitor and test for the presence or arrival of avian influenza and other significant avian pathogens; (2) use trained professionals to collect samples and other data; (3) use the GNAIS for conducting disease surveillance, field investigations, training and capacity-building activities, and research; and (4) transmit information related to global distribution and characteristics of avian influenza to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary, acting through the eligible organization, to: (1) use surveillance reports and other sources to identify and investigate local disease outbreaks of avian influenza; (2) develop a long-term baseline of regional data to identify when and where outbreaks might occur and paths of dispersal; (3) provide technical assistance for disease prevention and control programs; (4) provide analytical disease findings to the Influenza Branch of CDC and other federal GNAIS partners; and ( 5) manage, map, and make available on an Internet database all results and information gathered under this Act. Directs the Secretary to request accredited colleges of veterinary medicine and other GNAIS partners to train members of the GNAIS network to: (1) monitor important bird areas around the world; and (2) test for the presence or arrival of avian influenza and other significant avian pathogens of zoonotic concern.</summary>
</bill>
