<bill session="111" type="h" number="4040" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Big Sur Forest Service Management Unit Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To redesignate the Monterey Ranger District of Los Padres National Forest in the State of California as the Big Sur Management Unit, to transfer certain Bureau of Land Management land for inclusion in the management unit, to adjust the boundaries of the Ventana and Silver Peak Wilderness Areas, to designate segments of Arroyo Seco River, Big Creek, Carmel River, San Antonio River, San Carpoforo Creek, and their tributaries as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400129"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2009--Introduced.
Big Sur Forest Service Management Unit Act of 2009 - Establishes the Big Sur Management Unit of Los Padres National Forest in California to replace the Monterey Ranger District in the Forest. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) all Bureau of Land Management (BLM) administered public lands within the boundaries of the Unit for inclusion in the Unit. Authorizes the lease or issuance of permits for the use of all or a part of Brazil Ranch. Designates the Unit as a Wildland Urban Interface Special Study Area. Requires the Secretary to: (1) make use of existing authority and resources to pioneer innovative fire pre-suppression methods consistent with public safety and wilderness values; (2) create and annually update a fire management plan applicable to the Unit; and (3) establish agency approval procedures for responding to fire emergencies in the Unit. Adjusts the boundaries of the Ventana Wilderness Area. Designates the Horse Canyon and Horse Pasture proposed wilderness additions as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Adjusts the boundaries of the Silver Peak Wilderness Area. Designates the Alder Creek proposed wilderness addition as wilderness and a component of such System. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to take measures in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by this Act necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases. Designates: (1) specified segments of the Arroyo Seco River, Big Creek, Carmel River, San Antonio River, and San Carpoforo Creek and their tributaries in Big Sur, California, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; (2) Forest Service Road 19S09, to be known as the Arroyo Seco-Indians Trail, as a National Recreation Trail; and (3) the Jeff Norman Botanical Area.</summary>
</bill>
