<bill session="111" type="s" number="3826" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulations From the Executive in Need of Scrutiny Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to provide that major rules of the executive branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3765"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
Regulations From the Executive in Need of Scrutiny Act of 2010 - Rewrites provisions regarding congressional review of agency rulemaking to require congressional approval of major rules of the executive branch before they may take effect (currently, major rules take effect unless Congress passes and the President signs a joint resolution disapproving them). Provides that if a joint resolution of approval of a major rule is not enacted by the end of 90 session days or legislative days after such resolution is introduced, the rule shall be deemed not to be approved and shall not take effect. Permits a major rule to take effect for 90 calendar days without such approval if the President determines such rule is necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency, for the enforcement of criminal laws, for national security, or to implement an international trade agreement.Sets forth procedures of the House of Representatives and the Senate for joint resolutions: (1) approving major rules; and (2) disapproving nonmajor rules.</summary>
</bill>
