<bill session="111" type="h" number="584" updated="2013-07-19T23:17:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Menopausal Hormone Replacement Therapies and Alternative Treatments and Fairness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for coverage of hormone replacement therapy for treatment of menopausal symptoms, and for coverage of an alternative therapy for hormone replacement therapy for such symptoms, under the Medicare and Medicaid Programs, group health plans and individual health insurance coverage, and other Federal health insurance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Labor, Oversight and Government Reform, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2009--Introduced.
Menopausal Hormone Replacement Therapies and Alternative Treatments and Fairness Act of 2009 - Amends the Social Security Act to include coverage of hormone replacement therapy for menopausal symptoms and alternative treatments for such therapy under Medicare (title XVIII of the Act). Includes alternative treatments for hormone replacement therapy for menopausal symptoms under Medicaid (title XIX of the Act). Requires coverage of hormone replacement therapy for menopausal symptoms and alternative treatments for such therapy on the same basis as outpatient prescription drugs under: (1) the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) (group health plans and group and individual health insurance); (2) the Internal Revenue Code (group health plans); and (3) federal employee health benefit plans. Includes alternative treatments for hormone replacement therapy for menopausal symptoms under veterans' benefits.</summary>
</bill>
