<bill session="113" type="h" number="2433" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stem Cell Research Advancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for human stem cell research, including human embryonic stem cell research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2013-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2013--Introduced.
Stem Cell Research Advancement Act of 2013 -Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct and support research that utilizes human stem cells, including human embryonic stem cells. Limits such research to human embryonic stem cells that have been derived from cells from human embryos that: (1) were created using in vitro fertilization for reproductive purposes and are no longer needed for those purposes, and (2) were donated by the individuals who sought reproductive treatment with written and voluntary informed consent for the embryos to be used for research purposes and without receiving any financial or other inducements. Requires the Secretary to maintain, review, and update as scientifically warranted guidelines applicable to the conduct or support of human stem cell research by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Prohibits the Secretary from using any funds for the conduct or support of human cloning. Defines "human cloning" to mean the implantation of the product of transferring the nuclear material of a human somatic cell into an egg cell from which the nuclear material has been removed or rendered inert into a uterus or the functional equivalent of a uterus. Requires the Secretary to update the guidelines maintained pursuant to this Act for consistency with such prohibition. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to include information on human stem cells in the biennial report to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
