<bill session="113" type="h" number="2886" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Cost of Carbon Transparency Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require agency notice and receipt of public comment before using any estimate for the social cost of carbon, to require reports on the results of and methods used to calculate any cost-benefit or regulatory impact analysis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2013-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2593"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Social Cost of Carbon Transparency Enhancement Act of 2013 - Prohibits the head of a federal agency from using an estimate for the social cost of carbon until the completion of the rulemaking notice period and the receipt of public comment on such estimate. Requires an agency head, after the completion of any cost-benefit or regulatory impact analysis used to promulgate rules or guidelines or to determine administrative actions, to: (1) submit to relevant congressional committees a report on the result of, and methods (including any method that determines the social cost of carbon) used to calculate, the cost-benefits or regulatory impact analysis; and (2) publish such report in the Federal Register. Prohibits the finalization of any cost-benefit or regulatory impact analysis for 60 days after the submission of such report and requires an agency head, during such 60-day period, to evaluate the potential benefits of each cost-benefit or regulatory impact analysis using specified criteria.</summary>
</bill>
