<bill session="110" type="h" number="1999" updated="2013-07-19T21:21:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hope Fund Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for assistance for the National Council of La Raza and the Raza Development Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2007-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community facilities"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2007--Introduced.
Hope Fund Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make a grant to the National Council of La Raza to provide technical and financial assistance to local non-profit organizations to undertake community development and affordable housing projects and programs serving low- and moderate-income households, particularly through organizations located in neighborhoods with substantial populations of income-disadvantaged households of Hispanic origin. Authorizes the National Council of La Raza, or the Raza Development Fund, to use such funds to: (1) provide technical and financial assistance for site acquisition and development, construction financing, and short- and long-term financing for housing, community facilities, and economic development; (2) leverage capital from private entities, including private financial institutions, insurance companies, and private philanthropic organizations; and (3) provide technical assistance, training, support, and advice to develop the management, financial, and administrative capabilities of housing development organizations serving low-income households, including Hispanic households.</summary>
</bill>
