<bill session="112" type="h" number="2326" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Innovation in Education Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish the National Education Innovation Network and the National Innovation Corps.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Innovation in Education Act of 2011 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require the Secretary of Education to establish and maintain a National Education Innovation Network of searchable databases or Internet websites that: (1) provide educators and administrators with information regarding the most promising practices and strategies for improving student achievement and turning around low-performing schools; and (2) allow educators and administrators to nominate new practices and strategies for inclusion in such databases or websites, recommend improvements to those already there, and exchange ideas with their peers. Directs the Secretary to provide grants and technical assistance to states to establish a National Education Innovation Corps that connects educators and administrators with evidence-based solutions to the most critical problems of practice in local educational agencies and chronically low-performing schools. Requires the Corps to be composed of: (1) knowledge brokers, who have expertise in education, research, and the implementation of innovations; and (2) practice experts, who have successful teaching experience. Allocates Corps grants among states in proportion to each state's share of school improvement funds under part A of title I of the ESEA.</summary>
</bill>
