<bill session="111" type="h" number="5169" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Event Data Recorder Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate rules to require that all motor vehicles be equipped with event data recorders by 2015, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5345"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
Event Data Recorder Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to modify certain federal motor vehicle safety standards to require that passenger automobiles (except trailers) be equipped with: (1) an event data recorder (EDR) meeting certain requirements; and (2) a standardized port for accessing and retrieving data stored in any EDR regardless of the manufacturer or model of the motor vehicle. Requires manufacturers of passenger automobiles to include EDRs in: (1) at least 25% of their fleet beginning in model 2013; (2) at least 65% of their fleet beginning in model year 2014; and (3) 100% of their fleet beginning in model year 2015. Requires the owner's manual of new motor vehicles sold or leased in the United States to indicate clearly the presence of EDRs. Prohibits the retrieval of information recorded or transmitted by an EDR by any other person than the owner of the motor vehicle in which such device is installed unless: (1) authorized by court order, the owner consents, or the information is retrieved by a government motor vehicle safety agency; and (2) the personally identifiable information of the owner or driver of the vehicle or vehicle identification number (VIN) is not disclosed in the retrieval of information.</summary>
</bill>
