<bill session="113" type="sr" number="203" updated="2013-11-02T06:51:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding efforts by the United States to resolve the Israeli-Palestinian conflict through a negotiated two-state solution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6078-6079" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2013--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) a two-state solution is the only outcome to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict which can ensure Israel's survival as a secure, democratic homeland for the Jewish people and fulfill the legitimate aspirations of the Palestinian people for their own state; (2) achievement of a two-state solution that would enhance stability and security in the Middle East is a fundamental U.S. security interest; (3) while only Israel and Palestine can make the difficult choices necessary to end their conflict, the United States remains indispensable to any viable effort to achieve that goal; (4) Secretary of State John Kerry is to be commended for his efforts to advance a negotiated two-state solution; and (5) the Senate pledges its support for a sustained U.S. diplomatic initiative to help Israel and Palestine conclude an agreement to end their conflict.</summary>
</bill>
