<bill session="109" type="h" number="5559" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Independent Health Record Bank Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the exchange of health information by encouraging the creation, use, and maintenance of lifetime electronic health records in independent health record banks, by using such records to build a nationwide health information technology infrastructure, and by promoting participation in health information exchanges by consumers through tax incentives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2006-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2006-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3454"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2006--Introduced.
Independent Health Record Bank Act of 2006 - Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to prescribe standards for the establishment and certification of independent health record banks to store individual electronic health records. Gives an individual ownership over his/her entire health record with the right to review its contents at any time during normal business hours. Allows a bank to generate revenue through the sale of nonidentifiable and partially identifiable health information contained in the bank for research purposes, but requires that such revenue be shared with account holders and allows such revenue to be shared with health care providers and payers. Excludes any such revenue from the gross income of the bank, account holder, or health care provider or payer. Requires prior authorization by an individual before access can be given to his/her electronic health record. Permits access to a limited, authenticated information set concerning an individual for emergency response purposes without the individual's prior consent. Requires the Board of Governors, acting through the Under Secretary for Technology or other appropriate official, to: (1) develop a program to certify entities to operate independent health record banks; and (2) establish an interagency council to develop standards for federal security auditing for entities operating banks. Imposes fines and/or imprisonment for the wrongful disclosure of information collected, maintained, or made available by a record bank. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax deduction for the cost paid by a taxpayer to maintain an independent health record bank account.</summary>
</bill>
