<bill session="109" type="s" number="1903" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Generic Prescription Drug Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to require drug manufacturers to report the average manufacturer price and the best price of authorized generic drugs and any other drugs sold under a new drug application approved under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2005-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Generic drugs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2005--Introduced.
Generic Prescription Drug Fairness Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for drug manufacturer reports to the Secretary of Health and Human Services on the average manufacturer price for each covered outpatient drug and the manufacturer's best price for single source and innovator multiple source drugs. Requires manufacturers to report also on the manufacturer's best price for each authorized generic drug and any other drugs sold under a new drug application approved under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Applies the basic rebate for single source and innovator multiple source drugs to authorized generic drugs and any other drugs sold under an approved new drug application.</summary>
</bill>
