<bill session="112" type="h" number="1326" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Furthering International Nuclear Safety Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To underscore the importance of international nuclear safety cooperation for operating power reactors, encouraging the efforts of the Convention on Nuclear Safety, supporting progress in improving nuclear safety, enhancing the public availability of nuclear safety information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400640"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2011-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2011-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2011--Introduced.
Furthering International Nuclear Safety Act of 2011 - Directs the President to instruct the U.S. delegate to the Convention on Nuclear Safety to encourage: (1) parties to more systematically assess their progress in improving safety; (2) parties to increase the number of national reports and related answers to questions available to the public by posting them to a publicly available website of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA); (3) the IAEA to assist the preparation of national reports and provide technical support to improve civilian nuclear program safety; (4) countries that currently have or are considering the establishment of a civilian nuclear power program to formally join the Convention; and (5) parties to expand cooperation on prediction and analysis capability for earthquakes, tsunamis, and on radiation as it is transported away from nuclear sites. Directs the Secretary of State to submit to Congress the U.S. government's strategic plan and goals for international nuclear safety cooperation for operating power reactors. Sets forth reporting requirements regarding: (1) implementation of such strategic plan, and (2) U.S. efforts to further international nuclear safety. Defines "party'' as a nation that has formally joined the Convention.</summary>
</bill>
