<bill session="112" type="h" number="1231" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12T14:25:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-12T14:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reversing President Obama's Offshore Moratorium Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Reversing President Obama's Offshore Moratorium Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Reversing President Obama's Offshore Moratorium Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require that each 5-year offshore oil and gas leasing program offer leasing in the areas with the most prospective oil and gas resources, to establish a domestic oil and natural gas production goal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412481" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412476" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412475" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412416" joined="2011-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 14.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-69.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-05-02T15:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="37">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 37.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-10T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 257 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1231 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted and that the bill, as amended, shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 257 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 257.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3189-3193" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1231 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted and the bill, as amended, shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 257 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Candice S. Miller to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 257, the amendment recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1231.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1231 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3193-3207" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed general debate on H.R. 1231.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly (VA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly (VA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly (VA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T16:59:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Keating amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Keating amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Keating demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tsongas amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tsongas amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Tsongas demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brown(FL) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Brown (FL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thompson (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Thompson (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Thompson (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 257, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Inslee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Inslee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Inslee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1231 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3237-3242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T13:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1231.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/11/2011 H3196" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Holt moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3240-3242" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3240" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require each oil and gas leasing program in the underlying bill to specify that all oil and natural gas produced from such leases under the program, is offered for sale in the United States and not exported. It would also require the Secretary of Interior, in developing a 5-year oil and gas leasing program, to seek to reduce the number of nonproducing offshore oil and gas leases by 50 percent by 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 243 (Roll no. 319).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-05-12T14:25:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="320" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 243 - 179 (Roll no. 320).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-05-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="52">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="257"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3410"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2365"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h280"/>
    <amendment number="h281"/>
    <amendment number="h282"/>
    <amendment number="h283"/>
    <amendment number="h284"/>
    <amendment number="h285"/>
    <amendment number="h286"/>
    <amendment number="h287"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/17/2011--Passed House amended.
Reversing President Obama's Offshore Moratorium Act - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to make available for leasing and to conduct lease sales including: (1) at least 50% of the available unleased acreage within each outer Continental Shelf (OCS) planning area considered to have the largest undiscovered, technically recoverable oil and gas resources (on a total btu basis) based upon the most recent national geologic assessment of the OCS, with an emphasis on offering the most geologically prospective parts of the planning area; and (2) any state subdivision of an OCS planning area that the Governor of such state requests be made available for leasing. Directs the Secretary, in the 2012-2017 5-year oil and gas leasing program, to make available for leasing OCS planning areas that: (1) are estimated to contain more than 2.5 billion barrels of oil; or (2) are estimated to contain more than 7.5 trillion cubic feet of natural gas. Directs the Secretary, in developing a 5-year oil and gas leasing program, to determine a domestic strategic production goal for the development of oil and natural gas. Makes the production goal for the 2012-2017 5-year oil and gas leasing program an increase by 2027 in daily production of at least: (1) 3 million barrels of oil, and (2) 10 billion cubic feet of natural gas.</summary>
</bill>
