<bill session="111" type="h" number="5670" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants for the improvement of storm water retention basins in the watersheds of estuaries in the National Estuary Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412264"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) conduct an evaluation of each storm water retention basin located in the watershed of an estuary for which a comprehensive conservation and management plan is in effect under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to identify basins whose pollution control capabilities are in need of improvement; and (2) make grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities (a state or political subdivision that has jurisdiction over a basin identified) for the improvement of pollution control capabilities of such basins. Directs the Administrator to give priority to grant proposals by eligible entities: (1) whose pollution control capabilities are the most deficient and the improvement of which will result in the greatest increase in water quality in the estuary involved; and (2) for basins for which an evaluation of pollution control capabilities has been conducted prior to the date of this Act's enactment as part of the implementation of a comprehensive conservation and management plan. Requires an eligible entity receiving a grant to use grant funds to carry out storm water retention basin improvements and monitoring and reporting requirements. Prohibits the Administrator from making a grant to an eligible entity unless it agrees to make available non-federal contributions equal to not less than 20% of the federal funds provided under the grant.</summary>
</bill>
