<bill session="111" type="hc" number="85" updated="2013-07-20T00:13:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02T19:16:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-02T19:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2010 and including the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2009 and 2011 through 2014.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400386"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-27T22:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on The Budget reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-60, by Mr. Spratt.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-03-27T22:35:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="25">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31T18:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 305 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 85 with 4 hours of general debate. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 305 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 305.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4370-4393" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 85 with 4 hours of general debate. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 305 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ellen O. Tauscher to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T20:59:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with four hours of general debate on H. Con. Res. 85.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01T23:59:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - General Debate on H. Con. Res. 85 continued beyond 12 midnight and on into April 2, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T00:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Maloney moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T00:27:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T00:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 85 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4415-4487" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with the remaining one hour of general debate on H. Con. Res. 85.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 85 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL LEAVE - Mr. Spratt asked unanimous consent that Members have 5 legislative days to revise and extend their remarks on H.Con.Res. 85. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Woolsey amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Jordan(OH) amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Lee(CA) amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H. Con. Res. 85.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4487" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-04-02T19:16:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="192" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 196 (Roll no. 192).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4431-4437" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="305"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="316"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sc" number="13"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="111" type="sc" number="13"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sc" number="13"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h72"/>
    <amendment number="h73"/>
    <amendment number="h74"/>
    <amendment number="h75"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2010, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2009, and FY2011-FY2014. Title I: Recommended Levels and Amounts - (Sec. 101) Recommends budgetary levels and amounts for FY2009-FY2014 with respect to: (1) federal revenues; (2) new budget authority; (3) budget outlays; (4) deficits (on-budget); (5) debt subject to limit; and (6) debt held by the public. (Sec. 102) Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority and outlays for specified major functional categories for FY2009-FY2014. Title II: Reconciliation - (Sec. 201) Sets forth reconciliation instructions for the Committees on: (1) Energy and Commerce; (2) Ways and Means; and (3) Education and Labor. Authorizes the House to direct the House Clerk to add at the end of a health care reform bill or an education investment bill, subject to these reconciliation instructions, the text of another such measure as passed by the House to form a single engrossed reconciliation bill. Title III: Reserve Funds - (Sec. 301) Creates certain deficit-neutral reserve funds, subject to specified conditions, for legislation concerning: (1) health care reform; (2) college access, affordability, and completion; (3) an increase in energy independence; (4) America's veterans and servicemembers; (5) certain tax relief; (6) a 9/11 health program; (7) child nutrition; (8) structural unemployment insurance reforms; (9) child support; (10) the Affordable Housing Trust Fund; (11) home visiting for certain individuals and families; and (12) a low-income home energy assistance program (LIHEAP) trigger. (Sec. 313) Creates a reserve fund, subject to specified conditions, for legislation concerning reauthorization of surface transportation programs. (Sec. 314) Creates a current policy reserve fund, subject to specified conditions, for legislation concerning: (1) Medicare improvements; (2) middle-class tax relief; (3) Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) reform; and (4) the Estate and Gift Tax. Title IV: Budget Enforcement - (Sec. 401) Prescribes adjustments for direct spending and revenues to maintain such current policy reserves, only if certain conditions and pay-as-you-go (PAYGO) requirements are met. Authorizes adjustments for the LIHEAP program, and prescribes other adjustments for the deposit insurance guarantee commitment (in effect as of the enactment of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 [EESA]). (Sec. 402) Authorizes or prescribes adjustments to discretionary spending limits, budgetary aggregates, and allocations for: (1) continuing disability reviews, Supplemental Security Income (SSI) redeterminations, and SSI asset verification by the Social Security Administration (SSA); (2) Internal Revenue Service (IRS) tax compliance; (3) the health care fraud and abuse control program; (4) unemployment insurance improper payments reviews; and (5) a Partnership Fund for Program Integrity Innovation in the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). States that new budget authority, outlays, and receipts resulting from adoption of legislation making appropriations for FY2009-FY2010 for overseas deployments and related activities, or appropriations for discretionary spending to meet emergency needs, shall not count for certain purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA). (Sec. 403) Prohibits House legislation that would require advance appropriations, except certain FY2011 or FY2012 programs, projects, activities, or accounts. (Sec. 404) Encourages all House committees to: (1) conduct rigorous oversight hearings to root out waste, fraud, and abuse in all aspects of federal spending and operations, giving particular scrutiny to issues raised by the Office of Inspector General or Comptroller General; and (2) make recommendations, based on these oversight efforts, to reduce wasteful federal spending to promote deficit reduction and long-term fiscal responsibility. (Sec. 405) Requires in the House the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any budget resolution to include in its allocation to the House Committee on Appropriations amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the SSA and of the Postal Service. Title V: Policy - (Sec. 501) Declares the policy of this resolution on: (1) middle-income tax relief and revenues; and (2) defense priorities. Title VI: Sense of the House - (Sec. 601) Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives on: (1) veterans' and servicemembers' health care; (2) homeland security; (3) American innovation and economic competitiveness; (4) pay parity; (5) college affordability; (6) Great Lakes restoration; and (7) the importance of child support enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
