<bill session="112" type="h" number="3014" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Computer Science Education Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to State educational agencies and institutions of higher education to strengthen elementary and secondary computer science education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2011-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2012-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1614"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Computer Science Education Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award states: (1) two-year formula grants to develop comprehensive plans to strengthen elementary and secondary computer science education, and (2) competitive five-year matching grants to implement the improvements proposed in their comprehensive plans. Requires such improvements to include: (1) challenging and grade-appropriate academic content standards for computer science, (2) grade-appropriate assessments of computer science learning, (3) programs to increase disadvantaged students' access to computer science courses, (4) computer science teacher training programs, (5) improved certification or licensure requirements and processes for such teachers, (6) programs to ensure that computer science courses are considered an integral part of the secondary school curriculum, (7) effective computer science curricula, and (8) computer science distance learning programs. Requires states to partner with institutions of higher education (IHEs) and local educational agencies in implementing such measures. Favors implementation grant applicants that emphasize serving low-performing schools and increasing the participation in computer science by students underrepresented in computing. Directs the Secretary to establish a Blue Ribbon Commission on Computer Science Education to provide recommendations to the Secretary and Congress for expanding and improving computer science education. Authorizes the Secretary to award five-year grants to IHEs to improve computer science teacher training.</summary>
</bill>
