<bill session="112" type="hr" number="587" updated="2013-07-20T01:08:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-20T15:16:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-20T15:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2087) to remove restrictions from a parcel of land situated in the Atlantic District, Accomack County, Virginia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-415, by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution makes in order the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill as original text for the purpose of amendment. The resolution makes in order only those amendments that are submitted for printing in the Congressional Record dated March 19, 2012, or pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-19T18:43:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="118">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 118.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Bishop (UT) called up the resolution H. Res. 587, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER AGAINST CONSIDERATION - Mr. Grijalva stated that the provisions of H. Res. 587 violate clause 9(b) of rule XXI of the Rules of the U.S. House of Representatives and made a point of order against the consideration of the resolution. Subsequently, the Chair noted that the required threshold of identifying the specific language in question had been met, and the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the question of consideration. At the conclusion of debate on the question of consideration, the Chair will put the question to wit: Will the House now consider the resolution?</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>On consideration of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 172 (Roll no. 112).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1405-1410" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 587.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1410" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-03-20T15:16:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="113" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 170 (Roll no. 113).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1405-1406" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="2087"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2012--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2087) to remove restrictions from a parcel of land situated in the Atlantic District, Accomack County, Virginia.</summary>
</bill>
