<bill session="110" type="h" number="2476" updated="2013-07-19T21:25:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">West Valley Remediation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the United States Department of Energy to remediate the Western New York Nuclear Service Center in the Town of Ashford, New York, and dispose of nuclear waste.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400642"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="81"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
West Valley Remediation Act of 2007 - Expresses the intent of Congress that the federal government should achieve complete remediation of all radioactive, solid, and hazardous waste contamination at the Western New York Nuclear Service Center in West Valley, New York.States that this Act: (1) establishes exclusive federal responsibility for the complete remediation of the Center; and (2) replaces and supersedes the West Valley Demonstration Project Act.Directs the Secretary of Energy to employ the best current technologies and develop new state-of-the-art technologies and methodologies to complete remediation of the Center, including: (1) decontamination and decommissioning; (2) transportation of high level radioactive waste to a federal repository for permanent disposal; and (3) disposal of low level radioactive and transuranic waste.Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to regulate the remediation of radioactive waste and nuclear materials at the Center according to prescribed guidelines. Directs the Secretary to: ( 1) prepare any environmental impact statement for decommissioning or long-term stewardship of the Center in cooperation with the NRC and federal and state agencies; (2) assume exclusive use and possession of the entire Center; (3) take title to land or facilities at the Center that have not been approved by the NRC for release for unrestricted use; and (4) take title to radioactive and nonradioactive wastes and materials located at the Center. Repeals the West Valley Demonstration Project Act upon assumption by the Secretary of exclusive use and possession of the entire Center.</summary>
</bill>
