<bill session="113" type="hc" number="61" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the execution-style murders of United States citizens Ylli, Agron, and Mehmet Bytyqi in the Republic of Serbia in July 1999.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1543-1544"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/2013--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) those individuals responsible for the July 1999 murders of U.S. citizens Ylli, Agron, and Mehmet Bytyqi in Serbia should be brought to justice; (2) it is reprehensible that no individual has ever been found guilty for executing the Bytyqi brothers, or of any other crimes associated with their deaths; (3) the government of Serbia and its relevant ministries and offices, including the Serbian War Crimes Prosecutor's Office, should make it a priority to investigate and prosecute those current or former officials believed to be responsible for their deaths; (4) the United States should devote sufficient resources to assist and monitor Serbia's efforts to investigate and prosecute those individuals believed to be responsible; and (5) progress in resolving this case should remain a significant factor in determining the further development of U.S.- Serbia relations.</summary>
</bill>
