<bill session="111" type="s" number="3404" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 to require the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to take actions to improve environmental conditions in the vicinity of the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel in Lake County, Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-707.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-320.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="606">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 606.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3123"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3123"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1417"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2010 - Amends the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 to expand requirements for the operation and maintenance of the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel, Colorado, to require the Secretary of the Interior to take any action necessary to maintain the structural integrity of the Tunnel to maintain public safety and to prevent an uncontrolled release of water. Makes the Secretary responsible for the operation and maintenance of the water treatment plant, including authorized sludge disposal. Authorizes the Secretary to offer to enter into one or more contracts with any appropriate individual or entity for the conduct of any required service. Authorizes the Secretary: (1) to enter into an agreement with any other entity or government agency to provide funding for an increase in any operation, maintenance, replacement, capital improvement, or expansion cost that is necessary to improve or expand the Treatment Plant; and (2) upon entering into an agreement, to make any necessary capital improvement to or expansion of the water treatment plant and to treat flows that are conveyed to the Plant, including any surface water diverted into the Tunnel and water collected by the dewatering relief well installed in June 2008. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to consult with the Secretary regarding each feature of the proposed new or amended Record of Decision for operable unit 6 of the California Gulch National Priorities List Site that may require any alteration to, or otherwise affect the operation and maintenance of, the Tunnel or the water treatment plant. Authorizes the Secretary to implement any improvement to, or new operation of, the Tunnel or water treatment plant only upon entering into an agreement with the EPA Administrator or other entity or agency to provide funding for the improvement or new operation. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
