<bill session="110" type="s" number="301" updated="2013-07-19T22:22:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nontraditional Student Success Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide higher education assistance for nontraditional students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S599"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="College administration"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2007--Introduced.
Nontraditional Student Success Act - Authorizes and appropriates specified funds for Federal Pell grants under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA). Increases yearly maximum grant amounts and revises requirements for the allowance of two Pell grants during a single award year. Requires the Secretary to publish annually in the Federal Register a revised table of income protection allowances. Excludes the earned income tax credit (EITC) from financial aid determinations. Authorizes the Secretary to select institutions of higher education for a Nontraditional Students Demonstration Program to test the effectiveness of providing expanded financial assistance to less than half-time students and students in compressed, modular, or other alternative schedules. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to eligible institutions to improve remedial education. Increases minimum grant amounts for the Federal TRIO programs. Permits student support services and educational opportunity centers to include career and academic (as well as personal) counseling. Makes awards under the Early Intervention and College Awareness Program for six years. Revises requirements for and reauthorizes the Program. Reauthorizes the Child Care Access Means Parents in School Program of campus-based child care services for low-income parents in postsecondary education. Directs the Secretary to establish a website and brochures for providing outreach about financial aid and education tax credits that targets employers, one-stop centers, Head Start centers, and other appropriate locations. Increases the activities for which grants to Hispanic-serving institutions, as well as grants from the Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education, may be used. Revises requirements for Special Programs for Students Whose Families Are Engaged in Migrant and Seasonal Farmwork. Reauthorizes the high school equivalency and the college assistance migrant programs. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the percentage Lifetime Learning income tax credit for qualified higher education expenses, but reduce the maximum annual dollar amount. Makes a portion of the credit refundable. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for making advance payments of such credits to eligible institutions on behalf of certified individuals.</summary>
</bill>
