<bill session="110" type="h" number="5563" updated="2013-07-19T21:52:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-12T15:07:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-03-12T15:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Generations Invigorating Volunteerism and Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GIVE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Congressional Commission on Civic Service Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize and reform the national service laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2008-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-11T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, George moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-11T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1468-1498" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1468-1494" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-11T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5563.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-11T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1560-1561" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2008-03-12T15:07:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="131" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 277 - 140 (Roll no. 131).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2857"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Grandparents"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Learning"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School-age child care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Service learning"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Summer employment"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2008--Introduced.
Generations Invigorating Volunteerism and Education Act, or the GIVE Act - Amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (NSCA) and the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 (DVSA) to revise the programs under such Acts and reauthorize appropriations for such programs through FY2012. Revises under NSCA: (1) the School-Based and Community-Based Service-Learning programs and Higher Education Innovative Programs for Community Service (Learn and Serve programs); (2) National Service Trust programs (AmeriCorps); (3) the National Civilian Community Corps (NCCC); and (4) the Investment for Quality and Innovation program. Eliminates the current Community-Based Learn and Serve programs. Establishes a new Learn and Serve program, Innovative Service-Learning Programs and Research, providing matching grants to: (1) provide community service-learning opportunities to elementary and secondary, college, and graduate students, including summer of service programs; and (2) research and evaluate service-learning. Includes among eligible AmeriCorps programs: (1) an E-corp program increasing community access to technology; (2) a program engaging citizens in public safety, health, and emergency preparedness services; (3) a youth mentoring program; (4) a program to reduce recidivism by re-engaging court-involved youth; and (5) the Education Awards Only program. Establishes an AmeriCorp pilot grant program for state-approved, member-selected, national service positions. Increases National Service educational awards for AmeriCorps, NCCC, and Volunteers in Service to America (VISTA) participants. Includes among needs to be met under the NCCC program, disaster relief, infrastructure improvement, environmental and energy conservation, and urban and rural development. Requires states to develop comprehensive plans for volunteer and paid service by Baby Boomers and older adults. Establishes an Office of Outreach and Recruitment in the Corporation for National and Community Service (Corporation). Requires the Corporation to plan pilot service programs to better utilize and serve veterans and displaced workers. Authorizes the Corporation to provide grants to innovative and model service programs that include service programs for disadvantaged youth. Eliminates federal funding for the Points of Light Foundation. Establishes a new Energy Conservation Corps program awarding: (1) matching grants to states for projects providing youth and young adults with career training in support of energy conservation, infrastructure and transportation improvement, and emergency operations; (2) competitive grants for school-based green Learn and Serve programs; and (3) competitive grants to National Senior Service Corps (Senior Corps) programs involving seniors in energy efficient housing, infrastructure rehabilitation, and environmental and energy conservation education projects. Revises under DVSA: (1) the VISTA program; and (2) the Senior Corps, including the Retired and Senior Volunteer program (RSVP), the Foster Grandparent program, and the Senior Companion program. Gives priority in VISTA participant selection to disadvantaged youth and retired adults of any profession. Authorizes new VISTA grant programs of national significance that provide poor and rural communities with: (1) services reintegrating formerly incarcerated individuals into society; (2) financial literacy and planning; (3) before-school and after-school services; (4) community economic development initiatives; (5) assistance to veterans and their families; and (6) health and wellness services. Eliminates the VISTA Literacy Corps, University Year for VISTA, and Literacy Challenge Grant programs. Raises the minimum and maximum stipend provided to VISTA participants. Prioritizes RSVP projects in specified areas. Makes anyone 55 years of age or older eligible as Senior Corps volunteers. Provides, under the Senior Corps demonstration program, incentive matching grants to Senior Corps programs that exceed specified performance measures, enroll most of their volunteers in outcome-based service programs, and increase their enrollment of Baby Boomer volunteers. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the number of AmeriCorps, VISTA, and NCCC participants should reach 100,000 by 2012. Congressional Commission on Civic Service Act - Establishes a Congressional Commission on Civic Service to provide recommendations to Congress on improving opportunities for individuals to volunteer or perform national service. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Corporation should try to: (1) coordinate its service programs so that senior citizens and their grandchildren can share volunteer opportunities and/or be assigned to the same geographic area; and (2) work with the National Endowment for the Humanities to provide opportunities for young service participants to collect oral histories from senior citizens.</summary>
</bill>
