<bill session="110" type="h" number="4084" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Quality of Life Study Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require a study on the Department of Veterans Affairs schedule for rating disabilities, to provide for the treatment of claims under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in the case of the death of a claimant, to require an annual report on the workload of the Court of Appeals for Veteran Claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412222"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court congestion and delay"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2007--Introduced.
Veterans Quality of Life Study Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to contract with the Institute of Medicine, or other appropriate entity, to conduct a study analyzing the extent to which the Department of Veterans Affairs schedule for rating disabilities accounts for or should be amended to account, measure, and compensate for loss of quality of life to veterans due to a disability resulting from a personal injury suffered or disease contracted in the line of duty. Provides that if a veteran who is a claimant dies before completing the submission of a claim for benefits, the person who would receive any accrued benefits due to such veteran shall be treated as the claimant for purposes of completing submission of the claim. Requires an annual report from the chief judge of the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims (Court) to the congressional veterans' committees summarizing the Court's workload. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Court should be provided with appropriate office space, without undue disruption, inconvenience, or cost. Requires a report from the Administrator of General Services to the veterans' committees on the feasibility of leasing additional space for the Court, and using the entire building in which the Court is now housed as a Veterans Courthouse and Justice Center.</summary>
</bill>
