<bill session="112" type="h" number="3202" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Mariners Job Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 46, United States Code, to require the Maritime Administrator, in making determinations regarding the non-availability of qualified United States flag capacity to meet national defense requirements, to identify any actions that could be taken to enable such capacity to meet some or all of those requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2011-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS28" subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1783"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/2011--Introduced.
American Mariners Job Protection Act - Amends federal shipping laws that require a determination by the Administrator of the Maritime Administration regarding the non-availability of qualified U.S. flag capacity to meet national defense requirements before the head of an agency responsible for the administration of navigation or vessel-inspection laws is authorized on its own initiative to waive compliance with such laws when it considers it necessary in the interest of national defense. Requires the Administrator, in making such determinations, to: (1) identify any actions that could be taken to enable such flag capacity to meet the national defense requirements, (2) provide each such determination to the Secretary of Transportation and the head of the agency for which the determination is made, and (3) publish each such determination on the Internet site of the Department of Transportation (DOT) within 48 hours after it is provided to the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to notify Congress of any waiver requests or issuances. Requires the notification of the issuance of a waiver to include the reasons why: (1) the waiver is necessary, and (2) specified actions are not feasible.</summary>
</bill>
