<bill session="111" type="h" number="5205" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Central Idaho Economic Development and Recreation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish certain wilderness areas in central Idaho and to authorize various land conveyances involving National Forest System land and Bureau of Land Management land in central Idaho.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3294"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2010--Introduced.
Central Idaho Economic Development and Recreation Act - Designates specified parcels of federal land in central Idaho as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Repeals existing law requiring review of portions of the Sawtooth National Recreation Area (SNRA) for possible inclusion in the NWPS. Provides for the use of an appropriate site in the vicinity of the Smiley Creek community in Blaine County in central Idaho for construction and use of a fire station for the Smiley Creek Rural Fire Protection District. Authorizes: (1) the use of such site through a special use permit or conveyance to the District; and (2) the issuance of a special use permit to the District for development of a well for fire protection and other public purposes. Requires the conveyance of specified parcels of federal land to Blaine and Custer Counties and the cities of Challis and Clayton in central Idaho. Sets forth requirements regarding travel management in Germania Creek Trail, Forest Service Trails 109 and 671, and Frog Lake Loop Trail. Authorizes such improvements as may be necessary for maintainance of the first mile of the Murdock Creek Trail as a primitive, nonpaved, and wheel-chair accessible trail.</summary>
</bill>
