<bill session="110" type="s" number="524" updated="2013-07-19T22:24:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Farm Assistance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide emergency agricultural disaster assistance for agricultural producers, manufacturers, and workers in the State of California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="925"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="925"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Citrus fruits"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Horticulture"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nuts"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2007--Introduced.
Emergency Farm Assistance Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to provide assistance: (1) to producers of specialty crops in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2005 or 2006; (2) to citrus producers in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2007; (3) to producers of other specialty crops in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2007; (4) to dairy producers in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2006; and (5) for livestock indemnity payments to producers in disaster counties that incurred losses in 2006 or 2007, or both. Directs the Secretary to make grants to California for an expedited disaster assistance program to qualified small businesses that suffered losses during the 2005, 2006, or 2007 crop year as a result of weather-related agricultural losses to the California specialty crop or livestock production sectors. Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to tree or fruit and tree nut producers in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2005, 2006, or 2007, or any combination of such years. Defines "tree" to include: (1) a tree (including a Christmas tree, ornamental tree, nursery tree, and potted tree); (2) a bush (including a shrub, nursery shrub, nursery bush, ornamental bush, ornamental shrub, potted bush, and potted shrub); and (3) a vine (including a nursery vine and ornamental vine). Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide unemployment assistance and temporary mortgage rental assistance to California agricultural workers (including low-income migrant and seasonal farmworkers) who are unemployed due to disasters in 2007. Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) food coupons and surplus commodities to such workers; and (2) emergency grants for California low-income migrant and seasonal farmworkers who are unemployed due to disasters in 2007.</summary>
</bill>
