<bill session="112" type="h" number="1277" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southern Borderlands Public Safety Communications Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants for public-private partnerships that finance equipment and infrastructure to improve the public safety of persons who are residents of rural areas of the United States near the border with Mexico by enhancing access to mobile communications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2012-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2011--Introduced.
Southern Borderlands Public Safety Communications Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to make competitive grants for public-private partnerships that finance equipment and infrastructure to improve the public safety of persons who are residents of rural areas of the United States near the border with Mexico by enhancing their access to reliable mobile communications. Directs the Secretary to focus on projects in areas impacted by the illegal smuggling and trafficking of people and drugs. Declares that persons eligible for grants include states, counties, municipalities, organizations representing agricultural producers and other rural Americans, and telecommunications providers. Repeals the International Forestry Cooperation Act of 1990 to offset sums appropriated under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
