<bill session="111" type="s" number="3719" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening Community Safety Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program for first responder agencies that experience an extraordinary financial burden resulting from the deployment of employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Strengthening Community Safety Act of 2010 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to make a grant to an eligible first responder agency for the additional costs incurred as a direct result of one or more of its employees who are reservists being placed on active duty. Defines "eligible first responder agency" as one for which the cost of operating has increased by not less than 5% as a direct result of such employees being placed on active duty. Prohibits the Administrator from making a grant for costs relating to an employee being placed on active duty if federal funds are used for that employee's pay or benefits. Authorizes the use of grant funds for: (1) pay or benefits for an individual hired to replace such an employee; (2) overtime expenses for an individual who performs tasks that would have been performed by such an employee; and (3) the cost of equipment, maintenance, or other activities the agency was unable to acquire or perform because of the cost of replacing such an employee or the need for which was caused by an employee being placed on active duty. Limits the grant period to six months.</summary>
</bill>
