<bill session="112" type="h" number="2230" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Gambling Regulation and Tax Enforcement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to regulate and tax Internet gambling.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2012-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Introduced.
Internet Gambling Regulation and Tax Enforcement Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) impose a tax on each Internet gambling licensee equal to 2% of all funds deposited by Internet gambling customers of such licensee for placing a bet or wager and an additional 50% tax on unauthorized bets or wagers; (2) require such licensees to keep daily records of gambling deposits and file informational returns identifying themselves and the individuals placing bets or wagers with them; (3) require licensees to pay state and Indian tribal governments an amount equal to the monthly pro rata state and Indian tribal government online gambling tax; (4) require withholding of tax on net Internet gambling winnings and on the gross amount of winnings of nonresident aliens; and (5) extend the excise tax on wagers to include wagers placed within the United States or any commonwealth, territory, or possession by a U.S. citizen or resident. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make grants to states to carry out an American Heritage Program through state arts agencies. Allocates .5% of the tax revenues received after December 31, 2010, that are attributable to Internet gambling to the American Heritage Block Grant Fund to finance the American Heritage Program. Amends the Social Security Act to establish the Transitional Assistance Trust Fund to finance state plans for transitional education and job training assistance to individuals who are, or were formerly, in foster care. Allocates 25% of the tax revenues received after December 31, 2010, that are attributable to Internet gambling to the Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
