<bill session="109" type="h" number="3443" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-10-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain water distribution facilities to the Northern Colorado Water Conservancy District.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2005-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10T17:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-290.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-10T17:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="160">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 160.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Drake moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11444-11446" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3443.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-13T15:18:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11444-11445" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 04/07/2006 without amendment. With written report No. 109-248.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="410">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 410.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-09-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10537" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-10-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-10-11" type="public" number="109-321">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-321.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1498"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2006--Public Law.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to convey the St. Vrain Supply Canal, the Boulder Creek Supply Canal that extends from the St. Vrain River to Boulder Creek, and the South Platte Supply Canal, all of which are facilities of the Colorado-Big Thompson Project located in the counties of Larimer, Boulder, and Weld, Colorado, to the Northern Colorado Water Conservancy District. Provides that the District shall not be required to provide additional consideration for this conveyance. Directs the Western Area Power Administration to continue to include the unpaid portion of the transferred facilities in its annual power repayment studies for the Loveland Area Projects until such facilities are repaid in accordance with the laws and policies regarding repayment of investment in effect on the date of this Act's enactment. Exempts the United States from liability for damages arising from prior ownership or operation of the transferred facilities. Provides that any actions or activities undertaken by the Secretary under this Act shall not affect or create any additional burdens or obligations on the New Consolidated Lower Boulder Reservoir and Ditch Company or the New Coal Ridge Ditch Company in the full exercise of their water rights, their real property rights, or their rights to utilize facilities affected. Directs the Secretary, if the facilities have not been conveyed to the District within one year of this Act's enactment, to report to to the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the House Committee on Resources, annually, on the reasons for the failure to convey such facilities and the schedule for completing the transfer.</summary>
</bill>
