<bill session="110" type="h" number="319" updated="2013-07-19T21:06:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2007-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2007-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E36-37"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-95.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-04-17T13:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="60">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 60.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1270"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1270"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="289"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="289"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="289"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2007--Reported to House amended.
Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Act - (Sec. 4) Establishes the Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area comprising the 175 mile-region following the Route 15 corridor and certain surrounding areas through Pennsylvania, Maryland, West Virginia, and Virginia. Designates the Journey Through Hallowed Ground Partnership as the management entity for the Area. Requires the board of trustees of the Partnership to include representatives from a broad cross-section of individuals, agencies, organizations, states, and governments that: (1) are partners of the Partnership; and (2) will oversee the development and implementation of the management plan. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Partnership to use funds made available under this Act to prepare, update, and implement the management plan, including for making grants to, and entering into cooperative agreements with, states and their political subdivisions, private organizations, non-profit organizations or any other person. Requires the Partnership to develop a management plan for the Area that presents comprehensive strategies and recommendations for conservation, funding, management, and development of the Area. Specifies conditions that the Partnership shall ensure before submitting the management plan to the Secretary of the Interior for approval, including that: (1) the Commonwealth of Virginia, the States of Maryland and West Virginia, the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, and any political subdivision thereof that would be affected by the management plan, receives a copy of such plan; and (2) at least one public hearing is conducted by the Partnership at a location within the Area in each congressional district included in whole or in part in the Area to review and receive comments on the management plan. Prohibits: (1) the Partnership from using federal funds received under this Act to acquire real property or any interest in real property; and (2) any state or local subdivision of a state from using any federal funds received pursuant to this Act to acquire any interest in real property by condemnation or otherwise. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary, as specified, to provide technical and financial assistance to the Partnership to carry out its duties under this Act. Instructs the Secretary, as a condition of providing financial assistance to the Partnership, to require the recipient to provide matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of financial assistance provided by the Secretary. States that recipient matching funds: (1) shall be derived from non-federal sources; and (2) may be made in the form of in-kind contributions of goods and services fairly valued. (Sec. 9) Bars the Secretary from making any grant or providing any other financial assistance under this Act after the expiration of the 15-year period beginning on the date that funds are first made available for this Act. (Sec. 10) Specifies private property and regulatory protections. (Sec. 11) Prohibits anything in this Act from precluding the Partnership from using federal funds available under Acts other than this Act for the purposes for which those funds were authorized. (Sec. 12) Authorizes appropriations. Limits: (1) the amount authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act to $1 million for any fiscal year; and (2) the total amounts that may be appropriated to carry out this Act to $10 million. .</summary>
</bill>
