<bill session="110" type="s" number="39" updated="2013-07-19T22:20:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ocean and Coastal Exploration and NOAA Act (OCEAN Act)</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Ocean Exploration Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">NOAA Undersea Research Program Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Ocean and Coastal Exploration and NOAA Act (OCEAN Act)</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">National Ocean Exploration Program Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">NOAA Undersea Research Program Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a coordinated national ocean exploration program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-02-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-39.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-03-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="90">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 90.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1834"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1834"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2400"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine biology"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Ocean currents"/>
    <term name="Ocean floor"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Salvage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2007--Reported to Senate amended.
Ocean and Coastal Exploration and NOAA Act (OCEAN Act) - Title I: National Ocean Exploration Program - National Ocean Exploration Program Act - (Sec. 102) Requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), in consultation with the National Science Foundation (NSF) and other appropriate federal agencies, to establish a coordinated national ocean exploration program that promotes collaboration among NOAA programs. Specifies program authorities. (Sec. 104) Requires NOAA to convene an ocean technology and infrastructure task force to develop and implement a specified strategy. (Sec. 105) Authorizes NOAA, NSF, and other agencies involved in the program to participate in interagency financing and share, transfer, receive, and spend funds appropriated to any federal participant in the program. (Sec. 106) Authorizes appropriations for the program for FY2008-FY2017. Title II: Undersea Research Program - NOAA Undersea Research Program Act of 2007 - (Sec. 202) Requires NOAA to establish an undersea research program to be conducted through a national headquarters, a network of regional undersea research centers, and the National Technology Institute. (Sec. 205) Specifies the research, exploration, education, and technology programs to be conducted through the network of regional centers and the National Technology Institute. (Sec. 206) Sets forth competitiveness requirements. (Sec. 207) Authorizes appropriations for the centers and the Institute for FY2008-FY2017. Title III: Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration - Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act - (Sec. 302) Requires NOAA to establish a program to develop a coordinated and comprehensive federal ocean and coastal mapping plan for the Great Lakes and coastal state waters, the territorial sea, the exclusive economic zone, and the U.S. continental shelf that: (1) enhances ecosystem approaches in decision-making for conservation and management of marine resources and habitats; (2) establishes research priorities; (3) supports the siting of research and other platforms; and (4) advances ocean and coastal science. Sets forth program parameters. (Sec. 303) Establishes an Interagency Committee on Ocean and Coastal Mapping. (Sec. 304) Requires the NOAA Administrator to submit to Congress a plan for an integrated ocean and coastal mapping initiative within NOAA. Sets forth plan requirements. Authorizes the Administrator to maintain and operate up to three joint ocean and coastal mapping centers, including a joint hydrographic center, to be co-located with an institution of higher education to serve as hydrographic centers of excellence and that are authorized to conduct activities necessary to carry out the purposes of this title. Requires the Administrator to continue developing a strategy for expanding contracting with private entities to minimize duplication and take maximum advantage of private sector capabilities in fulfilling the Administration's mapping and charting responsibilities. (Sec. 305) Sets forth reporting requirements. (Sec. 306) Authorizes appropriations to carry out this title for FY2008-FY2015.</summary>
</bill>
