<bill session="111" type="h" number="5093" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Space to Schools Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to establish a program for displaced aerospace professionals to become certified elementary, secondary, or vocational school teachers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2010-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2010--Introduced.
Space to Schools Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to implement a program to encourage individuals who are former employees of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), its suppliers, or related contractors who have relevant work experience in the aerospace industry to pursue careers as elementary, secondary, or vocational school teachers. Sets forth educational background requirements for program participants. Requires program participants to enter into an agreement to: (1) obtain certification or licensing as an elementary, secondary, vocational, or technical school teacher, and to become a highly qualified teacher; and (2) accept an offer of full-time employment as an elementary, secondary, vocational, or technical school teacher for at least three school years and commit to teaching science, technology, engineering, or mathematics after obtaining such certification or licensing. Directs the Secretary to provide program participants with: (1) a stipend for use in obtaining certification or licensing; or (2) a larger bonus if they agree to perform their service in high-need schools. Requires the Secretary to establish an Advisory Board to oversee the program.</summary>
</bill>
