<bill session="112" type="s" number="1346" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restrict the use of offshore tax havens and abusive tax shelters to inappropriately avoid Federal taxation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4518-4527"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2669"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2075"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2011--Introduced.
Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to impose restrictions on foreign jurisdictions or financial institutions operating in the United States that are of prime money laundering concern or that impede U.S. tax enforcement. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish a rebuttable presumption against the validity of transactions by institutions that do not comply with reporting requirements under the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (FATCA), (2) treat certain foreign corporations managed and controlled primarily in the United States as domestic corporations for tax purposes, (3) require tax withholding agents and financial institutions to report certain information about beneficial owners of foreign-owned financial accounts, (4) treat credit default swap payments sent offshore as taxable U.S. source income, (5) allow the use of tax return information to evaluate foreign financial account reports, (6) increase penalties for promoting abusive tax shelters and for aiding and abetting the understatement of tax liability, (7) prohibit tax advisor contingent fee agreements for obtaining a tax savings or benefit, and (8) impose additional requirements for third party summonses used to obtain information in tax investigations that do not identify the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued (i.e., John Doe summons). Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to: (1) require corporations registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to report annually, on a country-by country basis, on employees, sales, financing, tax obligations, and tax payments; and (2) authorize a fine of up to $1 million for failure to disclose any holding or transaction involving equity or debt instruments known to involve a foreign entity that would otherwise be subject to disclosure requirements. Requires the Secretary to publish a proposed rule in the Federal Register requiring unregistered investment companies, including hedge funds or private equity funds, to establish anti-money laundering programs and submit suspicious activity reports. Extends anti-money laundering requirements to persons engaged in the business of forming new businesses or other legal entities. Requires federal banking agencies and the SEC to develop examination techniques to detect and prevent abusive tax shelter activities or the aiding or abetting of tax evasion by financial institutions. Requires the Secretary to: (1) disclose tax return information to federal financial regulators for purposes of tax shelter investigations; (2) disclose to Congress documents relating to a determination to grant, deny, revoke, or restore the tax-exempt status of an organization; and (3) expand the standards applicable to tax practitioners for issuing written advice on transactions which have a potential for tax avoidance or evasion.</summary>
</bill>
