<bill session="113" type="h" number="1299" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">White Sands Missile Range Security Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">White Sands Missile Range Security Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the transfer of certain public land currently administered by the Bureau of Land Management to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army for inclusion in White Sands Missile Range, New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-24T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-120, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-24T11:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-24T11:44:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="85">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 85.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2013--Reported to House amended, Part I.
White Sands Missile Range Security Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to transfer certain Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land in Dona Ana County, New Mexico, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army for inclusion in the White Sands Missile Range for use for military purposes. Requires the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register a legal description and map of the public land to be transferred. Requires the transfer to be made without reimbursement, except that the Secretary of the Army shall reimburse the Secretary for any costs incurred in preparing the legal description and map. Requires the Secretary, if a grazing permit or lease exists for any part of such land to be transferred, to transfer or relocate the grazing allotments associated with such permit or lease to other public land that is acceptable to the permit or lease holder so that the grazing continues to have the same value to such holder. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) establish a reservation in favor of the United States with respect to any water or water right on lands transferred by this Act, or (2) authorize the appropriation of water on lands transferred by this Act except in accordance with applicable state law. Withdraws such land from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws and geothermal leasing laws, so long as such lands remain under the Secretary of the Army's administrative jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
