<bill session="113" type="s" number="404" updated="2013-11-02T06:55:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Green Mountain Lookout Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve the Green Mountain Lookout in the Glacier Peak Wilderness of the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2013-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="908"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2013--Introduced.
Green Mountain Lookout Heritage Protection Act - Amends the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984, with respect to certain lands in the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie and Wenatchee National Forests in the state of Washington designated as part of the Glacier Peak Wilderness, to specifically allow the operation and maintenance of Green Mountain Lookout. Prohibits the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Forest Service, from moving the Lookout from its current location on Green Mountain in the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest unless the Secretary determines that its move is necessary to preserve the Lookout or to ensure the safety of individuals on or around Green Mountain. Requires the Secretary, if such a determination is made, to move the Lookout to a location outside of the lands described in this Act, above.</summary>
</bill>
