<bill session="112" type="h" number="3757" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing Health for Ocean Resources and Environment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SHORE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the ability of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Coast Guard, and coastal States to sustain healthy ocean and coastal ecosystems by maintaining and sustaining their capabilities relating to oil spill preparedness, prevention, response, restoration, and research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2011-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Bering Sea"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2011--Introduced.
Securing Health for Ocean Resources and Environment Act or the SHORE Act - Requires the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere to: (1) review the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's (NOAA) capacity to respond to oil spills; (2) be responsible for developing and maintaining oil spill trajectory modeling capabilities; (3) create and update NOAA's environmental sensitivity index products for each coastal area of the United States and for each offshore area that is leased or under consideration for leasing for offshore energy production; (4) review the current state of NOAA's capacity to monitor, map, and track subsea hydrocarbons; (5) establish a national information center on oil spills; (6) establish an initiative concerning the effects of oil spills resulting from aging and abandoned oil infrastructure; (7) develop an inventory of offshore abandoned or sunken vessels in the U.S. exclusive economic zone and identify priorities for potential preemptive removal of oil or other actions that may be effective to mitigate the risk of oil spills from such vessels; and (8) develop standard national protocols for oil spill response and clean up assessments and develop guidance and tools for oil spill responders. Amends the Oil Pollution Act to: (1) revise provisions concerning the uses of the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund, (2) establish a Gulf of Mexico Regional Citizens' Advisory Council to oversee and monitor facilities and tank vessels and establish offices in Gulf States, and (3) revise limits on liability and removal costs of responsible parties with respect to discharge of oil into or upon the navigable waters or adjoining shorelines or the exclusive economic zone from single-hull and double-hull tank ships and barges. Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to eligible coastal states to implement and revise specified policies and procedures for responding to oil spills. Requires the Under Secretary, to: (1) establish a long-term marine environmental monitoring and research program for the marine and coastal environment of the Gulf of Mexico to assess impacts of the oil spill caused by Deepwater Horizon on trust resources (defined as natural resources belonging to, managed by, held in trust by, appertaining to, or otherwise controlled by the United States, any state, an Indian Tribe, or a local government); and (2) direct research and take action to improve the ability of the United States to conduct oil spill prevention, response, and recovery in Arctic waters. Requires the Commandant of the Coast Guard to: (1) assess and take action to reduce the risk of, and improve the capability of the United States to respond to, a maritime disaster in the U.S. Beaufort and Chukchi Seas; (2) identify areas in waters in which routing or other navigational measures are warranted to reduce the risk of oil spills and potential damage to natural resources; and (3) analyze data on oil transported as cargo on vessels in U.S. navigable waters. Requires the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating to: (1) require response plans approved by the Coast Guard under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to be updated at least once every five years and to utilize the best commercially available technology and methods to contain and remove a worst case discharge and to mitigate or prevent a substantial threat of such discharge, and (2) establish a program to evaluate and validate oil pollution containment and removal methods and technologies. Amends the Clean Water Act to revise provisions concerning the national response system to discharges of oil and hazardous substances, including requiring the President to issue guidance for Area Committees to use with respect to the closing and reopening of fishing grounds following an oil spill. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) safety inspections of tank vessels that enter a U.S. port or place; (2) notices to states of transferring oil in bulk as cargo to, from, or within vessels; (3) notices to states and Indian tribes of marine casualties; and (4) publishing Incident Action Plans prepared and approved as a part of the response to an oil spill. Establishes the Federal Oil Spill Research Committee to coordinate a program of oil pollution research, technology development, and demonstration.</summary>
</bill>
