<bill session="110" type="h" number="6547" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spokane Tribe of Indians of the Spokane Reservation Grand Coulee Dam Equitable Compensation Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for equitable compensation to the Spokane Tribe of Indians of the Spokane Reservation for the use of tribal land for the production of hydropower by the Grand Coulee Dam, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2008-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2494"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2008--Introduced.
Spokane Tribe of Indians of the Spokane Reservation Grand Coulee Dam Equitable Compensation Settlement Act - Establishes in the Treasury the Spokane Tribe of Indians Settlement Fund. Requires the payment of compensation to the Spokane Business Council for the use of tribal lands for the generation of hydropower from the Grand Coulee Dam. Requires the use of such funds, in part, for a Cultural Resource Repository and Interpretive Center concerning the culture and history of the Spokane Tribe. Directs the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration to make specified settlement payments to the Spokane Tribe. Allows payments made to the Spokane Business Council or Spokane Tribe to be used or invested by the Business Council in the same manner and for the same purposes as other Spokane Tribal governmental funds. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer administrative jurisdiction from the Bureau of Reclamation to the Bureau of Indian Affairs over certain land located within the exterior boundaries of the Spokane Indian Reservation. Provides that payments by the Secretary and the Administrator and restoration of ownership of land in trust constitute full satisfaction of the claim of the Spokane Tribe to a fair share of the annual hydropower revenues generated by the Grand Coulee Dam project for the past and continued use of land of the Spokane Tribe for the production of hydropower at Grand Coulee Dam.</summary>
</bill>
