<bill session="109" type="s" number="2339" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ryan White CARE Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the HIV Health Care Services Program under title 26 of the Public Health Service Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2006-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10576-10578"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4830"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5009"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hepatitis"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Intravenous drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2006--Introduced.
Ryan White CARE Act Amendments of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize appropriations for HIV health care services programs. Requires recipients of HIV-related grants to expend not less than 75 percent of such funds on primary medical care. Amends the formula for awarding grant funds to consider the number of HIV (currently, AIDS) cases. Makes ineligible for funding any state or locality that imposes significant barriers to partner notification programs or routine testing. Provides for treatment for hepatitis B or hepatitis C for HIV-positive individuals who are co-infected. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require: (1) rapid routine testing of each client at any entity receiving funding from certain federal programs; and (2) federally funded health facilities to offer routine testing for pregnant women and newborns. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to annually purchase and distribute rapid HIV tests. Requires the Secretary to issue guidelines for therapeutics to be included in state formularies. Allows states to use grant funds to provide services to Medicaid-eligible individuals with HIV. Amends the AIDS Housing Opportunity Act to make grant allocations based on the number of HIV (currently, AIDS) cases. Requires the Secretary to ensure that not less than 75 percent of grant amounts are used for the provision, construction, maintenance, or development of housing assistance. Requires the Secretary to provide state AIDS officials with the authority to request and obtain all necessary information in order to coordinate HIV care and treatment with other federally funded projects.</summary>
</bill>
