<bill session="111" type="h" number="6149" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coin and Precious Metal Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require disclosures to consumers by coin and precious metal bullion dealers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400426"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2010--Introduced.
Coin and Precious Metal Disclosure Act - Requires a coin or precious metal dealer to disclose clearly and conspicuously in writing to the consumer before any sale of coins (including gold coins) or precious metal bullion: (1) any fee incurred by the customer upon sale consummation; and (2) the purchase price, the melt value, and the reasonable resale value of the coin or precious metal bullion. Requires telephone sales solicitations for such coins or precious metal bullion to disclose the same information before the transaction is consummated. Treats a violation of this Act as an unfair or deceptive act or practice in violation of the Federal Trade Commission Act, and subject to penalties. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce this Act as though the Federal Trade Commission Act applies. Empowers states to enforce compliance with this Act, but entitles the FTC, upon notice of a state civil action, to intervene and be heard on all matters arising in it, remove it to the appropriate federal district court, and file petitions for appeal. Exempts from this Act the sale of rare and collectable coins whose: (1) precious metal content constitutes only a limited or insignificant portion of the overall value of the coin; and (2) value is not affected by the increase or decline in the value of such precious metals.</summary>
</bill>
