<bill session="111" type="sr" number="566" updated="2013-07-20T00:21:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-25">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the situation in Kyrgyzstan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-06-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5463-5464" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5463-5464" label="text as passed in Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5462" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the Senate: (1) calling upon all parties in Kyrgyzstan to refrain from violence and to attend to displaced and injured civilians, paying particular attention to the Uzbek population along the Kyrgyzstan-Uzbekistan border; (2) that the Provisional Government of Kyrgyzstan should restore order and the democratic process, address the tensions that divide Kyrgyz society, and bring to justice those responsible for the violence; (3) supporting an investigation into the causes of the violence in southern Kyrgyzstan; (4) welcoming the commitment of U.S. assistance to Kyrgyzstan for programs supporting humanitarian relief, reconstruction, and community stabilization; (5) commending the government of Uzbekistan for cooperating with international organizations in meeting the needs of Uzbek refugees; (6) that the government of Uzbekistan should maintain an open border to ensure that displaced populations seeking refuge have emergency humanitarian assistance and protection services; (7) calling upon the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe to help restore order; and (8) commending the efforts of relief organizations and persons responding to the humanitarian needs of those displaced by the violence.</summary>
</bill>
