<bill session="110" type="s" number="2989" updated="2013-07-19T22:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement a National Neurotechnology Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3899-3900"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="5989"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Artificial intelligence"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Brain diseases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Neurology"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Psychiatry"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2008--Introduced.
National Neurotechnology Initiative Act - Defines "neurotechnology" to mean the science and technology that allows an individual to analyze, understand, treat, and heal the brain and nervous system.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement a National Neurotechnology Initiative, under which the Secretary shall: (1) establish goals, priorities, and metrics for evaluation for federal neurotechnology research, development, and commercialization; (2) increase the investment in federal research, development, and translational programs in neurotechnology to achieve such goals; and (3) increase interagency coordination.Requires the Secretary to establish the National Neurotechnology Coordination Office and the National Neurotechnology Advisory Council.Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to develop the Blueprint for Neuroscience Research to: (1) identify pervasive challenges in neuroscience and any technological barriers to solving such challenges; and (2) support the development of new tools, training opportunities, and other resources to assist neuroscientists in basic and clinical research. Directs the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to require the Directors of the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research, the Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research, and the Center for Devices and Radiological Health to improve the timelines of the review process for neurology and psychiatry.Requires the Director of the National Neurotechnology Coordination Office to establish the American Neurotechnology Study Center.</summary>
</bill>
