<bill session="110" type="sr" number="381" updated="2013-07-19T22:16:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-14">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution remembering and commemorating the lives and work of Maryknoll Sisters Maura Clarke and Ita Ford, Ursuline Sister Dorothy Kazel, and Cleveland Lay Mission Team Member Jean Donovan, who were executed by members of the Armed Forces of El Salvador on December 2, 1980.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-11-14" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14419-14420" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S14419-14420" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S14404-14405" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Catholic Church"/>
    <term name="Church and social problems"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Hunger"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Missionaries"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2007--Passed Senate without amendment.
Remembers and commemorates the lives and work of Sisters Maura Clarke, Ita Ford, and Dorothy Kazel and lay missionary Jean Donovan, and extends sympathy and support for the families, friends, and religious communities of the four U.S. churchwomen. Continues to find inspiration in their lives and work. Calls upon the people of the United States and religious congregations to participate in local, national, and international events commemorating the 25th anniversary of their martyrdom. Calls upon the President, the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and the heads of other U.S. agencies to support the government of El Salvador, and private sector, nongovernmental, and religious organizations in their efforts to reduce poverty and to promote educational opportunity, health care, and social equity for the people of El Salvador.</summary>
</bill>
