<bill session="110" type="s" number="2231" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cooperative Conservation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Bureau of Reclamation Water Management Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Conservation Bank Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Working Landscape Projects Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to strengthen cooperative conservation efforts and to reduce barriers to the use of partnerships to enable Federal natural resource managers to meet their obligations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13443"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13443-13446" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land banking"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2007--Introduced.
Cooperative Conservation Enhancement Act - Sets forth this Act's findings and purposes.Working Landscape Projects Act of 2007 - Sets forth provisions for the funding and reimbursement of landscape project partners for administrative, governance, and information dissemination activities necessary for the implementation of landscape projects. Conservation Bank Program Act - Sets forth provisions for the establishment, use, and operation of conservation banks.Sets forth provisions regarding the promotion of partnerships between the Department of the Interior and other public and private entities. Sets forth provisions regarding cooperation between the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to: (1) the promotion of customer service and efficiency; and (2) involving the use of funds among specified agencies under their jurisdiction. Authorizes: (1) the Fish and Wildlife Service Coastal Program; and (2) Cooperative Conservation Challenge Cost-Share Agreements. Bureau of Reclamation Water Management Improvement Act - Authorizes grants and cooperative agreements for funding up to 50% of the costs of planning, designing, or constructing improvements for water conservation and use purposes. Establishes within the Department an Office of Collaborative Action and Dispute Resolutions.</summary>
</bill>
