<bill session="109" type="h" number="2990" updated="2013-07-19T19:30:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-12T15:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-12T15:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit Rating Agency Duopoly Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Credit Rating Agency Duopoly Relief Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Credit Rating Agency Duopoly Relief Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve ratings quality by fostering competition, transparency, and accountability in the credit rating agency industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400646"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2005-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2005-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2005-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2005-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5255"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T19:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Price (GA) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Financial Services have until 12:00 p.m. on July 7 to file a report on H.R. 2990. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-07T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 109-546.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-07T12:56:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="306">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 306.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 906 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2990 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 906 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 906.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5080-5094" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5087-5089" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2990 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 906 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Boozman to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2990.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Oxley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kanjorski amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2990.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5094" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-07-12T15:22:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="368" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 255 - 166 (Roll no. 368).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="906"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3850"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1180"/>
    <amendment number="h1181"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/12/2006--Passed House amended.
Credit Rating Agency Duopoly Relief Act of 2006 - (Sec. 4) Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (Act) to define a credit rating agency as any person: (1) engaged in the business of issuing credit ratings on the Internet or through another readily accessible means, for free or for a reasonable fee, but excluding a commercial credit reporting company; (2) employing either a quantitative or qualitative model, or both, to determine credit ratings; and (3) receiving fees from either issuers, investors, or other market participants, or a combination of them. Defines a nationally recognized statistical rating organization (NRSRO) as a credit rating agency that has been in business as a credit rating agency for at least the past three consecutive years and is registered under the Act. Prescribes procedural requirements for mandatory NRSRO registration and certification. Authorizes the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to: (1) take action against any NRSRO that issues credit ratings in contravention of the procedures, criteria, and methodologies that it includes in its registration application or makes and disseminates in required reports; and (2) censure, restrict, suspend for a period not exceeding 12 months, or revoke NRSRO registration for violations of this Act. Declares it is unlawful for an NRSRO to represent or imply that it has been sponsored, recommended, or approved, or that its abilities or qualifications have been passed upon, by any federal agency or officer. States it is unlawful for an unregistered credit rating agency to declare itself an NRSRO. Requires an NRSRO to establish and enforce written policies and procedures to: (1) prevent the misuse in violation of this Act of material, nonpublic information by itself or any associated person; and (2) address and manage potential conflicts of interest. Grants the SEC discretion to adopt rules or regulations to prohibit, or require the management or disclosure of, any conflicts of interest relating to the issuance of credit ratings by an NRSRO. Authorizes the SEC to adopt rules that prohibit unfair, coercive, or abusive practices relating to the issuance of credit ratings by an NRSRO. Requires an NRSRO to: (1) designate a compliance officer for ensuring compliance with securities laws and regulations; and (2) furnish to the SEC certified statements of financial condition by an independent public accountant. Requires the SEC staff, within 30 days of enactment of this Act, to cease designation of persons and companies as NRSRO, as the term is used under current regulations. Declares void and of no force or effect the no-action relief that the SEC has granted with respect to the designation of certain NRSRO. (Sec. 5) Includes an NRSRO among the financial entities required to maintain SEC-prescribed records and reports. States that any report an NRSRO may be required by SEC rules to make and disseminate to the SEC shall be deemed furnished to the SEC. (Sec. 6) Instructs the Comptroller General to study and report to certain congressional committees on: (1) factors that have led to the consolidation of credit rating agencies; (2) the resulting impact upon securities markets; (3) the problems, if any, faced by business organizations resulting from limited competition among credit rating agencies; and (4) whether and to what extent federal or state regulations impede such competition.</summary>
</bill>
