<bill session="109" type="h" number="5016" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27T23:16:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-27T23:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Las Cienegas Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Las Cienegas Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Las Cienegas Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the exchange of certain Bureau of Land Management land in Pima County, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-635.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-06T20:24:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="375">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 375.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7655-7656" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5016.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-27T23:16:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7655-7656" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3051"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3497"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wells"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Passed House amended.
Las Cienegas Enhancement Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), if Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC, offers to convey to the Secretary title to the Empirita-Simonson parcel of land (the non-federal land) to accept the offer and convey to Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC, the Sahuarita parcel of land (the federal land). Requires the values of the federal and non-federal land exchanged to be equal. Sets forth requirements for: (1) an independent appraisal of the federal and non-federal land; and (2) the equalization of the values of such land if they are not equal, including by the payment by Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC, or the Secretary of a cash equalization payment.. Requires: (1) the deposit of any cash equalization payment received by the Secretary in the Federal Land Disposal Account; and (2) amounts so deposited to be available to the Secretary for the acquisition of lands and interests in land in southern Arizona. Subjects the exchange of the federal and non-federal land to any easements, rights-of-way, and other valid encumbrances on such land in existence on the enactment of this Act. Requires Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC, to: (1) pay the costs of carrying out the exchange of such land, including any direct costs related to any environmental reviews and mitigation of the federal land; and (2) convey to Pima County, Arizona, a certain parcel of land. Instructs the Secretary to provide to the Secretary of Agriculture a right of way through the non-federal land for motorized public road access to the boundary of the Coronado National Forest. Requires the Secretary, upon acquisition of the non-federal land, to include the acquired land as part of the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area. Modifies the boundary of the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area to exclude the 40-acre tract that, as of the enactment of this Act, is leased by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to the town of Elgin, Arizona, for a sanitary landfill.</summary>
</bill>
