<bill session="112" type="h" number="6424" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End the Congressional Revolving Door Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that a former Member of Congress or former Congressional employee who receives compensation as a lobbyist shall not be eligible for retirement benefits or certain other Federal benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2012--Introduced.
End the Congressional Revolving Door Act - Prohibits a former Member of Congress or former congressional employee who is a registered lobbyist, and entitled to compensation as such, from being eligible for any benefits beginning after enactment of this Act under: the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS), including the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP); the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), including the TSP; the Federal Employees' Health Benefits (FEHB) Program, including federal enhanced dental and vision benefits; or the Federal Employees' Group Life Insurance (FEGLI) Program. States that nothing in this Act shall be considered to prevent the payment of any: (1) CSRS or FERS lump-sum credit to which an individual is entitled, or (2) nonforfeitable amount in an individual's Thrift Savings Fund account.</summary>
</bill>
