<bill session="112" type="h" number="2609" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Livability for All Americans Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an Office of Livability in the Office of the Secretary of Transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2011--Introduced.
Enhancing Livability for All Americans Act of 2011 - Establishes within the Office of the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) an Office of Livability. Requires the Office Director to establish a program to award competitive grants to eligible entities to assist: (1) capital investments in surface transportation projects with a significant impact on enhancing the livability in a region, metropolitan area, community, or neighborhood; and (2) communities in developing strategic growth plans that provide a vision and goals for development over a minimum 20-year period and integrate long-term innovative transportation and land use planning. Requires priority be given to: (1) investment projects that increase the number of transportation options, improve access to housing, jobs, and services, and reduce greenhouse gas; and (2) innovative planning applicants who have proposed strategic growth plans for communities with transportation systems characterized by poor access to job centers and schools, limited transportation options for residents, and significant traffic congestion. Requires the Director to: (1) develop statistical and analytical capabilities to ascertain specified transportation data; and (2) collaborate with other federal agencies to carry out activities that promote the development of livable communities, increase transportation choices, and improve the environment, public health, and quality of life.</summary>
</bill>
