<bill session="110" type="s" number="1135" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Arbitration Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 1 of title 9, United States Code, to establish fair procedures for arbitration clauses in contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4614-4615"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4615-4616" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Small claims courts"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2007--Introduced.
Fair Arbitration Act of 2007 - Requires a contract containing an arbitration clause, in order to be binding on the parties, to: (1) have a heading "ARBITRATION CLAUSE" printed in bold, capital letters; (2) state explicitly whether participation in arbitration is mandatory or optional; (3) identify a source that a consumer or employee can contact for additional information regarding the arbitration program; and (4) provide notice that all parties retain the right to resolve a dispute in a small claims court for a claim of $50,000 or less. Entitles each party under arbitration to: (1) a competent, neutral arbitrator and independent, neutral administration of the dispute; (2) representation by an attorney or other representative at such party's expense; (3) a fair arbitration hearing; (4) a face-to-face hearing; (5) the right to present evidence and cross examine witnesses; (6) a written explanation of the basis for the arbitrator's decision; and (7) the right to opt out of binding arbitration and into the small claims court (for claims of $50,000 or less). Prescribes procedures for complaints by any party of denial of rights by the other party or the arbitrator.</summary>
</bill>
