<bill session="111" type="s" number="1252" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote ocean and human health and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6558-6559"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6559-6560" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-296.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="573">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 573.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Oceans and Human Health Act to expand the interagency oceans and human health research program to include coasts and the Great Lakes and to direct the President, through the National Science and Technology Council (NSTC), to deliver information, products, and services to reduce public health risks and enhance health benefits from the ocean. Directs the NSTC, through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, to submit to Congress, within two years after enactment of this Act and every five years thereafter, an update of the 2007 Interagency Oceans and Human Health Research Implementation Plan. Requires that such update define the roles of specified federal agencies to avoid duplication of activities and coordinate federal efforts in support of the research program. Adds surveillance, forecasting, mitigation, prevention, and outreach goals to federal research priorities. Extends the program's scope to atmospheric sciences, food-borne diseases, corals, and shellfish. Authorizes social, economic, and behavioral studies of human health and well-being. Authorizes coordination with interagency working groups of the Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology, through the NSTC, to monitor and reduce marine public health problems, including climate change. Authorizes development of new technologies for detecting and reducing hazards to human health from ocean sources, including genomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and sensors to detect distribution, concentration, toxicity, or virulence of infectious microbes, harmful algae, toxins, and chemical contaminants in ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes waters, sediments, organisms, and seafood. Requires the NSTC to submit to the President and Congress a biennial report (currently, an annual report), including funding recommendations. (Sec. 3) Requires the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to establish an Oceans and Human Health Program (OHHP) to coordinate certain activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including forecasting long term health impacts, surveillance of public health threats, risk assessment, and development of ocean health products and services. Directs NOAA to develop a strategic implementation plan. Requires the OHHP to support: (1) centralized research coordination; (2) an external advisory panel; (3) NOAA national centers of excellence; (4) diagnostic laboratories; (5) transition of discoveries from research activities into applications; (6) research grants; and (7) distinguished scholars and training. Extends advisory group membership to public health professionals and veterinarians. Revises focus of NOAA centers of excellence to areas defined in this Act. Authorizes establishment of a competitive program to recognize highly distinguished external scientists in any area of oceans and human health research and to involve those scientists in collaborative work with NOAA's OHHP. Requires the Secretary to coordinate among OHHP, the Integrated Ocean Observing System, Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia Program, and NOAA to develop specified forecasting systems and avoid duplication of activities. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on NOAA's plans to implement recommendations of its Science Advisory Board Working Group on Oceans and Health. Permits NOAA to: (1) accept and use federal, state, and private funds and in-kind contributions; (2) apply for and hold patents and receive royalties; and (3) accept reimbursement for sharing personnel and facilities with public and private partners. (Sec. 4) Revises requirements for dissemination of information, and for reporting on the results of the research, assessments, and findings, developed under OHHP. (Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations for FY2010-FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
