<bill session="109" type="s" number="825" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crossroads of the American Revolution National Heritage Area Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Crossroads of the American Revolution National Heritage Area in the State of New Jersey, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3819"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3820-3821" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="American Revolution"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2005--Introduced.
Crossroads of the American Revolution National Heritage Area Act of 2005 - Establishes the Crossroads of the American Revolution National Heritage Area in New Jersey. Designates the Crossroads of the American Revolution Association, Inc. as the Area's management entity. Directs the Association to submit, and to assist local governments, regional planing organizations, and nonprofit entities in implementing, an area management plan which includes strategies for conservation, funding, management, and development of the Area.Bars the Association from using Federal funds received under this Act to acquire real property, but allows it to use any other source of funding, including other Federal funding, intended for the acquisition of real property.Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide assistance to: (1) the Area to develop and implement the management plan; and (2) State or local government or nonprofit organizations for treatment of historical objects or structures eligible for listing on the National Register of Historic Places. Authorizes the Superintendent of Morristown National Historical Park to provide operational assistance supporting implementation of the management plan to public and private organizations within the Area, including the Association.</summary>
</bill>
