<bill session="113" type="s" number="496" updated="2013-11-02T06:56:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers Undertake Environmental Land Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FUELS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to change the Spill Prevention, Control, and Countermeasure rule with respect to certain farms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="311"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2013--Introduced.
Farmers Undertake Environmental Land Stewardship Act or the FUELS Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in implementing the Spill Prevention, Control, and Countermeasure rule with respect to any farm, to require certification of compliance with such rule by: (1) a professional engineer for a farm with an individual tank with an aboveground storage capacity greater than 10,000 gallons, an aggregate aboveground storage capacity of at least 42,000 gallons, or a reportable oil discharge history; or (2) the owner or operator of the farm (via self-certification) for a farm with an aggregate aboveground storage capacity greater than 10,000 gallons but less than 42,000 gallons and no reportable oil discharge history of oil. Directs the Administrator to exempt from all requirements of such rule any farm with an aggregate aboveground storage capacity of 10,000 gallons or less and no reportable oil discharge history. Excludes from the aggregate storage capacity of a farm all containers on separate parcels that have a capacity of less than 1,320 gallons.</summary>
</bill>
