<bill session="112" type="h" number="6649" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-31T13:37:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-31T13:37:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Naval Vessels Transfer Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the transfer of naval vessels to certain foreign recipients.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2012-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7508-7511" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6649.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-12-31T13:37:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7508" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T13:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/31/2012--Passed House amended.
Naval Vessels Transfer Act of 2012 - Authorizes the President to transfer on a grant basis to: (1) Mexico, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates CURTS and MCCLUSKY; (2) Thailand, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates RENTZ and VANDEGRIFT; and (3) Turkey, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates HALYBURTON and THACH. Authorizes the President to transfer on a sale basis the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates TAYLOR, GARY, CARR, and ELROD to the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office of the United States (which is the Taiwan instrumentality designated pursuant to the Taiwan Relations Act). Authorizes the President to transfer any vessel named in this Act to any country named in this Act such that the total number of vessels transferred to such country does not exceed the total number of vessels authorized for transfer to such country by this Act. States that: (1) the value of such vessels transferred on a grant basis shall not be counted against the aggregate value of excess defense articles transferred to countries in any fiscal year under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961; (2) transfer costs shall be charged to the recipient; and (3) to the maximum extent practicable, the country to which a vessel is transferred shall have necessary vessel repair and refurbishment carried out at U.S. shipyards (including U.S. Navy shipyards). Terminates transfer authority three years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
