<bill session="111" type="h" number="4271" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Adult Education and Family Literacy Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform and strengthen the workforce investment system of the Nation to put Americans back to work and make the United States more competitive in the 21st Century.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2009-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/10/2009--Introduced.
Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (WIA) to revise requirements and reauthorize appropriations for: (1) WIA title I, workforce investment systems for job training and employment services; and (2) WIA title II, adult education and family literacy education programs. Revises and reauthorizes workforce investment systems with respect to: (1) state and local planning, allocation, work force investment board membership, and performance accountability; (2) one-stop centers; (3) consolidated funding for adult program activities, including job training, dislocated worker retraining, the employment service system, and reemployment grants; (4) training programs for both out-of-school and in-school youth, including challenge grants; and (5) national job training programs, including the Job Corps and programs for Native Americans, migrant and seasonal farmworkers, and veterans. Requires the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor to be the principal agency to administer WIA title I workforce investment systems for job training and employment services and title III (Job Corps). Exempts religious organizations, with respect to their employment of individuals of a particular religion, from WIA nondiscrimination requirements. Prescribes requirements for the approval of state Workforce Innovation in Regional Economic Development (WIRED) plans for the carrying out of certain workforce development activities. Repeals Wagner-Peyser Act provisions relating to the U.S. Employment Service. Directs the Secretary of Labor to oversee the development, maintenance, and continuous improvement of a nationwide workforce and labor market information system. Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for: (1) vocational rehabilitation services under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; and (2) the Helen Keller National Center Act.</summary>
</bill>
