<bill session="109" type="s" number="1577" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to facilitate the transfer of Spearfish Hydroelectric Plant Number 1 to the city of Spearfish, South Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-460.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5566"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Exempts the Spearfish Hydroelectric Plant Number 1 located in Lawrence County, South Dakota, from the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey, to study the hydrology of Spearfish Creek, South Dakota. Expresses the sense of Congress that the city of Spearfish, South Dakota, in order to provide for the restoration and improvement of Spearfish Creek, should: (1) uphold the Memorandum Agreement of the city of Spearfish and the Spearfish Canyon Landowners Association, dated September 14, 2004; and (2) take action to release additional water flow of approximately five to 10 cubic feet per second between the Maurice Intake Dam and the Spearfish Diversion.</summary>
</bill>
