<bill session="111" type="s" number="1029" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Skills Incentive Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to create a new incentive fund that will encourage States to adopt the 21st Century Skills Framework.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5439-5440"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
21st Century Skills Incentive Fund Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to states to establish statewide 21st Century Skills initiatives. Conditions grant eligibility on a state's: (1) developing a comprehensive plan for such initiative; (2) showing a commitment to advancing such skills within standards and assessments, curriculum, professional development, and the learning environment; (3) achieving broad support for the initiative among state education, business, and civic leaders; and (4) implementing 21st century assessments of education that measure core subjects and 21st century themes, life and career skills, thinking and innovation skills, and information media and technology skills. Directs the Secretary to establish a 21st Century Skills Incentive Fund from which grants shall be awarded. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require that the percentage limitation on corporate charitable contributions be applied separately to cash contributions to state 21st Century Skills initiatives and all other corporate charitable contributions.</summary>
</bill>
