<bill session="109" type="h" number="6009" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Awareness of Problem Gambling Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address problem gambling.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400269"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Mass media"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting of sports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Comprehensive Awareness of Problem Gambling Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a national campaign to raise awareness of problem gambling issues. Requires the Secretary to: (1) administer and coordinate the voluntary donation of resources to assist in implementing new programs and augmenting existing national campaigns to provide national strategies for dissemination of information intended to address problem gambling; (2) encourage media outlets throughout the country to provide information aimed at preventing problem gambling; and (3) target radio and television audiences of sporting events and gambling. Requires the President: (1) to establish and implement a national program of research on problem gambling; (2) to appoint an advisory commission to coordinate the activities of federal agencies relating to such research; (3) to consider the National Gambling Impact Study Commission's recommendations; and (4) acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to develop a Treatment Improvement Protocol for problem gambling. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to states, local governments, and nonprofit agencies to provide comprehensive services with respect to treatment and prevention of, and education about, problem gambling issues. Expresses the sense of Congress that every state should contribute a percentage of its revenue from gambling towards prevention and treatment of, and services and education about, problem gambling.</summary>
</bill>
