<bill session="112" type="h" number="4394" updated="2013-07-20T01:48:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Financial Literacy Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide incentives to encourage financial institutions and small businesses to provide continuing financial education to customers, borrowers, and employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2012--Introduced.
National Financial Literacy Act of 2012 - Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to require federal financial supervisory agencies jointly to prescribe regulations establishing: (1) minimum standards to be met by a community-based financial literacy program in order to be eligible for consideration as a qualified community-based financial literacy program; (2) procedures for financial institutions to apply to a federal financial supervisory agency for approval of such a program; and (3) a requirement that financial institutions submit a regular report on how the institution supported and promoted financial literacy in its entire community, including low- and moderate-income neighborhoods. Authorizes a federal financial supervisory agency to take an institution's direct support of a qualified community-based financial literacy program into account when it assesses the institution's record of meeting the community's credit needs. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit to small businesses for 35% of the expenses paid or incurred for providing qualified continuing financial education to their employees. Requires that preference in federal contracts, loans, and other financial or nonfinancial assistance for small businesses and corporations be given to those providing continuing financial education to their employees.</summary>
</bill>
