<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1566" updated="2013-07-19T23:09:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30T12:15:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-30T12:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the 50th anniversary of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) and the pioneering of college students whose determination and nonviolent resistance led to the desegregation of lunch counters and places of public accommodation over a 5-year period.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T00:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cohen moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T00:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6440-6442" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T00:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1566.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T00:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 1566.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T00:39:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T12:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6484-6485" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-07-30T12:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="503" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 0 (Roll no. 503).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6440-6441" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T12:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Recognizes the 50th anniversary of the founding of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC). Commemorates the significance and importance of SNCC and its role in organizing the national sit-in movement and the role that they played in the desegregation of U.S. society and for creating the political climate necessary to pass legislation to expand civil rights and voting rights. Encourages the people of the United States to recognize and celebrate the legal victories of the national sit-in movement that sought to eradicate segregation in U.S. society. States that the House of Representatives aspires to work with the same courage, determination, dignity, and commitment exemplified by those pioneering students who dared to challenge a segregated society by addressing modern-day inequalities and injustice.</summary>
</bill>
