<bill session="109" type="s" number="3841" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize appropriations for the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program in the States of Arizona, California, and Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2006-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2006-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8974-8975"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5180"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/5/2006--Introduced.
Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage and implement the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program, and to enter into an agreement with Arizona, California, and Nevada providing for the use of water from the Lower Colorado River for habitat creation and maintenance, in accordance with the Habitat Conservation Plan, Biological Assessment and Biological and Conference Opinion, Environmental Impact Statement/Environmental Impact Report, Funding and Management Agreement, Implementing Agreement. Permits any party to an agreement entered into with the United States pursuant to the Program to commence a civil action in U.S. district court to enforce the agreement or to declare the rights and obligations of the parties under the program documents. Grants the district court jurisdiction over any such action.</summary>
</bill>
