<bill session="109" type="s" number="3693" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-08-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make technical corrections to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-07-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7933-7934, S7936-7941" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7936-7941" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20T10:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-29T01:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cannon asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-29T01:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/28/2005 H6222-6227" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-07-29T01:49:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/28/2005 H6222-6227" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-29T01:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-29T01:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of S. Con. Res. 112, enrollment corrections on S. 3693 have been made.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-07-29">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-08-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-08-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-08-12" type="public" number="109-271">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-271.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3402"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sc" number="112"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sc" number="112"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian courts"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Indian women"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Rural crime"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/12/2006--Public Law.
Makes technical corrections and other amendments to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (the Act) and other related federal legislation. (Sec. 1) Establishes as new short titles for specified provisions of the Act: (1) the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2005; and (2) the Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act of 2005. Delays the effective date of specified provisions of the Act until FY2007. Makes certain definitions and grant conditions in the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 applicable to provisions of the Act relating to crimes on campuses, outreach to underserved populations, and cultural services. Defines "tribal nonprofit organization" for purposes of the Act. Modifies universal grant conditions of the Act to qualify states for waivers of matching fund requirements based on demonstrated financial need. (Sec. 2) Extends the authorization of appropriations for sex offender management programs through FY2011. Amends federal criminal code provisions relating to domestic violence and stalking to modify the definition of "spouse or intimate partner." Eliminates provisions of the Act relating to training, technical assistance, and data collection for violence against women "STOP" grants and grants to encourage arrest. Modifies the reporting requirement for recipients of grants for outreach to underserved populations. Extends to three years the compliance period for making forensic medical exams available to victims of sexual assault. Expands grant purposes for community-based programs for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Modifies funding allocations under the grant program to combat violent crimes against women relating to law enforcement, prosecutors, and victims services. (Sec. 3) Repeals the sexual assault services program enacted by the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 and reestablishes such program in the Violence Against Women Act of 1994. (Sec. 4) Modifies: (1) grant purpose provisions relating to violent crimes on campuses; and (2) grantee reporting requirements to require annual rather than biennial reports on programs to combat such crime. (Sec. 5) Makes technical amendments to housing provisions of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act, and the United States Housing Act of 1937. Amends the Housing Act of 1937 to: (1) prohibit the denial of assisted housing benefits to individuals who are victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking; and (2) allow the eviction of assisted housing tenants who engage in criminal acts of domestic violence against family members or others. (Sec. 6) Amends the Immigration and Naturalization Act to modify provisions relating to admissibility, waivers, removal, and adjustment of status for Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) self-petitioners. Allows the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive inadmissibility for a VAWA self-petitioner if there is a connection between the alien's battering or subjection to extreme cruelty and the alien's removal, departure from the United States, or reentry or reentries into the United States. (Sec. 7) Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (OCCSSA) to: (1) modify grant allocations to Indian tribal governments for programs to combat violence against women and to encourage arrests and enforce protection orders; and (2) authorize the Attorney General to make grants to such governments for free (or minimal cost) legal assistance to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault who are seeking legal relief. Amends the Safe Homes for Women Act of 1994, the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, and the Violence Against Women Act of 2000 to modify grant allocations for specified programs to combat violence against Indian tribal women. (Sec. 8) Transfers grant authority for the organized retail theft national database and the juvenile and young adult witness assistance program from the Attorney General to the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance in the Office of Justice Programs. Repeals provisions of the Act relating to state grants and reporting requirements under OCCSSA. Extends restrictions on payments to private entities for Justice Department employee training facilities to include meals, lodging, or other expenses related to internal training or conference meetings. Extends the application period for grants under the Bureau of Justice Assistance Grant Programs (Byrne Grants) from 90 to 120 days after the date funds for such grants are appropriated. Transfers grant authority for the matching grant program for school security from the Attorney General to the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services. Increases FY2006 authorizations of appropriations for: (1) the U.S. Marshals Service; (2) the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF); (3) fees and expenses of witnesses; and (4) the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission. Transfers responsibility for Drug Courts technical assistance and training from the Community Capacity Development Office to the Bureau of Justice Assistance. Changes effective dates for various programs under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
