<bill session="112" type="s" number="1165" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Button Cell Battery Safety Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect children and other consumers against hazards associated with the accidental ingestion of button cell batteries by requiring the Consumer Product Safety Commission to promulgate consumer product safety standards to require child-resistant closures on remote controls and other consumer products that use such batteries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2011-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3688-3689"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2011--Introduced.
Button Cell Battery Safety Act of 2011 - Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate: (1) a standard requiring button cell battery compartments of battery-operated or assisted consumer products to be secured in a manner that reduces access to such batteries by children that are three years of age or younger; and (2) standards requiring warning labels to be included in any literature that accompanies such a product, on packaging for such batteries sold to consumers, and directly on such a product in a manner that is visible to the consumer upon installation or replacement of the battery. Requires such labels to clearly identify the hazard of ingestion and to instruct consumers to keep new and used batteries out of the reach of children and to seek immediate medical attention if a battery is ingested. Exempts such regulations from procedures for consumer product safety rules. Makes such regulations effective one year after the standard is promulgated.</summary>
</bill>
