<bill session="109" type="h" number="1076" updated="2013-07-19T19:13:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Detention of Enemy Combatants Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the President to detain an enemy combatant who is a United States person or resident who is a member of al Qaeda or knowingly cooperated with members of al Qaeda, to guarantee timely access to judicial review to challenge the basis for a detention, to permit the detainee access to counsel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E351"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Detention of Enemy Combatants Act - Authorizes the detention of a U.S. person or resident (excluding a prisoner of war) as an enemy combatant if that individual is an al Qaeda member or knowingly cooperated with an al Qaeda member in planning, authorizing, committing, aiding, or abetting a terrorist act against the United States. Directs the Secretary of Defense to prescribe, publish, and report the standards, process, and criteria: (1) to be used in determining that an American citizen or lawful resident is an enemy combatant; and (2) for that individual's detention. Requires rules for the detention of enemy combatants to: (1) establish clear standards and procedures that meet specified requirements, including preserving the Government's ability to detain those who may threaten the United States; and (2) guarantee timely access to judicial review and permit the detainee access to counsel.Authorizes a U.S. person to be detained as an enemy combatant only while there is in effect a presidential certification that: (1) the U.S. armed forces are in a state of armed conflict with al Qaeda and an investigation, prosecution, or post-trial proceeding regarding such person is ongoing; or (2) detention is warranted to prevent such individual from aiding persons attempting to commit terrorist acts against the United States.Grants the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia exclusive jurisdiction to review any detention under this Act.Requires that detainees be: (1) detained at an appropriate location; (2) treated humanely; (3) afforded adequate food, water, shelter, clothing, and medical treatment; (4) sheltered under hygienic conditions; and (5) allowed the free exercise of religion consistent with specified requirements.</summary>
</bill>
