<bill session="113" type="s" number="195" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health in Schools Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend projects relating to children and violence to provide access to school-based comprehensive mental health programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights and Human Rights. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSHR" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights and Human Rights" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="628"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2013--Introduced.
Mental Health in Schools Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise a community children and violence program to assist local communities and schools in applying a public health approach to mental health services, including by: (1) revising eligibility requirements for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; and (2) providing for comprehensive school mental health programs that are culturally and linguistically appropriate, trauma-informed, and age appropriate. Requires a comprehensive school mental health program funded under this Act to assist children in dealing with trauma and violence. Makes only a partnership between a local educational agency and at least one community program or agency that is involved in mental health eligible for such funding. Sets forth assurances required for eligibility, including that: (1) the local education agency will enter into a memorandum of understanding with at least one relevant community-based entity that clearly states the responsibilities of each partner; (2) the program will include training of all school personnel, family members of children with mental health disorders, and concerned members of the community; and (3) the program will demonstrate the measures to be taken to sustain the program after funding terminates. Requires grantees to comply with the health information privacy requirements of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA). Requires the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to develop a fiscally appropriate process for evaluating grant program activities, including: (1) the development of guidelines for the submission of program data by recipients; and (2) the development of measures of outcomes to be applied by recipients in evaluating programs, to include student and family measures and local educational measures.</summary>
</bill>
