<bill session="111" type="h" number="1745" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23T15:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-23T15:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Health Care Accessibility Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Family Health Care Accessibility Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Family Health Care Accessibility Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide liability protections for volunteer practitioners at health centers under section 330 of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2009-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 111-607.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-16T16:21:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="352">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 352.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6848-6850" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1745.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6941-6942" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-09-23T15:36:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="543" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 1 (Roll no. 543).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/22/2010 H6848-6849" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2010--Passed House amended.
Family Health Care Accessibility Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to deem a health professional volunteer providing primary health care to an individual at a community health center to be an employee of the Public Health Service for purposes of any civil action that may arise from providing services to patients. Sets forth conditions for such liability protection, including: (1) the service is provided to the individual at a community health center or through offsite programs or events carried out by such center; (2) the provider is sponsored by the community health center; (3) the health care practitioner does not receive any compensation for providing the service, except repayment for reasonable expenses; (4) before the service is provided, the health care practitioner or the center posts a clear and conspicuous notice at the site where the service is provided of the extent to which the legal liability of the health care practitioner is limited pursuant to this Act; (5) at the time the service is provided, the health care practitioner is licensed or certified in accordance with applicable law regarding the provision of the service; and (6) the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) transfers funds to an account to cover costs for such coverage. Considers an entity as sponsoring the health care practitioner if: (1) the entity submits an application to the Secretary; and (2) the Secretary determines that the health care practitioner is deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service. Requires the Attorney General to submit to Congress a report providing an estimate of the amount of claims (together with related fees and expenses of witnesses) that, by reason of the actions or omissions of health professional volunteers, will be paid pursuant to this Act during the calendar year that begins in the following fiscal year. Requires the Secretary to transfer such estimated amount from the claims fund to the appropriate accounts in the Treasury, subject to the extent of amounts in the fund. Makes this Act effective on October 1, 2011, except permits upon its enactment: (1) the Secretary to issue regulations for carrying out this Act and to accept and consider applications under this Act; and (2) the Attorney General to submit reports to Congress under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
