<bill session="109" type="h" number="5939" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Criminal Terrorism Improvements Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to improve the criminal law relating to terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Antiaircraft missiles"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Virus diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2006--Introduced.
Criminal Terrorism Improvements Act of 2006 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose the death penalty or life imprisonment on individuals who cause the death of a person while committing a terrorist act. Authorizes the death penalty for: (1) developing, possessing, or threatening to use radiological weapons against a person or against U.S. property; (2) causing the death of an individual by using missile systems designed to destroy aircraft, by using radiological dispersal devices, or by using the variola virus; and (3) use of atomic weapons with intent to injure the United States. Increases criminal penalties for: (1) attempting or conspiring to kill a U.S. national; (2) engaging in physical violence with the intent to injure a U.S. national; (3) financing terrorism or concealing assets to be used for terrorist activities; and (4) providing material support to terrorists or receiving military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization. Amends the crime of receiving military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization to include attempts or conspiracies to receive such training. Denies certain federal benefits to individuals convicted of a federal crime of terrorism. Expands the authorization for interception of communications (wiretapping) to include all federal crimes of terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
