<bill session="111" type="s" number="3917" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal features of the electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, if the Strawberry Water Users Association conveys its interest, if any, in an electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, and the District agrees to assume from the United States all liability for the administration, operation, maintenance, and replacement of the electric distribution system, to convey and assign to the District: (1) all interest of the United States in all fixtures owned by the United States as part of the electric distribution system and the federal lands and interests where the fixtures are located; (2) license for use of the shared power poles; and (3) a license for use and access to all Strawberry Valley Project land and interests in irrigation and power facilities lands on which the electric distribution system is located that are necessary for other Project facilities, including land underlying the Strawberry Substation, if the ownership of such underlying land or interest is retained by the United States, and any corridors in which federal land and interests are abutting public streets and roads and would provide access to those facilities.</summary>
</bill>
