<bill session="110" type="s" number="2201" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HOME Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Home Ownership Mortgage Emergency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the penalty-free use of retirement funds for mortgage delinquency relief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13090-13091"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13091" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2007--Introduced.
Home Ownership Mortgage Emergency Act, or the HOME Act - Exempts any qualified mortgage delinquency relief distribution from the 10% additional tax imposed by the Internal Revenue Code on early distributions from qualified retirement plans.Provides that the aggregate amount of distributions received by an individual which may be treated as qualified mortgage delinquency relief distributions for any taxable year shall not exceed the excess (if any) of $100,000, over the aggregate amounts treated as qualified mortgage delinquency relief distributions received by such individual for all prior taxable years.Defines the term "qualified mortgage delinquency relief distribution," with the exception of such aggregate dollar limitation, as any distribution from an eligible retirement plan made on or after the enactment of this Act and before January 1, 2010, to an individual whose: (1) acquisition indebtedness, with respect to the taxpayer's principal residence, is in delinquency for at least 60 days; and (2) adjusted gross income for the taxable year of such distribution does not exceed a specified amount.Declares that qualified mortgage delinquency relief distributions shall not be treated as eligible rollover distributions (thus exempting them from certain trustee to trustee transfer and withholding rules).Treats such relief distributions as meeting certain plan distribution requirements of the Code.</summary>
</bill>
