<bill session="113" type="s" number="247" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Harriet Tubman National Historical Parks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Harriet Tubman National Historical Parks Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Harriet Tubman National Historical Park in Auburn, New York, and the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park in Caroline, Dorchester, and Talbot Counties, Maryland, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S522-523"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S523-524" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden with an amendment. With written report No. 113-23.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="54">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 54.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="513"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="664"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Harriet Tubman National Historical Parks Act - Establishes in Caroline, Dorchester, and Talbot Counties, Maryland, the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park System. Establishes in Auburn, New York, the Harriet Tubman National Historical Park also as a unit of the National Park System. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with certain entities for the historical preservation and interpretation of such park. Requires the Secretary to complete a general management plan for such park. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1996, with respect to the federal share of project costs for navigation and safety improvements, Chesapeake and Delaware Canal, Baltimore Harbor Connecting Channels, Delaware and Maryland, to offset the costs of such park.</summary>
</bill>
