<bill session="112" type="h" number="5638" updated="2013-07-20T01:58:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Service Member Anti-Hazing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary concerned to develop and implement policies and procedures to prevent and respond to hazing in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2012-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2012--Introduced.
Service Member Anti-Hazing Act - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to: (1) develop and implement a policy to prevent and respond to hazing of members of that military department; (2) develop and implement a program to train such members on the dangers of, and need to, avoid hazing and a program of training on issues of diversity, which each member shall attend at least annually; (3) expand any policies for reporting incidents to include a phone service for the anonymous reporting of such incidents; and (4) develop and implement a procedure to transfer to another unit a victim of a substantial hazing incident. Establishes the Military Hazing Prevention Oversight Panel to make recommendations to the Secretary concerned on the development of the policies, programs, and procedures required above, and on ways to improve them.</summary>
</bill>
