<bill session="113" type="s" number="1301" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Eastside Forests Restoration, Old Growth Protection, and Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the restoration of forest landscapes, protection of old growth forests, and management of national forests in the eastside forests of the State of Oregon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5711-5712"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2013--Introduced.
Oregon Eastside Forests Restoration, Old Growth Protection, and Jobs Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Chief of the Forest Service, in a covered area of Oregon to seek to: (1) conserve and restore forest and watershed health and other ecosystems; (2) reduce the risk of, and increase the resistance and resiliency of the land to, uncharacteristic disturbances; (3) allow for characteristic natural disturbances; and (4) harvest wood to maintain adequate levels of industry infrastructure to accomplish such goals. Defines "covered area" as an area selected by the Secretary that is within Oregon and not within the area covered by the Record of Decision for Amendments to Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management Planning Documents Within the Range of the Northern Spotted Owl, dated April 1994. Requires the Secretary to: (1) implement covered area ecological restoration projects to help achieve these goals; and (2) offer, and promptly implement, covered area mechanical treatment projects emphasizing sawtimber as a byproduct. Requires each vegetation management project to protect and restore aquatic and riparian-dependent resources. Establishes the Eastside Forest Scientific and Technical Advisory Panel to advise the Secretary, collaborative groups, and the public about the development and implementation of goals to improve forest and watershed health and related social and economic goals. Instructs the Secretary to prepare a large scale environmental impact statement to support a record of decision for vegetation management projects in National Forests in the eastern part of Oregon for projects: (1) that are located wholly in dry ponderosa pine and dry mixed conifer forests types, (2) that are on a pilot landscape, (3) that are endorsed by or the product of a collaborative group, and (4) no portion of which is located in an inventoried roadless area. Directs the Secretary to carry out a project to support the ability of USDA to address the restoration of forests in cooperation with states.</summary>
</bill>
