<bill session="111" type="s" number="3939" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Earmark Reform and Federal Spending Transparency and Accountability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reform earmarking and increase transparency and accountability for all expenditures authorized by Congress and all executive agencies of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7902-7907"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2010--Introduced.
Earmark Reform and Federal Spending Transparency and Accountability Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit, between January 1 of an odd-numbered year and December 31 of the next even-numbered year, an earmark beneficiary from making contributions aggregating more than $5,000 to any requesting candidate with respect to such earmark beneficiary. Defines "requesting candidate" as any Senator or Member who requested a congressionally directed spending item, limited tax benefit, or limited tariff benefit (earmark) which benefits the earmark beneficiary. Prohibits the employees of the personal staff of a Member of Congress, except for one designee, from attending a political fund raiser held on the Member's behalf. Requires the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives each to post on the respective public website a link to the earmark database maintained by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). Requires the head of each federal department and agency to post on the respective public website a link to a searchable database that lists each contract, grant, cooperative agreement, and other expenditure made by the department or agency. Amends Rule XLIV (Congressionally Directed Spending and Related Items) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require a Senator requesting an earmark in any legislation or an accompanying joint statement of managers to certify in the required written statement to the chairman and ranking member of the committee of jurisdiction that the earmark recipient is qualified to handle the project. Requires the Comptroller General, in an annual report to Congress, to use the OMB database to: (1) randomly select a percentage of each of the programs and projects funded through earmarks in the preceding fiscal year; (2) audit each selected one; and (3) provide a detailed accounting of how, if it does so, the earmark contributes to an already existing program or project.</summary>
</bill>
