<bill session="111" type="hr" number="685" updated="2013-07-19T23:01:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-29T13:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-29T13:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3326) making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-233, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The bill shall be considered as read through page 147, line 4. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, except as provided in section 2, no amendment shall be in order except those amendments printed in the report of the Committee on Rules. All points of order against such amendments are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. After disposition of the amendments specified, the Chair and Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on Appropriations or their designees each may offer one pro forma amendment to the bill for the purpose of debate, which shall be controlled by the proponent. The Chair may entertain a motion that the Committee rise only if offered by the Chair of the Committee on Appropriations or his designee. the Chair may not entertain a motion to strike out the enacting words of the bill (as described in clause 9 of rule XVIII). During consideration of H.R. 3326, the Chair may reduce to two minutes the minimum time for electronic voting under clause 6 of rule XVIII and clauses 8 and 9 of rule XX.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-28T17:48:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="98">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 98.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Polis called up H.Res. 685 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T11:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 685 because it violated the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 685. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair put the question of consideration of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>On question of consideration. Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8976-8986" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 685.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-07-29T13:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="655" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 185 (Roll no. 655).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8976-8977" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3326"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h391"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/28/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3326) making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
