<bill session="110" type="h" number="1886" updated="2013-07-19T21:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent public financing of oil or gas field development projects, surveying or extraction activities, processing facilities, pipelines, or terminals, or other oil and gas production or distribution operations or facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Export-Import Bank of the United States from guaranteeing, insuring, or extending credit: (1) in connection with an oil or gas project; or (2) to any entity that may use the guarantee, insurance, or credit to finance such a project. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit the Overseas Private Investment Corporation from issuing any contract of insurance or reinsurance or any guarantee, or entering into any financing agreement for an oil or gas project, or to taking such actions respecting any person who will insure or finance such project. Amends the International Financial Institutions Act to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to use U.S. influence to oppose multilateral development institution assistance to gas or oil development projects.</summary>
</bill>
