<bill session="110" type="s" number="1253" updated="2013-07-19T22:31:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Centennial Challenge Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a fund for the National Park Centennial Challenge, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="2008-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5310-5311"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5311" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-185.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2959"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2959"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2007--Introduced.
National Park Centennial Challenge Fund Act - Establishes in the Treasury the National Park Centennial Challenge Fund (the Challenge Fund) which shall consist of qualified donations transferred from the Donations to the National Park Service account and amounts appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury, in accordance with this Act. Makes available all amounts deposited in the Challenge Fund to the Secretary of the Interior for signature projects and programs under this Act (projects and programs identified by the Director of the National Park Service (NPS) as those that will help prepare the national parks for another century of conservation, preservation, and enjoyment). Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to develop a list of signature projects and programs eligible for funding from the Challenge Fund. Requires that such list be submitted to the President and specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
