<bill session="109" type="sr" number="139" updated="2013-07-19T20:08:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-12">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing support for the withdrawal of Russian troops from Georgia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300045" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-05-12" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5182-5183" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5183" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5171-5172" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the Russian Federation should respect the territorial integrity and sovereignty of the Republic of Georgia; (2) President Mikheil Saakashvili and the Government and people of Georgia deserve congratulations for the successful reforms carried out since President Saakashvili's inauguration; (3) the United States should support such reforms and assist Georgia in strengthening its democratic institutions and resolving its separatist conflicts peacefully; and (4) the United States should support Georgia in negotiating an agreement to end Russia's military presence in Georgia, in accordance with Russia's obligations under the ``Istanbul Commitments.'' Supports President Bush's efforts to encourage Russia and Georgia to reach agreement on the closure of Russian military bases in Georgia. Commends President Bush for being the first U.S. President to visit Georgia since its recognition as an independent and sovereign country.</summary>
</bill>
