<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1212" updated="2013-07-19T23:06:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25T15:08:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-25T15:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 1586) to impose an additional tax on bonuses received from certain TARP recipients, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-456, by Ms. Slaughter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill with an amendment debatable for one hour. The resolution also provides for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules. In addition, the requirement waives the requirement for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is reported.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-24T17:29:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="181">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 181.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2325-2330" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1212.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T11:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2330" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T11:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1212, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2331-2332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-03-25T15:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="188" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 190 (Roll no. 188).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2325" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="1586"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 1586) to impose an additional tax on bonuses received from certain TARP recipients.</summary>
</bill>
