<bill session="109" type="s" number="2654" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection of Young Consumers Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Youth Financial Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect consumers, and especially young consumers, from skyrocketing consumer debt and the barrage of credit card solicitations, to establish a financial literacy and education program in elementary and secondary schools to help prepare young people to be financially responsible consumers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3592-3593"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2006--Introduced.
Protection of Young Consumers Act of 2006 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit consumer reporting agencies from furnishing reports in connection with firm offers of credit or insurance that are not initiated by consumers under age 21. Allows consumers who are at least 18, but not yet 21, to elect, in writing, to have their names and addresses included in any list of names provided by such agencies in connection with such transactions. Youth Financial Education Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a new title IV part D Promoting Youth Financial Literacy. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to state educational agencies to implement financial education programs for elementary and secondary school students. Makes a state's allocation proportionate to its share of such students. Directs the Secretary to: (1) make a competitive five year grant to, or contract with, a national nonprofit organization to establish a national clearinghouse for instructional materials and information on model financial education programs and best practices; and (2) develop and use performance measures to evaluate the financial education programs and clearinghouse established pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
