<bill session="109" type="h" number="5952" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bodegas as Catalysts for Healthy Living Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase access to and consumption of fresh fruits, vegetables, and healthy alternatives in low-income communities with high incidences of obesity and obesity-related disease.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Small Business, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Beverages"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Exercise"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Obesity"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2006--Introduced.
Bodegas as Catalysts for Healthy Living Act - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to make grants to local organizations that represent small business concerns and local redevelopment agencies to assist: (1) independently owned and operated small businesses, such as bodegas and corner stores, in expanding their inventories to include fresh fruits and vegetables and healthy alternatives (as defined by the Department of Agriculture); and (2) community-based organizations, such as community health centers, in carrying out consumer outreach and education programs to encourage the purchase of fresh fruits, vegetables, and healthy alternatives and to inform communities about health risks and the benefits of healthy living. Requires small businesses and community-based organizations to collaborate in carrying out the purposes of this Act. Limits grant amounts to $100,000. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to cover additional primary and preventive services relating to obesity treatment and prevention, supervised exercise sessions, stress testing, lifestyle modification education, and nutrition education.</summary>
</bill>
