<bill session="110" type="s" number="2720" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to withhold Federal financial assistance from each country that denies or unreasonably delays the acceptance of nationals of such country who have been ordered removed from the United States and to prohibit the issuance of visas to nationals of such country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2008-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2008-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2008-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-03-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="605">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 605.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="5761"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2008--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit funds from being dispersed to a country that denies or unreasonably delays the acceptance of its citizens, nationals, or residents who have been ordered removed under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) from the United States. Amends INA to prohibit visa issuance to citizens, nationals, or residents of such country unless: (1) the country is in full compliance with travel document requirements under this Act; or (2) Congress waives such prohibition. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to report to Congress every three months listing countries that deny or delay such repatriation. Imposes assistance and visa prohibitions on a listed country that does not issue appropriate travel documents for such aliens. Authorizes presidential waiver of such assistance and visa prohibitions.</summary>
</bill>
