<bill session="111" type="s" number="3322" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation Establishment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to establish a United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2010--Introduced.
United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation Establishment Act of 2010 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to establish the United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation. Authorizes the Corporation to: (1) implement integrated spent nuclear fuel management consistent with federal policy on a self-sustaining basis through the use of a spent nuclear fuel management enterprise that will eliminate the need for federal funding; and (2) assume responsibility for the activities, obligations, and use of resources of the federal government with respect to spent nuclear fuel management. Establishes in the Treasury the United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation Fund. Directs the President to appoint a Transition Manager to transfer spent nuclear fuel management obligations, functions, personnel, and funds from the Secretary of Energy to the Corporation. Designates the Corporation the exclusive marketing agent on behalf of the United States for entering into contracts to provide spent nuclear fuel management and related products and services.</summary>
</bill>
