<bill session="113" type="s" number="905" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Building Code Incentive Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to enhance existing programs providing mitigation assistance by encouraging States to adopt and actively enforce State building codes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1878"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="924"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Safe Building Code Incentive Act of 2013 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Stafford Act) to authorize the President to increase the maximum total of contributions for a major disaster by an amount equal to 4% of the estimated aggregate amount of grants to be made under the Act if, at the time of a declaration of a major disaster, the affected state certifies that it has in effect and is actively enforcing a state building code that: (1) is consistent with the most recent version of a nationally recognized model building code, (2) has been adopted by the state within six years of the most recent version of the nationally recognized code, and (3) uses the nationally recognized code as a minimum standard. Directs the President to approve the additional assistance upon determining that such certification is sufficient and is submitted not later than 90 days after the date of a declared disaster. Requires the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to set appropriate standards for the periodic update, resubmittal, and approval of state building codes, consistent with similar mitigation planning requirements under the Stafford Act. Makes this Act applicable to major disasters declared on or after October 24, 2012. Allows 90 days from this Act's enactment for submission of the required certification for disasters declared between October 24, 2012, and such enactment.</summary>
</bill>
