<bill session="110" type="s" number="3366" updated="2013-07-19T22:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Refuge Ecology Protection, Assistance, and Immediate Response Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect, conserve, and restore native fish, wildlife, and their natural habitats at national wildlife refuges through cooperative, incentive-based grants to control, mitigate, and eradicate harmful nonnative plant species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7782-7783"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7783-7785" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="767"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Plant protection"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2008--Introduced.
Refuge Ecology Protection, Assistance, and Immediate Response Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide under the Refuge Ecology Protection, Assistance, and Immediate Response Grant Program or the REPAIR Program (established by this Act): (1) a grant to any eligible applicant to carry out a qualified plant control project to control harmful nonnative species; and (2) a grant to any state to carry out an assessment project to identify harmful nonnative plant and animal species, assess the needs to restore, manage, or enhance native fish, wildlife, and habitats, identify priorities, and identify mechanisms to increase capacity building for native fish, wildlife, and habitats. Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial assistance for not more than three fiscal years to enable an immediate response to outbreaks of harmful nonnative plant species that threaten or may negatively impact refuge resources that are at a stage at which rapid eradication or control is possible, and to ensure eradication or immediate control of such species. Directs the Secretary, consistent with the National Wildlife Refuge System Volunteer and Community Partnership Enhancement Act of 1998, to establish a cooperative volunteer monitoring and control program to administer and coordinate projects implemented by partner organizations concerned with national wildlife refuges to address harmful nonnative species that threaten national wildlife refuges or adjacent lands.</summary>
</bill>
