<bill session="109" type="s" number="4055" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-09">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Crime Victims' Restitution Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Preserving Crime Victims' Restitution Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to address the effect of the death of a defendant in Federal criminal proceedings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2006-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10971-10973"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 S11840-11841" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-12-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 S11840-11841" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-11T15:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-11T18:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6374"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5240"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/9/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Preserving Crime Victims' Restitution Act of 2006 - Amends the federal criminal code to establish guidelines for federal criminal cases in which a defendant dies before entry of a final judgment of guilt (deceased defendants). Provides, as a general rule, that the death of a defendant who has been convicted of a federal criminal offense shall not be the basis for abating or otherwise invalidating a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, a verdict returned, a sentence announced, or a judgment entered prior to the death of such defendant, or for dismissing or invalidating the indictment, information, or complaint on which such a plea, verdict, sentence, or judgment is based, except as provided by this Act.Requires a trial court, in a case in which a defendant admits guilt or is found guilty by a jury, but dies before final judgment, to: (1) enter a judgment with the notation that the defendant died before judgment was entered; and (2) commence a special restitution proceeding upon the motion of the government or any victim of the defendant's crime.Permits the use of a guilty plea of a deceased defendant in subsequent civil proceedings.Allows the personal representative of a defendant's estate to file an appeal of the deceased defendant's conviction and of other matters involving such defendant. Provides rules for appointment of counsel, tolling of filing dates, and restitution for pending litigation involving a deceased defendant.Allows the government to seek, or continue to pursue, civil forfeiture of property related to the deceased defendant's crime, subject to the applicable statute of limitations.Makes this Act applicable to any criminal case or appeal pending on or after July 1, 2006.</summary>
</bill>
