<bill session="111" type="s" number="1932" updated="2013-07-20T00:41:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Post 9/11 Troops to Teachers Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow members of the Armed Forces who served on active duty on or after September 11, 2001, to be eligible to participate in the Troops-to-Teachers Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2010-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10780"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2009--Introduced.
Post 9/11 Troops to Teachers Enhancement Act - Amends the Troops-to-Teachers program of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (which provides veterans with teacher certification stipends in exchange for three years of service in a high-need local educational agency [LEA] or public charter school). Expands program eligibility to cover certain individuals: (1) who, on or after September 11, 2001, serve at least 90 continuous days on active duty in the Armed Forces before being honorably released from such service; or (2) who, on or after January 8, 2002, are separated or released from active duty after at least four (currently, six) years of continuous active duty immediately preceding such separation or release, and agree to serve in the Armed Forces Reserves for at least three years. Makes any LEA that is receiving school improvement funds eligible to host Troops-to-Teachers program participants. Directs the Secretary of Education to establish an Advisory Board, composed of federal, state, and veteran service organization representatives, to collect, study, and disseminate feedback from the program and report to Congress on how the program is operating and might be improved. Reserves specified funding to carry out the Troops-to-Teachers program through FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
