<bill session="112" type="h" number="6003" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Terrorism Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to prevent terrorism, including terrorism associated with homegrown violent extremism and domestic violent extremism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412440" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2012-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1112"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM05" subcommittee="Counteterrorism and Intelligence" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2012--Introduced.
Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Terrorism Act of 2012 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through Department of Homeland Security (DHS) officials responsible for counterterrorism and addressing the threat of violent extremism, to: (1) develop guidance, outreach, training, and programs in furtherance of national counterterrorism policy; and (2) develop and distribute to state, local, and tribal authorities courses and materials that comply with the Grant Programs Directorate Information Bulletin No. 373 or successor bulletin for integration into the curricula for recruits and recurrent training for experienced law enforcement officers. Requires guidance for homeland security grant programs to inform recipients that expenditures on any training, programs, presentations, and speakers regarding counterterrorism that includes information about violent extremism, homegrown violent extremism, or domestic violent extremism that is acquired from an entity other than DHS must be approved in advance by DHS's Chief Privacy Officer and the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties. Directs DHS's Inspector General to: (1) regularly review expenditures of homeland security grant programs by state, local, and tribal authorities on training, programs, presentations, and speakers that are not acquired through the Secretary regarding counterterrorism, violent extremism, homegrown violent extremism, and domestic violent extremism; and (2) evaluate whether each expenditure is consistent with national counterterrorism priorities and constitutional civil rights and civil liberties, including prohibiting racial, ethnic, and religious profiling.</summary>
</bill>
