<bill session="110" type="h" number="1368" updated="2013-07-19T21:15:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Personalized Health Information Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to provide financial incentives to encourage the adoption and use of interactive personal health records.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2007--Introduced.
Personalized Health Information Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program to provide financial incentives for the use of interactive qualifying personal health records by Medicare and other patients and their health care providers in order to: (1) provide patients (or their authorized representatives) access to and control over their personal health data and information and educational information; (2) make available to authorized health care providers a more accurate minimum data set of patient information at all points of care; and (3) accomplish other specified objectives. Requires that under the program each qualified physician receive an incentive payment for each qualifying patient. Directs the Secretary to: (1) publish online a list of qualifying physicians who participate in Medicare and have received such payments; and (2) take steps to educate Medicare beneficiaries and providers and other patients about the benefits of qualifying personal health records. Sets forth requirements for a qualified web-based personal health record, including that such record: (1) is controlled solely by the patient; (2) meets minimum security standards; (3) is capable of exchanging standards-based clinical and patient data with other health data sources and users; (4) is capable of sending patient-specific patient education, reminders, and clinical messages to the patient; and (5) is capable of providing de-identified data for public health analysis and research purposes. Requires the Secretary to: (1) set minimum security, privacy, and data use standards for such health records; (2) establish a consumer protection board to recommend standards and procedures to the Secretary; and (3) establish a PHR Incentive Fund to make incentive payments. Authorizes such Fund to accept contributions from: (1) the Secretary for Medicare beneficiaries; (2) drug manufacturers for messages regarding medical adherence programs; and (3) other Fund partners.</summary>
</bill>
