<bill session="110" type="h" number="2645" updated="2013-07-19T21:26:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Judicial Initiative Mental Health and Substance Abuse Treatment Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to improve mental health and substance abuse treatment by providing grants for justice system personnel training, treatment pograms, and diversion programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2007--Introduced.
Judicial Initiative Mental Health and Substance Abuse Treatment Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to direct the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to make grants to train state juvenile justice system officers and employees regarding appropriate access to mental health and substance abuse treatment services for juveniles. Directs the Attorney General to make grants to partnerships between state and local juvenile justice and mental health agencies for programs to divert juveniles from incarceration and for mental health and substance abuse screening and treatment.Establishes a Federal Coordinating Council on Criminalization of Juveniles to study and coordinate federal criminal and juvenile justice and mental health and substance abuse activities.Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require states seeking eligibility for violent offender incarceration grants to implement (or begin to implement), not later than January 1, 2008, a program of mental health screening and treatment for juvenile and other offenders during periods of incarceration and supervision.</summary>
</bill>
