<bill session="111" type="h" number="5884" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Seniors Financial Fraud Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a separate office within the Federal Trade Commission to prevent fraud targeting seniors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3040"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3494"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2010--Introduced.
Seniors Financial Fraud Prevention Act of 2010 - Establishes a separate office within the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) for the prevention of fraud targeting seniors and requires the office to assist the FTC in monitoring the market for mail, telemarketing, television, and Internet fraud which targets seniors. Requires the FTC through such office: (1) to disseminate to seniors and their families and caregivers information on mail, telemarketing, television, and Internet fraud targeting seniors, including on ways of referring complaints to appropriate law enforcement agencies; (2) in response to a request about a particular entity or individual, to provide publicly available information on any record of civil or criminal law enforcement action for such fraud; and (3) to maintain a website as a resource for such individuals on those kinds of fraud. Requires the FTC through such office to establish procedures to: (1) log and acknowledge complaints from individuals who certify that they believe they have been victims of mail, telemarketing, television, or Internet fraud; (2) provide certain information on those kinds of fraud; and (3) refer such complaints to appropriate entities, including state consumer protection agencies and entities and appropriate law enforcement agencies, for potential law enforcement action.</summary>
</bill>
