<bill session="112" type="h" number="1714" updated="2013-07-20T01:25:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iran Human Rights and Democracy Promotion Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote human rights and democracy in Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412420"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and South Asia .</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and South Asia" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA20" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="879"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2011--Introduced.
Iran Human Rights and Democracy Promotion Act of 2011 - Expresses the sense of Congress that Mahmoud Ahmadinejad of Iran is responsible for directing the commission of serious human rights abuses against Iranian citizens on or after June 12, 2009. Amends the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 to require the President: (1) upon receipt of credible information that a person may be an official of the government of Iran or acting on behalf of that government who is complicit in the commission of serious human rights abuses against Iranian citizens on or after June 12, 2009, to investigate and determine within 180 days whether the person is such a described individual; and (2) submit a list of such persons to Congress every 180 days or as new information becomes available. Requires the President: (1) upon receipt of credible information that a person may have transferred to Iran goods or technologies, or provided post-transfer services, that may be used to commit human rights abuses to investigate and determine within 180 days whether the person engaged in such activity; (2) submit a list of such persons to Congress every 180 days or as new information becomes available; and (3) freeze the assets of a listed person. Amends the Iran Freedom Support Act to: (1) extend the President's authority to provide financial and political assistance to support democracy in Iran through December 31, 2016; and (2) expand the forms of such assistance. Requires the President to appoint a Special Representative on Human Rights and Democracy in Iran within the Department of State. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Secretary should support efforts to research and catalogue prisoners of conscience and cases of human rights abuses inside Iran, (2) the U.S. government should offer political asylum to such political prisoners as well as assisting with their relocation to other countries if requested, and (3) the Special Representative and all representatives of the U.S. government should publicly call for the release of Iranian dissidents by name and raise individual cases of Iranian dissidents and prisoners of conscience as appropriate. Requires the President to submit to Congress a comprehensive strategy to promote Internet freedom and access to information in Iran.</summary>
</bill>
