<bill session="109" type="h" number="3206" updated="2013-07-19T19:32:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit Union Charter Choice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act provisions relating to any conversion of a credit union charter to a mutual savings bank or savings association charter, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400644"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2005-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Savings banks"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2005--Introduced.
Credit Union Charter Choice Act - Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to repeal requirements governing oversight by the National Credit Union Administration of the member vote concerning charter conversions of credit unions to mutual savings banks or savings associations. Revamps requirements governing credit union notification to the National Credit Union Administration Board of intent to convert to a mutual savings bank or savings association. Sets forth a Board approval process regarding materials submitted by converting credit unions in connection with such conversions. Requires the member vote on a proposed conversion to be conducted by secret ballot, with an independent inspector of elections appointed by the converting credit union to receive and tally the votes. Requires the board of directors of the converting credit union to certify vote results to the Board. Denies the Board any further review or approval authority over the conversion process, absent fraud or reckless disregard for fairness during the voting process that affects the vote outcome.</summary>
</bill>
