<bill session="109" type="s" number="2369" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require a more reasonable period for delayed-notice search warrants, to provide enhanced judicial review of FISA orders and national security letters, to require an enhanced factual basis for a FISA order, and to create national security letter sunset provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2006-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1791-1792"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1792-1793" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2006--Introduced.
Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) reduce from 30 to seven days after the issuance of a warrant the period in which notice must be given to the subject of the warrant that it was issued to search for and seize any property or material that constitutes evidence of a criminal offense; and (2) repeal provisions treating as conclusive the certification of the Attorney General or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation that certain disclosures of information endanger national security. Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) to: (1) authorize judicial review of nondisclosure orders (orders prohibiting persons from disclosing that the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) has sought information); (2) repeal the requirement prohibiting judicial review of production or nondisclosure orders until one year after such order. Requires a production order (an order from the FBI Director to produce any tangible thing, such a book, document, or record) to either: (1) pertain to a foreign power, agent of a foreign power, or an individual in contact with, or known to, a suspected agent of a foreign power; or (2) be relevant to the activities of a suspected agent of a foreign power who is the subject of the authorized investigation. Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to sunset, as of December 31, 2009, the national security letter authority provisions added to the federal criminal code, the Fair Credit Reporting Act, the Right to Financial Privacy Act, and the National Security Act of 1947.</summary>
</bill>
