<bill session="109" type="s" number="1968" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Court Security Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect judges, prosecutors, witnesses, victims, and their family members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2006-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12448-12449"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1710"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1751"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Weapons"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2005--Introduced.
Court Security Improvement Act of 2005 - Amends the federal judicial code to require the Director of the U.S. Marshals Service and the Judicial Conference of the United States to consult and coordinate with each other on a continuing basis on security requirements for the judicial branch. Extends protections against disclosure of judges' personal information through 2009 and includes family members of judges in such disclosure protections. Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit: (1) the recording of fictitious liens against the property of federal judges and law enforcement officers; (2) the public disclosure of restricted personal information about judges, law enforcement officials, jurors, witnesses, or their immediate family members, with the intent to harm such individuals; and (3) the possession of dangerous weapons in federal court facilities. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) authorize the Attorney General to make grants to states, local governments, and Indian tribes to create and expand victim and witness protection programs; and (2) allow grants to states to improve security for for state and local court systems. Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize grants to states to create and expand victim and witness protection programs. Revises compensation standards for judges of the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims. Extends life insurance coverage to active and retired bankruptcy, magistrate, and territorial judges and health insurance coverage for surviving family members of federal judges.</summary>
</bill>
