<bill session="111" type="h" number="2627" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Windstorm Impact Reduction Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
National Windstorm Impact Reduction Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Act of 2004 to revise provisions governing the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program. Designates the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) as the lead agency for Program planning, management, and coordination. Establishes the Interagency Working Group on Wind Impact Reduction (IWG) to coordinate activities and facilitate communication among Program agencies in reducing the impacts of windstorms. (Repeals provisions regarding the existing Interagency Working Group responsible for Program planning, management, and coordination.) Requires the Director of NIST to: (1) establish a Program Office to provide planning, management, and coordination functions; (2) facilitate preparation of a coordinated annual crosscut budget and report for the Program; (3) facilitate preparation of the IWG's biennial report to Congress and the National Science and Technology Council; (4) support research and development for building codes and standards; (5) promote implementation of research results; (6) support deployment of interagency teams to investigate major windstorm events and data collection and analysis; (7) support the organization and deployment of interagency teams to investigate major windstorm events and the gathering, publishing, and archiving of collected data and analysis results; and (8) participate in, coordinate, or support other Program mitigation activities. Sets forth the duties of the Program Office (including ensuring coordination and synergy across Program agencies) and of the IWG (including preparation of an interim working plan for Program operations and a strategic plan for achieving Program objectives). Includes the National Science Foundation (NSF), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), the Department of Transportation (DOT), the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), and the Army Corps of Engineers as Program agencies. Authorizes appropriations for the Program for FY2010-FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
