<bill session="111" type="s" number="3402" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REAL Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energey Access Through Leasing Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage residential use of renewable energy systems by minimizing upfront costs and providing immediate utility cost savings to consumers through leasing of such systems to homeowners, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2010-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1379"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Access Through Leasing Act of 2010 or the REAL Act of 2010- Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make loan guarantees for the financing of renewable energy systems leased for residential use. Prohibits the Secretary from insuring a loan unless the renewable energy system owner certifies that the systems financed will be leased only to homeowners that grant easements to install, maintain, use and otherwise access the system that include the right to sell electricity produced during the life of the renewable energy system to a wholesale or retail electrical power grid. Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that a discount given under this Act does not adversely affect the homeowner's mortgage requirements; and (2) fix and collect premiums for insurance of loans under this Act that shall be paid for by the renewable energy system owner and that shall be adequate to cover the expenses and probable losses of administering the program. Prohibits the Secretary from assessing any other fee, premium, or charge in connection with such loan insurance. Establishes the Renewable Energy Lease Insurance Fund, into which the Secretary shall deposit any such premiums. Terminates the Secretary's authority to insure and make commitments to insure new loans under this Act ten years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
