<bill session="109" type="s" number="1405" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Patient Access to Inpatient Rehabilitation Hospitals Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to extend the 50 percent compliance threshold used to determine whether a hospital or unit of a hospital is an inpatient rehabilitation facility and to establish the National Advisory Council on Medical Rehabilitation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2006-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2005-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8318-8319"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8319-8320" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3373"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2005--Introduced.
Preserving Patient Access to Inpatient Rehabilitation Hospitals Act of 2005 - Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services, during the period between July 1, 2005, and the date two years after the enactment of this Act, from: (1) requiring a compliance rate, pursuant to the criterion (commonly known as the "75 percent rule") used to determine whether a hospital or hospital unit is an inpatient rehabilitation facility, that is greater than the 50 percent compliance threshold that became effective on July 1, 2004; (2) changing the designation of any inpatient rehabilitation facility in compliance with the 50 percent threshold; or (3) conducting medical necessity review of inpatient rehabilitation facilities using any guidelines other than the national criteria established in the Medicare Benefits Policy Manual. Directs the Secretary to establish procedures for: (1) making any necessary retroactive adjustment to restore the status of a facility as an inpatient rehabilitation facility as a result of this Act; (2) making any necessary payments to inpatient rehabilitation facilities based on such adjustment for discharges occurring on or after July 1, 2005, and before enactment of this Act; and (3) developing and implementing an appeals process that provides for expedited review of any adjustment to the status of a facility as an inpatient rehabilitation facility made during such period Directs the Secretary to establish the National Advisory Council on Medical Rehabilitation to provide advice and recommendations to: (1) Congress and the Secretary concerning the coverage of rehabilitation services under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act; and (2) appropriate federal agencies on how best to utilize available research funds and authorities focused on medical rehabilitation research.</summary>
</bill>
