<bill session="113" type="h" number="2397" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24T19:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24T19:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400439"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-113, by Mr. Young (FL).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-17T19:27:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="81">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 81.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 312.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4877-4936" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4889-4908" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2397, under a structured rule, and consideration of H.R. 2610, under an open rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on both bills. Additionally, the resolution provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions for both bills.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 312 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Candice S. Miller to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walberg amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Delaney amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gabbard amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gabbard amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Gabbard demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grayson amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Israel amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Young of Florida amendments en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 10, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Young of Florida amendments en bloc No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment No. 14, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Frelinghuysen demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 15, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pocan amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nugent amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nugent amendment No. 17, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nugent demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Heck (NV) amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lujan Grisham (NM) amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T16:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shea-Porter amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the O'Rourke amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moran amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moran amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Moran demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Terry amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Terry amendment No. 24, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Terry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Poe (TX) amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Poe (TX) amendment No. 25, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Poe (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T17:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bonamici amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walberg amendment No. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walberg amendment No. 27, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Walberg demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2397 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4936-4976" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Young of Florida amendments en bloc No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cicilline amendment No. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cicille amendment No. 28, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cicille demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cohen amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cohen amendment No. 29, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cohen demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Coffman amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:59:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Coffman amendment No. 30, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Coffman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T19:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment No. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment No. 33, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garamendi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fleming amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Fleming amendment No. 35, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rigell amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:33:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rigell amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rigell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scalise amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Terry amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wittman amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flores amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flores amendment No. 41, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flores demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cole amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeLauro amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeLauro amendment No. 44, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Calvert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment No. 45, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Quigley amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Quigley amendment No. 46, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Denham amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Denham amendment No. 47, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Frelinghuysen demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T21:54:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jones (NC) amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jones (NC) amendment No. 48, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Jones (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kline amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the LaMalfa amendment No. 51, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. LaMalfa demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Meadows amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T23:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mulvaney amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mulvaney amendment No. 55, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Frelinghuysen demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Palazzo amendment No. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Palazzo amendment No. 57.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provsions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rohrabacher amendment No. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stockman amendment No.60.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Stockman amendment No. 60, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Stockman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walorski amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walorski amendment No. 62, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Walorski demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T00:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bonamici amendment No. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T01:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bonamici amendment No. 65, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Bonamici demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T01:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hanabusa amendment No. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T01:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frelinghuysen moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T01:14:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T01:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2397 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5002-5031" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kilmer amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kilmer amendment No. 67, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kilmer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 69.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 69, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 70, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pierluisi amendment No. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:40:00-04:00">
      <text>MOMENT OF SILENCE - The House observed a moment of silence in memory of Officer Jacob J. Chestnut and Detective John M. Gibson of the United States Capitol Police.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brooks (Al) amendment No. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment No. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schiff amendment No. 73, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Schiff demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment No. 74.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment No. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Radel amendment No. 97.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Massie amendment No. 98.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments which had been debated and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Pompeo amendment No. 99.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pompeo amendment No. 99, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pompeo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 312, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Amash amendment No. 100.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment No. 100, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Amash demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>WITHDRAWING DEMAND FOR RECORDED VOTE - Mr. Terry asked unanimous consent to withdraw his demand for a recorded vote on the Terry amendment No. 24 and that the amendment be considered as adopted pursuant to the earlier voice vote thereon. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of general debate on H.R. 2397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5029" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Frankel (FL) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5029-5030" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5029" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Frankel (FL) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to set aside an additional $25 million for US-Israeli Cooperative Programs, including a $20 million increase for Iron Dome and a $5 million increase for the Arrow System Improvement Program.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5029" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 192 - 231 (Roll no. 413).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="414" datetime="2013-07-24T19:31:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 315 - 109 (Roll no. 414).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24T19:33:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="312"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="933"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="444"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1429"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Chad"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Democratic Republic of the Congo"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h344"/>
    <amendment number="h345"/>
    <amendment number="h346"/>
    <amendment number="h347"/>
    <amendment number="h348"/>
    <amendment number="h349"/>
    <amendment number="h350"/>
    <amendment number="h351"/>
    <amendment number="h352"/>
    <amendment number="h353"/>
    <amendment number="h354"/>
    <amendment number="h355"/>
    <amendment number="h356"/>
    <amendment number="h357"/>
    <amendment number="h358"/>
    <amendment number="h359"/>
    <amendment number="h360"/>
    <amendment number="h361"/>
    <amendment number="h362"/>
    <amendment number="h363"/>
    <amendment number="h364"/>
    <amendment number="h365"/>
    <amendment number="h366"/>
    <amendment number="h367"/>
    <amendment number="h368"/>
    <amendment number="h369"/>
    <amendment number="h370"/>
    <amendment number="h371"/>
    <amendment number="h372"/>
    <amendment number="h373"/>
    <amendment number="h374"/>
    <amendment number="h375"/>
    <amendment number="h376"/>
    <amendment number="h377"/>
    <amendment number="h378"/>
    <amendment number="h379"/>
    <amendment number="h380"/>
    <amendment number="h381"/>
    <amendment number="h382"/>
    <amendment number="h383"/>
    <amendment number="h384"/>
    <amendment number="h385"/>
    <amendment number="h386"/>
    <amendment number="h387"/>
    <amendment number="h388"/>
    <amendment number="h389"/>
    <amendment number="h390"/>
    <amendment number="h391"/>
    <amendment number="h392"/>
    <amendment number="h393"/>
    <amendment number="h394"/>
    <amendment number="h395"/>
    <amendment number="h396"/>
    <amendment number="h397"/>
    <amendment number="h398"/>
    <amendment number="h399"/>
    <amendment number="h400"/>
    <amendment number="h401"/>
    <amendment number="h402"/>
    <amendment number="h403"/>
    <amendment number="h404"/>
    <amendment number="h405"/>
    <amendment number="h406"/>
    <amendment number="h407"/>
    <amendment number="h408"/>
    <amendment number="h409"/>
    <amendment number="h410"/>
    <amendment number="h411"/>
    <amendment number="h412"/>
    <amendment number="h413"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/17/2013--Reported to House without amendment.
Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014 - Title I: Military Personnel - Appropriates funds for FY2014 for active-duty and reserve personnel in the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force (the military departments), and for National Guard personnel in the Army and Air Force. Title II: Operation and Maintenance - Appropriates funds for FY2014 for operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) for the military departments, other agencies of the Department of Defense (DOD), the reserve components, and the Army and Air National Guard. Appropriates funds for: (1) the United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces; (2) environmental restoration for the military departments, DOD, and at formerly used defense sites; (3) overseas humanitarian, disaster, and civic aid; (4) assistance to the republics of the former Soviet Union and to countries outside of the former Soviet Union for facilitating the elimination and the safe and secure transportation and storage of nuclear, chemical, and other weapons; and (5) the Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund. Title III: Procurement - Appropriates funds for FY2014 for procurement by the military departments, including for the procurement of aircraft, missiles, weapons, tracked combat vehicles, and ammunition and for shipbuilding and conversion by the Navy. Appropriates funds for: (1) defense-wide procurement, and (2) certain procurements under the Defense Production Act of 1950. Title IV: Research, Development, Test and Evaluation - Appropriates funds for FY2014 for research, development, test and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) by the military departments and defense agencies. Appropriates funds for the independent activities of the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation. Title V: Revolving and Management Funds - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Defense Working Capital Funds, and (2) National Defense Sealift Fund programs, projects, and activities and for expenses of the National Defense Reserve Fleet. Title VI: Other Department of Defense Programs - Appropriates funds for: (1) DOD medical and health care programs; (2) the destruction of the U.S. stockpile of lethal chemical agents and munitions and of other chemical warfare materials that are not in such stockpile; (3) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities of DOD; and (4) the Office of the Inspector General. Title VII: Related Agencies - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund, and (2) the Intelligence Community Management Account. Title VIII: General Provisions - Sets forth authorized, restricted, and prohibited uses of authorized funds. (Sec. 8007) Requires DOD to submit a report to the congressional defense committees to establish the baseline for application of FY2014 reprogramming and transfer authorities. (Sec. 8010) Allows for the use of procurement funds for multiyear contracts for: (1) the E-2D Advanced Hawkeye; (2) an SSN 774 Virginia class submarine; (3) KC-130J, C-130J, HC-130J, MC-130J, and AC-130J aircraft; (4) ground-based midcourse defense system ground-based interceptors; and (5) government furnished equipment. (Sec. 8012) Prohibits the management of DOD civilian personnel on the basis of any end-strength during FY2014. (Sec. 8021) Authorizes DOD to incur obligations of up to $350 million for DOD military compensation, construction projects, and supplies and services in anticipation of receipts of contributions from the government of Kuwait. (Sec. 8023) Prohibits the use of funds to establish a new federally funded research and development center (FFRDC). Limits the federal compensation to be paid to FFRDC members or consultants. Prohibits the use of FY2013 funds for new building construction, cost-sharing payments for projects funded by government grants, absorption of contract overruns, or certain charitable contributions. Limits the staff years of technical effort that may be funded for FFRDCs from FY2013 funds. (Sec. 8024) Provides Buy American requirements with respect to the DOD procurement of carbon, alloy, or armor steel plating. (Sec. 8027) Requires the Secretary of Defense to report to Congress on the amount of DOD purchases from foreign entities in FY2014. (Sec. 8029) Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to convey to Indian tribes located in Nevada, Idaho, North Dakota, South Dakota, Montana, Oregon, Minnesota, and Washington relocatable military housing units currently located at Grand Forks, Malmstrom, Mountain Home, Elllsworth, and Minot Air Force Bases that are excess to the needs of the Air Force. Requires the Operation Walking Shield Program to resolve any housing unit conflicts arising after such conveyance. (Sec. 8035) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) by a DOD entity without compliance with the Buy American Act; (2) to establish additional field operating agencies of DOD elements, except for those funded within the National Foreign Intelligence Program and Army agencies established to eliminate, mitigate, or counter the effects of improvised explosive devices or to improve the effectiveness and efficiencies of biometric activities; (3) to convert to contractor performance a function currently performed by DOD civilian employees, unless specific conditions are met; (4) for assistance to the Democratic People's Republic of North Korea, unless specifically appropriated for such purpose; and (5) to reduce the civilian medical and medical support personnel assigned to military treatment facilities below the September 30, 2003, level. (Sec. 8040) Rescinds specified funds from various accounts under prior defense appropriations Acts. (Sec. 8045) Prohibits the transfer to any other department or agency, except as specifically provided in an appropriations law, of funds available to DOD or the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) for drug interdiction or counter-drug activities. (Sec. 8049) Prohibits current fiscal year DOD funds from being obligated or expended to transfer to another nation or international organization defense articles or services for use in any United Nations (UN) peacekeeping or peace enforcement operation or for any other international peacekeeping, peace enforcement, or humanitarian assistance operation, unless Congress is given 15 days' advance notice. (Sec. 8056) Authorizes the DOD Secretary, on a case-by-case basis, to waive limitations on the procurement of defense items from a foreign country if: (1) the Secretary determines that such limitations would invalidate cooperative or reciprocal trade agreements for the procurement of defense items, and (2) such country does not discriminate against the same or similar defense items procured in the United States for that country. Provides exceptions. (Sec. 8057) Prohibits the use of appropriated funds to support any training program involving a unit of the security forces of a foreign country if the Secretary has received credible information that such unit has committed a gross violation of human rights, unless all necessary corrective steps have been taken. Requires the monitoring of such information. Authorizes the Secretary to waive such prohibition under extraordinary circumstances and requires a report to the defense committees within 15 days after any such waiver. (Sec. 8062) Authorizes members of the National Guard serving on full-time duty to support ground-based elements of the National Ballistic Missile Defense System. (Sec. 8063) Prohibits appropriated funds from being used to transfer specified armor-piercing ammunition to any nongovernmental entity, except an entity performing demilitarization services for DOD. (Sec. 8064) Authorizes the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to waive payment for the lease of non-excess DOD personal property to certain, youth, social, or fraternal nonprofit organizations. (Sec. 8068) Authorizes the transfer of specified DOD O&amp;M funds to the Global Security Contingency Fund, after congressional notification. (Sec. 8070) Earmarks specified procurement and RDT&amp;E funds for the Israeli Cooperative Programs (missile defense). (Sec. 8075) Requires the FY2014 budget to include separate budget justification documents for costs of U.S. Armed Forces' participation in contingency operations for the military personnel, O&amp;M, and procurement accounts. (Sec. 8076) Prohibits funds from being used for RDT&amp;E, procurement, or deployment of nuclear armed interceptors of a missile defense system. (Sec. 8077) Appropriates funds to DOD for grants to the United Service Organizations and the Red Cross. (Sec. 8079) Prohibits funds from being available for integration of foreign intelligence information unless such information has been lawfully collected and processed during the conduct of authorized foreign intelligence activities. (Sec. 8080) Requires reserve members called or ordered to active duty in a national emergency to be notified in writing of their expected mobilization period. Allows the Secretary to waive such requirement in order to respond to a national security emergency or to meet dire operational requirements. (Sec. 8084) Earmarks specified Navy O&amp;M funds for the Asia Pacific Regional Initiative Program for enabling the Pacific Command to execute theater security cooperation activities such as humanitarian assistance and for the payment of incremental and personnel costs of training and exercising with foreign security forces. (Sec. 8087) Requires the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to report to the intelligence committees to establish the baseline for application of reprogramming and transfer authorities for FY2014. Prohibits funds provided for the National Intelligence Program (NIP) from being available for reprogramming or transfer until the report is submitted, unless the DNI certifies to such committees that the reprogramming or transfer is necessary as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 8088) Makes specified Intelligence Community Management Account funds available for transfer by the DNI to other departments and agencies for government-wide information sharing activities. (Sec. 8090) Directs the DNI to submit annually to Congress a future-years intelligence program reflecting estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in the President's budget. (Sec. 8092) Requires DOD to continue to report incremental contingency operations costs for Operations New Dawn and Enduring Freedom on a monthly basis. (Sec. 8094) Makes O&amp;M funds available for remittances to the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund. (Sec. 8095) Requires any agency receiving funds appropriated under this Act to post on its public website any report required to be submitted to Congress in this or any other Act, upon the determination by such agency head that it shall serve the national interest. Provides exceptions when posting the report would compromise national security or for reports containing proprietary information. (Sec. 8096) Provides specific requirements on the use of this Act's funds for any federal contract in excess of $1 million with respect to contractor resolution of claims under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. Allows the Secretary to waive such requirements to avoid harm to national security. (Sec. 8097) Prohibits funds from being distributed to the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN) or its subsidiaries. (Sec. 8098) Earmarks specified O&amp;M funds for operations of the integrated Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center in Chicago, Illinois. (Sec. 8101) Allows DOD funds to be used for the purchase of heavy and light armored vehicles for the physical security of personnel or for force protection purposes, up to a limit of $250,000 per vehicle. (Sec. 8102) Earmarks specified DOD O&amp;M funds for grants to support critical existing and enduring military installations and missions on Guam. Requires the Secretary to notify the defense committees at least 15 days prior to obligating funds for such purpose. (Sec. 8107) Prohibits any federal funds from being used to transfer or release to or within the United States or its territories or possessions Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who is not a citizen or member of the Armed Forces and who is or was held by DOD on or after June 24, 2009, at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo). (Sec. 8108) Prohibits any federal funds from being used to transfer any individual detained at Guantanamo to the custody or control of that individual's country of origin or any other foreign country or entity until 30 days after the Secretary certifies to Congress that such country is not a designated state sponsor of terrorism and has agreed to ensure that such individual cannot take action to threaten the United States or its citizens or allies in the future. Prohibits the Secretary from making a transfer to a country or entity if there is a confirmed case of an individual who was detained at Guantanamo any time after September 11, 2001, and transferred to such country or entity subsequently engaging in terrorist activity. Provides an exception to the latter prohibition for specified purposes, requiring 30 days' prior congressional notification. (Sec. 8109) Prohibits any federal funds from being used to construct, acquire, or modify any facility in the United States or its territories or possessions to house any individual who, as of June 24, 2009, is located at Guantanamo, and who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and (2) is either in DOD custody or control or otherwise under detention at Guantanamo. (Sec. 8110) Prohibits the use of funds to enter into a contract with, make a grant to, or provide a loan or loan guarantee to any corporation: (1) against which an unpaid federal tax liability has been assessed, or (2) that was convicted of a felony criminal violation within the preceding 24 months. (Sec. 8112) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) in contravention of federal criminal laws against human trafficking or the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, (2) to support any military training or operation that includes child soldiers, (3) in contravention of the War Powers Resolution, or (4) to contract with any person or entity convicted of fraud against the federal government. (Sec. 8116) Reduces by $437 million the total amount available for FY2014 for the pay of civilian DOD personnel. (Sec. 8119) Prohibits DOD funds from being used to purchase any equipment from Rosoboronexport until the Secretary certifies to the defense committees that: (1) such company is cooperating fully with the Defense Contract Audit Agency, (2) such company has not delivered S-300 advanced anti-aircraft missiles to Syria, and (3) no new contracts have been signed between such company and the Bashar al Assad regime in Syria since January 1, 2013. Allows the Secretary to waive such prohibition upon certification that it is in the national security interest to do so and requires a waiver report to such committees. Requires the Secretary to use competitive procedures to award any contract that will use U.S. funds for the procurement of helicopters for the Afghan Security Forces. (Sec. 8120) Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2000 to repeal a required annual report with regard to an Air Force multiyear aircraft lease pilot program. (Sec. 8121) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) for the purchase or manufacture of U.S. flags unless such flags are treated as covered items under Buy American requirements; (2) in contravention of Uniform Code of Military Justice requirements and procedures concerning actions for certain sex-related offenses; (3) for the direct personal benefit of the President of Afghanistan; or (4) to eliminate or reduce funding for a DOD program, project, or activity for FY2015 until the proposed change is either enacted in an appropriations Act or made pursuant to the reprogramming or transfer provisions of this Act. (Sec. 8122) Appropriates funds to DOD: (1) to implement the sexual assault special victims program, and (2) for transfer only to military personnel accounts. Title IX: Overseas Deployments and Other Activities - Appropriates funds for FY2014 for overseas contingency operations directly related to the global war on terrorism, including for: (1) military personnel, (2) O&amp;M, (3) the Overseas Contingency Operations Transfer Fund; (4) the Afghanistan Infrastructure Fund, (5) the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund, (6) procurement, (7) National Guard and reserve equipment, (8) RDT&amp;E, (9) Defense Working Capital Funds, (10) the Defense Health Program, (11) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities, (12) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund, and (13) the Office of the Inspector General. (Sec. 9002) Authorizes the Secretary, in the national interest, to transfer up to $4 billion of the amounts made available to DOD in this title between any such appropriations for that fiscal year. Requires prompt congressional notification of each transfer. (Sec. 9004) Authorizes the Secretary to use funds appropriated in this title to purchase motor vehicles for use by military and civilian DOD employees in Iraq and Afghanistan, with a limit of $75,000 per passenger vehicle and $250,000 per each heavy or light armored vehicle. (Sec. 9005) Authorizes the use of up to $60 million to fund the Commander's Emergency Response Program (urgent humanitarian relief and reconstruction assistance in Afghanistan). (Sec. 9006) Allows DOD O&amp;M funds to be used to provide supplies, services, transportation, and other logistical support to coalition forces supporting military and stability operations in Afghanistan. Requires quarterly reports from the Secretary to the defense committees regarding such support. (Sec. 9007) Prohibits any funds from being obligated or expended to: (1) establish any military installation or base for providing for the permanent stationing of U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq or Afghanistan, or (2) exercise U.S. control over any oil resource of Iraq. (Sec. 9008) Prohibits funds from being used in contravention of specified laws enacted or regulations promulgated to implement the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment. (Sec. 9009) Prohibits funds provided for the Afghanistan Security Forces Funds from being obligated prior to the approval of a financial and activity plan by the Afghanistan Resources Oversight Council of DOD. (Sec. 9011) Earmarks specified Army O&amp;M funds to allow the Task Force for Business and Stability Operations in Afghanistan to carry out strategic business and economic assistance activities in Afghanistan in support of Operation Enduring Freedom. Requires the Secretary, at least 15 days in advance of making funds available for any such project costing $5 million or more, to submit to the defense committees a detailed justification and timeline for the project. (Sec. 9012) Allows the use of specified O&amp;M funds to support U.S. government transition activities in Iraq by funding operations and activities of the Office of Security Cooperation in Iraq and security assistance teams. Requires 15 days' prior notification from the Secretary to the defense committees with respect to each proposed site. (Sec. 9013) Rescinds a specified amount from the general provisions, 2009 account. (Sec. 9014) Prohibits DOD O&amp;M funds from being used for payments to Pakistan as reimbursement for support provided with respect to U.S. military operations unless the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of State, certifies to the appropriations committees that the government of Pakistan: (1) is cooperating with the United States in certain counterterrorism efforts, (2) is not supporting terrorist activities against U.S. or coalition forces in Afghanistan, and (3) is dismantling improvised explosive device networks and preventing the proliferation of nuclear-related material and expertise. Authorizes the DOD Secretary to waive such restrictions on a case-by-case basis by certifying to such committees that it is in the U.S. national security interests to do so. Title X: Additional General Provisions - (Sec. 10001) Declares that the amount by which the allocation of new budget authority made by the House Committee on Appropriations under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority is $0.</summary>
</bill>
