<bill session="111" type="h" number="4137" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Bedford Whaling Nation Historical Park Resources Assistant Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide preservation and interpretation assistance for resources associated with the New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
New Bedford Whaling Nation Historical Park Resources Assistant Act - Amends the Omnibus Park and Public Lands Management Act to: (1) authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assist in the interpretation and preservation of specified properties associated with the New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park in Massachusetts; (2) set forth a non-federal matching requirement for funding a cooperative agreement for the preservation of the National Historic Landmark Schooner Ernestina; and (3) prohibit any funds authorized under the Act from being used for the operation and routine maintenance of the Schooner Ernestina.</summary>
</bill>
