<bill session="113" type="h" number="1073" updated="2013-11-02T06:27:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-20T19:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-20T19:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Terrorism Conventions Implementation and Safety of Maritime Navigation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Nuclear Terrorism Conventions Implementation and Safety of Maritime Navigation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for protection of maritime navigation and prevention of nuclear terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2013-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-85.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-20T15:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="60">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 60.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Collins (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2781-2785" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1073.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2786-2787" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="162" datetime="2013-05-20T19:07:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 390 - 3 (Roll no. 162).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2781-2784" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Nuclear Terrorism Conventions Implementation and Safety of Maritime Navigation Act of 2013 - Title I: Safety of Maritime Navigation - (Sec. 101) Amends the federal criminal code to provide that existing prohibitions against conduct that endangers the safe navigation of a ship: (1) shall apply to conduct that is committed against or on board a U.S. vessel or a vessel subject to U.S. jurisdiction, in U.S. territorial seas, or by a U.S. corporation or legal entity; and (2) shall not apply to activities of armed forces during an armed conflict or in the exercise of official duties. Sets forth procedures regarding the delivery of a person who is suspected of committing a maritime navigation or fixed platform offense to the authorities of a country that is a party to the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Maritime Navigation. Subjects property used or intended to be used to commit or to facilitate the commission of a maritime navigation offense to civil forfeiture. (Sec. 102) Prohibits: (1) using in or on a ship or a maritime fixed platform any explosive or radioactive material, biological, chemical, or nuclear weapon, or other nuclear explosive device in a manner likely to cause death or serious injury or damage when the purpose is to intimidate a population or to compel a government or international organization to act or abstain from acting; (2) transporting on board a ship such material or device (or certain related material or technology) that is intended for such use, with specified exceptions; (3) transporting on board a ship a person known to have committed a maritime navigation offense intending to assist such person to evade prosecution; (4) injuring or killing any person in connection with such an offense; or (5) conspiring, attempting, or threatening to commit such an offense. Sets forth: (1) the circumstances in which the United States can exercise jurisdiction over such offenses, and (2) exceptions applicable to activities of the armed forces. Provides for civil forfeiture of property used to commit or to facilitate a violation. (Sec. 105) Includes offenses involving violence against maritime navigation and maritime transport involving weapons of mass destruction within the definition of "federal crime of terrorism." Title II: Prevention of Nuclear Terrorism - (Sec. 201) Prohibits anyone, knowingly, unlawfully, and with intent to cause death, serious bodily injury, or substantial damage to property or the environment, from: (1) possessing radioactive material or making or possessing a nuclear explosive device or a radioactive material dispersal or radiation-emitting device; (2) using radioactive material or a device, using, damaging, or interfering with the operation of a nuclear facility in a manner that causes or increases the risk of the release of radioactive material, or causing radioactive contamination or exposure to radiation; or (3) threatening, attempting, or conspiring to commit such an offense. Sets forth: (1) the circumstances in which the United States can exercise jurisdiction over such offenses, and (2) exceptions applicable to activities of the armed forces. Includes such offenses within the definition of "federal crime of terrorism." (Sec. 202) Amends provisions prohibiting transactions involving nuclear materials to: (1) prohibit, intentionally and without lawful authority, carrying, sending, or moving nuclear material into or out of a country; and (2) establish an exception for activities of the armed forces.</summary>
</bill>
