<bill session="109" type="s" number="73" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Animal Feed Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote food safety and to protect the animal feed supply from bovine spongiform encephalopathy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S249"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S249-250" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Bovine spongiform encephalopathy"/>
    <term name="Brain diseases"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deer"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Elk"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Animal Feed Protection Act of 2005 - Makes it unlawful for any person to introduce into interstate or foreign commerce a covered article that contains: (1) specified risk material from a ruminant, or any material from a ruminant that was in any foreign country when there was a risk of transmission of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), and may contain specified risk material from a ruminant; or (2) any material from a ruminant exhibiting signs of a neurological disease. States that the head of a Federal agency may: (1) seize and destroy an article that is introduced into interstate or foreign commerce in violation of this Act; or (2) require any person who is in violation of this Act to cease the violation, to recall any sold article and refund the purchase price, to destroy or forfeit the article to the United States for destruction, or to cease production operations until the head of the appropriate Federal agency determines that there is no longer a violation of this Act. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for related civil and monetary penalties. Defines "covered article" as: (1) animal feed, nutritional supplement, or medicine; and (2) any other article that is ordinarily ingested, implanted, or otherwise taken into an animal. Sets forth exceptions. Defines "specified risk material" as: (1) the skull, brain, trigeminal ganglia, eyes, tonsils, spinal cord, vertebral column, or dorsal root ganglia of cattle and bison 30 months of age and older, or sheep, goats, deer, and elk 12 months of age and older; (2) the intestinal tract of any ruminant; and (3) any other material of a ruminant that may carry a prion disease.</summary>
</bill>
