<bill session="112" type="s" number="834" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus SaVE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve education and prevention related to campus sexual violence, domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2011-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2016"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act or Campus SaVE Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each institution of higher education (IHE) participating in a title IV program to include in its annual security report on campus security policy and crime statistics a statement of current policies for reporting crimes or other emergencies in or on noncampus buildings or property (currently, only reporting of crimes on campus is required). Requires such report to include statistics concerning the occurrence of domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking incidents reported to campus security authorities or local police.Requires schools to protect victim confidentiality when reporting criminal threats to the campus community. Directs IHEs to include in their annual security report a statement of policy regarding its programs to prevent domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking and the procedures it follows when such an offense is reported. Requires such procedures to include: (1) the provision, in writing, to students or employees that report that they have been the victim of such an offense certain information regarding their rights, disciplinary processes, victim services, and safety planning; (2) a description of how the IHE will help enforce any protective order; and (3) information about how the IHE will protect victim confidentiality. Requires an IHE's policy regarding such offenses to include: (1) education that promotes awareness of the offenses; (2) possible sanctions or protective measures imposed following disciplinary action; (3) procedures victims should follow after such an offense occurs; (4) information about to whom the alleged offense should be reported; (5) institutional disciplinary procedures; and (6) the notification of victims regarding their options for, and assistance in, changing academic, living, transportation, and working situations. Directs the Secretary of Education to seek the counsel of the Attorney General and Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) regarding the development, and dissemination to IHEs, of best practices for preventing and responding to incidents of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</summary>
</bill>
