<bill session="113" type="h" number="531" updated="2013-11-02T06:23:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Crimes and Identity Theft Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent identity theft and tax crimes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2013--Introduced.
Tax Crimes and Identity Theft Prevention Act - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to take necessary action to correct a tax return or tax information affected by the misuse of a taxpayer's identity within 90 days after receiving notice of such misuse from the taxpayer. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) authorize the Secretary to disclose tax return information to federal, state, and local law enforcement personnel who are personally and directly engaged in the investigation of identity theft; (2) impose a fine and/or prison term on any person who knowingly or willfully misappropriates another person's tax identification number; (3) increase the civil and criminal penalties for improper disclosure or use of tax information by tax return preparers; and (4) require the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to report to Congress on the number of reported tax fraud cases and on actions taken in response to such reports. Directs the Secretary to: (1) implement an identity theft tax fraud prevention program that provides for a unique personal identification number (PIN) on tax returns; (2) establish a fraudulent tax refund prevention program that adds additional triggers to the refund database to identify potentially fraudulent tax refunds; and (3) review whether current federal tax law prevents the effective enforcement of local, state, and federal identity theft statutes. Authorizes the Commissioner to transfer appropriated funds to be used solely to prevent and resolve potential tax fraud cases. Directs the Commissioner to establish in the Criminal Investigation Division of the IRS the position of Local Law Enforcement Liaison to coordinate the investigation of tax fraud with state and local law enforcement agencies. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report on the role of prepaid debit cards and commercial tax preparation software in facilitating fraudulent tax returns through identity theft. Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from disclosing information contained on the Death Master File relating to a deceased individual to persons who are not certified to access such information. Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to state and local law enforcement agencies for the investigation and prosecution of tax crimes.</summary>
</bill>
