<bill session="111" type="h" number="3230" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish within the National Science Foundation the Innovation Inspiration school grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412220"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research and Science Education" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish an Innovation Inspiration school grant program to make grants to eligible entities for the promotion of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) and for participation in robotics and STEM competitions. Specifies that the goals of such grant program are to: (1) support eligible entities in non-traditional STEM education teaching methods; (2) support participation by student teams in certain not-for-profit STEM robotics competitions; (3) foster innovation and broaden access to careers in STEM by engaging students in after-school programs; and (4) encourage collaboration between students, engineers, and professional mentors in designing, building, programming, and competing in challenges with sophisticated robots. Instructs the Director to establish: (1) a communications and outreach program publicizing the grant program; and (2) an evaluation and monitoring program for determining the efficacy of the grant program.</summary>
</bill>
