<bill session="113" type="s" number="1068" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Amendments Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and amend the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Act of 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Amendments Act of 2013 - Reauthorizes and amends authorities relating to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's Commissioned Officer Corps (NOAA Corps). Amends the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Act of 2002 to prohibit officers serving in positions of importance and responsibility and officers recalled from retired status from being counted in or against the computation of authorized strengths or the total number of authorized commissioned officers on the lineal list. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to prescribe obligated service requirements for appointments, training, promotions, separations, continuations, and retirement of officers not otherwise covered by law. Revises original appointment and reappointment requirements. Authorizes the reappointment of individuals who previously served in the NOAA Corps to the grade the individual held prior to separation. Permits reappointments to certain designated positions of importance and responsibility to be made only by the President. Directs the Secretary to coordinate with the Secretary of Defense (DOD) and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating to promote and streamline inter-service transfers, give preference to such inter-service transfers for recruitment purposes, and reappoint such inter-service transfers to the equivalent grade in the NOAA Corps. Establishes: (1) training, physical fitness, and academic standards; (2) membership criteria for personnel boards; and (3) guidelines for officer candidate appointments and a basic officer training program. Modifies temporary appointment requirements. Permits temporary appointments in the grade of ensign, lieutenant junior grade, or lieutenant to be made by the President. Applies specified rights and benefits of the Armed Forces to the NOAA Corps, including benefits and services for members being separated or recently separated, military family programs, advanced education assistance, active duty agreements, and reimbursement requirements. Establishes: (1) an education loan repayment program in exchange for active duty service obligations of certain students enrolled at accredited educational institutions and other eligible persons, (2) a student loan interest payment program for specified loans under the Higher Education Act of 1965 to eligible active duty officers who have not completed more than three years of active duty service, and (3) a pre-commissioning education assistance program for certain students enrolled at accredited educational institutions who agree to accept appointment as active duty officers. Expands to make applicable to the NOAA Corps: (1) pay and allowances requirements of the Armed Forces, (2) competitive service position consideration requirements for honorably separated applicants, (3) uniformed service civilian employment and reemployment rights, and (4) laws protecting communications of members of the Armed Forces with Members of Congress and the Inspector General and prohibiting retaliatory personnel actions for specified communications.</summary>
</bill>
