<bill session="113" type="h" number="396" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Pay Adjustment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the annual rates of pay for Members of Congress by 20 percent, and to prohibit an adjustment in such rates during a year unless the Federal government did not run a deficit in the previous fiscal year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412284"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="391"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Congressional Pay Adjustment Act - Reduces the annual rate of pay in 2015 for Members of Congress by 20% of the 2013 pay rate. Maintains the pay rate for subsequent pay periods at the 2013 rate. Prohibits a Member of Congress from receiving a cost-of-living adjustment under the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 during any fiscal year (beginning with FY2014) unless the Secretary of the Treasury reports to Congress (beginning with FY2013) that a federal budget deficit did not exist in the previous fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
