<bill session="113" type="h" number="2602" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Timely Repatriation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for sanctions on countries that have refused or unreasonably delayed repatriation of an alien who is a national of that country, or that have an excessive repatriation failure rate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2013-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2013--Introduced.
Timely Repatriation Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to publish a report every six months listing countries that have: (1) refused or unreasonably delayed repatriation of an alien who is a national of that country, and the total number of such aliens; and (2) an excessive repatriation failure rate. Directs the Secretary of State	with respect to a listed country: (1) to not issue visas to attendants, servants, and personal employees of such country's diplomats and officials/employees; and (2) reduce the number of visas available for such country's diplomats and officials/employees by 10% for each six months that a country is listed. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to exempt a country from inclusion if the total number of nonrepatriations outstanding is less than 10% for the preceding 3-year period.</summary>
</bill>
