<bill session="109" type="h" number="5077" updated="2013-07-19T19:49:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Numismatic Rarities Certainty Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide a clear line of demarcation with regard to private ownership of any coin, medal, or numismatic item made or issued by the United States Government before January 1, 1933, that is not in the possession of the United States Government, to establish certain guidelines and requirements with respect to the inventory, preservation, public display, and disposition of certain United States coins, medals, and numismatic items that were struck or made after December 31, 1932, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2006-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2006--Introduced.
Numismatic Rarities Certainty Act of 2006 - Amends federal law governing coins and currency to provide that any coin, medal, or numismatic item made or issued by the United States before January 1, 1933, that is not in the possession of the federal government as of the date of the enactment of this Act, shall not be considered to be property of the United States unless it is reacquired by the United States for value given in a sale or exchange. Requires transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury of any coins, medals, and numismatic items that were struck or made by the U.S. government after 1932, which were never issued by the U.S. government, and yet come into its possession. Prescribes guidelines for disposition of such items, including historic preservation, public display, and sales at public auction. Requires the Secretary to compile an inventory of all coins, medals, or numismatic items that are either: (1) in the possession of the U.S. government; or (2) on loan to, or were at any time presented to or retained by, any person or entity (other than in accordance with a specific requirement of federal law), regardless of when such item was struck or made.</summary>
</bill>
