<bill session="112" type="h" number="1216" updated="2013-07-20T01:20:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-25T14:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-25T14:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to convert funding for graduate medical education in qualified teaching health centers from direct appropriations to an authorization of appropriations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412278"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-27T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-64.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-27T17:54:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 269 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1216 and H.R. 1540. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides for 1 hour of general debate and waives all points of order against consideration of the measures. The rule provides one motion to recommit H.R. 1216 with or without instructions. The rule also provides that after general debate on H.R. 1540, the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion and that no further consideration of the bill shall occur except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 269.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3361-3388" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3368" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1216 and H.R. 1540. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides for 1 hour of general debate and waives all points of order against consideration of the measures. The rule provides one motion to recommit H.R. 1216 with or without instructions. The rule also provides that after general debate on H.R. 1540, the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion and that no further consideration of the bill shall occur except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 269 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ted Poe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tonko amendment number 2 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tonko amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tonko demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T15:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cardoza amendment number 9 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cardoza amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cardoza demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Foxx amendment number 7 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Weiner moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Failed by recorded vote: 14 - 397 (Roll no. 335).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Guthrie moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T18:45:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T18:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1216 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3396-3401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole continued with debate on the already pending Foxx amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:20:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Foxx amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Foxx amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Weiner amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Guthrie moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1216 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3430-3431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of a amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker and Democratic leader were recognized for one minute to introduce Father Patrick J. Conroy as the new Chaplin of the House of Representatives.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3432-3434" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Clyburn moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3432-3434" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3432" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyburn motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to require that the Secretary prioritize qualified teaching health centers in underserved areas, when determining the amounts payable to such centers in a given fiscal year.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3433" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 236 (Roll no. 339).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-05-25T14:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="340" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 234 - 185 (Roll no. 340).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="269"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="269"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h296"/>
    <amendment number="h297"/>
    <amendment number="h298"/>
    <amendment number="h299"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/27/2011--Reported to House without amendment.
Amends the Public Health Service Act to convert funding from direct appropriations to an authorization of appropriations for a program of payments to qualified teaching health centers for approved graduate medical residency training programs. Rescinds any unobligated balances appropriated for such program.</summary>
</bill>
