<bill session="110" type="sr" number="179" updated="2013-07-19T22:14:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution welcoming the Prime Minister of Singapore on the occasion of his visit to the United States and the 40th anniversary of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), expressing gratitude to the Government of Singapore for its strong cooperation with the United States in the campaign against terrorism, and reaffirming the commitment of the United States to the continued expansion of friendship and cooperation between the United States and Singapore.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300010"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5400" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="ASEAN countries"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="Southeast Asia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2007--Introduced.
Welcomes the Prime Minister of Singapore, His Excellency Lee Hsien Loong, to the United States. Congratulates the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), and Singapore as one of its founding members, on ASEAN's 40th anniversary. Expresses gratitude to the government of Singapore for promoting security and prosperity in Southeast Asia and cooperating with the United States in the global campaign against terrorism. Reaffirms the commitment of the United States to continue strengthening the friendship and cooperation between the United States, Singapore, and the other countries of the ASEAN region.</summary>
</bill>
