<bill session="111" type="h" number="5460" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Teen Parent Graduation and College Achievement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to establish grant programs to help pregnant and parenting students stay in school, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/2010--Introduced.
Teen Parent Graduation and College Achievement Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to award grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) and institutions of higher education (IHEs) to help pregnant and parenting students stay in school by expanding their access to services. Includes tutoring, pregnancy-related health care, child care, transportation, after-school support, academic counseling, school social work, or family planning among such services. Requires LEA and IHE grantees to: (1) enter into partnerships and share grant funds, when appropriate, with public agencies or community-based organizations to help pregnant or parenting students stay in school; and (2) use no more than 10% of their grant for administrative costs.</summary>
</bill>
