<bill session="111" type="h" number="6401" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a biennial budget for the United States Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2010-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="169"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate Committee on the Budget"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2010--Introduced.
Biennial Budgeting and Appropriations Act of 2010 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require: (1) biennial (instead of annual) budget resolutions; (2) biennial appropriations Acts; and (3) biennial government strategic and performance plans. Makes conforming amendments to the Rules of the House of Representatives. Defines the budget biennium as the two consecutive fiscal years beginning on October 1 of any odd-numbered year. Requires: (1) a federal agency, upon request by a congressional committee, to provide appropriate information regarding its appropriations requests and program administration; (2) the Comptroller General to furnish to such committee summaries of any audits or reviews of such program which the Comptroller General has completed during the preceding six years; and (3) the Comptroller General, Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), and the Director of the Congressional Research Service (CRS) to furnish such committee appropriate information, studies, analyses, and reports. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to determine and report to Congress on the impact and feasibility of changing the definition of a fiscal year, and the budget process based on that definition, to a two-year fiscal period with a biennial budget process based on such period. Requires the President's budget submission for FY2014 to include: (1) an identification of the budget accounts for which an appropriation should be made for each fiscal year of the FY2014-FY2015 biennium; and (2) budget authority that should be provided for each such fiscal year for the budget accounts. Directs: (1) the House and Senate committees, during the first session of the 113th Congress, to work with the Comptroller General to develop plans to transition program authorizations to a multi-year schedule; and (2) the Comptroller General, during such Congress, to continue to provide assistance to Congress with respect to programmatic oversight, and in particular to assist the congressional committees in designing and conforming programmatic oversight procedures for FY2014-FY2015 biennium.</summary>
</bill>
