<bill session="113" type="h" number="2196" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GREAT Teachers and Principals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Education Achievement Training Academies for Teachers and Principals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create and expand innovative teacher and principal preparation programs known as teacher and principal preparation academies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E750-751"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1052"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Growing Education Achievement Training Academies for Teachers and Principals Act or the GREAT Teachers and Principals Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to states to: (1) create or approve teacher or principal preparation academies and create or designate authorizers of those academies; (2) support the creation and operation of such academies; and (3) award subgrants to nonprofit entities to establish or expand such academies, measure their effectiveness, or recruit enrollees who have demonstrated strong potential to be effective teachers or principals. Requires each academy to enter into a charter with an authorizer that specifies the goals and outcomes expected of the academy and the obligations of the authorizer. Prohibits authorizers from renewing an academy's charter if it fails to produce the minimum number or percentage of effective teachers or principals specified in its charter. Requires each academy to provide: (1) enrollees with a significant portion of their training through clinical preparation that partners them with successful teacher or principal mentors, and (2) certificates of completion only to graduates who demonstrate a track record of success in preparing students for college and careers. Requires state grantees to recognize a certificate of completion from an academy as at least the equivalent of a master's degree in education for the purposes of teacher or principal hiring, retention, compensation, and promotion in the state. Directs the Secretary to enter into an interagency agreement with the Corporation for National and Community Service under which the Corporation approves national service positions for candidates at each teacher or principal preparation academy receiving financial assistance under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
