<bill session="111" type="h" number="5782" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reduce and End our Deficits Using Commonsense Eliminations in the Treas-HUD and OPIC Programs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">OPIC Repeal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement cost savings within the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and to terminate the Overseas Private Investment Corporation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412264"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC)"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2010--Introduced.
Reduce and End our Deficits Using Commonsense Eliminations in the Treas-HUD and OPIC Programs Act - Prohibits the total amount obligated in the Treasury for each of FY2011-FY2015 by: (1) the Bureau of the Public Debt from exceeding $186.244 million; and (2) the Financial Management Service from exceeding $235.132 million. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, for pay periods ending in FY2011 and subsequent fiscal years, in coordination with the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), to issue electronic pay stubs to Department of the Treasury employees who receive their pay by electronic funds transfer. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the requirement for advance payment of the earned income tax credit. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1939 to set the payment standard for a market area efficiency dwelling unit as the standard for rent subsidies under Section 8 of the housing voucher program for one-person households. Prohibits the use of the payment standard for a one-bedroom dwelling unit or any larger dwelling unit. OPIC Repeal Act - Abolishes the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), and makes conforming amendments to the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.</summary>
</bill>
