<bill session="111" type="h" number="4913" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Free Speech About Science Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act concerning the distribution of information on legitimate scientific research in connection with foods and dietary supplements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/2010--Introduced.
Free Speech About Science Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow food producers to make a disease or health-related claim about a food if such claim is based on legitimate scientific research. Requires such a claim to: (1) be stated so that it is an accurate, balanced summary of such research and enables the public to comprehend the information provided in the claim and the relative significance of such information in the context of a total daily diet; and (2) identify each party that funded research to support the claim. Allows a disease or health-related statement for a dietary supplement if: (1) the statement claims to diagnose, treat, cure, or prevent a specific disease or class of diseases, based on legitimate scientific research; (2) the manufacturer of the supplement has substantiation that such statement is truthful and not misleading; and (3) the health claim includes a citation to the research supporting such claim and identifies each party that funded such research. Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from restricting the distribution of information that is not false or misleading and that is based on legitimate scientific research in connection with the sale of food.</summary>
</bill>
