<bill session="109" type="s" number="2170" updated="2013-07-19T20:32:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-22">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for global pathogen surveillance and response.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-12-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14399-14402" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S14399-14402" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S14329-14332" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-22T16:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-22T17:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syndromes"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2005 - (Sec. 3) Defines specified terms for purposes of this Act. (Sec. 4) Prohibits assistance under this Act to an eligible developing country that does not: (1) permit World Health Organization (WHO) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP) personnel to investigate infectious disease outbreaks within its borders; and (2) provide pathogen surveillance data to appropriate U.S. and international agencies and organizations. Authorizes the Secretary of State to waive such prohibition for national security purposes. (Sec. 5) Prohibits any participating foreign national from having unsupervised access to agents that may be used in a biological weapon. (Sec. 6) Establishes a public health education and training fellowship program for eligible nationals to pursue: (1) a master of public health degree with a concentration in epidemiology; or (2) advanced public health training in epidemiology. Authorizes fellowship recipients to take CDCP or equivalent courses on diagnosis and containment of bioterrorism agents. Authorizes, and sets forth the conditions for, program participation by U.S. citizens. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to support short training courses in-country (not in the United States) for laboratory technicians and other public health personnel in: (1) laboratory techniques relating to the identification, diagnosis, and tracking of pathogens responsible for possible infectious disease outbreaks; and (2) syndrome surveillance reporting and rapid analysis of syndrome information using Geographic Information System (GIS). (Sec. 8) Authorizes the President to furnish assistance to eligible developing countries to purchase and maintain: (1) public health laboratory equipment necessary to collect, analyze, and identify pathogens which may cause disease outbreaks or may be used as a biological weapon; and (2) related communications equipment and information technology. Gives procurement preference to U.S.-manufactured equipment and supplies. (Sec. 10) Authorizes a federal agency head, upon the request of a U.S. chief of diplomatic mission or an international health organization, and with the Secretary's concurrence, to assign to the respective U.S. mission or organization any public health officer or employee of the agency for the purpose of enhancing disease and pathogen surveillance efforts in developing countries. (Sec. 11) Directs CDCP and the Department of Defense (DOD) to: (1) increase the number of personnel assigned to their respective laboratories located in eligible developing countries that conduct infectious disease research; and (2) expand the operations of those laboratories, especially in the implementation of on-site training of foreign nationals and regional outreach efforts. (Sec. 12) Authorizes: (1) the President to provide assistance to enhance the surveillance and reporting capabilities for WHO and existing regional and international health networks, and develop new health networks; and (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish new country or regional foreign epidemiology training programs in eligible developing countries. (Sec. 13) Directs the President to establish the Office of Foreign Biological Threat Detection and Warning within either DOD, the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), or CDCP with the technical ability to conduct event detection and rapid threat assessment related to biological threats in foreign countries. (Sec. 14) Directs the Secretary to report to Congress respecting program implementation under this Act and related funding requirements. (Sec. 15) Authorizes FY2006 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
