<bill session="110" type="h" number="3361" updated="2013-07-19T21:33:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-12T20:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-03-12T20:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Protection Technical Corrections Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Pension Protection Technical Corrections Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections related to the Pension Protection Act of 2006.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T20:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pomeroy moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1598-1606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3361.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-03-12T20:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1598-1604" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stark asked unanimous consent that H.R. 3361 be engrossed in the form submitted to the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-03-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="621">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 621.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6382"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7327"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1974"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2008--Passed House amended.
Pension Protection Technical Corrections Act of 2008 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code, as amended by the Pension Protection Act of 2006, to make changes to rules governing defined benefit and defined contribution pension plans. (Sec. 2) Modifies rules relating to increases in pension plan benefits while a waiver or amortization extension is in effect or with respect to retroactive amendments to such plans. Revises the definition of "target normal cost" with respect to increases and decreases in such costs. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe rules for quarterly contributions to pension plans with a shortfall in 2008. (Sec. 3) Revises the criteria for use of the shortfall funding method for multiemployer defined benefit plans. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, to establish criteria for required notices relating to multiemployer plans in endangered or critical status. Revises: (1) criteria for implementation and enforcement of a multiemployer plan default schedule; (2) the definition of plan sponsor for purposes of multiemployer plan funding rules; and (3) the method for calculating the excise tax on trustees of multiemployer plans for failure to adopt a timely rehabilitation plan. (Sec. 4) Extends until 2009 the temporary interest rate for pension plan funding. (Sec. 5) Limits the coverage of the missing participant rules to qualified plans that did not provide for employer contributions. (Sec. 6) Revises requirements relating to: (1) annual funding notices for single and multiemployer defined benefit plans; (2) termination information for pension plan participants; (3) periodic pension benefit statements; and (4) notices to pension plan participants or beneficiaries of blackout periods (i.e, restrictions on plan operations, including investment changes).(Sec. 7) Modifies pension plan requirements relating to investment advice, prohibited transactions, and fiduciary rules. (Sec. 8) Provides that failure to meet pension plan preservation of capital requirements constitutes a violation of ERISA age discrimination rules.(Sec. 9) Modifies rules relating to: (1) the deduction limit for single-employer pension plans; (2) deductions for employer contributions to one or more defined contribution plans; (3) rollovers from retirement plans to Roth individual retirement accounts (IRAs); (4) rollovers by nonspouse beneficiaries of retirement plans; (5) distributions from public pension plans for health and long-term care insurance for public safety officers; and (6) survivor annuity plans of special trial judges of the U.S. Tax Court. Exempts assets transfers from health accounts to maintain a pension plan's funded status from the excise tax on reversions.(Sec. 10) Revises the definition of "one-participant retirement plan" for purposes of ERISA diversification and participation requirements.Expands rules allowing automatic contributions to employer pension plans. Requires the administrator of a combined pension plan (consisting of a defined benefit plan and a qualified cash or deferred arrangement) to treat such plans separately upon termination.(Sec. 11) Provides that former spouses shall be entitled to survivor benefits under the Railroad Retirement Act if: (1) the employee completed 10 years of service in the railroad industry (or five years of service after December 31, 1995); (2) the spouse or former spouse has attained age 62; and (3) the employee attains age 62 (or if deceased, would have attained age 62). Makes such provision effective for payments due after August 2007.(Sec. 12) Prohibits states from reducing unemployment compensation by the amount of pension rollovers.</summary>
</bill>
