<bill session="112" type="h" number="6282" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management, to convey to the City of Carlin, Nevada, in exchange for consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States, to any Federal land within that city that is under the jurisdiction of that agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412500"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if an offer is received from the city of Carlin, Nevada, to purchase federal land within the city, through the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey to the city all interest of the United States in such land in exchange for consideration equal to the fair market value of the land. Requires the Secretary to determine the fair market value of the federal land based on an appraisal according to nationally recognized appraisal standards. Permits the city to pay or reimburse the Secretary, as appropriate, for reasonable transaction and administrative personnel costs associated with such conveyance, including the costs of appraisal, title searches, maps, and boundary and cadastral surveys. Prohibits a conveyance or combination of conveyances under this Act from being considered a major federal action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Releases the United States from all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product (or derivative of a petroleum product) solid waste, mine materials, or mining related features existing on the federal land.</summary>
</bill>
