<bill session="109" type="h" number="3756" updated="2013-07-19T19:37:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Increased Penalties for Environmental Crimes Related to Methamphetamine Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act and title 18, United States Code, with respect to methamphetamine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2005-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug paraphernalia"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2005--Introduced.
Increased Penalties for Environmental Crimes Related to Methamphetamine Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) prohibit cultivating or manufacturing (currently, cultivating) a controlled substance on federal property; and (2) increase the term of imprisonment to be imposed on anyone who, in committing a controlled substances violation, knowingly or intentionally uses a poison, chemical, or other hazardous substance on federal land and thereby creates a serious hazard to humans, wildlife, or domestic animals, degrades or harms the environment or natural resources, or pollutes an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water. Amends the federal criminal code to include within the definition of "hazardous or injurious device" equipment and chemicals used in the illegal manufacture of a controlled substance.</summary>
</bill>
