<bill session="111" type="h" number="1345" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-08T15:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-08T15:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Hatch Act Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">District of Columbia Hatch Act Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">District of Columbia Hatch Act Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">District of Columbia Hatch Act Reform Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to eliminate the discriminatory treatment of the District of Columbia under the provisions of law commonly referred to as the "Hatch Act".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E576"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 111-172.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-06-19T15:56:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="88">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Watson moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9298-9299" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1345.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-09-08T15:19:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9298" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="627">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 627.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>By Senator Lieberman from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 111-339.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
District of Columbia Hatch Act Reform Act of 2010 - Amends federal law commonly referred to as the "Hatch Act" (concerning political activities of federal, state, and local employees) to: (1) include the District of Columbia or an agency or department thereof within the definition of a "state or local agency" under such Act; (2) ensure that individuals employed by an educational or research institution, establishment, agency, or system supported in whole or in part by the District are exempt from Hatch Act restrictions; (3) exempt the duly elected head of an executive department of the District who is not classified under the District's merit or civil-service system from the prohibition against being a candidate for elective office; and (4) direct the Merit Systems Protection Board to issue an order to withhold federal funds upon finding that a District employee ordered removed for violating the Hatch Act has been reappointed in the District within 18 months. Excludes District of Columbia employees and officials from the definition of "employee" for purposes of provisions applicable to the political activities of only federal employees. Makes such amendments effective on the date a law is enacted by the District that places restrictions on political activities of employees of the District of Columbia government.</summary>
</bill>
