<bill session="111" type="s" number="3239" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to repeal unwarranted provisions from the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and to more efficiently use taxpayer dollars in health care spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2519"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to repeal a specified exception for certain hospitals to the special rule for FY2010 regarding use of a particular hospital wage index (promulgated in the Federal Register on August 27, 2009) in "Section 508" hospital reclassifications. ("Section 508" refers to Section 508 of the Medicare Modernization Act of 2003, which allows the temporary reclassification of a hospital with a low Medicare area wage index, for reimbursement purposes, to a nearby location with a higher Medicare area wage index, so that the "Section 508 hospital" will receive the higher Medicare reimbursement rate.) Repeals as well PPACA provisions that: (1) grant Medicare coverage to individuals exposed to certain environmental health hazards; (2) increase the Medicare reimbursement for frontier states; and (3) authorize appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for debt service on, or direct construction or renovation of, a health care facility that provides research, inpatient tertiary care, or outpatient clinical services and is critical for the provision of greater access to health care within a state. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to reduce the special adjustment to the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for states recovering from a major disaster.</summary>
</bill>
