<bill session="111" type="h" number="5070" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Smart Electronics Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assess the potential of smart electronics to reduce home and office electricity demand, to incorporate smart electronics into the Energy Star Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2010--Introduced.
Smart Electronics Act - Requires the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to submit a report to Congress that: (1) assesses the potential for cost-effective integration of smart electronics technologies and capabilities in all products that are reviewed by the Department of Energy (DOE) and the EPA for potential designation as Energy Star products; (2) assesses the growth of consumer electronics utilization and the associated energy consumption; (3) analyzes the potential energy savings and electricity cost savings that could accrue through specific Energy Star program focus on smart electronics; and (4) analyzes and ranks the potential of cost-effective smart electronics technologies. Defines "smart electronics" to mean consumer electronics with one or more of the following: (1) power-factor correction; (2) stand-by power; (3) communication with smart grid and in-home and networked energy monitoring equipment; (4) on-demand and variable processing speed semiconductors; (5) off-peak operation and charging; (6) low power switchable modes; or (7) the ability to achieve greater efficiency with multiple functions on semiconductors. Requires the Secretary and the Administrator, to the extent that it is consistent with report findings, to: (1) develop a smart electronics emphasis as part of the implementation of the Energy Star program; and (2) establish a Smart Electronics Registry that provides a voluntary mechanism for electronics manufacturers and sellers to register their smart electronics products. Directs the Secretary and the Administrator, in operating the Registry, to work with: (1) manufacturers to develop testing and verification protocols to ensure that products qualify as smart electronics; and (2) sellers to develop qualification criteria for smart electronics sales location labeling.</summary>
</bill>
