<bill session="111" type="s" number="3468" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop the Sale of Murderabilia to Protect the Dignity of Crime Victims Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 87 of title 18, United States Code, to end the terrorizing effects of the sale of murderabilia on crime victims and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2010--Introduced.
Stop the Sale of Murderabilia to Protect the Dignity of Crime Victims Act of 2010- Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit a federal or state prison inmate convicted of a crime of violence from knowlingly placing in the mail or causing to be delivered in interstate or foreign commerce any property, article, or object. Sets forth exceptions for a mailing or delivery of title to real property, title to motor vehicles, or a security to satisfy debt that is: (1) imposed by law or a court order; or (2) incurred through a contract for legal services, a mortgage on the primary residence of the immediate family of the inmate, the education or medical care of the inmate or a member of the immediate family of the inmate, or life, health, home, or car insurance. Provides for civil and criminal forfeiture of real or personal property used to commit such a crime or obtained as a result of such crime. Provides civil remedies, including injunctions, damages, and attorney fees, for persons aggrieved by prisoners using the mail in violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
