<bill session="113" type="h" number="2548" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electrify Africa Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a comprehensive United States government policy to assist countries in sub-Saharan Africa to develop an appropriate mix of power solutions for more broadly distributed electricity access in order to support poverty alleviation and drive economic growth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2013-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Electrify Africa Act of 2013 - Directs the President to establish a multiyear strategy to assist countries in sub-Saharan Africa develop an appropriate mix of power solutions to provide sufficient electricity access to people living in rural and urban areas in order to alleviate poverty and drive economic growth. Expresses the sense of Congress that the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) should: (1) prioritize where loan guarantees to African financial institutions would facilitate involvement in African power projects, and where partnerships and grants would increase access to electricity; and (2) consider providing grants to develop national, regional, and local energy and electricity policy plans, and expand electricity access to the poorest. Urges: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury to use U.S. influence at each institution in the World Bank Group and the African Development Bank to encourage power sector and electrification investments in sub-Saharan Africa, (2) the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) to prioritize investment in the electricity sector of sub-Saharan Africa, and (3) the Trade and Development Agency to promote U.S. private sector participation in energy sector development projects in sub-Saharan Africa.</summary>
</bill>
