<bill session="109" type="h" number="1320" updated="2013-07-19T19:15:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secure Borders Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To secure the borders of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400337"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Aerial photography"/>
    <term name="Air travel"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dogs"/>
    <term name="Drone aircraft"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Spanish language"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2005--Introduced.
Secure Borders Act - Establishes the Land Border Infrastructure Improvement Fund. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to conduct a vulnerability assessment of land ports of entry (POEs). Directs the Secretary to: (1) make permanent specified pre-enrollment programs that allow expedited inspections at POEs for participants; (2) develop a comprehensive plan to deploy technological surveillance systems along U.S. borders; (3) increase the number of K-9 units working within U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP); (4) ensure that radiation portal monitors are installed at all southern border POEs no later than September 30, 2005; (5) contract with an independent entity to study the necessary allocation of personnel at POEs and Border Patrol sectors; and (6) provide ongoing training for inspectors. Requires the Commissioner of Customs to submit a report to Congress on the One Face at the Border Initiative (a Department of Homeland Security [DHS] initiative that unifies customs, immigration, and agricultural inspection functions by cross-training CBP personnel). Requires the Secretary to: (1) submit unclassified and classified versions of a comprehensive border security strategy; (2) integrate the IDENT and IAFIS databases; and (3) make interoperable those databases used by inspectors in secondary inspections. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to create the positions of Northern Border Coordinator and Southern Border Coordinator within the DHS's Directorate of Border and Transportation Security. Requires the President to submit information regarding progress toward implementation of the Smart Border Accords. Expresses the sense of Congress that Mexicans and Canadians should be treated with parity in establishing periods of lawful admission. States that, once the entry-exit data system required by the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 is fully implemented, the period of admission for aliens holding border crossing cards shall be six months. Requires the Secretary to create an Office of US-VISIT Outreach to inform local border officials, residents, and businesses about developments in the US-VISIT program. Amends the Immigration and Naturalization Service Data Management Improvement Act of 2000 to reconstitute the integrated entry-exit system task force. Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure implementation of electronic arrival/departure records no later than December 1, 2005; (2) report on the development and distribution of a transportation worker identification card; and (3) establish standards and verification procedures for the security of intermodal cargo containers. Establishes the Office of Tribal Security within DHS. Requires the Secretary to transfer the CBP Customs Patrol Officers unit operating on the Tohono O'odham Indian reservation (known as the Shadow Wolves) to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE). Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) immigration cases involving incarcerated criminal aliens should be processed while the alien is in prison; and (2) appropriations should be authorized for staff increases for judicial and prosecutorial offices to better enforce immigration laws. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to create a new subclass in the S (witness or informant) nonimmigrant visa category for certain aliens in possession of critical reliable information regarding commercial alien smuggling organizations or enterprises. Provides for adjustment of status for such nonimmigrants. Imposes increased penalties for, and establishes a rewards program to combat, aggravated alien smuggling. Requires enhanced sentences and fines for alien smuggling. Amends the Federal criminal code to enhance penalties for smuggling merchandise into the United States. Requires sentencing enhancements for merchandise smuggling that results in a death. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to create an Office of Overseas Service within DHS's Office of International Affairs. Requires the Secretary to: (1) report on implementation of prior recommendations regarding visa security; (2) establish an electronic advance passenger screening system for visa waiver program (VWP) participants as part of an integrated entry-exit system; (3) create a VWP Office; and (4) provide fraud detection and foreign language training for inspectors inspecting VWP aliens. Requires the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (CIS) Ombudsman to launch a public information campaign and to establish an advisory group. Directs the Comptroller General to assess CIS and report findings to the Secretary, the Secretary of State, and appropriate congressional committees. Requires: (1) the Secretary to study biometric identifiers that might be used for immigration benefit applications and petitions; and (2) all fingerprints taken for adjudicating such applications or petitions to be digitized, and all such applications or petitions to be registered using a biometric identifier, by January 1, 2005.</summary>
</bill>
