<bill session="113" type="h" number="1532" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Autofill Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a program to populate downloadable tax forms with taxpayer return information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2013-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2013--Introduced.
Autofill Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) establish a program to allow taxpayers to download income tax forms that are populated with tax return information (e.g., wages, withholding, and self-employment income) previously reported to the Secretary for the taxable year; (2) establish standards for data download to tax preparation software; and (3) provide on the website of the Department of the Treasury a secure function that allows a taxpayer to download, as both a printable document file and in a form suitable for input to automatic tax preparation software, the 1040, 1040A, and 1040EZ forms that are populated with tax return information previously reported to the Secretary. Establishes deadlines for reporting tax return information to the Secretary and for making such information available for populating tax returns.</summary>
</bill>
