<bill session="112" type="h" number="3251" updated="2013-07-20T01:38:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that Federal assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for the construction of certain emergency levees is not conditioned on the subsequent dismantlement of those levees, except as provided for in a status certificate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400224"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2011-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2011-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2011--Introduced.
Prohibits federal assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for the construction of a covered levee from being conditioned on its dismantlement, except as provided for in a status certificate. Requires the Chief of Engineers to provide a status certificate for each levee constructed with federal assistance provided under that Act. Defines "covered levee" to mean a levee or similar structure constructed: (1) in response to a major disaster or emergency; and (2) in an area in which at least one other such structure was constructed in response to such a disaster or emergency, and subsequently dismantled, during the 10-year period preceding the date on which the President declares the major disaster or emergency. Defines "status certificate" to mean a written determination by the Chief of Engineers that a levee or similar structure: (1) is constructed in a manner that satisfies standards applicable to a permanent levee or similar structure, is not constructed in a manner that satisfies such standards but there is an adequate plan for improvements to ensure that such standards will be satisfied, or is not constructed in a manner that satisfies such standards and there is no adequate plan for improvements; and (2) may safely remain in place subject to specified conditions and for a specified period.</summary>
</bill>
