<bill session="111" type="hr" number="884" updated="2013-07-19T23:03:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-04T11:45:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-04T11:45:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3639) to amend the Credit Card Accountablity Responsibility and Disclosure Act of 2009 to establish an earlier effective date for various consumer protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-326, by Mr. Perlmutter.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-03T17:40:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="128">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 128.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The rule provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted and provides that the bill, as amended shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04T10:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12294-12301" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 884.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04T11:38:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 176 (Roll no. 841).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12299-12300" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12299" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-11-04T11:45:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="842" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 175 (Roll no. 842).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12294" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04T11:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3639) to amend the Credit Card Accountablity Responsibility and Disclosure Act of 2009 to establish an earlier effective date for various consumer protections.</summary>
</bill>
