<bill session="109" type="hr" number="567" updated="2013-07-19T18:59:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the condolences of the Nation to the victims of the 2005 hurricane season, commending the resiliency of the people of the States of Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, and Texas and committing to stand by them in the relief and recovery effort.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400167"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2005--Introduced.
Declares that the House of Representatives: (1) expresses the condolences of the Nation to the victims of all hurricanes which occurred in 2005; (2) commends the resiliency and courage of the people of Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, and Texas and the National Hurricane Center and its staff for its diligence and effectiveness in tracking and reporting storms; (3) commits to continue to provide the necessary resources and to stand by the victims of the 2005 hurricane season people in the relief, recovery, and rebuilding efforts; and (4) encourages hurricane preparedness and readiness in the event of future hurricanes.</summary>
</bill>
