<bill session="110" type="s" number="2390" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fire-Safe Communities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote fire-safe communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14628-14630"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5218"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5218"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2007--Introduced.
Fire-Safe Communities Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to publish a federal model ordinance for municipalities at risk (subdivisions located in a fire hazard area) that includes specified elements regarding fire prevention and management, such as: (1) specifications for construction materials and techniques for use in such communities; and (2) standards for roads, culverts, and bridges.Authorizes the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to modify, for a municipality at risk, the requirements of the Fire Management Assistance Grant Program related to the provision of a non-federal share of funds, so that if such a municipality has adopted an applicable model ordinance and is making significant progress toward implementing it, the Under Secretary may reduce the required non-federal share to 10% of the grant amount.Directs the Under Secretary to provide grants to: (1) municipalities at risk to encourage responsible development in state-identified fire-prone regions and to mitigate the catastrophic effects of fires; and (2) states to create or update fire-hazard assessment maps.Amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to: (1) include as a purpose of the Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program to enhance the capacity of local governments to integrate fire-resistant community and home design into local planning, zoning, building code, and brush clearing ordinances; and (2) authorize a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing assistance to fire-safe communities located near federal land.</summary>
</bill>
