<bill session="112" type="s" number="1635" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Juan Mountains Wilderness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to designate certain lands in San Miguel, Ouray, and San Juan Counties, Colorado, as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-642.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2011--Introduced.
San Juan Mountains Wilderness Act of 2011- Designates specified lands in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests and specified land of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Colorado as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Designates specified lands in such National Forests and San Juan National Forest as the Sheep Mountain Special Management Area. Sets forth provisions regarding water rights in the lands designated as wilderness or a special management area by this Act. Withdraws lands designated as wilderness or a special management area under this Act, as well as land within the Naturita Canyon Mineral Withdrawal Area, from: (1) entry, appropriation, and disposal under public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. Releases certain parts of the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Study Area that were not designated as wilderness by this Act from further study for designation as wilderness.</summary>
</bill>
