<bill session="109" type="h" number="3862" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Flexibility for Displaced Workers Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for appropriate waivers, suspensions, or exemptions from provisions of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 with respect to individual account plans affected by Hurricane Katrina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2005-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2005--Introduced.
Pension Flexibility for Displaced Workers Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Labor, for a one-year period, to provide appropriate waivers, suspensions, or exemptions from title I provisions of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) with respect to individual account plans affected by Hurricane Katrina. Exempts any person from liability for any violation of such title based upon acts or omissions covered by such waivers, suspensions, or exemptions and in compliance with their terms. Amends ERISA to extend the Secretary's current authority to postpone certain deadlines for up to one year in cases of pension or employee benefit plans, or any sponsor or other persons with respect to such plans, that are affected by presidentially-declared disasters or terrorist or military actions. Applies such postponement authority to actions required under any regulation issued or any plan provision (as well as, currently, to any action required or permitted to be completed under ERISA).</summary>
</bill>
