<bill session="113" type="hr" number="57" updated="2013-11-02T06:16:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that in order to continue aggressive growth in the Nation's telecommunications and technology industries, the United States Government should "Get Out of the Way and Stay Out of the Way".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2013--Introduced.
Declares that it is the sense of the House of Representatives that, in order to continue aggressive growth in the nation's telecommunications and technology industries, the U.S. government should "Get Out of the Way and Stay Out of the Way" by: (1) promoting investment through deregulation and free-market competition; (2) making additional spectrum available for commercial use through unencumbered auctions, reallocation of federal spectrum, and efficient spectrum sharing; (3) establishing a national goal of transmitting high-quality, real-time voice, data, graphics, and video at increasingly higher speeds to all people in the United States, especially in rural and underserved areas; (4) ensuring individual privacy without compromising market efficiencies; and (5) promoting cyber threat sharing for allowing the private sector to actively defend their communications networks.</summary>
</bill>
