<bill session="113" type="h" number="2325" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Due Process and Military Detention Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the disposition of certain persons detained in the United States pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1147"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2013--Introduced.
Due Process and Military Detention Amendments Act - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (such Act) to provide that, in the case of a person detained in the United States pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force or such Act, disposition under the law of war shall occur immediately upon custody and shall only mean transfer for trial and proceedings by a court established under article III of the Constitution or an appropriate state court. Requires such trial and proceedings to have all due process provided under the Constitution. Prohibits any person detained, captured, or arrested in the United States or a U.S. territory or possession from being transferred to the custody of the Armed Forces for detention under the Authorization for Use of Military Force or such Act. Repeals the requirement of detention in military custody pending disposition under the law of war for individuals determined to be a member or part of al Qaeda or an associated force who has participated in planning or carrying out an attack or attempted attack against the United States or its coalition partners.</summary>
</bill>
