<bill session="112" type="s" number="2181" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PRE ED Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preparing and Reinvesting in Early Education Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for loan forgiveness for early childhood educators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1542-1543"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="85"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2012--Introduced.
Preparing and Reinvesting in Early Education Act of 2012 or PRE ED Act of 2012 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to include early childhood educators in the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) and Direct Loan (DL) forgiveness programs for teachers. Makes early childhood educators eligible for FFEL or DL forgiveness if they are not in default on the loan being forgiven and have: (1) been employed as a full-time early childhood educator for five consecutive complete school years or a comparable period, as determined by the Secretary of Education; and (2) obtained an associate or baccalaureate degree in early childhood education prior to that period of service. Caps at $25,000 the amount of an early childhood educator's FFEL or DL that may be forgiven. Includes early childhood educators with associate degrees in early childhood development, early child education, or a related field in the program providing FFEL forgiveness for service in areas of national need. (Currently, early childhood educators are required to have completed a baccalaureate or advanced degree in such a field to qualify for participation in that program.)</summary>
</bill>
