<bill session="110" type="hr" number="440" updated="2013-07-19T20:54:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any comprehensive plan to combat illegal immigration must increase resources for border patrol, establish an instant employment eligibility verification system, renew a limited temporary worker program, prohibit blanket amnesty for illegal aliens who have deliberately broken the law, and give priority to law-abiding, highly-skilled immigrants applying for legal citizenship.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400150"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Amnesties"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that to deter further illegal immigration and strengthen the U.S. economy the following must be included in any immigration bill considered by the 110th Congress: (1) increased resources for federal and state authorities to strengthen border patrol efforts; (2) vigorous prohibition of the hiring of illegal aliens coupled with the establishment of an instant employment eligibility verification system; (3) a renewed and limited temporary worker program; (4) a prohibition of blanket amnesty for illegal aliens that does not harm the innocent victims of circumstance; and (5) priority for law-abiding, highly-skilled immigrants.</summary>
</bill>
