<bill session="110" type="s" number="175" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a feasibility study of alternatives to augment the water supplies of the Central Oklahoma Master Conservancy District and cities served by the District.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-86.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-111.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="245">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 245.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1337"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1337"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1337"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Reported to Senate amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to conduct a feasibility study of alternatives to augment the water supplies of the Central Oklahoma Master Conservatory District and cities served by the District. Limits the federal share of the costs to 50%. Permits the non-federal share to be in the form of in-kind services that the Secretary determines would contribute substantially toward the conduct and completion of the study. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
