<bill session="111" type="h" number="4058" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans to Work Pilot Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish the Veterans to Work Program providing for the employment of individuals, especially veterans, who participate in apprenticeship programs on designated military construction projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412332" joined="2009-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2009--Introduced.
Veterans to Work Pilot Program Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to establish the Veterans to Work pilot program to determine: (1) the maximum extent to which apprentices may be employed on designated military construction projects; (2) the maximum extent to which such apprentices are veterans; and (3) the feasibility of expanding the employment of apprentices to military construction projects other than those designated. Requires the Secretary, for each of FY2011-FY2015, to designate for the pilot program at least 20 military construction projects, taking into account specified considerations. Requires each contractor or subcontractor on a designated project to assure that it participates in a qualified apprenticeship or other training program for each craft or trade classification of worker that it intends to employ on the construction project.</summary>
</bill>
