<bill session="109" type="h" number="895" updated="2013-07-19T19:12:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Waste Terrorist Threat Assessment and Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for interagency planning for preparing for, defending against, and responding to the consequences of terrorist attacks against the Yucca Mountain Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2005-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400324" joined="2005-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2005-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Science, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Science, and Technology" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2005--Introduced.
Nuclear Waste Terrorist Threat Assessment and Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to coordinate the development and implementation of an interagency plan to prepare for and defend against terrorist crimes targeting the Yucca Mountain Project (high-level nuclear waste repository being studied at Yucca Mountain, Nevada). Requires that the plan: (1) include a comprehensive analysis of the safety and vulnerability of the Project to Federal crimes of terrorism; (2) address specified types of attacks; (3) give special emphasis to addressing the use of nuclear waste as a radiological weapon, the use of specified technologies, and sabotage or theft of high-level nuclear waste; (4) include a comprehensive strategy for defending against terrorism; and (5) include an analysis of the economic, public health, and environmental costs and impacts of implementing the interagency plan. Directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to coordinate the development and implementation of a comprehensive interagency plan to ensure that Federal, State, and local government response plans and programs can respond adequately to the consequences of terrorism against the Project. Requires the Secretary and FEMA to enter into appropriate arrangements with the National Research Council for technical review of the plans. Prohibits the Secretary of Energy from submitting a license application regarding, and prohibits the Nuclear Regulatory Commission from issuing a license for, a Yucca Mountain repository unless: (1) such plans are completed and included in the final environmental impact statement for Yucca Mountain; (2) public hearings have been held for affected populations; (3) the Secretary has certified that the Project is not vulnerable to terrorism; and (4) the Secretary has prepared and transmitted to Congress a report on the potential liability costs and damages resulting from a wide range of Federal terrorism crimes against the Project.</summary>
</bill>
