<bill session="113" type="s" number="316" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Postal Service Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to recalculate and restore retirement annuity obligations of the United States Postal Service, to eliminate the requirement that the United States Postal Service prefund the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund, to place restrictions on the closure of postal facilities, to create incentives for innovation for the United States Postal Service, to maintain levels of postal service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412586" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2013-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="630"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1718"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Postal Service Protection Act of 2013 - Sets forth rules for the recalculation of annuities for employees of the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) and for the redetermination of surplus or supplemental liabilities under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS). Prescribes the "average pay" to be used in calculating annuities and surplus amounts. Authorizes the transfer of surplus postal retirement contributions in FY2013 to the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund, the Postal Service Fund, and the Employees' Compensation Fund under the Federal Employees' Compensation Act (FECA) and to USPS for payment of its debt obligations. Eliminates the requirement for pre-funding of the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund. Sets forth criteria for the closing or consolidation of postal facilities. Allows USPS to provide any nonpostal service or product in a manner consistent with the public interest. Provides for the mailing of wine and beer sent by a licensed winery or brewery in accordance with the laws of the state, territory, or district where the addressee or agent takes delivery. Establishes in USPS the position of the Chief Innovation Officer who shall have proven expertise and success in the postal and shipping industry and in innovation, marketing, technology, and management. Establishes a Postal Innovation Advisory Commission. Requires the Postmaster General to report to specified congressional committees and the Postal Regulatory Commmission on a comprehensive strategy for maximizing USPS revenue through innovative postal and nonpostal products and services. Prohibits USPS from reducing the frequency of mail delivery to fewer than six days each week or from increasing the expected delivery time for market-dominant products.</summary>
</bill>
