<bill session="110" type="h" number="6747" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Motorcoach Enhanced Safety Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the safety of motorcoaches, to allow a credit against income tax for the cost of motorcoaches complying with Federal safety requirements, for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2326"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Motorcoach Enhanced Safety Act of 2008- Directs the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to prescribe regulations requiring motorcoaches to be installed with: (1) safety seat belts at each seating position; (2) advanced glazing in each portal to prevent passenger ejection; (3) improved firefighting equipment; and (4) enhanced compartmentalization safety countermeasures and certain other motor vehicle safety features.Requires the Secretary to complete, and report to Congress on, a study on improving bus crashworthiness, bus crash avoidance, and bus fire protection and passenger evacuation.Amends federal transportation law to direct the Secretary to prescribe regulations: (1) requiring providers of motorcoach services registered with the the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to undergo periodic safety reviews; (2) establishing a training curriculum and providing certification for each driver of a motorcoach seeking a commercial driver's license (CDL) passenger endorsement; (3) improving CDL testing; (4) requiring a driver of a commercial motor vehicle that transports for compensation not fewer than 9 and not more than 15 passengers to have a CDL; (5) requiring a federal medical qualification certificate to be made a part of CDLs; (6) requiring the annual review of state licensing authorities to assess the accuracy of physical examination reports and medical certificates of CDL applicants that are submitted by medical examiners to such authorities; and (7) requiring that all commercial motor vehicles be equipped with electronic on-board recorders that record driver hours of service. Sets forth a deadline for the Secretary to establish the national registry of medical examiners.Requires a state to carry out an annual commercial motor vehicle inspection program in order to receive a grant for the development or implementation of programs for improving motor carrier safetyAmends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for the purchase of qualified new motorcoaches and for the cost of improvements to existing motorcoaches to satisfy new federal safety requirements. Limits the amount of such credit to $45,000. Terminates such credit after 2026.Directs the Secretary to develop and administer supplemental grants, not to exceed $20,000, for the cost of retrofitting motorcoaches to comply with federal motor vehicle safety standards. Limits eligibility for such grants to certain motorcoach operators who have a fleet of not more than 25 motorcoaches and have total annual revenues of less than $5 million.Amends the Small Business Act to set forth loan and loan guarantee requirements for the motorcoach industry.</summary>
</bill>
