<bill session="109" type="s" number="1088" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Streamlined Procedures Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish streamlined procedures for collateral review of mixed petitions, amendments, and defaulted claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2005-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5540-5543"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-366.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3035"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Pardons"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2005--Introduced.
Streamlined Procedures Act of 2005 - Amends the federal judicial code to revise the law and procedures for habeas corpus petitions. Denies or restricts the jurisdiction of federal courts to hear habeas corpus petitions that: (1) have been procedurally barred in a state court; (2) are based upon errors in sentences or sentencing ruled as harmless error by a state court; (3) pertain to capital cases; or (4) challenge the exercise of a states's executive clemency or pardon power. Revises deadlines for filing appeals to federal courts of state habeas corpus decisions. Revises procedures for mixed habeas corpus petitions (petitions bringing claims exhausted and unexhausted in state court) to require petitioners to describe how they have exhausted each claim in state court. Requires unexhausted claims to be dismissed with prejudice. Limits the ability of habeas corpus petitioners to amend petitions or modify or add additional claims. Requires any period in which a petitioner does not have a habeas corpus petition pending in a state court to be charged against the one year limitation period for filing a federal habeas corpus petition from a state court decision. Requires requests for financial support for petitioners in a habeas corpus proceeding to be decided by a judge other than the judge presiding over such proceeding. Requires any amount of financial support authorized by a judge to be publicly disclosed. Extends crime victims' rights to federal habeas corpus proceedings arising out of a state conviction.</summary>
</bill>
