<bill session="111" type="h" number="4039" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ending Defensive Medicine and Encouraging Innovative Reforms Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the medical justice system by encouraging the prompt and fair resolution of disputes, enhancing the quality of care, ensuring patient access to health care services, fostering alternatives to litigation, and combating defensive medicine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2009-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2009--Introduced.
Ending Defensive Medicine and Encouraging Innovative Reforms Act of 2009 - Provides for reform of health care lawsuits by: (1) allowing a party against whom a judgment for medical malpractice has been awarded to pay future damages of $50,000 or more in periodic payments; (2) making each party liable for that party's share of damages only; (3) requiring a court to appoint a qualified specialist to review a health care lawsuit and file a statement of opinion regarding whether such lawsuit has a reasonable and meritorious basis; (4) requiring the losing party to pay the costs and reasonable attorneys fees of the prevailing party; (5) absolving health care providers from liability if such providers acted consistently with accepted clinical practice guidelines; and (6) providing that evidence of Medicare payments and reimbursements made to health care providers shall not, in a health care lawsuit, constitute a determination that a health care provider has or has not met the applicable standard of care. Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) provide protections from civil liability for certain emergency medical personnel and health center volunteer practitioners; (2) grant incentive payments to states for medical liability reform; and (3) impose liability limits and other restrictions on health care lawsuits in states that have not adopted medical liability reforms. Protects disaster relief volunteers, nonprofit organizations, and other entities from civil liability for injuries related to disaster relief services, except for injuries caused by willful, wanton, or reckless misconduct.</summary>
</bill>
