<bill session="112" type="h" number="3391" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive National Mercury Monitoring Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of a national mercury monitoring program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2011-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2011-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1183"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2011--Introduced.
Comprehensive National Mercury Monitoring Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a long-term national-scale mercury monitoring program that monitors long-term changes in: (1) mercury levels in air and watersheds, and (2) mercury and methylmercury levels in water and soil and in aquatic and terrestrial organisms. Requires the Administrator to: (1) select multiple monitoring sites representing different U.S. ecoregions that include national parks, wildlife refuges, national estuarine reserves, and other sensitive ecological areas in which substantive changes are expected from reductions in domestic mercury emissions; (2) establish and publish standardized measurement protocols for the program; and (3) establish a centralized database for environmental mercury data. Establishes a Mercury Monitoring Advisory Committee to advise the Administrator on the establishment, site selection, measurement, recording protocols, data integration, standardization protocols, reporting, funding, and operation of the program. Requires the Administrator to report on the program every two years and include, every four years, an assessment of the reduction in mercury deposition rates that must be achieved in order to prevent adverse human and ecological effects.</summary>
</bill>
