<bill session="110" type="h" number="6977" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Loan Shark Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to protect consumers from usury and unreasonable fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Introduced.
Loan Shark Prevention Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to limit: (1) the annual percentage rate (APR) applicable to any extension of credit to a maximum of 8 percentage points above the interest rate on tax underpayments established under the Internal Revenue Code; and (2) the amount of any fee or charge that a creditor may impose, under the terms of a credit transaction, to $15. Declares that, in the case of any credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan, no fee (including any annual fee, late payment fee, or over-the-limit fee) may be imposed on such account until 30 days after the obligor receives a specific notice of the imposition of such fee. Requires such a notice to explain how, when, and why a fee will be imposed and what options the obligor may have for addressing the fee or any reason for it, including the prevention of any future imposition of such fee.</summary>
</bill>
