<bill session="110" type="h" number="7259" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Security Clearance Oversight and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to revise reporting requirements related to security clearances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2008-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2220-2221"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2008--Introduced.
Security Clearance Oversight and Accountability Act - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to direct the President: (1) every four years, to conduct an audit of how the executive branch determines whether a security clearance is required for a particular position in the federal government, and report audit results to Congress; (2) every year, to report to Congress on the security clearance process with respect to government employees, government contractors, and intelligence community personnel; and (3) to submit a one-time report to Congress on security clearance investigations and adjudications. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to report annually to Congress on security clearance determinations completed or ongoing during the preceding fiscal year that have taken longer than one year to complete.</summary>
</bill>
