<bill session="112" type="s" number="511" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Boutique Fuel Reduction Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to provide for a reduction in the number of boutique fuels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1412"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2011--Introduced.
Boutique Fuel Reduction Act of 2011 - Amends the Clean Air Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to temporarily waive a control or prohibition respecting the use of a fuel or fuel additive if: (1) it is in the public interest to grant such a waiver; and (2) the Administrator determines, and the Secretary of Energy (DOE) concurs, that extreme and unusual fuel or fuel additive supply circumstances exist that are the result of an unexpected problem with distribution or delivery equipment. Requires the Administrator, after providing notice and an opportunity for comment, to remove a fuel from the list of approved fuels under all state implementation plans (SIPs) if the Administrator determines that the fuel: (1) has ceased to be included in any SIP (current law), or (2) is identical to a federal fuel control or prohibition established and enforced by the Administrator (currently, identical to a federal fuel formulation implemented by the Administrator). Directs the Administrator, on removing a fuel from the list, to publish a revised list that reflects such removal. Repeals the limitation on the Administrator's authority to approve a control or prohibition respecting any new fuel in a SIP plan if such new fuel increases the total number of fuels on such list. Provides that nothing in such Act limits the authority of the Administrator to approve a control or prohibition relating to any new fuel in a SIP if: (1) the new fuel completely replaces a fuel on the list published; and (2) the Administrator publishes in the Federal Register, after providing notice and an opportunity for public comment, a determination that the control or prohibition will not cause any fuel supply or distribution interruption or have any significant adverse impact on fuel producibility in the affected area or any contiguous area.</summary>
</bill>
