<bill session="109" type="h" number="5830" updated="2013-07-19T19:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wright Amendment Reform Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Wright Amendment Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 29 of the International Air Transportation Competition Act of 1979 relating to air transportation to and from Love Field, Texas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2006-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Aviation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 109-600, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than Sept. 15, 2006 for consideration of such provisions of the bill as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(l), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-15T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-600, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-15T18:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="395">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 395.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6228"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3661"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3661"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2006--Reported to House amended, Part II.
Wright Amendment Reform Act - Amends the International Air Transportation Competition Act of 1979, with respect to provisions concerning air transportation to or from Love Field, Texas (the Wright Amendment), to authorize domestic air carriers and foreign air carriers (with respect to foreign air transportation) to offer for sale and provide through service and ticketing air transportation to or from Love Field, Texas, and any U.S. or foreign destination through any point within Texas, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Kansas, Arkansas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Missouri, and Alabama (effectively expanding domestic and foreign air service to and from Love Field, Texas). Terminates such provisions (including the amendment made by this Act) eight years after enactment of this Act. Prohibits: (1) a person from providing nonstop air passenger service for compensation between Love Field, Texas, and any point or points outside the 50 states or the District of Columbia; and (2) a federal official or employee from designating Love Field, Texas, as an initial point of entry into the United States or a last point of departure from the United States. Limits charter flights at Love Field, Texas, to: (1) destinations within the 50 states and the District of Columbia; and (2) no more than 10 per month per air carrier for charter flights beyond the states of Texas, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Kansas, Arkansas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Missouri, and Alabama. Requires: (1) air carriers, with specified exceptions, who lease gate space for flights to and from Love Field, Texas, to depart from and arrive at such gates; and (2) operators of charter flights from Love Field, Texas, who do not lease gate space to depart from nonterminal facilities or one of the terminal gates at Love Field, Texas. Deems any action taken by the city of Dallas, the city of Forth Worth, Southwest Airlines, American Airlines, and the Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport Board to implement a certain agreement to resolve the "Wright Amendment Issues" dated July 11, 2006, to be in compliance with certain obligations under federal transportation. Declares that nothing in such agreement shall affect general aviation service at Love Field, Texas. Directs the city of Dallas, Texas, to reduce the number of gates available for air service at Love Field, Texas, to no more than 20 gates (and, thereafter, with a limit not to exceed a maximum of 20 gates). Grants the Department of Transportation (DOT) exclusive authority to review actions taken under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
