<bill session="109" type="h" number="2718" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Idaho Land Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the exchange of certain Federal land within the State of Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400305"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1131"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Idaho Land Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, if the State of Idaho offers to convey specified State land to the United States, to accept the offer, and on receipt of title to such land, simultaneously convey to the State specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and National Forest System land (the Federal land). Requires the value of the exchanged Federal and State lands to be: (1) equal; or (2) made equal by cash payment to the United States or the State. Sets forth requirements for the disposition and use of proceeds from cash equalization payments received by the United States. Requires the conveyance of certain easements or other rights-of-way. Directs the city of Boise, Idaho, to pay the administrative costs associated with such land exchange. Transfers administrative jurisdiction over specified BLM land in Shoshone County, Idaho, from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Agriculture. Considers the boundaries of the Idaho Panhandle National Forest and Clearwater National Forest, as modified by the exchange authorized by this Act, to be the boundaries of such Forests as of January 1, 1965. Revokes any public land orders withdrawing any of the Federal land from appropriation or disposal under the public land laws necessary to permit disposal of such land. Withdraws the Federal and State land from: (1) location, entry, and patent under the mining and public land laws; and (2) disposition under the mineral leasing laws and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970.</summary>
</bill>
