<bill session="109" type="h" number="1562" updated="2013-07-19T19:18:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemical Facility Security Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect human health and the environment from the release of hazardous substances by acts of terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400139"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2005-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2005-12-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2005--Introduced.
Chemical Facility Security Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate certain combinations of chemical sources and substances of concern as high-priority categories based on the severity of the threat of a terrorist release, taking into account specified factors. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations requiring owners or operators of chemical sources to conduct vulnerability assessments and develop and implement site security plans that address the results. Directs chemical sources not in high-priority categories to certify completion of such assessments and implementation of such plans. Requires the Secretary, in promulgating regulations and establishing procedures, protocols, and standards for such assessments and plans, to consider specified factors, including the likelihood that a chemical source will be the target of terrorism and the potential scope of injury. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) designate or exempt certain categories of stationary sources as chemical sources; and (2) designate, exempt, and adjust threshold quantities of substances of concern. Establishes a five-year assessment and plan review requirement for chemical sources not in high-priority categories. Requires high-priority chemical sources to provide the Secretary with any changes to assessments and plans within 90 days. Sets forth disclosure protections and requires the development of confidentiality protocols for information obtained under this Act. Establishes penalties for unauthorized disclosures. Establishes enforcement mechanisms for noncompliance with assessment or plan requirements. Sets forth recordkeeping and site inspection requirements. Exempts from this Act chemical sources required to prepare assessments and plans under specified Federal laws. Authorizes civil and administrative penalties.</summary>
</bill>
