<bill session="111" type="s" number="3112" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Travel Restriction Reform and Export Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to remove obstacles to legal sales of United States agricultural commodities to Cuba and to end certain travel restrictions to Cuba.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1496-1497"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1531"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4645"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2010--Introduced.
Travel Restriction Reform and Export Enhancement Act - Prohibits the President from: (1) regulating or prohibiting travel to or from Cuba by U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents or any transactions incident to such travel; and (2) restricting direct transfers from a Cuban financial institution to a U.S. financial institution executed in payment for a product authorized for sale under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000. States that: (1) any regulation restricting or prohibiting such Cuban travel shall have no effect; and (2) such prohibition shall not apply in time of war or armed hostilities between the United States and Cuba, or of imminent danger to the public health or the physical safety of U.S. citizens or legal residents. Amends the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 to define "payment of cash in advance" as the payment by the purchaser of an agricultural commodity or product and the receipt of such payment by the seller prior to: (1) the transfer of title of such commodity or product to the purchaser; and (2) the release of control of such commodity or product to the purchaser.</summary>
</bill>
