<bill session="109" type="s" number="1980" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide habitable living quarters for teachers, administrators, and other school staff, and their households, in rural areas of Alaska located in or near Alaska Native villages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12609-12610"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12610-12611" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13306"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2005--Introduced.
Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to provide funds to the Alaska Housing Finance Corporation to make grants or loans to a school district located within a qualified community for: (1) construction of new housing units within the community, and the purchase and rehabilitation of existing structures to be used as such; (2) rehabilitation or leasing of housing units within a qualified community and the purchase or lease of real property on which such housing units will be constructed, purchased, or rehabilitated; and (3) repayment of a loan used for such purposes or any other activities normally associated with them. Defines qualified community as a home rule or general law city incorporated under the laws of Alaska, or an unincorporated community situated outside the city limits, which: (1) has a population of 6,500 or fewer individuals; (2) is situated within or near a Native Village that includes the Metlakatla Indian Community of the Annette Islands Reserve; and (3) is not connected by road (except the Alaska Marine Highway System or a road through Canada) or railroad to the municipality of Anchorage, Alaska. Requires occupants of such housing units, with certain exceptions, to be teachers, administrators, other school staff, and members of their households.</summary>
</bill>
