<bill session="111" type="h" number="5201" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Outdoor Lighting Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the energy efficiency of outdoor lighting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E744-745"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2010--Introduced.
Outdoor Lighting Efficiency Act - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to set forth provisions concerning establishing energy efficiency standards for: (1) pole-mounted outdoor luminaires manufactured on or after three years after this Act's enactment; and (2) high light output double-ended quartz halogen lamps manufactured on or after January 1, 2016. Sets forth control requirements for luminaires, including requiring luminaires to be sold with: (1) integral controls that have the capacity of operating the luminaire at specified power levels; and (2) internal electronics and connective wiring or hardware that enable the area luminaire to operate at specified power levels. Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to: (1) determine whether the standards for such luminaires should be amended; and (2) publish rules containing the amendments to such standards, if any, by specified deadlines. Sets forth provisions concerning establishing test procedures for efficiency standards with respect to such luminaires. Requires the National Electrical Manufacturers Association to develop and publish on a publicly available website a table including standard lamp types by wattage, ANSI (American National Standards Institute) code, initial lamp lumen value, lamp orientation, and lamp finish. Sets forth provisions concerning the adoption of the table by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to establish labeling rules for such luminaires. Prohibits the manufacture of general purpose mercury vapor lamps on or after January 1, 2016. Provides that state energy conservation standards that are adopted by January 1, 2015, pursuant to statutory requirements to adopt efficiency standards for reducing outdoor lighting energy use enacted prior to January 31, 2008, will not be preempted by federal standards.</summary>
</bill>
