<bill session="109" type="h" number="2541" updated="2013-07-19T19:26:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Stem Cell Research bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Joe Testaverde Adult Stem Cell Research Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the expansion, intensification, and coordination of the activities of the National Institutes of Health regarding qualifying adult stem cell research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2005-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2005--Introduced.
Joe Testaverde Adult Stem Cell Research Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to expand, intensify, and coordinate NIH activities regarding qualifying adult stem cell research. Defines "qualifying adult stem cell" to mean a human stem cell obtained from a human placenta, umbilical cord blood, an organ or tissue of a living or deceased human being who has been born, or an organ or tissue of unborn human offspring who died of natural causes (such as spontaneous abortion). Requires the Director to award grants and contracts to plan, establish, improve, and provide basic operating support for no less than five centers of excellence regarding such research. Requires each center to conduct basic and clinical research, including investigations into the cause, diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control, and treatment of disease. Allows a center to: (1) make individuals aware of opportunities to participate as subjects in research; and (2) provide referrals for health and other services. Requires the Director to provide for: (1) a program under which samples of tissues and genetic materials that are of use in qualifying adult stem cell research are donated, collected, preserved, and made available for such research; and (2) means through which the public can obtain information on NIH programs and activities related to such research and through which the Director can receive comments from the public.</summary>
</bill>
