<bill session="113" type="s" number="642" updated="2013-11-02T06:57:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consistency, Accuracy, Responsibility, and Excellence in Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act and title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make the provision of technical services for medical imaging examinations and radiation therapy treatments safer, more accurate, and less costly.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1146"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Consistency, Accuracy, Responsibility, and Excellence in Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require personnel (excluding physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants) who furnish the technical component of medical imaging examinations or radiation therapy procedures for medical purposes (except certain exempt individuals and suppliers) to possess current: (1) certification in the medical imaging or radiation therapy modality and service they furnish from a certification organization designated under this Act; and (2) state licensure or certification, if required by the state, where such services and modalities are within the profession's scope of practice as defined by the state. Gives individuals enrolled in specified training or certification programs when the list of approved certification organizations is published an additional six months after completion of a training program to become fully qualified under this Act. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) establish a program for designating certification organizations after consideration of specified criteria; (2) provide a process for individuals whose training or experience is determined to be equal to, or in excess of, that of a graduate of an accredited educational program in that specialty to demonstrate that their experience meets the educational standards for qualified personnel in their imaging modality or radiation therapy procedures; and (3) publish a list of designated certification organizations. Authorizes the Secretary to waive standards under this Act or to develop alternative standards for rural or health professional shortage areas as appropriate. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to allow Medicare payment for medical imaging and radiation therapy services only if the examination or procedure is furnished by an individual who meets this Act's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
