<bill session="112" type="h" number="270" updated="2013-07-20T01:12:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a 10 percent reduction in pay for Members of Congress, to make Federal civilian employees subject to a period of mandatory unpaid leave, to reduce appropriations for salaries and expenses for offices of the legislative branch during fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E55"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="335"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2011--Introduced.
Freezes the annual rate of pay for Members of Congress through December 31, 2012, and reduces it by 10% in 2013. Requires the President to subject executive branch employees to two weeks of mandatory unpaid leave (or the pro rata equivalent in the case of employees serving for less than the entire fiscal year) during FY2012. Requires the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to apply such requirement to judicial branch employees. Allows exceptions for reasons of national security or reasons relating to the public health or safety, including effective law enforcement. Limits the aggregate amount which may be appropriated or otherwise made available for FY2012 for allowances and expenses (including salaries) of any legislative branch office, except the U.S. Capitol Police, to 96% of the aggregate amount appropriated or otherwise made available for FY2011 for such allowances and expenses.</summary>
</bill>
