<bill session="112" type="s" number="1739" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Minnesota Chippewa Tribe Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the use and distribution of judgment funds awarded to the Minnesota Chippewa Tribe by the United States Court of Federal Claims in Docket Numbers 19 and 188, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6767"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6767-6768" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-626.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1272"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2011--Introduced.
Minnesota Chippewa Tribe Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to reimburse the Minnesota Chippewa Tribe for the amount, plus interest, that the Tribe contributed for the distribution of judgment funds and the payment of attorneys' fees and litigation expenses associated with the litigation of Docket No. 19 and Docket No. 188 before the U.S. Court of Federal Claims. Requires that the Tribe's claim for reimbursement of expended funds be certified by the Tribe as being unreimbursed to it from other funding sources. Requires the Tribe to provide the Secretary with updated membership rolls for the Boise Forte Band, Fond du Lac Band, Grand Portage Band, Leech Lake Band, Mille Lacs Band, and White Earth Band of the Tribe. Directs the Secretary to set aside a specified amount of the judgment funds for distribution to each member enrolled with each Band and then divide the remaining funds into equal shares for each Band.</summary>
</bill>
