<bill session="109" type="h" number="4539" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area Technical Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Cache La Poudre River Corridor Act to designate a new management entity, make certain technical and conforming amendments, enhance private property protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2102"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2005--Introduced.
Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area Technical Amendments Act of 2005 - Amends the Cache La Poudre River Corridor Act to redesignate the Cache La Poudre Corridor as the "Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area." Designates the Poudre Heritage Alliance as the management entity for the Area. Provides for the immediate removal of private property included within the boundaries of the Area upon request from the owner. Prohibits the Alliance from using federal funds received under this Act to acquire real property. Prohibits the acquisition of any land or interest in land by the Secretary of the Interior or the Alliance under this Act without the owner's consent. Requires the Alliance to prepare and submit a management plan for the Area. Allows the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the Alliance for the purpose of carrying out the plan. Prohibits any privately owned property from being preserved, conserved, or promoted by the plan unless the owner gives the Alliance consent for such preservation, conservation, or promotion after receiving notification from the Alliance of the proposed preservation, conservation, or promotion. Specifies private property protections. Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance to the Alliance (excluding technical assistance and administrative oversight) under the Act ten years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
