<bill session="111" type="h" number="4166" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Health Professionals Educational Assistance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to educational assistance for health professionals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400339"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2009--Introduced.
Veterans Health Professionals Educational Assistance Act of 2009 - Reinstates the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health professionals educational assistance scholarship program and permits furnishing scholarships to new participants in the program through 2014. Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, as additional requirements under such program, to: (1) modify the program in such a way that program graduates can be employed as soon as possible upon graduation and to actively assist and monitor graduates to ensure certifications are obtained in a minimal period following graduation; (2) require program participants to perform clinical tours; and (3) assign to each program participant a mentor who is employed at the same facility where the participant performs post-graduation obligated service. Increases maximum payments under the VA education debt reduction program. Allows the Secretary to waive such limits. Authorizes the Secretary to provide an educational loan repayment program for clinical researchers from disadvantaged backgrounds, in order to secure clinical research for the Veterans Health Administration. Directs the Secretary to: (1) transfer specified funds to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) for including VA facilities on a list of facilities eligible for assignment of participants in the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program; and (2) identify all VA medical centers and community-based outpatient clinics that may be eligible for such assignments.</summary>
</bill>
