<bill session="111" type="h" number="4001" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for environmental restoration activities and forest management activities in the Lake Tahoe Basin.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="2724"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2724"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2009--Introduced.
Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2009 - Amends the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the U.S. Forest Service, to: (1) conduct forest management activities in the Lake Tahoe Basin in a manner that helps achieve and maintain the environmental threshold carrying capacities established by the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency (Agency) and attains multiple ecosystem benefits, unless the attainment of such benefits would excessively increase the project's cost in relation to the additional benefits gained; (2) establish post-project ground condition criteria for ground disturbance caused by forest management activities; and (3) provide for monitoring to ascertain the attainment of such conditions. Requires the Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit to: (1) manage vehicular parking and traffic in the Unit; and (2) support the attainment of the environmental threshold carrying capacities. Withdraws federal land located in the Unit from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing. Requires the Chair of the Lake Tahoe Federal Interagency Partnership to submit to Congress a prioritized list of all Environmental Improvement Program projects for the Basin. Authorizes: (1) the Secretary, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to implement specified projects and projects included in the prioritized list that have been subject to environmental review and approval under federal and state law and the Tahoe Regional Planning Compact; and (2) funding for such projects. Requires the Director to deploy strategies that meet or exceed specified criteria for preventing the introduction of aquatic invasive species into the Lake Tahoe Basin and that apply to all watercraft to be launched on water within the Basin. Requires the Administrator to implement a Lake Tahoe Science Program that includes: (1) developing and updating an integrated multiagency programmatic assessment and monitoring plan and evaluating the effectiveness of the Agency's Environmental Improvement Program; and (2) providing support to governments in reducing pollutants that contribute to the loss of lake clarity. Provides for the establishment of a grant to develop a Basin watershed strategy.</summary>
</bill>
