<bill session="110" type="s" number="934" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Florida National Forest Land Management Act of 2003 to authorize the conveyance of an additional tract of National Forest System land under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3371"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3371" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-493.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1374"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Florida National Forest Land Management Act of 2003 to: (1) authorize the conveyance of an additional tract of federal land pursuant to the Act; and (2) provide for the disposition of the net proceeds derived from sales or exchanges under the Act to be available for expenditure by the Secretary of Agriculture for the acquisition, construction, or maintenance of administrative improvements for units of the National Forest System in Florida. Permits: (1) proceeds from the sale or exchange of such additional tract to be used exclusively for the purchase of inholdings in the Apalachicola National Forest; and (2) proceeds from any sale or exchange of land under this Act to be used for administrative improvements, as authorized above, only if the land generating the proceeds was improved with infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
