<bill session="110" type="s" number="2653" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ACTION Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Competitiveness Through International Openness Now Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to further United States security by restoring and enhancing the competitiveness of the United States for international students, scholars, scientists, and exchange visitors and by facilitating business travel to the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1068-1070"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1070-1072" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business travel"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
American Competitiveness Through International Openness Now Act of 2008 or the ACTION Act of 2008 - Directs the President to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategic plan for increasing U.S. competitiveness for international students, scholars, scientists, and exchange visitors. Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the International Education Coordinating Council. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) revise the "intent" criterion with respect to foreign students; and (2) permit specified employment-based visas to be renewed in the United States. Extends the security clearance for nonimmigrant scientists. Provides for: (1) security clearance portability under specified circumstances; (2) periodic review of the technology alert list (as defined by this Act); and (3) expansion of the social security number enumeration-at-entry program to include eligible exchange visitor nonimmigrants (J-visa) at all U.S. ports of entry. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 with respect to temporary driver's licenses and temporary identification cards. Directs the Secretary of State to establish an expedited visa trusted traveler program for international students, researchers, scholars, and individuals engaged in business.</summary>
</bill>
