<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1376" updated="2013-07-19T21:02:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24T19:32:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-24T19:32:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commemorating the 80th anniversary of the Okeechobee Hurricane of September 1928 and its associated tragic loss of life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412197" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1567"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T20:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-856.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-16T20:59:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="267">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 267.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Edwards (MD) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9367-9369" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1376.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-24T19:32:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9367" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T19:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Passed House amended.
Memorializes the loss of approximately 3,000 lives due to the Okeechobee Hurricane of 1928.Recognizes: (1) the importance of hurricane preparedness measures, enhanced evacuation, emergency plans, and disaster response training especially in economically disadvantaged communities to prevent a disproportionate impact of natural disasters and disparities in disaster response; and (2) the role of relevant federal agencies, research institutes, universities, and disaster response organizations in providing intensity forecasting, long-range projections of hurricane activity, emergency management, and hurricane and storm damage reduction to better prepare for, respond to, and mitigate the impacts of storms and hurricanes.Expresses support for initiatives to enhance our understanding of storm impacts on physical structures.Urges the state of Florida and local governments to: (1) commemorate and memorialize the 80th anniversary of the Okeechobee Hurricane and its associated tragic loss of life; and (2) recognize mass graves of the victims.Urges the federal government, and state and local governments, to: (1) encourage hurricane and disaster preparedness, education, response, and mitigation; and (2) support programs and initiatives that promote such activities, especially in economically disadvantaged and migrant communities.Commends the Army Corps of Engineers for its ongoing rehabilitation of the Herbert Hoover Dike. Encourages continued federal, state, and local government collaboration toward expeditious completion of the rehabilitation effort.Recommits to hurricane preparedness, safety education, response, and mitigation for all communities.</summary>
</bill>
