<bill session="112" type="h" number="1953" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to include procedures for requests from Indian tribes for a major disaster or emergency declaration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E943"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2283"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the Chief Executive of an affected Indian tribal government (the person recognized by the Secretary of the Interior as the chief elected administrative officer of that government) to submit a request for a declaration by the President that, consistent with requirements of that Act, a major disaster or emergency exists. Provides that: (1) in implementing assistance authorized by the President in response to such requests, references to "state" and "governor" shall mean "Indian tribal government" (the governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or community that the Secretary acknowledges to exist as an Indian tribe under the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994) and the Chief Executive of an affected Indian tribal government; and (2) nothing in this Act shall prohibit a tribal government from receiving such assistance through a presidential declaration at the request of a state if the President does not make a declaration under this Act for the same incident. Requires any non-federal contributions of less than $200,000 required under such Act to be paid by an Indian tribal government to be waived. Allows any required non-federal contribution more than $200,000 to be adjusted or waived in accordance with criteria established by the President.</summary>
</bill>
