<bill session="112" type="s" number="1492" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in Clark County, Nevada, for the environmental remediation and reclamation of the Three Kids Mine Project Site, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2011-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5262"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5262-5263" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-642.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2512"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Henderson Redevelopment Agency of the city of Henderson, Nevada, the Three Kids Mine Project Site for the environmental remediation and reclamation of the Site. Requires Henderson Redevelopment Agency to pay the fair market value, if any, of the federal land, as determined and as adjusted based on remediation and reclamation costs. Excludes from the determination of fair market value any existing contamination associated with historical mining on such land. Adjusts the boundary of the River Mountains Area of Critical Environmental Concern to exclude any part of the Project Site. Releases the United States, upon making the conveyance, from any and all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product, solid waste, or mining related materials at the Three Kids Mine Project Site in existence on or before the date of the conveyance.</summary>
</bill>
