<bill session="111" type="s" number="3960" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tyler Clementi Higher Education Anti-Harassment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent harassment at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6425"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Introduced.
Tyler Clementi Higher Education Anti-Harassment Act of 2010 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each institution of higher education (IHE) participating in a title IV program (except foreign schools) to include in its annual security report a statement of policy regarding harassment that includes: (1) a prohibition of harassment of students by other students, faculty, and staff; (2) a description of its programs to prevent harassment; (3) a description of the procedures that students should follow if harassment occurs; and (4) a description of the procedures it will follow once an incident of harassment has been reported. Defines "harassment" to include certain conduct undertaken through technological means that limits a student's ability to benefit from the IHE's programs, or creates a hostile or abusive educational environment at the school. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to IHEs to initiate, expand, or improve programs to: (1) prevent the harassment of students; (2) provide counseling or redress services to students who have been harassed or accused of subjecting other students to harassment; and (3) train students, faculty, or staff to prevent harassment or address harassment if it occurs. Directs the Secretary to publish a report of best practices for combating harassment at IHEs.</summary>
</bill>
