<bill session="110" type="h" number="6793" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for grants to assist municipalities to facilitate the ability of local farmers to grow food crops and certain livestock to be sold locally, grants to enable local nongovernmental farming associations to support the formation of community-supported agricultural projects, and grants to provide start-up funds to farmers who must diversify their operations in order to participate in the projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG14" subcommittee="Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural societies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants to: (1) municipalities to facilitate the ability of local farmers to grow food crops or raise livestock for local community sale; (2) local nongovernmental farming associations that promote community-based farming or to qualified farmers to provide technical, advisory, and other assistance for a municipally-based agricultural project; and (3) provide startup funding to agricultural producers who must diversify in order to participate in a community-supported agricultural project. Directs the Secretary to provide marketing assistance to a participating farmer who has received a lease or loan guarantee that has not been terminated to assist the farmer in marketing to community institutions, including schools, child care centers, and senior centers.</summary>
</bill>
