<bill session="109" type="h" number="4288" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Cold Weather Injury Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide a presumption of service connection for injuries classified as cold weather injuries which occur in veterans who while engaged in military operations had sustained exposure to cold weather.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2005--Introduced.
Veterans Cold Weather Injury Compensation Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and maintain a registry of veterans who, while in active military service, were exposed for a significant period of time to sustained periods of extremely cold weather (seven days or more of average temperatures of 32 degrees or lower). Requires such registry to be used to determine the association, if any, between the disabilities of such veterans and the exposure to such weather.Presumes cold-weather injuries in such veterans to be service-connected and therefore compensable through veterans' disability compensation.Directs the Secretary, within 90 days, to prescribe initial regulations on injuries determined to have a positive association with sustained exposure to cold weather.</summary>
</bill>
