<bill session="112" type="s" number="792" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the waiver of certain debts relating to assistance provided to individuals and households since 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2011-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2394-2395"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="478">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 478.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to waive a debt owed to the United States relating to federal assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to individuals and households in relation to a major disaster declared by the President during the period of August 28, 2005-December 31, 2010, if: (1) such assistance was distributed based on an error by FEMA, (2) there was no fault on behalf of the debtor, and (3) the collection of the debt would be against equity and good conscience. Prohibits the Administrator from waiving such a debt that involves fraud, the presentation of a false claim, or misrepresentation by the debtor or any party having an interest in the claim. Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), at&#160;3-month intervals until 18 months after this Act's enactment, to submit a report that assesses the cost-effectiveness of FEMA's efforts to recoup improper payments under the individuals and households program under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
