<bill session="111" type="h" number="786" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make permanent the temporary increase in deposit insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 111-18.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-02-23T16:02:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="6">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 6.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2009--Reported to House amended.
Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) and the Federal Credit Union Act (FCUA) to redefine the standard maximum deposit insurance amount and the standard maximum share insurance amount as being $250,000, respectively (thus making such increase permanent). Amends the FDIA to: (1) extend from five years to eight years the period during which the restoration plan for the Deposit Insurance Fund (DIF) must rebuild its statutory reserve ratio; (2) increase to $100 billion the borrowing authority of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC); and (3) authorize the FDIC to impose special assessments upon depository institution holding companies to recover losses to the DIF. Amends the FCUA to: (1) increase to $6 billion the borrowing authority of the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA); and (2) require the NCUA Board to establish a Share Insurance Fund (SIF) restoration plan whenever the Board projects that the SIF equity ratio will fall below, or the SIF equity ratio actually does fall below, the required minimum amount. Sets forth restoration plan requirements.</summary>
</bill>
