<bill session="111" type="h" number="3455" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make available funds from the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 for funding a voluntary employees' beneficiary association with respect to former employees of Delphi Corporation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412266" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1663"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into an agreement with a volunteer employees' beneficiary association (VEBA) established after enactment of this Act for the benefit of eligible separated employees of Delphi Corporation (and their dependents) in order to transfer amounts to the VEBA for purposes of establishing, or obtaining coverage under, a health care plan for the benefit of such employees (and dependents). Limits the application of this Act to employees with respect to whom the obligation of Delphi Corporation or General Motors Corporation to provide health care coverage has been discharged in a bankruptcy proceeding. Directs the Secretary to make available up to $3 billion in Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) funds, under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA), to provide health care coverage that is substantially the same as the coverage the obligation for which was so discharged.</summary>
</bill>
