<bill session="112" type="s" number="1391" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the disability compensation evaluation procedure of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder or mental health conditions related to military sexual trauma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2012-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-668.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="930"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to accept as proof of service-connection of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) alleged to have been incurred in or aggravated by active military service a diagnosis of PTSD by a mental health professional, together with written testimony by the veteran and a written determination by the professional that such disorder is related to the veteran's service, notwithstanding the fact that there is no official record of such incurrence or aggravation in such service, and to resolve every reasonable doubt in favor of the veteran. Allows such service-connection to be rebutted by clear and convincing evidence to the contrary. Provides the same conditions (with the same authorized rebuttal) with respect to acceptance of proof of service-connection of certain mental health conditions alleged to have been incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma experienced during active military service.</summary>
</bill>
