<bill session="110" type="s" number="553" updated="2013-07-19T22:25:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eightmile Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Eightmile Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Eightmile River in the State of Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-104.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-94.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="224">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 224.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="986"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="986"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Eightmile Wild and Scenic River Act - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (the Act) to designate specified segments in the Eightmile River in Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) manage Eightmile River in accordance with the Eightmile Watershed Management Plan, dated December 8, 2005, and such amendments to the Plan as the Secretary determines to be consistent with this Act; and (2) coordinate the management responsibilities of the Secretary relating to the River with the Eightmile River Coordinating Committee, as described in such Plan. Allows the Secretary, concerning cooperative agreements for the administration of any component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, to enter into a cooperative agreement with: (1) the State of Connecticut; (2) the towns of Salem, Lyme, and East Haddam, Connecticut (the towns); and (3) appropriate local planning and environmental organizations. Requires that each such cooperative agreement authorized: (1) shall be consistent with the management plan; and (2) may include provisions for financial or other assistance from the United States. Bars the Eightmile River from being: (1) administered as part of the National Park System; or (2) subject to regulations that govern such System. Considers, with respect to the Eightmile River, each zoning ordinance adopted by the towns in effect as of December 8, 2005, to satisfy each standard and requirement under the Act regarding the prohibition on the federal acquisition of certain lands by condemnation for inclusion in any national, wild, scenic, or recreational river area. Makes the provisions of the Act that prohibit federal acquisition of land by condemnation applicable to the acquisition of land for the Eightmile River. Limits the authority of the Secretary to acquire land for the purpose of managing the River as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System to acquisition by donation or with the consent of the owner of the land and subject to the additional criteria set forth in the management plan. Recognizes specified tributaries of the Eightmile River Watershed as integral to the protection and enhancement of the River and that watershed. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
