<bill session="111" type="h" number="2870" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing Cabin Baggage Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To standardize and clarify the dimensions of carry-on baggage and personal items on air carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400630"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2010-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2009--Introduced.
Securing Cabin Baggage Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) (TSA), to issue regulations to limit: (1) the size of baggage and personal items carried on board a passenger aircraft; and (2) a passenger to only one carry-on bag and one personal item. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to modify certain federal regulations regarding carry-on baggage to require air carrier carry-on baggage programs to limit each passenger boarding an aircraft to one piece of carry-on baggage and one personal item. Authorizes air carriers to establish smaller size limitations for such items. Specifies items and persons to be excluded from TSA and FAA carry-on baggage limitations, including cockpit and cabin crew in uniform. Requires the TSA and FAA to notify passengers via their websites of federal carry-on baggage and personal item limitations. Requires the TSA to: (1) to install a template with a maximum depth and width to prevent the conveyor belt passage at each checkpoint of carry-on baggage or personal items that exceed federal size limitations; and (2) require passengers with carry-on baggage or personal items that exceed such limitations to check them in.</summary>
</bill>
