<bill session="112" type="s" number="978" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the criminal penalty provision for criminal infringement of a copyright, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="77">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 77.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2011--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Amends the federal criminal code to provide for imprisonment for up to 5 years, a fine, or both, for criminal infringement of a copyright where the offense consists of 10 or more public performances by electronic means, during any 180-day period, of one or more copyrighted works and where: (1) the total retail value of the performances, or the total economic value of such performances to the infringer or to the copyright owner, would exceed $2,500; or (2) the total fair market value of licenses to offer performances of those works would exceed $5,000. Includes, within copyright provisions protecting works from criminal infringement, the public performance of a work being prepared for commercial distribution.</summary>
</bill>
