<bill session="109" type="s" number="1908" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nanoscience to Commercialization Institutes Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Under Secretary of Technology of the Department of Commerce to award grants to establish up to eight Nanoscience to Commercialization Institutes throughout the United States to develop commercial applications for nanotechnology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11745-11746"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11746" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5008"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Nanotechnology"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Semiconductors"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2005--Introduced.
Nanoscience to Commercialization Institutes Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Under Secretary of Technology of the Department of Commerce to award grants to eligible entities to establish up to eight Nanoscience to Commercialization Institutes throughout the United States to assist in the commercialization of nanotechnology. Instructs the Under Secretary to ensure that each Institute is located at either a public university or federal laboratory. Requires grants awarded pursuant to this Act to be used to establish at least one Institute in each of the following areas of nanotechology or microtechnology: (1) energy; (2) printable electronics; (3) medical; (4) transportation; (5) textiles; and (6) agriculture. Specifies matching requirements for for-profit manufacturing companies conducting research and development in micro- and nanotechnologies. Makes any institution of higher education that has a federally funded nanotechnology center or that is the primary lead of a nanotechnology center not eligible for a grant under this Act. Directs the Under Secretary to establish a peer review committee to review the goals and progress made by each Institute. Requires each grant recipient to submit a report to such committee describing its Institute's accomplishments and goals as a condition of continued grant funding.</summary>
</bill>
