<bill session="113" type="h" number="1268" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Mitigation Expense Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for qualified flood mitigation expenses incurred with respect to certain residences for which the chargeable premium rate under the national flood insurance program is increasing and to provide increased funding for mitigation programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412443"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Financial Services, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2013--Introduced.
Flood Mitigation Expense Relief Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow qualified taxpayers a tax credit, up to $5,000 in a taxable year, for flood mitigation expenses. Defines "qualified taxpayer" as: (1) a taxpayer who is the holder of a flood insurance policy under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 and who owns insured property for which the chargeable premium rate under such policy was increased or will increase and which has an elevation lower than the base flood elevation or is located in an area designated as having a higher flood risk, and (2) a small business with 50 or fewer employees. Terminates such credit after 2022. Authorizes appropriations to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to carry out: (1) the predisaster hazard mitigation program authorized by the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and (2) the flood mitigation assistance program authorized by the National Flood Insurance Act of 1969. Specifies that such funds may be used only for mitigation activities and acquisition by states and communities of properties located in higher flood risk areas. Terminates the Energy Star program of the Department of Energy (DOE) and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and rescinds any amounts not obligated or expended for such program.</summary>
</bill>
