<bill session="111" type="s" number="3292" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Weekends Without Hunger Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch to establish a weekend and holiday feeding program to provide nutritious food to at-risk school children on weekends and during extended school holidays during the school year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2808"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2010--Introduced.
Weekends Without Hunger Act - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to implement a five-year pilot program providing commodities to nonprofits for the provision of nutritious food to at-risk school children on weekends and during extended school holidays during the school year. (At-risk school children are those who participate in the school lunch program and reside in an area served by a school in which at least 50% of the students receive free or reduced price meals under the school lunch or breakfast programs.) Includes elementary and secondary schools, school food authorities, and emergency feeding agencies as eligible nonprofit recipients of such commodities. Requires commodity recipients to satisfy safe food storage, handling, and delivery standards established by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
