<bill session="109" type="s" number="3663" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business International Trade Enhancements Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to increase the maximum amount for international trade loans, to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to assign an international finance specialist, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2006-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7555-7556"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7556" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2006--Introduced.
Small Business International Trade Enhancements Act of 2006 - Amends the Small Business Act to increase: (1) the ceiling on a Small Business Administration (SBA) international trade loan (ITL) guarantee under the Export Working Capital Program from $1.75 million to $2.75 million; (2) the maximum ITL to $3.67 million; and (3) the maximum available for export working capital, supplies, or financing from $1.25 million to $2 million. Allows the use of an ITL for working capital. Allows an ITL to be secured by a second lien position on the property or equipment financed by the loan or on other assets of the small business concern. (Currently a first lien position or first mortgage on the property, equipment, or other business assets is required.) Directs the SBA Administrator to assign to the Office of International Trade (OIT) one additional full-time international finance specialist to carry out the export promotion efforts in Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama. Requires such specialist to be located at the U.S. Export Assistance Center in the New Orleans, Louisiana. Directs the Administrator to ensure that the number of full-time equivalent OIT employees (international finance specialists) assigned to the district and foreign one-stop shops for U.S. exporters operated by the United States and Foreign Commercial Service is at least the number of such employees (16) so assigned on January 1, 2006.</summary>
</bill>
