<bill session="110" type="s" number="2659" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to ensure that all trailers or mobile homes purchased by the Federal Emergency Management Agency meet the safety standards established by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for housing used in programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Formaldehyde"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2008--Introduced.
Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to ensure that any trailer or mobile home purchased by FEMA meets safety standards established by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under provisions relating to limitations on hazardous materials in housing to be used in Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) programs, including any such standards for formaldehyde, lead, or any other hazardous material, contamination, toxic chemical or gas, or radioactive substance that could affect the health or safety of an occupant.</summary>
</bill>
