<bill session="109" type="sr" number="388" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-02">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution urging the Government of National Unity of Sudan and the Government of Southern Sudan to implement fully the Comprehensive Peace Agreement that was signed on January 9, 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-03-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1660-1661" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1660-1661" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1658" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Wealth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Urges the government of National Unity of Sudan to implement the Comprehensive Peace Agreement. Calls on the government of National Unity to achieve an equitable distribution of wealth and resources between the North and the South, and to provide a full accounting of Sudan's oil revenues. Urges the U.S. government to: (1) maintain pressure on the government of National Unity to implement the Agreement and resolve the Darfur crisis; and (2) address any legal barriers preventing humanitarian and reconstruction operations in Southern Sudan. Supports the continued provision of U.S. humanitarian and reconstruction assistance to the people of Southern Sudan, in addition to the assistance allocated for the people of Darfur. Urges: (1) the government of National Unity to use the Agreement as the basis for a peaceful resolution of the conflicts in Darfur and other areas of Sudan; and (2) all countries in the region and the international community to support the Agreement's full implementation.</summary>
</bill>
