<bill session="111" type="h" number="5654" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to provide oil spill relief employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1258"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6112"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3792"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2010--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Restoration Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to award national emergency grants to a state to provide oil spill relief employment assistance for an area of the state that has been affected by an oil or hazardous substances spill of national significance (covered incident). Makes assistance available to: (1) provide oil spill relief employment of unemployed or dislocated workers on projects to clean, restore, or reconstruct lands, marshes, waters, and structures located within an area of a covered incident, as well as for food, clothing, shelter and other humanitarian assistance to affected individuals; (2) establish cleanup standards; (3) provide employment and training of, and protective equipment to, workers; (4) increase a state's capacity to provide information about public and private services at one-stop centers and other access points to individuals adversely affected by a covered incident; and (5) provide temporary employment by public sector entities. Requires the Secretary to require states receiving oil spill relief employment assistance to provide assurance that Davis-Bacon Act (locality pay) wages are paid to all employees and contractors who work on such projects. Limits an individual's oil spill employment to six months, subject to extension for a period determined by the Secretary. Establishes a Gulf Coast Community Conservation Corps (Gulf Coast CCC), administered by the Corporation for National and Community Service, to carry out national service programs that provide a covered incident area with oil spill relief specified in this Act. Authorizes the Corporation to transfer funds from the National Service Trust Fund to provide in-service or post-service national service educational benefits to individuals participating in a Gulf Coast CCC national service program. Requires parties responsible for a covered incident to reimburse the federal government for costs incurred in carrying out the activities authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
