<bill session="112" type="h" number="5861" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a grant pilot program to provide housing to elderly homeless veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/30/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretaries of Veterans Affairs (VA) and Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to jointly establish a two-year pilot program of grants to nonprofit organizations to provide homeless veterans with non-transitional housing. Authorizes the Secretaries to award two grants of up to $25 million each under the program. Allows recipients to use such grant to: (1) purchase real property to provide up to 200 homeless veterans with non-transitional housing, and (2) refurbish or renovate such property. Makes eligible for such housing veterans of at least 55 years of age who: (1) have been continuously homeless for a year or more or, during the last three years, had at least four separate periods of living on the streets, in an emergency shelter, or a combination thereof; and (2) have a condition that limits their ability to work or perform activities of daily living. Directs the VA Secretary to provide case management for veterans receiving such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
