<bill session="110" type="h" number="2967" updated="2013-07-19T21:29:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campaign Taxpayer Reimbursement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the use of Federal funds in support of any travel undertaken by the President, Vice President, or certain other executive branch officials which includes the attendance by the official at any political campaign or fundraising event unless the sponsor of the event reimburses the Federal government for the actual costs incurred in support of the travel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400254"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2007--Introduced.
Campaign Taxpayer Reimbursement Act of 2007 - Prohibits the use of federal funds to carry out or support any travel undertaken by a covered executive branch official away from his or her designated post of duty if at any time while the official is away he or she attends any political campaign or fundraising event, unless the official's office is reimbursed by the appropriate political committee for the actual travel costs incurred. Makes special rules for presidential and vice presidential travel. Applies this Act to travel by Members of the House of Representatives. Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require political committee reimbursement of certain state and local government security costs resulting from attendance by a covered executive branch official, other than the President or Vice President, at a political campaign or fundraising event.</summary>
</bill>
