<bill session="109" type="s" number="3858" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cascade-Siskiyou National Monument Voluntary and Equitable Grazing Conflict Resolution Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Interior to cancel certain grazing leases on land in Cascade-Siskiyou National Monument that are voluntarily waived by the lessees, to provide for the exchange of certain Monument land in exchange for private land, to designate certain Monument land as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2006-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Natural monuments"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/6/2006--Introduced.
Cascade-Siskiyou National Monument Voluntary and Equitable Grazing Conflict Resolution Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to offer compensation, equal to $300 per authorized animal unit month, to a lessee in exchange for the lessee's waiver of a lease to use a grazing allotment to graze domestic livestock for commercial purposes in the Cascade-Siskiyou National Monument, Oregon.Requires the Secretary to terminate any grazing lease waived and permanently retire the associated grazing allotment (or allotment portion) from livestock grazing use.Allows a landowner to donate a grazing lease to the Secretary without receiving compensation. Prohibits the Secretary from issuing a grazing license on specified allotments in and near the Monument, and requires the Secretary to retire such allotments permanently.Authorizes the Secretary to offer to convey to the Box R Ranch, and to convey if the offer is accepted, certain Bureau of Land Management land in exchange for the Rowlett parcel.Designates approximately 23,000 acres of Monument land as the Soda Mountain Wilderness in the National Wilderness Preservation System. Grandfathers existing grazing leases on such land, but prohibits grazing in the applicable Wilderness portion upon retirement of any such lease.</summary>
</bill>
