<bill session="112" type="h" number="6570" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to consolidate certain CBO reporting requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-14T12:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Garrett moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-14T12:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6351-6352" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-14T12:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6570.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-11-14T12:41:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6351-6352" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-11-14T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-11-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6870" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-11-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-12-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-12-04" type="public" number="112-204">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-204.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2012--Public Law.
Amends the Jobs Accountability Act, in title XV of division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, to revise the deadline for comments by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) on information contained in specified quarterly reports to the appropriate agency by each recipient of federal recovery funds with respect to an estimate of the number of jobs created and retained by the expenditure or obligation of such funds on a project or activity. Requires these comments on the quarterly reports in a year to be due 45 days after the report for the last quarter of the year is submitted. (Currently, such reports are due within 45 days after submission to the appropriate agency.) Terminates the requirement of the CBO and GAO comments on January 1, 2016. Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to change from semiannual to annual the required reports to the President and Congress from the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) of specified information and estimates regarding the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP). Terminates these TARP reporting requirements with the annual period on the last day of which all troubled assets acquired by the Secretary of the Treasury have been sold or transferred out of the ownership or control of the federal government.</summary>
</bill>
