<bill session="112" type="sc" number="18" updated="2013-07-20T02:16:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution setting forth the President's budget request for the United States Government for fiscal year 2012, and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2013 through 2021.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3184-3190" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Budget discharged pursuant to Section 300 of the Congressional Budget Act.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="61">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 61.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 0 - 97. Record Vote Number: 78.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="hc" number="34"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="19"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="20"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="21"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="37"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="39"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="40"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="41"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="42"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2012, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2013-FY2021. Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2012-FY2021 with respect to: (1) federal revenues, (2) new budget authority, (3) budget outlays, (4) deficits, (5) public debt, and (6) debt held by the public. Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority, outlays, and administrative expenses for the Social Security Administration (SSA), including the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, U.S. Postal Service discretionary administrative expenses, and specified major functional categories for FY2012-FY2021. Provides for adjustments to budgetary aggregates and allocations for: (1) continuing disability reviews and Supplemental Security Income (SSI) redeterminations for the Social Security Administration (SSA), (2) IRS tax enforcement, (3) health care fraud and abuse control, (4) unemployment insurance improper payments reviews, and (5) adjustments to support ongoing overseas deployments and other activities. Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate any legislation that would require advanced appropriations, other than for: (1) up to $28.821 billion in new budget authority in FY2013 for programs, projects, activities, or accounts identified in the joint explanatory statement of managers accompanying this resolution; (2) the Corporation for Public Broadcasting; (3) the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for the Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts of the Veterans Health Administration; and (4) the Department of Defense (DOD) for the Air Force Missile Procurement account for procurement of the Advanced Extremely High Frequency satellite. Sets forth requirements for the treatment of emergency legislation. Allows the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to adjust the estimate of budgetary effects of legislation that: (1) amends or supersedes the system for updating physician payments under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, (2) amends the Estate and Gift Tax under the Internal Revenue Code, (3) extends the Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) relief for individuals, and (4) extends middle-class tax cuts under the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (EGTRRA) and the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief and Reconciliation Act of 2003 (JGTRRA). Permits the Chairman to make such adjustments only for points of order in specified legislation relating to: (1) pay-as-you-go, and (2) long- and short-term deficits. Requires the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any budget resolution in the Senate to include in its committee allocations to the Committees on Appropriations amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the SSA and of the Postal Service.</summary>
</bill>
