<bill session="112" type="s" number="3274" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, to produce a report on enhancing the competitiveness of the United States in attracting foreign direct investment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2012-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2012-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2012-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="5910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2012--Introduced.
Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2012 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) U.S. ability to attract inbound investment is directly linked to U.S. long-term economic prosperity, competitiveness, and security; (2) Congress and federal departments and agencies should consider potential impact upon U.S. ability to attract foreign direct investment when evaluating proposed legislation or regulatory policy; and (3) it is a top national priority to enhance U.S. competitiveness, prosperity, and security by removing unnecessary barriers to inward global investment and the U.S. jobs it creates and promoting policies to ensure the United States remains the premier destination for global companies to invest, hire, innovate, and manufacture their products. Amends the Foreign Direct Investment and International Financial Data Improvements Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to conduct an interagency review of U.S. laws and policies on foreign direct investment in the United States and develop recommendations to make the United States more competitive in attracting and retaining strong investment flows from abroad.</summary>
</bill>
