<bill session="112" type="s" number="1590" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness for Small Businesses in Federal Contracting Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to develop a new classification system for small business size determinations and to promulgate rules to eliminate the nonmanufacturer exception to small business size determinations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2011--Introduced.
Fairness for Small Businesses in Federal Contracting Act of 2011 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a new classification system for industries for purposes of determining whether businesses meet the small business size standards established herein that replaces the North American Industrial Classification System. Requires: (1) the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be amended to integrate the new system, and (2) the Administrator of General Services to integrate the new system into the Integrated Acquisition Environment. Directs the SBA Administrator to: (1) eliminate the nonmanufacturer exception to small business size determinations, (2) require contracting officers to use the size standard established for retail and wholesale industries in federal procurements for products and services that are not manufactured by the offeror, and (3) require such officers to use only SBA size standards for manufacturing industries if the federal government issues a contract for the purchase of a product or good that is manufactured by the offeror.</summary>
</bill>
