<bill session="111" type="h" number="3759" updated="2013-07-19T23:46:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-19T14:33:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-01-19T14:33:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BLM Contract Extension Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">BLM Contract Extension Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to grant economy-related contract extensions of a certain timber contracts between the Secretary of the Interior and timber purchasers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to grant market-related contract extensions of certain timber contracts between the Secretary of the Interior and timber purchasers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2009-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12T16:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-394.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-01-12T16:52:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="231">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 231.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19T14:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19T14:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H151-152" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19T14:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3759.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-01-19T14:33:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H151" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19T14:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19T14:33:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2791"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/2010--Passed House amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), upon a written request from a timber purchaser, to make a one-time modification to the term of the purchaser's qualifying contract by adding three years to the contract expiration date if the request: (1) is received within 90 days of enactment of this Act; and (2) contains a provision releasing the United States from all liability, including further consideration or compensation, as a result of the modification made to the contract. Defines qualifying contract as a contract that was awarded during the period beginning on January 1, 2005, and ending on December 31, 2008, that has not been terminated by BLM for the sale of timber from BLM lands for which there is unharvested volume remaining, for which the contract is not a salvage sale, and for which there is not an urgent need to harvest because of deteriorating timber conditions that developed after the contract was awarded. Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress a report on a plan and timeline for the promulgation of new regulations authorizing BLM to extend and renegotiate timber contracts because of changes in market conditions. Bars this Act from having the effect of surrendering any claim by the United States against any timber purchaser arising under a timber sale contract, including a qualifying contract, before the date on which the contract's term is adjusted as described in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
