<bill session="109" type="s" number="305" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to recruit volunteers to assist with or facilitate the activities of various agencies and offices of the Department of the Interior.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1056"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-19.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="584"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2005--Introduced.
Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to recruit, train, and accept, without regard to the civil service laws, the services of individuals, contributed without compensation as volunteers, to assist with or facilitate the activities administered by the Secretary through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the U.S. Geological Survey, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Office of the Secretary. Prohibits: (1) the Secretary, in accepting the services of volunteers, from permitting the use of volunteers in law enforcement, in regulatory and enforcement work, in policy-making processes, or to displace any employee; and (2) volunteer services authorized by this Act from being conducted on private property unless the officer or employee charged with supervising the volunteer obtains from the property owner appropriate consent to enter the property. Authorizes the Secretary to accept the services of a volunteer in hazardous duty only if the Secretary determines that the volunteer is skilled in performing hazardous activities. Directs the Secretary to ensure that an appropriate U.S. officer or employee provides adequate and appropriate supervision of each individual that volunteers under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to provide for services and costs incidental to the use of volunteers under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
