<bill session="112" type="s" number="3710" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Career And Technical Innovation Fund Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to establish a career and technical innovation fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/27/2012--Introduced.
Career And Technical Innovation Fund Act of 2012 - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to authorize the Secretary of Education to reserve a specified amount of funds appropriated for FY2013-FY2017 for certain activities of national significance, including: (1) capacity building, (2) technical assistance, (3) evaluation, and (4) dissemination of best practices. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants, for a period of three years, to local educational agencies, area career and technical education schools, postsecondary vocational institutions and institutions of higher education, entities that carry out apprenticeship programs, and other partners to carry out specified programs and activities that meet certain performance standards to improve the effectiveness of career and technical education programs and teachers as well as increase student achievement to meet the needs of the future workforce. Requires the Secretary to set aside a specified amount of funds awarded to eligible entities for any fiscal year for projects to improve student outcomes in rural areas. Prescribes grant eligibility requirements.</summary>
</bill>
