<bill session="110" type="h" number="2798" updated="2013-07-19T21:28:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-23T13:09:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-23T13:09:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Overseas Private Investment Corporation Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Overseas Private Investment Corporation Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Overseas Private Investment Corporation Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Overseas Private Investment Corporation Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the programs of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400371"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 6 - 2 .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 5.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-19T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-241.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-19T15:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="151">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 151.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sherman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8204-8210" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2798.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-07-23T13:09:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8204-8208" label="text as passed in House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-273.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-03-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="593">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 593.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2349"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armenia"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Azerbaijan"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Militia movements"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Overseas Private Investment Corporation Reauthorization Act of 2008 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to extend Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) authority to make loans and issue investment insurance and investment guarantees through September 30, 2011.(Sec. 3) States that OPIC may insure, reinsure, guaranty, or finance a project only if the country in which the project is to be undertaken: (1) is eligible for designation as a beneficiary developing country under the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP) and has not been determined to be ineligible for such designation based upon its record on worker rights or child labor; or (2) if not eligible for such GSP designation, the government has taken or is taking steps to afford workers internationally recognized worker rights.Gives preference to projects in countries that have adopted and enforce laws that provide international worker rights.(Sec. 4) Requires that OPIC give preferential consideration to investment projects in less developed countries whose governments are receptive to private enterprise.(Sec. 5) Requires that OPIC institute a climate change mitigation action plan that includes the following: (1) clean and efficient energy technology; (2) environmental impact assessments; and (3) reports to the appropriate congressional committees. Directs OPIC to provide notice of consideration of approval of a project to provide financing of $10 million or more which significantly involves an extractive industry (as defined by this Act) to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 60 days before approval. Gives preference to projects where the investor and the host country have agreed to implement Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative principles.(Sec. 6) Provides for increased project transparency. Directs OPIC to maintain an Office of Accountability to provide project problem-solving services and to review OPIC compliance with environmental, social, worker rights, human rights, and transparency policies.(Sec. 7) Sets forth provisions respecting transparency and accountability of OPIC investment funds. (Sec. 8) Prohibits OPIC assistance for any railway connection that connects Azerbaijan and Turkey without traversing or connecting with Armenia.(Sec. 9) Prohibits OPIC assistance to an applicant who is involved in a "discouraged transaction" with state sponsors of terrorism. Defines "discouraged transaction" as: (1) an investment commitment of $20 million or more by the investor in the energy sector of a state sponsor of terrorism; (2) a loan or credit extension of more than $5 million to the government of a state sponsor of terrorism that is outstanding on the date OPIC enters into a contract with the investor and for which payment is not required within 45 days; and (3) the transfer by the investor of goods that are included on the U.S. Munitions List to a state sponsor of terrorism within the three-year period preceding the date OPIC enters into a contract with the investor.Exempts from such prohibition investments, business, or projects in certain areas of Sudan (Southern Sudan, Southern Kordofan/Nuba Mountains State, Blue Nile State, and Abyei, Darfur) if OPIC determines that such activities will provide humanitarian relief, promote self-sufficiency, or support peace agreements.(Sec. 10) Directs OPIC to notify the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations within 15 days after OPIC's maximum contingent liability outstanding at any one time exceeds the previous fiscal year's maximum contingent liability by 25%.(Sec. 11) Authorizes OPIC programs in Iraq. (Sec. 12) Directs OPIC to: (1) report to House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations on the feasibility of broadening OPIC assistance to projects that provide support to low-income home buyers; and (2) provide such assistance if feasible.(Sec. 13) Requires that OPIC commit adequate staff and resources to assist small businesses and investors in the United States obtain insurance, reinsurance, financing, and other types of OPIC support.(Sec. 14) Makes technical corrections.</summary>
</bill>
