<bill session="109" type="s" number="48" updated="2013-07-19T20:13:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize appropriations for the New Jersey Coastal Heritage Trail Route, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S235"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S235" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with amendments. With written report No. 109-41.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="57">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Revises provisions regarding the authorization of appropriations for the Coastal Heritage Trail Route in New Jersey. Provides for the use of funds made available under this Act only for technical assistance and the design and fabrication of interpretive materials, devices, and signs. Prohibits the use of such funds for operation, repair, or construction costs, except for the costs of constructing interpretive exhibits. Limits the Federal share of any project carried out with funds made available under this Act to 50 percent of the total projected costs and requires the Federal share to be provided on a matching basis. Terminates the authorities provided to the Secretary of the Interior under this Act on September 30, 2007. Requires the Secretary to prepare a strategic plan that describes opportunities to increase participation in the planning, development, and administration of the route and organizational options for sustaining the route.</summary>
</bill>
