<bill session="109" type="h" number="2250" updated="2013-07-19T19:24:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Valuing Our Trust in Elections Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Attorney General to investigate allegations of violations of Federal criminal law regarding elections not later than 30 days after receiving the allegation, to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish standards for the distribution of voter registration application forms and the handling of absentee ballots, to require individuals to produce photo identification as a condition of registering to vote or voting in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2006-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5776"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2005--Introduced.
Valuing Our Trust in Elections Act - Directs the Attorney General, within 30 days after receiving a complaint or other allegation, backed by evidence, of a violation of any Federal criminal law regarding voter intimidation, election fraud, or any provision relating to a Federal election, to initiate an investigation, and report to the chief election official of the State involved every 60 days until the investigation is completed. Amends the Help America Vote Act to require: (1) each State to establish standards for the distribution of voter registration application forms for Federal elections; and (2) the Election Assistance Commission to establish standards for the prevention of fraud and abuse in the handling of absentee ballots in such elections. Requires each State to distribute, collect, and process absentee ballots in Federal elections in accordance with such standards. Provides for appropriate penalties for enforcement. Requires individuals who register to vote and voters who vote in person, unless exempted by State law in certain circumstances, to provide a current, valid government-issued photo identification. Directs the Commission to make payments to eligible States for assisting individuals with covering the costs of obtaining the government-issued photo identification an individual must present or provide in order to receive a Federal election ballot. Requires certain training programs for poll workers.</summary>
</bill>
