<bill session="111" type="h" number="5350" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To continue restrictions against and prohibit diplomatic recognition of the Government of North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2010-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1980"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2010--Introduced.
North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2010 - Continues diplomatic, economic, and military sanctions against the government of North Korea as a supporter of international terrorism until the President certifies to Congress that North Korea: (1) is no longer engaged in the illegal transfer of missile or nuclear technology, particularly to Iran and Syria; (2) is not assisting foreign terrorist organizations, engaged in counterfeiting U.S. currency, or engaged in illicit narcotics traffic; (3) has released specified U.S. citizens, Japanese nationals, and surviving Korean War prisoners of war; and (4) has undertaken specified actions regarding family reunification, penal reforms, refugee access, and religious organization communications. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should redesignate North Korea as a state sponsor of terrorism. Finds that the United States did not grant diplomatic recognition to North Korea upon its establishment as a client regime of the former Soviet Union in 1948. Continues diplomatic nonrecognition of North Korea until such benchmarks have been met. Directs the President, in the case of a North Korean missile, rocket, or other airborne launch or the conducting of a nuclear test in violation of U.N. Security Council Resolutions 1695, 1718, and 1874, to instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use U.S. influence to secure adoption of a Security Council resolution condemning North Korea's action and requiring implementation of comprehensive sanctions against North Korea.</summary>
</bill>
