<bill session="112" type="s" number="587" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FRAC Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fracturing Responsibility and Awareness of Chemicals Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to repeal a certain exemption for hydraulic fracturing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held with the Subcommittee on Water and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1084"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2011--Introduced.
Fracturing Responsibility and Awareness of Chemicals Act or the FRAC Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to repeal the exemption from restrictions on underground injection of fluids or propping agents granted to hydraulic fracturing operations relating to oil and gas production activities under such Act. Requires: (1) state underground injection programs to direct a person conducting hydraulic fracturing operations to disclose to the state (or the Administrator if the Administrator has primary enforcement responsibility in such state) the chemicals intended for use in underground injections before the commencement of such operations and the chemicals actually used after the end of such operations; and (2) a state or the Administrator to make such disclosure available to the public. Requires the applicable person using hydraulic fracturing, when a medical emergency exists and the proprietary chemical formula of a chemical used in such hydraulic fracturing is necessary for medical treatment, to disclose such formula or the specific chemical identity of a trade secret chemical to the state, the Administrator, or the treating physician or nurse upon request, regardless of the existence of a written statement of need or a confidentiality agreement. Authorizes such person to require the execution of such statement and agreement as soon as practicable.</summary>
</bill>
