<bill session="111" type="s" number="744" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Affordable Tutoring of Our Children Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from an employee's gross income any employer-provided supplemental instructional services assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4070-4071"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4071" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4391"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2009--Introduced.
Affordable Tutoring of Our Children Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the tax exclusion for employer-provided dependent care assistance to allow employees an additional exclusion for payments of supplemental instructional services assistance to their dependents between the ages of 5 and 19 who have not obtained a high school diploma or who have been awarded a general education degree. Defines "supplemental instructional services assistance" to include instructional or other academic enrichment services that are: (1) in addition to instruction provided during the school day; (2) specifically designed to increase academic achievement; (3) in the core academic studies of English, reading or language arts, mathematics, science, foreign languages, civics and government, economics, arts, social studies, and geography; and (4) provided by a state certified instructor or accredited organization.</summary>
</bill>
