<bill session="111" type="s" number="685" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require new vessels for carrying oil fuel to have double hulls, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2009-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3685-3686"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with amendments. With written report No. 111-26.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-06-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="77">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 77.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7764-7769" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7764-7768" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>The committee amendments were withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-09-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1875"/>
    <amendment number="s4688"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Requires double hull protection of oil fuel tanks on certain vessels with a tank capacity of at least 600 cubic meters. Defines "oil fuel" as any oil used as fuel in connection with the vessel's propulsion and auxiliary machinery. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to: (1) provide guidance to all vessel traffic personnel that clearly defines the use of authority to direct or control vessel movement when such direction or control is justified in the interest of safety; and (2) require vessel traffic personnel communications to identify the vessel, rather than the pilot, when vessels are operating in vessel traffic service pilotage areas. Requires the Secretary to identify, and report to Congress concerning, requirements for the necessary expansion, improvement, or construction of buildings, networks, communications, or other infrastructure to improve the effectiveness of existing vessel traffic service systems, or necessary to support recommended new vessel traffic service systems, including all necessary costs for construction, reconstruction, expansion, or improvement. Requires a review and validation of the recruiting, retention, training, and expansion of vessel traffic service personnel. (Sec. 4) Requires that at least one trained and experienced pollution investigator be on duty or on call at all times for each Coast Guard Sector Command. (Sec. 5) Modifies requirements regarding the duration of merchant mariner's documents and certificates of registry. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the extending of licenses, certificates of registry, and merchant mariner's documents in specified circumstances. Terminates that authorization on December 31, 2011. (Sec. 7) Limits to one the number of reports regarding port security terrorism exercises that the Coast Guard is required to submit each year to the House of Representatives Committee on Appropriations. (Sec. 8) Requires that compliance with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 be determined by reference to the latest statement titled "Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation" for this Act.</summary>
</bill>
