<bill session="110" type="s" number="201" updated="2013-07-19T22:22:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">9/11 Heroes Health Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program for individuals still suffering health effects as a result of the September 11, 2001, attacks in New York City and at the Pentagon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1414"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="120"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/2007--Introduced.
9/11 Heroes Health Improvement Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants to eligible entities to provide medical and mental health monitoring, tracking, and treatment to individuals whose health has been directly impacted as a result of the attacks on New York City and at the Pentagon on September 11, 2001. Includes as eligible individuals firefighters, police officers, paramedics, workers, volunteers, residents, students, and any other individual who worked at Ground Zero, Fresh Kills (recovery site on Staten Island), or the Pentagon or lived or worked in the vicinity of such areas, whose health has deteriorated as a result of the attacks, and who has been evaluated by a physician or mental health professional for 9/11-related health conditions and needs treatment for such conditions. Sets the order of priority for individuals covered under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
