<bill session="110" type="s" number="3571" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Impact Assessments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIA Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to stimulate social policy and community environments to improve health by encouraging policies and programs to improve community health by policy and design, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9423"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
Health Impact Assessments Act of 2008 or the HIA Act of 2008 - Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a study to determine the best practices, standardized tools, and models for using health impact assessments as a method to promote health and reduce health disparities through social policy, land use, the built environment, and other public policies and projects.Requires the Comptroller General to review: (1) the positive and negative health consequences of federal policies and programs; and (2) how to consider health impact assessments for any federal, state, local project that involves federal funding or work performed by the federal government.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award a grant to an institution of higher education to: (1) provide for expertise on health impact assessment to states, local health departments, metropolitan planning organizations, and local planning departments; (2) collect and disseminate best practices and provide technical assistance and training about the scope and uses of health impact assessments related to community planning and policy making; (3) develop necessary data and evidence to inform health impact assessments and land use and community design and other broad policy decisions; and (4) carry out a demonstration project to establish and implement effective processes and models for designing and administering health impact assessments.Requires the Director to expand CDC's capacity to promote the health impact assessment processes, including by developing guidance for assessing the public participation and potential health effects of social policy decisions.</summary>
</bill>
