<bill session="113" type="hr" number="220" updated="2013-11-02T06:17:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the contributions of the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E691-692"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2013--Introduced.
Recognizes the important contributions that the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora has made in regulating international trade in endangered species and protecting endangered species worldwide. Recognizes the increasing importance of the Convention in addressing effects of trade on species, while taking into account multiple and compounding threats on species and ecosystems such as over-exploitation, habitat loss, invasive species, disease, and the effects of climate change. Applauds the Convention's recent leadership in reaffirming strong protections for the African elephant, sharks, and other endangered species. Urges: (1) renewed, expanded, and accelerated commitments to the Convention by all Parties to ensure the Convention's contribution to species conservation; (2) the U.S. delegation to the Convention to utilize international cooperation to encourage other Parties to the Convention to collaborate effectively to curb excessive exploitation of species for international trade; and (3) the Convention to adopt stronger protections for the polar bear, sharks, bluefin tuna, and other endangered species at the 17th meeting of the Conference of the Parties in South Africa in 2016.</summary>
</bill>
