<bill session="113" type="hr" number="51" updated="2013-11-02T06:16:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that adding art and design into Federal programs that target the Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) fields encourages innovation and economic growth in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2013--Introduced.
Recognizes the importance of art and design in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) fields. Supports the designation of a STEM-to-STEAM Month. Encourages the inclusion of art and design in the STEM fields during the reauthorization of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act and the Higher Education Act. Encourages the Secretaries of Commerce and Education, the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), and the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to develop a STEM to STEAM Council in order to facilitate a comprehensive approach to incorporate art and design into federal STEM programs.</summary>
</bill>
