<bill session="113" type="h" number="796" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to use the commercially available volume of cellulosic biofuel in setting requirements for the renewable fuel program under the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act, with respect to reductions in requirements to use cellulosic biofuel under the renewable fuel program, to remove the requirement that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) determine volumes of transportation fuel based upon estimates of projected sales provided by the Energy Information Administration. Revises cellulosic biofuel use requirements to require the Administrator to reduce the applicable volume of renewable fuel and advanced biofuels requirement by the same or a lesser volume of the cellulosic biofuel requirements of the renewable fuel program. Limits, for such purposes, the projected volume of cellulosic biofuel production for a calendar year to not more than 5% or 1 million gallons (whichever is greater) more than the total volume of cellulosic biofuel that was commercially available for the most recent calendar year for which such volume is known.</summary>
</bill>
