<bill session="111" type="s" number="3100" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reinstate and extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project involving the Little Wood River Ranch.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-619.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 111-196.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="404">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 404.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), upon the request of the licensee for the project numbered 12063 (Little Wood River Ranch, Idaho), to: (1) extend for three years after enactment of this Act the time period during which the licensee is required to commence the construction of project works; or (2) if the license for Project No. 12063 has been terminated, reinstate the license and extend for three years after enactment of this Act the time period during which the licensee is required to commence the construction of project works.</summary>
</bill>
