<bill session="111" type="h" number="850" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business CHOICE Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Cooperative for Healthcare Options to Improve Coverage for Employees (CHOICE) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage the development of small business cooperatives for healthcare options to improve coverage for employees (CHOICE) including through a small business CHOICE tax credit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2009-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="859"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Cooperative for Healthcare Options to Improve Coverage for Employees (CHOICE) Act of 2009 or the Small Business CHOICE Act of 2009 - Provides for the establishment and governance of Fully Funded Small Business Health Insurance cooperatives, which are small businesses that form a captive insurance company chartered in a qualified state to provide excess claims coverage insurance that meets certain qualifications to its members. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish an independent commission on Fully Funded Small Business Health Insurance Cooperatives to: (1) promote the development of such cooperatives; (2) make recommendations to the Secretary regarding minimum capital requirements; and (3) conduct oversight of such cooperatives.Exempts such cooperatives from certain state laws, rules, regulations, or orders, including any that would: (1) prohibit the establishment of a cooperative; (2) impose any material requirements, procedures, or standards on a cooperative that are not generally applicable to other entities engaged in a substantially similar business; or (3) discriminate against a cooperative or any of its members. Preempts any state law that conflicts with, hinders, poses an obstacle to, or frustrates the purpose of this Act.Sets forth provisions governing the provision of claims information, including protected health information, from health insurance issuers to cooperatives.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the small business CHOICE tax credit for small employers for costs related to providing qualified employer-subsidized health coverage for employees and their families. Disallows such a credit unless the employee offers a qualified small business wellness program to covered employees and family members.</summary>
</bill>
