<bill session="111" type="h" number="4952" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HAITI Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haiti Assistance Implementation, Transparency, and Inspection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Office of the Special Coordinator for Assistance to Haiti, to establish the Office of the Special Inspector General for Assistance to Haiti, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2010-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Haiti Assistance Implementation, Transparency, and Inspection Act or HAITI Act - Establishes, in the Executive Office of the President, the Office of the Special Coordinator for Assistance to Haiti which shall: (1) advise the President on U.S. government programs for the relief and development of Haiti; (2) implement a comprehensive strategy for such programs' coordination and oversight; and (3) directly approve such programs. Terminates the Office two years after enactment of this Act. Directs the Special Coordinator to promote partnerships between the U.S. government and private entities (including foundations, universities, corporations, community-based organizations, and other nongovernmental organizations) in or on behalf of Haiti. Establishes the Office of the Special Inspector General for Assistance to Haiti which shall provide for the independent and objective conduct and supervision of audits and investigations relating to U.S. government programs for the relief and development of Haiti. Directs the Special Inspector General to appoint a Special Assistant Inspector General for Auditing and a Special Assistant Inspector General for Investigations. Terminates the Office 180 days after the date on which unexpended amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for U.S. government programs for the relief and development of Haiti are less than $25 million. Directs the President to: (1) ensure that U.S. government programs for the relief and development of Haiti are grounded in an exhaustive U.S. assessment of Haiti's development needs and capacity; and (2) seek to lead efforts to ensure that any pledged international assistance for Haiti is based on defined objectives and includes measures that provide for mutual accountability and oversight.</summary>
</bill>
