<bill session="109" type="s" number="1569" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Long-Term Care Partnership Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to facilitate the establishment of additional long-term care insurance partnerships between States and insurers in order to promote the use of long-term care insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance portability"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
State Long-Term Care Partnership Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to provide for establishment of long-term care insurance partnerships between states and insurers (Qualified State Long-Term Care Insurance Partnerships (QSLTCIPs)). Defines a QSLTCIP as a state plan amendment that provides for the disregard of any assets or resources in an amount equal to the insurance benefits payments made under a long-term care insurance policy (including a certificate issued under a group insurance contract), but only if the policy meets certain requirements, including coverage of an insured who, at the time coverage first becomes effective, is a resident of such state or of a state that maintains a QSLTCIP. Directs the Secretary to establish procedures for educating consumers regarding QSLTCIPs and long-term care insurance policies issued in connection with them.</summary>
</bill>
