<bill session="110" type="h" number="249" updated="2013-07-19T21:05:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-26T12:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-04-26T12:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore the prohibition on the commercial sale and slaughter of wild free-roaming horses and burros.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2007-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2007-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E34"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-93.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-04-17T13:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="58">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 58.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-24T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 331 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 249 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 331 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 331.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4182-4192" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 249 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 331 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lincoln Davis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 249.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Price of Georgia amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of the debate on Price of Georgia amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price of Georgia demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of an amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 249.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4190" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Price (GA) moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Price of Georgia motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with amendments inserting a new paragraph clarifying that the underlying legislation shall not take effect until 60 days after the date on which the Secretary certifies to Congress that the long-term care of all animals not sold as a result of this Act does not exceed $500,000 annually.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4190" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 234 (Roll no. 268).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4190-4191" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-04-26T12:37:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="269" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 277 - 137 (Roll no. 269).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="331"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Wild animal trade"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h115"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/26/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Amends the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act to: (1) prohibit the sale or transfer of any free-roaming horse or burro or its remains on U.S. public lands for consideration for processing into commercial products; and (2) repeal provisions permitting the sale of certain excess animals or their remains and excluding from criminal fine or imprisonment a person who processes or permits the processing of such animals' remains.</summary>
</bill>
