<bill session="113" type="s" number="1226" updated="2013-11-06T04:46:43-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SECTORS Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Employment Clusters To Organize Regional Success Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote industry growth and competitiveness and to improve worker training, retention, and advancement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="919"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Strengthening Employment Clusters to Organize Regional Success Act of 2013 or SECTORS Act of 2013 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require the Secretary of Labor to award renewable three-year competitive industry or sector partnership grants to eligible entities to develop strategies that: (1) encourage growth and competitiveness through work with employers within a targeted industry cluster; (2) help workers move toward economic self-sufficiency and ensure that they have access to supportive services; (3) address the needs of firms with limited human resources or in-house training capacity, including small- and medium-sized firms; and (4) coordinate with entities that carry out state and local workforce investment, economic development, and education activities.</summary>
</bill>
