<bill session="112" type="s" number="754" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Roads Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Transportation to establish and maintain a national clearinghouse for records relating to alcohol and controlled substance testing of commercial motor vehicle operators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="14"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2459"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1950"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2011--Introduced.
Safe Roads Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish a national clearinghouse for verified positive alcohol and controlled substance test results and test refusals as well as violations of Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) alcohol and controlled substances regulations of commercial motor vehicle operators. Prohibits the release of clearinghouse information to a commercial motor carrier employer unless there has been compliance with all applicable federal privacy laws and regulations. Authorizes the Secretary to collect fees from such employers and other authorized users for informational requests. Prohibits an employer from hiring an individual to operate a commercial motor vehicle unless the employer has determined that the individual, for the preceding three-year period, has: (1) been tested for use of alcohol and controlled substances; (2) not tested positive for their use, or tested positive but has completed the return-to-duty process; (3) not refused to be tested; and (4) not violated FMCSA alcohol and controlled substances regulations. Directs the Secretary to establish a process: (1) to require employers to request and review any clearinghouse records of individuals before their employment as a commercial motor vehicle operator and for each year thereafter as long as the individual is so employed; and (2) for an individual and a state licensing authority to request and receive information from the clearinghouse. Subjects persons who violate the requirements of this Act to both civil and criminal penalties. Requires the Secretary to take certain actions to enhance DOT oversight of testing sites.</summary>
</bill>
