<bill session="112" type="h" number="3755" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom to Mourn in Peace Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit demonstrations at places of mourning during a funeral, memorial service, or other bereavement ceremony honoring a deceased veteran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2011--Introduced.
Freedom to Mourn in Peace Act of 2011 - Expands the prohibition on demonstrations at certain funerals, memorial services, or bereavement ceremonies for a deceased veteran to any property where such a service is held unless the demonstration has been approved by the cemetery superintendent or the owner of the property on which the funeral is held. (Current law only prohibits such demonstrations on property of a cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration or on the property of Arlington National Cemetery.) Extends to 1,000 feet the distance within which certain demonstrations that impede access to or egress from such a cemetery or property are prohibited during the period beginning 60 minutes before and ending 60 minutes after such a service, provided that there is a visible sign at applicable distances stating the time interval during which a service will be held.</summary>
</bill>
