<bill session="111" type="h" number="4223" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Academic, Social, and Emotional Learning Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support evidence-based social and emotional learning programming.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2010-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Academic, Social, and Emotional Learning Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award a five-year grant to an experienced nonprofit organization to establish a National Technical Assistance and Training Center for Social and Emotional Learning that provides training and technical assistance to states, local educational agencies (LEAs), and community-based organizations to identify, promote, and support evidence-based social and emotional learning standards and programming in elementary and secondary schools. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive five-year grants to states and LEAs to work with the Center in developing and implementing such standards and programming in elementary and secondary schools. Gives grant priority to applicants that have a plan for sustaining the program beyond the grant period and serve schools that have high numbers or percentages of: (1) low-income students; and (2) students in schools identified as needing improvement, corrective action, or restructuring under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA). Directs the Secretary to conduct an independent evaluation of the activities funded by such grants to states and LEAs. Amends the ESEA to include: (1) programming that meets the social and emotional needs of students as part of the School Dropout Prevention program and the Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities program; and (2) teacher and principal training in practices that address those needs as part of the Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund program.</summary>
</bill>
