<bill session="109" type="s" number="1215" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the acquisition of interests in underdeveloped coastal areas in order better to ensure their protection from development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2006-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2005-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2005-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6318"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-03-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Stevens with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-224.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-03-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="378">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 378.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3187"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land banking"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2006--Reported to Senate amended.
Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection program to protect the environmental integrity of undeveloped coastal and estuarine areas that: (1) have significant conservation, recreation, ecological, historical, or aesthetic values; and (2) are threatened by conversion from their natural, undeveloped, or recreational state to other uses. Directs the National Ocean Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to administer the program. Authorizes the Secretary to make program grants competitively to coastal states with approved coastal zone management plans or National Estuarine Research Reserve units for acquiring property in such areas from willing sellers. Prohibits more than 75% of the funding for any project from being derived from federal sources. Authorizes the Secretary to waive such prohibition for underserved communities, for communities unable to draw on other funding because of small populations or low income, or for other appropriate reasons. Permits appraised land value and costs associated with land acquisition, land management planning, remediation, restoration, and enhancement to be used for the non-federal cost share of a project. Authorizes the Secretary to provide specified funding for a regional watershed protection demonstration project that: (1) leverages land acquisition funding from other federal conservation or acquisition programs; (2) involves funding from and participation by multiple federal, state, and nongovernmental entities; (3) creates conservation corridors and preserves unique coastal habitat; (4) protects unfragmented habitats under imminent threat of development or conversion; (5) provides water quality protection for areas under the National Estuarine Research Reserve program; and (6) provides a model for future regional watershed protection projects. Reserves funds for acquisitions benefiting the National Estuarine Research Reserve. Requires a grant recipient to provide assurances that: (1) acquired property will be held in perpetuity and managed for the purposes for which the property entered the program; or (2) if such property is divested, funds equal to its correct value will be returned to the Secretary for redistribution in the grant process. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
