<bill session="112" type="s" number="803" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security Enforcement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to implement a comprehensive border security plan to combat illegal immigration, drug and alien smuggling, and violent activity in the southwest border of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1507"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3801"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1485"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2011--Introduced.
Border Security Enforcement Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to deploy at least 6,000 National Guard personnel to perform operations in the Southwest Border region (Region) (the area in the United States that is within 150 miles of the U.S.-Mexico international border) to assist U.S. Customs and Border Protection in securing such border. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to increase, by September 30, 2016, the number of Border Patrol agents stationed in the Region by 5,000. Directs the Attorney General (DOJ), the Secretary, and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to: (1) implement Operation Streamline in the Region; and (2) reimburse state, local, and tribal law enforcement for related detention costs. Authorizes the chief judge of each federal judicial district in the Region to appoint additional full-time magistrate judges who shall have the authority to hear all cases and controversies in the district in which the respective judges are appointed. Directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to enhance border enforcement preparedness and operational readiness through Operation Stonegarden. Directs the Secretary to: (1) construct, as needed, additional Border Patrol stations in the Region to provide operational support in rural, high-trafficked areas; (2) upgrade existing Border Patrol forward operating bases and establish new bases as needed; (3) complete the construction of a permanent checkpoint near Tubac, Arizona, and deploy additional temporary roving checkpoints in the Region. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to direct the Secretary to: (1) complete the required 700 mile southwest border fencing by December 31, 2011; and (2) construct double- and triple-layer fencing at appropriate locations in the Region. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) and the Secretary of the Interior to provide U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel with access to federal lands under their respective jurisdictions (within 150 miles of the Region) for security activities. Directs the Secretary to establish a two-year grant program to improve emergency communications for persons who live or work in the Region and who are at greater risk from border violence. Provides for: (1) specified equipment and technology enhancements; and (2) reimbursement of state, county, tribal, and municipal costs associated with the prosecution and pre-trial detention of federally initiated criminal cases declined by local U.S. Attorneys' offices. Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to include ultralight vehicles within the definition of "aircraft" for purposes of aviation smuggling provisions. Provides for DOD-DHS cooperation in identifying DOD equipment and technology that could be used by U.S. Customs and Border Protection to improve security along the U.S.-Mexico border by: (1) detecting border tunnels and ultralight aircraft, and (2) enhancing wide aerial surveillance.</summary>
</bill>
