<bill session="110" type="h" number="4338" updated="2013-07-19T21:41:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a procedure to safeguard the surpluses of the social security and medicare hospital insurance trust funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax expenditures"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2007--Introduced.
Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to make it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any concurrent resolution on the budget (or related measure) that would set forth a surplus for any fiscal year less than the surplus of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for that fiscal year. Creates an exception to such point of order if a violation of it would result from an assumption in the measure of an increase in outlays or a decrease in revenue relative to the baseline underlying the measure for Social Security or Medicare reform legislation for any such year. Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any (spending or tax) measure if its enactment would cause the surplus for any fiscal year covered by the most recently agreed to budget resolution to be less than the surplus of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for that fiscal year. Creates an exception to such point of order similar to the other one. Declares that, if the President's budget recommends an on-budget surplus for any fiscal year less than the surplus of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for that fiscal year, then it shall include a detailed proposal for Social Security or Medicare reform legislation.</summary>
</bill>
