<bill session="109" type="h" number="3894" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06T19:24:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-06T19:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Housing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Housing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for waivers under certain housing assistance programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to assist victims of Hurricane Katrina in obtaining housing.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To provide for waivers under certain housing assistance programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to assist victims of Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita in obtaining housing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400006"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2005-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Baker moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8663-8668" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3894.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:49:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T19:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8694-8695" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-10-06T19:24:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="511" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 418 - 0 (Roll no. 511).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8663-8664" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Passed House amended.
Hurricane Katrina Emergency Housing Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to waive specified requirements under the section 8 (United States Housing Act of 1937) housing voucher and project-based assistance programs for an individual or family: (1) who resides or resided on August 25, 2005, in any area subject to a presidential disaster or emergency declaration in connection with Hurricane Katrina, or who resides or resided on September 24, 2005, in any area subject to a presidential disaster or emergency declaration in connection with Hurricane Rita; (2) whose residence became uninhabitable or inaccessible as a result of such disasters or emergencies; and (3) who was receiving such rental benefits as of such applicable date. Specifies voucher requirements that may be waived as: (1) tenant rent contributions; (2) assistance eligibility; (3) income verification; (4) one-year lease requirement; (5) public housing agency (PHA) initial housing inspection; (6) portability restrictions; (7) certain lease addenda permitting termination of tenancy; and (8) access to federally funded programs by persons having limited English proficiency. Terminates waiver authority 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, unless the Secretary determines that such waivers are no longer needed, in which case the period specified is the six-month period beginning on such date of enactment. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary to directly administer section 8 vouchers if the appropriate PHA is unable to do so because of Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita. (Sec. 4) Specifies project-based requirements that may be waived as: (1) tenant rent contributions; (2) income verification; (3) one-year lease requirement; (4) public housing agency (PHA) initial housing inspection; (5) certain lease addenda permitting termination of tenancy; and (6) access to federally funded programs by persons having limited English proficiency. Terminates waiver authority 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, unless the Secretary determines that such waivers are no longer needed, in which case the period specified is the six-month period beginning on such date of enactment. (Sec. 5) States that: (1) a project-based housing assistance contract covering a project damaged or destroyed by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita shall not expire because of the damage or destruction of dwelling units in the project; and (2) the contract's expiration date shall be the later of the contract date or three months after the units are first made habitable. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator of the General Services Administration, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, other appropriate agency heads, the Federal National Mortgage Association (FNMA), and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (FHLMC) to compile an inventory of federal civilian and defense facilities and other properties that can be used: (1) for emergency housing; (2) as construction sites for temporary housing; or (3) to provide permanent housing. Directs the Secretary to provide Congress with an aggregate inventory report. (Sec. 7) Directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report on state emergency housing planning.</summary>
</bill>
