<bill session="109" type="sr" number="573" updated="2013-07-19T20:11:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-19">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling on the United States Government and the international community to support the successful transition from conflict to sustainable peace in Uganda.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2006-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-09-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9731-9732" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9732" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9729" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Cults"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Commends the delegates from the government of Uganda and the Lord's Resistance Army for agreeing to a cessation of hostilities. Recognizes the government of Southern Sudan's leadership in mediating the cessation of hostilities and establishing a framework for peace. Expresses the support of the citizens of the United States for the people of Uganda who have endured decades of violence resulting from that conflict. Entreats all parties to address issues of accountability and impunity for war crimes and crimes against humanity and to support national reconciliation efforts. Encourages the government of Uganda to improve the professionalism of its military personnel, with an emphasis on enhancing respect for human rights, accountability for abuses, and effective protection of civilians. Urges the government of Uganda to augment its resettlement plan by: (1) expanding social services; (2) deploying professional civil servants; and (3) developing the legal, political, and security infrastructure necessary to facilitate the freedom of movement of civilians to their homes, land, and areas within and around camps, and essential to fulfill the needs of returnees and former combatants. Calls on the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), as well as the international community to: (1) provide humanitarian assistance through nongovernmental organizations; (2) pay particular attention to victimized women and children; and (3) provide assistance for the demobilization and reintegration of rebel combatants and abductees, and diplomatic and logistical support for the cessation of hostilities agreement and progress towards peace in Uganda.</summary>
</bill>
