<bill session="111" type="h" number="3008" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Strategic Gasoline Reserve for Purposes of National Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Strategic Gasoline Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2009--Introduced.
National Strategic Gasoline Reserve for Purposes of National Security Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a Strategic Gasoline Reserve system with a total capacity of 10 million barrels of regular unleaded gasoline. Directs the Secretary to: (1) transmit to Congress, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the governor of each state in which a Gasoline Reserve will be sited a plan for the transportation of its contents to wholesale or retail markets in the event of an emergency sale; (2) complete the process of filling the Gasoline Reserve to a minimum of 90% within two years of submitting a transportation plan to Congress; (3) review the gasoline supply annually to ensure the reserves in the Gasoline Reserve do not exceed their shelf life; and (4) have in place a plan for assuring that the inventory is sold and replaced in a manner that assures the integrity of the product at all times. Directs the Secretary of Energy to sell gasoline from the Gasoline Reserve if the governor of an affected state submits a written request and the President issues an Executive order requiring immediate release from any or all Gasoline Reserves at any time that the President determines certain emergency conditions are satisfied.</summary>
</bill>
