<bill session="111" type="h" number="6049" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Visitor Center Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with Kiowa County, Colorado, to restore the Murdock Building in Eads, Colorado, for use as the visitor center for the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412298"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Visitor Center Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement with Kiowa County, Colorado: (1) to assist in the renovation of the Murdock Building in Eads, Colorado; (2) for use of a part of the Murdock Building by the National Park Service (NPS) as the visitor center and administrative offices for the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site (the Park); and (3) to provide up to $650,000 to Kiowa County toward the cost of renovations and furnishing of the Murdock Building. Sets forth a federal matching requirement. Requires the use of such federal funds for making improvements to, and installing furnishings within, those parts of the Murdock Building used by the Park. Prohibits the use of such funds to pay for personnel or other costs associated with the operation of the Murdock Building as a park visitor center.</summary>
</bill>
