<bill session="110" type="s" number="3464" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Intellectual Property Protection and Enforcement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to improve the international protection and enforcement of intellectual property rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2008-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2008--Introduced.
International Intellectual Property Protection and Enforcement Act of 2008 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the United States Trade Representative (USTR), within 90 days after submitting the annual National Trade Estimate, to develop an action plan for foreign countries that have spent at least one year on the priority watch list that calls for such countries to meet benchmarks designed to assist them to achieve: (1) effective protection of intellectual property rights; and (2) equitable market access for U.S. persons that rely upon intellectual property protection. Authorizes the President to impose certain economic sanctions on foreign countries that do not substantially comply with the benchmarks of an action plan. Directs the President to ensure that an intellectual property attach&#233; with the title of Minister-Counselor is placed in the U.S. embassy of each foreign country that has a commercially significant relationship with the United States.</summary>
</bill>
