<bill session="109" type="h" number="3970" updated="2013-07-19T19:39:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bioterror and Pandemic Preparedness Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide liability protections for certain pandemics and countermeasures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2005-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1437"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Introduced.
Bioterror and Pandemic Preparedness Protection Act - Amends the federal judicial code to establish an exclusive federal cause of action for all claims relating to a qualified pandemic or epidemic product or a security countermeasure. Restricts all causes of action for such claims against a manufacturer, distributor, or health care provider and instead provides for sole and exclusive action against the United States. Gives jurisdiction over such an action to the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia. Establishes a rebuttable presumption of immunity for the federal government in any such action concerning: (1) a security countermeasure that has been procured for or donated to the National Strategic Stockpile; (2) a qualified pandemic or epidemic product that has been procured by or donated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services; or (3) a designated security countermeasure or qualified pandemic or epidemic product in an actual or potential public health emergency. Allows a party to petition the Attorney General to investigate claims against a manufacturer, distributor, administrator, or heath care provider. Disallows judicial review of the Attorney General's decision as to whether to undertake such an investigation. Declares that the immunity presumption shall be overcome by a determination by the Attorney General, by finding clear and convincing evidence, that the manufacturer, distributor, administrator, or health care provider intentionally or with willful disregard violated the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or the Public Health Service Act and that such violation: (1) caused the product to present a significant or unreasonable human health risk; and (2) proximately caused the injury alleged by the party.</summary>
</bill>
