<bill session="112" type="h" number="6690" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the Secretary of the Air Force from retiring or transferring certain aircraft of the Air National Guard or Air Force Reserve.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2012-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2012--Introduced.
Bars the Secretary of the Air Force from divesting, retiring, or transferring to any Air Force aircraft assigned to units of the Air National Guard or Air Force Reserve as of December 31, 2012, until Congress receives: (1) the reports required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 concerning an analysis of the costs of deployable units of the active components and the reserve components of the Armed Forces, and (2) the report of the National Commission on the Structure of the Air Force required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 concerning a comprehensive study on the structure of the Air Force. Allows the divestment or retirement of C-5A aircraft if such aircraft is replaced through a transfer of C-5B, C-5M, or C-17 mobility aircraft in order to maintain all Guard and Reserve units at current or higher assigned manpower levels to operate the aircraft so transferred.</summary>
</bill>
