<bill session="111" type="h" number="3728" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Detainment Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make certain improvements in the laws applicable to the detention of individuals at United States detainment facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2450-2451"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2009--Introduced.
Detainment Reform Act of 2009 - Directs the President, with respect to non-U.S. individuals taken into custody, to make a specific determination whether the individual poses a danger to U.S. security and interests based on specified criteria, including whether the individual is an agent of a foreign power against which the use of military force was authorized under the Authorization for Use of Military Force. Allows the U.S. to detain, for up to 14 days, an individual determined to pose such a danger. Requires the U.S., after such period, to initiate detention proceedings provided under this Act or other legal authority, release the individual, transfer the individual to a foreign government, or transfer the individual to an international tribunal with appropriate jurisdiction. Outlines procedures for detention proceedings, requiring a determination that the individual is an imperative threat to security, with the burden of proof upon the U.S. by a preponderance of the evidence. Requires the protection of national security information during such proceedings. Requires: (1) the head of any military or federal department or agency that has custody or control of a detainee, upon such detention, to notify the International Committee of the Red Cross of such custody or control; (2) Red Cross access to such detainees; and (3) a report on conditions of detainees and detainee facilities. Provides for the disposition of detainees entitled to the right of habeas corpus review, requiring each such detainee to be: (1) charged with an offense and transferred to a detention facility for further legal proceedings; (2) transferred to an international tribunal with appropriate jurisdiction; (3) transferred to the custody of the individual's country of citizenship or a different country, provided the transfer is consistent specified conditions; or (4) held in detention after being determined an imperative threat to security. Expresses the sense of Congress concerning the investigation, prosecution, and treatment of individuals and organizations suspected of involvement with international terrorism. Requires detainees to be held in accordance with conditions of confinement guaranteed by Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions. Requires a report identifying those nations, persons, or organizations considered to be forces covered by the Authorization for the Use of Military Force (P.L. 107-40) as having planned, committed, or aided the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, or as having harbored such persons or organizations as co-belligerents.</summary>
</bill>
