<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1766" updated="2013-07-19T23:11:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-16T19:25:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-16T19:25:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R.4853) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the funding and expenditure authority of the airport and Airway Trust Fund, to amend title 49, United States Code, to extend authorizations for the airport improvement program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-15T20:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-682, by Ms. Slaughter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-15T20:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Makes in order a motion offered by the chair of the Committee on Ways and Means that the House concur in the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 4853 with the amendment printed in the report from the Committee on Rules. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the motion except those arising under clause 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-15T20:10:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="254">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 254.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Slaughter called up the resolution, H.Res. 1766, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T10:29:00-05:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER AGAINST CONSIDERATION - Mr. Flake stated that the provisions of H.Res. 1766 violate section 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 and made a point of order against the consideration of the resolution. Subsequently, the Chair noted that the required threshold of identifying the specific language in question had been met, and the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the question of consideration. At the conclusion of debate on the question of consideration, the Chair will put the question to wit: Will the House now consider the resolution?</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T10:41:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Flake point of order, the Chair put the question on consideration of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T10:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1766.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T12:18:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H. Res. 1766.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T12:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H. Res. 1766.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T12:40:00-05:00">
      <text>WITHDRAWAL OF RESOLUTION - Mr. McGovern withdrew the resolution from consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T17:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8524-8532, H8545-8551" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T17:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1766.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-12-16T19:25:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="644" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 214 - 201 (Roll no. 644).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8524-8525" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16T19:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="4853"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h785"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/15/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 4853) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the funding and expenditure authority of the airport and Airway Trust Fund, to amend title 49, United States Code, to extend authorizations for the airport improvement program.</summary>
</bill>
