<bill session="112" type="h" number="2465" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-29T17:03:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-29T17:03:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Workers' Compensation Modernization and Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Workers' Compensation Modernization and Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Employees' Compensation Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400224"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Walberg moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7908-7916" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2465.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-11-29T17:03:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7908-7909" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T17:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/29/2011--Passed House amended.
Federal Workers' Compensation Modernization and Improvement Act - Modifies the definition of "medical, surgical, and hospital services and supplies" under the Federal Employees' Compensation Act (FECA) to include physician assistants and advanced practice nurses and to provide for the reimbursement for services provided by such assistants and nurses. Permits such assistants and nurses to certify disability due to traumatic injury during a continuation of pay period. Extends eligibility for compensation under FECA for disability or death resulting from an attack by a terrorist or terrorist organization. Allows additional FECA benefits, up to $50,000, for workers who sustain an injury that results in a serious disfigurement of the face, head, or neck. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to require, as a condition of receiving compensation under FECA, a claimant to consent to the release by the Social Security Administration (SSA) of such claimant's social security earnings information. Provides for the continuation of pay, for up to 135 days, of an employee who has filed a claim for wage loss due to a traumatic injury in a zone of armed conflict. Requires a claim for wage loss to be filed not later than 45 days following termination of assignment to the zone of armed conflict or return to the United States, whichever occurs later. Grants a right of subrogation to the United States for the continuation of pay of a federal employee. Allows payment of up to $6,000 of funeral and burial expenses for deaths of federal employees that result from an injury sustained in the performance of duty. Allows payment of administrative expenses from the Employees' Compensation Fund. Provides for compliance of the budgetary effects of this Act with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
