<bill session="111" type="h" number="1690" updated="2013-07-19T23:26:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coastal State Renewable Energy Promotion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to coastal states to support voluntary State efforts to initiate and complete surveys of coastal waters to identify potential areas suitable for the exploration, development, and production of renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2009--Introduced.
Coastal State Renewable Energy Promotion Act - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize grants to eligible coastal states to support voluntary state efforts to initiate and complete surveys of portions of coastal state waters and federal waters adjacent to a state's coastal zone to identify potential areas suitable or unsuitable for the exploration, development, and production of renewable (wind, wave, current, tidal, or ocean thermal) energy that are consistent with the enforceable policies of coastal management plans. Requires that survey results be made available to the public. Requires suitable areas to be given priority consideration by federal agencies for the siting, licensing, leasing, or permitting of renewable energy facilities.</summary>
</bill>
