<bill session="111" type="h" number="6430" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve educational assistance for veterans who served in the Armed Forces after September 11, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5933"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3447"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Improvement Act of 2010 - Revises provisions concerning the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) post-9/11 veterans' educational assistance program to, among other things: (1) revise definitions concerning eligibility, and include certain National Guard service as service qualifying for such assistance; (2) revise assistance amounts (including monthly stipends), and types of approved programs of education; (3) allow the pursuit of educational programs at institutions other than institutions of higher learning, including on-job training and apprenticeships, flight training, and correspondence courses; (4) provide an assistance amount for programs of education pursued while on active duty; (5) provide an annual effective date for stipend rates; (6) repeal the limit on the use of such assistance for the payment of only one licensing or certification test; (7) allow the use of educational assistance for the payment of national admission tests and tests for determining course credit; (8) bar the duplication of benefits under certain VA educational assistance programs; (9) bar the concurrent receipt of educational assistance benefits transferred to children; (10) allow the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make certain subsistence allowance payments to enrolled veterans when an institution is temporarily closed; (11) increase the amount of the reporting fee paid by the Secretary to an institution for providing information concerning an individual's enrollment in a program of education; (12) limit assistance benefits to individuals who enlisted or reenlisted before October 1, 2012; and (13) revise cost-of-living adjustments under the Montgomery GI Bill educational assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
