<bill session="109" type="h" number="6022" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower PRICED Drugs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower Prices Reduced with Increased Competition and Efficient Development of Drugs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to market exclusivity for certain drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2006-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2300"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Generic drugs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Lower Prices Reduced with Increased Competition and Efficient Development of Drugs Act or the Lower PRICED Drugs Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require an abbreviated application for a new drug containing certain antibiotics, the approved labeling for which includes a method of use that is claimed by a patent, to include a statement: (1) that identifies the relevant patent and the approved use covered by the patent; and (2) that the applicant is not seeking approval of such use. Requires the court to consider the totality of circumstances and the public interest in deciding whether to shorten the 30-month period that delays the approval of an abbreviated drug application when a patent infringement case is filed against the applicant. Limits market exclusivity provided for conducting pediatric studies of new or already approved drugs to only those drugs for which the Secretary of Health and Human Services approves labeling that provides specific, therapeutically meaningful information about the use of the drug in pediatric patients. Sets forth provisions governing petitions seeking any action relating to the approval of certain new drug or abbreviated new drug applications, including the delay of such approval. Allows the Secretary to approve a petition to delay approval only when necessary to protect the public health. Requires the Secretary to take final agency action on a petition within 180 days of receipt, with no extensions allowed. Extends the 30-month period that the Secretary has to approve or disapprove an abbreviated application for a new drug by the amount of time that lapses from the date the Secretary receives a petition and the date of the final agency action on the petition, without regard to whether the Secretary grants or denies the petition.</summary>
</bill>
