<bill session="111" type="h" number="2595" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restrict certain exports of electronic waste.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to: (1) prohibit the export of restricted electronic waste to countries that are not members of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development or the European Union, or Liechtenstein; (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), annually, to identify countries that permit trade in used electronic equipment and parts; and (3) impose criminal penalties for knowingly exporting restricted electronic waste in violation of this Act. Allows certain exceptions to such export ban. Defines "restricted electronic waste" to include electronic equipment, such as computers, televisions, printers, copiers, video players, and similar used electronic products, that contain circuit boards and other parts containing mercury or polychlorinated biphenyls, antimony, beryllium, cadmium, chromium, or lead and cathode ray tubes and batteries containing lead and other toxic ingredients.</summary>
</bill>
