<bill session="110" type="h" number="2968" updated="2013-07-19T21:29:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Summer Food Service Rural Expansion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to make permanent the summer food service pilot project for rural areas of Pennsylvania and apply it to rural areas of every State.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400321"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1755"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2007--Introduced.
Summer Food Service Rural Expansion Act - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act with respect to the summer food service programs for children in service institutions (e.g., schools and summer camps). Revises the condition limiting eligibility to institutions conducting a regularly scheduled food service for children from areas in which poor economic conditions exist (i.e., where at least 50% of the children meet eligibility requirements for certain free or reduced price school meals.) Eliminates the special 2005 and 2006 exemption from this requirement for rural areas in Pennsylvania which lowers the threshold eligibility to areas where at least 40% of the children meet eligibility requirements for free or reduced price school meals. Applies such 40% threshold to rural areas of all states and makes it permanent.</summary>
</bill>
