<bill session="112" type="h" number="4008" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cavernous Angioma CARE Center Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Cavernous Angioma CARE Center (Clinical Care, Awareness, Research and Education) of Excellence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2012-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="2082"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2012--Introduced.
Cavernous Angioma CARE Center Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Cavernous Angioma Clinical Care, Awareness, Research, and Education Center of Excellence at a university health sciences research and clinical center in the southwest United States to: (1) provide basic, translational, and clinical research with respect to new diagnostic, prevention, and novel treatment methodology for individuals with cavernous angioma; and (2) serve as a model for, and provide support to, medical schools and research institutions. Requires the Director of the Center to: (1) ensure that the Center provides community-, family-, and patient-centered culturally sensitive care; (2) encourage and coordinate opportunities for individuals to participate in clinical research studies that will advance medical research and care; and (3) develop the Center as a model and training facility for other facilities throughout the United States that are engaged in research regarding, and care for individuals with, cavernous angioma.</summary>
</bill>
