<bill session="112" type="h" number="1940" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure compliance with the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction by countries with which the United States enjoys reciprocal obligations, to establish procedures for the prompt return of children abducted to other countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2011-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412415" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2011-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2011-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Financial Services, the Judiciary, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA20" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO30" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2011--Introduced.
International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2011 - Establishes within the Department of State an Office on International Child Abductions which shall be headed by the Ambassador at Large for International Child Abductions. States that Ambassador at Large shall be a principal adviser to the President and the Secretary of State regarding matters of international child abduction and refusals of rights of access. Authorizes the Ambassador at Large to represent the United States in such diplomatic matters and international forums. States that the primary responsibilities of the Ambassador at Large shall be to: (1) promote measures to prevent the international abduction of children from the United States, (2) advocate on behalf of abducted children whose habitual residence is the United States, (3) assist left-behind parents in the resolution of abduction or refusal of access cases, and (4) advance mechanisms to prevent and resolve cases of international child abduction. Directs the President to: (1) annually review the status of unresolved cases in each foreign country to determine whether the government has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation, and if so, designate such country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation; (2) notify the appropriate congressional committees of such designation; and (3) take specified presidential or commensurate actions to bring about a cessation of noncooperation. Sets forth consultation, notification, and reporting requirements for the President and the Secretary. Prohibits judicial review of any presidential determination or agency action under this Act. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and the International Financial Institutions Act to require the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the President, respectively, in determining whether a country engages in a pattern of gross human right violations for purposes of assistance considerations, to consider whether such country has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation regarding unresolved cases of international child abduction or denial of rights of access, or has failed to undertake serious efforts to locate children abducted to such country. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to consider for tariff preference purposes whether a country has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation regarding unresolved cases of international child abduction or denial of rights of access. Amends the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 to require, for issuance of a passport for a child under 14 years old living outside the United States, that the person executing the passport application provides documentary evidence that such person is a U.S. citizen, has joint custody over the child, and is executing such application outside the United States.</summary>
</bill>
