<bill session="109" type="h" number="3865" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Malpractice Insurance Corporation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of medical malpractice insurance corporations which may operate and function without hindrance or impedance in any or all of the States, to limit frivolous medical malpractice lawsuits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2005--Introduced.
Medical Malpractice Insurance Corporation Act - Authorizes the establishment of corporations to provide medical malpractice insurance to health care professionals and providers based on customary coverage terms and liability amounts. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to certify corporations as medical malpractice insurance corporations if they meet the requirements of this Act, which include that excess earnings of such corporations are used to reduce premiums paid by the insured. Allows such corporations to operate and function without hindrance or impedance in all states. Prohibits any medical malpractice liability action from being brought against a health care professional or provider without an affidavit from a qualified specialist or medical expert that there is a reasonable and meritorious cause for filing the action. Requires the Secretary to establish medical malpractice arbitration panels to hear and render decisions on all medical malpractice claims. Mandates participation in such panels. Allows participants dissatisfied with the results to bring a federal civil action. Requires the Attorney General to proscribe regulations to ensure that such arbitration: (1) is affordable; (2) encourages timely resolution of medical malpractice claims; (3) encourages the consistent and fair resolution of such claims; and (4) provides for reasonable convenient access to dispute resolution.</summary>
</bill>
