<bill session="111" type="h" number="1334" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Living Wage Responsibility Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for livable wages for Federal Government workers and workers hired under Federal contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E580"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2009--Introduced.
Federal Living Wage Responsibility Act - Requires the federal government and any employer under a federal contract or subcontract exceeding $10,000 to pay each of their respective workers: (1) an hourly wage (or salary equivalent) necessary for such employee to earn, while working 40 hours a week on a full-time basis, not less than the amount of the federal poverty level for a family of four; and (2) an additional amount, based on the locality in which a worker resides, sufficient to cover the costs to such worker to obtain specified fringe benefits not provided by the worker's employer. Exempts employers that are: (1) small business concerns; or (2) nonprofit, tax-exempt organizations, if the ratio of the total compensation of the chief executive officer to that of the full-time equivalent of their lowest-paid employee is not greater than 25 to 1. Directs the Secretary of Labor to enforce this Act. Makes federal contractors that are part of a pattern or practice of violations of such wage requirements subject to federal contract suspension, a five-year ineligibility period, and liability for government costs of obtaining a replacement contractor. Provides for judicial review of the Secretary's determinations, and authorizes the President to suspend the provisions of this Act in times of emergency. Allows an aggrieved worker to bring a civil action against an employer for appropriate relief for a violation of this Act, if the employer has not paid or reinstated the worker as a result of the administrative action.</summary>
</bill>
