<bill session="111" type="s" number="3816" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Creating American Jobs and Ending Offshoring Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create American jobs and to prevent the offshoring of such jobs overseas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2010-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2010-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2010-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2010-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7278-7279" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="578">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 578.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-24">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7438" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-24">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the bill presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7438" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7438" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-24">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7438" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7461-7498" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7580-7585" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action state="PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the bill not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 45. Record Vote Number: 242.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7584-7585" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7584" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4659"/>
    <amendment number="s4660"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/21/2010--Introduced.
Creating American Jobs and Ending Offshoring Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) exempt from employment taxes for a 24-month period employers who hire a employee who replaces another employee who is not a citizen or permanent resident of the United States and who performs similar duties overseas; (2) deny any tax deduction, deduction for loss, or tax credit for the cost of an American jobs offshoring transaction (defined as any transaction in which a taxpayer reduces or eliminates the operation of a trade or business in connection with the start-up or expansion of such trade or business outside the United States); and (3) eliminate the deferral of tax on income of a controlled foreign corporation attributable to property imported into the United States by such corporation or a related person, except for property exported before substantial use in the United States and for agricultural commodities not grown in the United States in commercially marketable quantities.</summary>
</bill>
