<bill session="111" type="h" number="3896" updated="2013-07-19T23:47:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Health Clinic Patient Access and Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to health care for individuals residing in underserved rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1355"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2009--Introduced.
Rural Health Clinic Patient Access and Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to rural health clinic reimbursement. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make incentive payments to rural health clinic employees or contractors for satisfactory reporting of data on clinic quality measures. Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow a community health center to contract with a federally certified rural health clinic for the delivery of primary health care services to individuals who would otherwise be eligible for free or reduced cost care if they were able to obtain it at the community health center. Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the diabetes education and medical nutrition therapy counseling services provided by federally qualified health clinics. Directs the Secretary to establish a demonstration project of grants to states to examine whether health care professionals can be recruited or retained to work in underserved rural areas by providing them with medical malpractice subsidies. States that a rural health clinic qualified under Medicare or Medicaid may be defined and certified by the Secretary as rural even if it fails to satisfy the requirement that it not be located in an urbanized area. Amends SSA title XVIII to establish the minimum Medicare Advantage plan payment rate for services furnished by a rural health clinic. Expresses the sense of the Senate concerning the adequacy of network-based health plans.</summary>
</bill>
