<bill session="112" type="s" number="1211" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preservation of Antibiotics for Medical Treatment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to preserve the effectiveness of medically important antibiotics used in the treatment of human and animal diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3837-3839"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3839-3841" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="965"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2011--Introduced.
Preservation of Antibiotics for Medical Treatment Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to deny an application for a new animal drug that is a critical antimicrobial animal drug unless the applicant demonstrates that there is a reasonably certainty of no harm to human health due to the development of antimicrobial resistance attributable to the nontherapeutic use of the drug. Defines "critical antimicrobial animal drug" as a drug intended for use in food-producing animals that contains specified antibiotics or other drugs used in humans to treat or prevent disease or infection caused by microorganisms. Requires the Secretary to withdraw approval of a nontherapeutic use of such drugs in food-producing animals two years after the date of enactment of this Act unless certain safety requirements are met. Directs specified congressional committees to hold hearings on the implementation of such a withdrawal of approval.</summary>
</bill>
