<bill session="109" type="s" number="794" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe and Complete Streets Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to improve the safety of nonmotorized transportation, including bicycle and pedestrian safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3664"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Bikeways"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Walking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
Safe and Complete Streets Act of 2005 - Amends Federal highway law to require each State transportation department to adopt a policy statement ensuring that the needs and safety of all road users (including the need for pedestrian and bicycle safety) are fully integrated into the planning, design, operation, and maintenance of the State's transportation system. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to take necessary actions to double the percentage of trips made by foot or bicycle while simultaneously reducing crashes involving bicyclists and pedestrians by ten percent. Requires the Secretary to allocate certain funds for research that directly benefits the planning, design, operation, and maintenance of the transportation system for nonmotorized users. Requires metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs) to certify, as part of the certification review of their bicycle and pedestrian programs, that the needs of bicyclists and pedestrians (including people who use wheelchairs and people with impaired vision) have been adequately addressed by their respective long-range transportation plans, including a target level that doubles the percentage of trips made by foot and bicycle. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) a safe routes to school program for the benefit of children in primary and middle schools; and (2) a task force to study and develop a strategy for advancing such programs nationwide. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a nonmotorized transportation pilot program to construct, in four communities, a network of nonmotorized transportation infrastructure facilities (including sidewalks, bicycle lanes, and pedestrian and bicycle trails) that connect directly with transit stations, schools, residences, businesses, recreation areas, and other community activity centers; and (2) develop specified statistical information on changes in motor vehicle, nonmotorized, and public transportation usage in those communities, and assess how such changes decrease congestion and energy usage, increase the frequency of biking and walking, and promote better health and a cleaner environment.</summary>
</bill>
