<bill session="111" type="s" number="3387" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the release of water from the marketable yield pool of water stored in the Ruedi Reservoir for the benefit of endangered fish habitat in the Colorado River, and for other purpose.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-707.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5362"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1601"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2010--Introduced.
Requires the release of 5,412.5 acre-feet of water from the marketable yield pool (the portion of the regulatory capacity that is dedicated to marketing purposes) of water stored in the Ruedi Reservoir (a component of the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project of the Bureau of Reclamation in western Colorado) for the benefit of endangered fish habitat in the Colorado River for calendar year 2013 and each year thereafter, at the request of the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. Requires such release during the late summer months to enhance low water flows in areas that comprise the endangered fish habitat in the Colorado River, unless otherwise requested by the Director. Provides that the release shall satisfy 50% of the commitment by certain water users to provide 10,825 acre-feet of water per year, as described in Appendix C of the document entitled "Final Programmatic Biological Opinion for Bureau of Reclamation's Operations and Depletions, Other Depletions, and Funding and Implementation of Recovery Program Actions in the Upper Colorado River above the Confluence with the Gunnison River."Makes this Act effective on the later of the date on which: (1) the Secretary of the Interior issues a finding of no significant impact, or a record of decision under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 regarding such release; and (2) an additional 5,412.5 acre-feet of water has been made available by means acceptable to water users to satisfy the remaining obligations of such users.</summary>
</bill>
