<bill session="112" type="h" number="3910" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Expansion Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to expand the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2012-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2012--Introduced.
Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Expansion Act of 2012 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of: (1) recycled water system facilities in California in cooperation with the Central Contra Costa Sanitary District, the Dublin San Ramon Services District, the Delta Diablo Sanitation District, the cities of Redwood City, Palo Alto, Hayward, Mountain View, and Pleasanton, the San Jose Water Company, and the Town of Yountville; and (2) recycled water distribution systems in California in cooperation with the Ironhouse Sanitary District. Limits the federal share of each project to 25%. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds for project operation and maintenance. Directs the Secretary to enter into individual agreements with the San Francisco Bay Area Regional Water Coalition participating agencies to fund projects under such Act. Allows the Secretary to include in such agreements a provision for the reimbursement of construction costs, including those construction costs incurred prior to this Act's enactment. Increases the authorization of appropriations for the design, planning, and construction of: (1) recycled water system facilities in cooperation with the city of Antioch, California; and (2) recycled water treatment facilities in cooperation with the city of San Jose, California, and the Santa Clara Valley Water District.</summary>
</bill>
