<bill session="112" type="h" number="3980" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Opportunity Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act with respect to procurement center representatives and acquisition planning, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412423" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2012-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2012-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 112-722.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-21T15:51:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="525">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 525.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2012--Introduced.
Small Business Opportunity Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to replace the position of breakout procurement representative within the Small Business Administration (SBA) with the position of procurement center representative. Requires such representatives to, among other things, review any acquisition plan with respect to a procurement requirement, and make recommendations regarding procurement method determinations and acquisition plans. Removes the requirement that such representatives review restrictions on competition, instead requiring them to review barriers to small business participation in federal contracting, as well as any bundled or consolidated solicitation or contract. Requires such representatives to: (1) have electronic access to any acquisition plan developed or in development with respect to a procurement activity, (2) be an advocate for the maximum practicable utilization of small businesses in federal contracting, and (3) be notified of and included in all applicable acquisition planning processes. Directs the Defense Acquisition University and the Federal Acquisition Institute to each provide a course on contracting requirements under the Small Business Act. Requires each federal department or agency having contracting authority to: (1) enumerate opportunities for participation by small businesses during all acquisition planning processes and in all acquisition plans, and (2) invite the participation of the appropriate Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and procurement representative in such planning processes and provide Director and representative access to all acquisition plans in development.</summary>
</bill>
