<bill session="112" type="s" number="1904" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Welfare Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Welfare Reform Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide information on total spending on means-tested welfare programs, to provide additional work requirements, and to provide an overall spending limit on means-tested welfare programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2012-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1135"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Welfare Reform Act of 2011 - Welfare Reform Restoration Act - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to revise the TANF program by: (1) eliminating the temporary modification of the caseload reduction credit, and (2) reducing funding of state family assistance grants. Restores the former name of the Food Stamp Act of 1977, and restores its text as if the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 had not been enacted; and (2) renames the supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits as the food stamp program. Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to revise work requirements for the food stamp program and require able-bodied work eligible adult members of a family unit to participate in a work activation program during a full month of participation in the food stamp program, fulfilling specified levels of work activity during that month. (Work activation means, not employment, but supervised job search, community service activities, education and job training, workfare, or drug and alcohol treatment.) Specifies a financial reward for any state that reduces its food stamp caseload below calendar 2006 levels. Declares that a food, food product, meal, or other specified item shall be considered a food under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 only if it is a bare essential. Requires the President to include means-tested welfare spending in every budget submission. Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 and the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to define and establish an aggregate cap for means-tested welfare spending. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide grants to states to reward reductions in poverty and government dependence and increases in self-sufficiency. Prohibits the expenditure for abortions, with certain exceptions, of any funds authorized or appropriated by federal law, and funds in any trust fund to which funds are authorized or appropriated by federal law. Prohibits funding for health benefits plans that cover abortion. Prohibits the allowance of any tax credit with respect to amounts paid or incurred for an abortion or with respect to amounts paid or incurred for a health benefits plan (including premium assistance) that includes coverage of abortion.</summary>
</bill>
