<bill session="110" type="s" number="2910" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TRUCC Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trust in Reliable Understanding of Consumer Costs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require brokers to disclose and pay independent truckers for any fuel surcharges received from shippers that relate to fuel costs paid for by the truckers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3404-3405"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5934"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5977"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Transportation rates"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2008--Introduced.
Trust in Reliable Understanding of Consumer Costs Act, or the TRUCC Act - Amends federal transportation law to require certain fuel costs disclosures and fuel costs reimbursements by a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder providing or arranging truckload transportation or service using fuel for which it does not bear the cost. Requires such a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder to: (1) reimburse persons (truckers) that do bear fuel costs for any such costs they have paid; and (2) give such persons a written list that identifies any freight charge, brokerage fee or commission, fuel surcharge or adjustment, and any other charges. Prohibits any person from causing a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder to present false or misleading information on a document or in an oral representation about the actual rate, charge, or allowance to any party to the transaction or transportation.</summary>
</bill>
