<bill session="112" type="s" number="1331" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Virginia Outer Continental Shelf Energy Production Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the inclusion of Lease Sale 220 in the outer Continental Shelf leasing program for fiscal years 2012-2017, to revise the map for the Mid-Atlantic planning area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2011-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/6/2011--Introduced.
Virginia Outer Continental Shelf Energy Production Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to include within the schedule of proposed lease sales in the outer Continental Shelf leasing program for FY2012-FY2017 Lease Sale 220 and any areas off the coast of Virginia included in the Mid-Atlantic planning area as a result of a revision to a specified map under this Act. Requires the Secretary to provide that the Secretary shall not make any tract available for lease within such schedule if the President determines that its lease would conflict with military operations relating to national security. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to deposit: (1) 50% of qualified revenues in the general fund of the Treasury, and (2) 50% in a special account for disbursement to Virginia and for designated state activities. Directs the Secretary to revise a certain Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Regulation and Enforcement map to ensure that the square footage of the leasable area in the Mid-Atlantic planning area is directly proportional to the length of the tidal shoreline of the Mid-Atlantic States.</summary>
</bill>
