<bill session="111" type="h" number="6224" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Cancer ALERT (Access to Life-Saving Early detection, Research and Treatment) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modernize cancer research, increase access to preventative cancer services, provide cancer treatment and survivorship initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Introduced.
21st Century Cancer ALERT (Access to Life-Saving Early detection, Research and Treatment) Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions related to the National Cancer Program, including to require the establishment of an entity within the National Cancer Institute (NCI) to augment ongoing efforts to advance new technologies in cancer research, support the national collection of tissues for cancer research purposes, and ensure the quality of tissue collection. Sets forth provisions governing clinical trials, including ethical and privacy standards. Requires the Director of NCI to award grants for research on cancers with a low five-year survival rate and rare cancers. Expands coverage of colorectal screenings and treatment, including through authorizing grants and allowing states to provide coverage under Medicaid for individuals needing treatment for colorectal cancer. Provides for biomarkers research. Expands coverage of tobacco cessation products under Medicaid. Provides for coverage under Medicare for payment of routine costs of care furnished to individuals participating in cancer clinical trials, comprehensive cancer planning services, and comprehensive cancer patient treatment education services. Requires the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to review and improve the policies, programs and activities of the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) relating to oncology products. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to expand and intensify CDC's cancer control programs. Provides for research on cancer survivorship related to childhood cancer and health disparities in outcomes. Requires the Secretary to convene a Workforce Development Collaborative on Psychosocial Care During Chronic Medical Illness.</summary>
</bill>
