<bill session="110" type="s" number="363" updated="2013-07-19T22:23:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HOPE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hope Offered through Principled, Ethically-Sound Stem Cell Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide increased Federal funding for stem cell research, to expand the number of embryonic stem cell lines available for Federally funded research, to provide ethical guidelines for stem cell research, to derive human pluripotent stem cell lines using techniques that do not create an embryo or embryos for research or knowingly harm human embryo or embryos, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hereditary diseases"/>
    <term name="Human embryology"/>
    <term name="In vitro fertilization"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2007--Introduced.
Hope Offered through Principled, Ethically-Sound Stem Cell Research Act or the HOPE Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct and support research to develop techniques for the isolation, derivation, production, or testing of pluripotent stem cells that have the flexibility of embryonic stem cells and that may result in improved understanding of, or treatments for, diseases and other adverse health conditions, provided that such techniques do not involve: (1) the creation of a viable human embryo for research purposes; (2) the destruction or discarding of a human embryo; or (3) knowingly subjecting a human embryo to risk of injury or death greater than that allowed on fetuses in utero. Establishes the National Stem Cell Research Review Board to: (1) monitor research to ensure that it is in compliance with this Act; (2) prioritize research with the greatest potential for near term benefits; and (3) ensure fair consideration of both embryonic and adult stem cell research for funding. Sets forth consent requirements for the donation of materials for research. Applies federal provisions protecting individually identifiable health information to donors. Amends the National Organ Transplant Act to prohibit the transfer of any human ovum, human blastocyst, human embryo, or stem cell derived from a human embryo for valuable consideration. Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit any person from knowingly receiving any valuable consideration for any therapy that: (1) affects interstate commerce or is funded by federal assistance; and (2) utilizes cells from a human embryo if the process of deriving such cells destroyed the embryo.</summary>
</bill>
