<bill session="112" type="s" number="2114" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Berry Amendment Extension Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the Department of Homeland Security from procuring certain items directly related to the national security unless the items are grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="679"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2012--Introduced.
Berry Amendment Extension Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to prohibit the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from procuring specified covered items directly related to national security interests (including such items as clothing, footwear, tents, protective equipment, sleep systems, or natural fiber products) that are not grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States, except to the extent satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity of any such product cannot be procured as and when needed or in a time period that meets U.S. national security needs. Makes this provision inapplicable to covered items that are or that include non-available articles. Allows the Secretary to accept delivery of covered items that contain non-compliant fibers if the total value of non-compliant fibers contained in the end item does not exceed 10% of its total purchase price. Makes additional exceptions for: (1) procurements by vessels in foreign waters, (2) emergency procurements, and (3) purchases for amounts not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold. Requires the Secretary to post a notification on the Internet website maintained by the General Services Administration (GSA) known as FedBizOpps and to notify specified congressional committees that an exception has been applied not later than seven days after the award of the contract. Directs the Secretary to ensure that: (1) each member of DHS's acquisition workforce who regularly participates in textile acquisition receives training on this Act's requirements, and (2) any such training includes comprehensive information on such requirements. Requires this Act to be applied in a manner consistent with U.S. obligations under international agreements.</summary>
</bill>
