<bill session="112" type="h" number="4262" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cosmetics Safety Enhancement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the safety of cosmetics.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2012-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2012--Introduced.
Cosmetics Safety Enhancement Act of 2012 - Amends the the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the registration of cosmetic products and cosmetic manufacturing facilities, including, for each product: (1) a unique facility identifier, (2) every product's brand name, and (3) product ingredients. Sets registration fees. Requires a cosmetic manufacturer: (1) before the introduction into interstate commerce of a cosmetic product, to establish a file containing scientific evidence substantiating the product's safety; (2) to report any serious adverse event information received that is associated with the use of a cosmetic product; and (3) maintain records concerning any cosmetic product that may be adulterated, misbranded, or otherwise in violation of the Act, including all records relating to cosmetic product safety substantiation or relating to serious adverse event reports. Deems a cosmetic product adulterated if its manufacture, packing, or holding do not conform to current good manufacturing practice regulations. Provides each manufacturer with an opportunity to cease distribution and recall of a cosmetic product if it is determined that there is a reasonable probability that the product is adulterated and the use of, or exposure to, such product will cause serious adverse health consequences or death to humans. Permits the issuance of an order requiring a recall if there is not a voluntary recall of an adulterated product.</summary>
</bill>
