<bill session="112" type="h" number="3682" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Centered Healthcare Savings Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and provide for comprehensive health reform, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2012-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and the Workforce, the Judiciary, Natural Resources, House Administration, Rules, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="299"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="346"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="371"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1050"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2010"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6299"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1098"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2011--Introduced.
Patient Centered Healthcare Savings Act of 2011 - Repeals the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) and the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, effective as of their enactment. Restores or revives provisions amended or repealed by such Act or such health care provisions. Sets conditions for lawsuits arising from health care liability claims regarding health care goods or services or any medical product affecting interstate commerce. Establishes a statute of limitations and limits noneconomic and punitive damages. Directs that the laws of the state designated by a health insurance issuer (primary state) shall apply to individual health insurance coverage offered by that issuer in the primary state and in any other state (secondary state), but only if the coverage and issuer comply with conditions of this Act. Revises provisions regarding the sharing of Medicare claims data for the purposes of analyzing cost and quality and improving transparency in the marketplace. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise provisions related to health savings accounts (HSAs), including to expand eligibility for HSAs to Medicare Part A beneficiaries, veterans eligible for service-connected disability benefits, individuals eligible for Indian health service assistance, and individuals eligible to receive benefits under certain TRICARE plans. Amends the bankruptcy code to treat HSAs as tax-exempt individual retirement accounts (IRAs) for purposes of exempting them from creditor claims. Reauthorizes the use of Medicaid health opportunity accounts. Requires each state to mitigate the cost of high risk individuals in the state through a state reinsurance program or a state high risk pool. Removes the prohibition on preexisting condition exclusions in the individual health insurance market. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to pay awards to states for reducing the premiums in the small group market or the individual market or for reducing the percentage of uninsured, nonelderly residents in a state. Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans, which are group health plans whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations and which meet certain ERISA certification requirements. Amends ERISA, the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to require group health plans that provide dependent coverage of children to treat an individual as a dependent until at least 23 years (currently, 26 years) of age. Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to increase civil money penalties, criminal fines, and prison sentences for fraud and abuse under the Medicare program. Exempts certain provisions from the repeal of PPACA under this Act, including provisions relating to physician-owned hospitals and background checks of employees of long-term care facilities and providers. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, to establish a plan to require liability insurance (including self-insurance), no fault insurance, and workers' compensation laws and plans to meet the determination and submission requirements for Medicare secondary payers.</summary>
</bill>
