<bill session="111" type="sj" number="37" updated="2013-07-20T00:16:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A joint resolution calling upon the President to issue a proclamation recognizing the 35th anniversary of the Helsinki Final Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2010-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6585"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6585-6586" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="726">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 726.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Calls upon the President to ensure U.S. leadership in advancing the aims of the Final Act of the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (Helsinki Final Act), including by issuing a proclamation: (1) recognizing the responsibility of the United States as an original signatory to the Act; (2) reasserting the U.S. commitment to full implementation of the Act; (3) urging all participating states to abide by their commitments under the Act and subsequent Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) documents; and (4) encouraging the people of the United States to join the President and Congress in observance of the 35th anniversary of the signing of the Act with appropriate activities. Calls upon the President to convey to all signatories of the Act that respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms, democratic principles, and economic liberty continue to be vital elements in promoting a new era of democracy, peace, and unity in the region covered by the OSCE.</summary>
</bill>
