<bill session="109" type="h" number="5507" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing the Homeland Through Agency Reporting Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish procedures for the issuance by the Commissioner of Social Security of "no match" letters to employers, and for the notification of the Secretary of Homeland Security regarding such letters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2006-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2006-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2006-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2006-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
Securing the Homeland Through Agency Reporting Enhancement Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) with respect to any case in which the Social Security account number in the wage records of an employee provided by the employer to the Social Security Administration do not match relevant records otherwise maintained by the Administration. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security, in such a case, to send a prompt written notice ("no match" letter): (1) informing the employer of the discrepancies; (2) requesting information that would assist the Commissioner in resolving the discrepancies; and (3) informing the employer that a copy of such notice is being forwarded to assist the Secretary of Homeland Security in the enforcement of applicable federal immigration laws relating to employment of individuals who are not authorized to work in the United States. Requires the Commissioner to forward such a copy to the Secretary of Homeland Security, including the information in which discrepancies appear.</summary>
</bill>
