<bill session="112" type="s" number="1534" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Identify Theft and Tax Fraud Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent identity theft and tax fraud.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5461-5462"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5462" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3215"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3482"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6205"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2011--Introduced.
Identify [sic] Theft and Tax Fraud Prevention Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) impose a fine and/or prison term on any person who knowingly or willfully misappropriates another person's tax identification number in connection with any list, return, account, statement, or other document submitted to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS); (2) increase the civil and criminal penalties for improper disclosure or use of taxpayer information by tax return preparers; (3) require the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to submit to the Senate Committee on Finance and the House Committee on Ways and Means an annual report on the number of reported cases of tax fraud and suspected tax fraud and the actions taken in response to such reports; and (4) require the head of the Federal Bureau of Prisons to submit to Congress a detailed plan on how it will use tax information provided by the IRS to reduce prison tax fraud. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) implement an identity theft tax fraud prevention program; and (2) review whether current federal tax law prevents the effective enforcement of local, state, and federal identity theft statutes. Authorizes the Commissioner to transfer appropriated funds to be used solely to prevent and resolve potential tax fraud cases. Directs the Commissioner to establish in the Criminal Investigation Division of the IRS the position of Local Law Enforcement Liaison to coordinate the investigation of tax fraud with state and local law enforcement agencies and communicate the status of tax fraud cases involving identity theft. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report on the role of prepaid debit cards and commercial tax preparation software in facilitating fraudulent tax returns through identity theft. Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from disclosing information contained on the Death Master File relating to a deceased individual to persons who are not certified to access such information.</summary>
</bill>
