<bill session="110" type="sr" number="472" updated="2013-07-19T22:17:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-04">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending the employees of the Department of Homeland Security, their partners at all levels of government, and the millions of law enforcement, fire service, and emergency medical services personnel, emergency managers,and other emergency response providers nationwide for their dedicated service in protecting the people of the United States and the Nation from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other large-scale emergencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2008-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-03-04" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1546-1547" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1547" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1531" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2008--Passed Senate without amendment.
Commends the public servants of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), on the fifth anniversary of DHS's establishment, for their contributions to the nation's security. Salutes the efforts of government officials and private individuals to enhance the nation's ability to prepare for and respond to terrorism, natural disasters, and other large-scale emergencies. Expresses appreciation for the sacrifices and commitment of law enforcement, fire service, and emergency response personnel. Urges government, businesses, and people to take steps that promote individual and community preparedness. Encourages continued efforts by every individual to enhance the nation's ability to address the full range of potential catastrophic incidents at all levels of government.</summary>
</bill>
