<bill session="109" type="hc" number="376" updated="2013-07-19T20:05:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-18T01:02:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-18T01:02:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Budget resolution FY2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2007 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2008 through 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-31T21:09:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on The Budget reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-402, by Mr. Nussle.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-31T21:09:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="220">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 220.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 766 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 376 with 4 hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 766 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T12:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 766.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1578-1609" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T12:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 376 with 4 hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 766 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with four hours of general debate on H. Con. Res. 376.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T16:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 376 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T17:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 817 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 376. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The amendments printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted in the House as in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T20:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 817 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T20:41:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE--AMENDMENT MODIFICATION - Mr. Spratt asked unanimous consent that during consideration of H. Con. Res. 376, pursuant to H. Res. 817, the amendment he had placed at the desk may be in order in lieu of amendment number 3 printed in part B of House Report 109-468. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/18/2006 H2709-2953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 817, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Watt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T22:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 817, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T22:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T22:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 817, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Spratt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Spratt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Spratt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T23:49:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T00:24:00-04:00">
      <text>FURTHER DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 816, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with a further 20 minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 376.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T00:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H. Con. Res. 376.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T00:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2753" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-05-18T01:02:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="158" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 210 (Roll no. 158).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T01:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hc" number="373"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hc" number="373"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="766"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="766"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="810"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="815"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="817"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sc" number="83"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sc" number="83"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House Agriculture"/>
    <term name="House Armed Services"/>
    <term name="House Budget"/>
    <term name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <term name="House Financial Services"/>
    <term name="House International Relations"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h830"/>
    <amendment number="h831"/>
    <amendment number="h832"/>
    <amendment number="h833"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/18/2006--Passed House amended.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2007, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2008-FY2011. Title I: Recommended Levels and Amounts - (Sec. 101) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2007-FY2011 with respect to: (1) federal revenues; (2) new budget authority; (3) budget outlays; (4) deficits (on-budget); (5) debt subject to limit; and (6) debt held by the public. Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority and outlays for specified major functional categories for FY2007-FY2011. Title II: Reconciliation - (Sec. 201) Requires recommendations to the House Committee on the Budget of changes in law sufficient to reduce the deficit by specified amounts by the following Committees: (1) Agriculture; (2) Armed Services; (3) Education and the Workforce; (4) Financial Services; (5) International Relations; (6) the Judiciary; (7) Transportation and Infrastructure; and (8) Ways and Means. Requires the House Committee on the Budget to report to the House a reconciliation bill carrying out all such recommendations without any substantive revision. Allows the Chairman of the Budget Committee (Chairman) to file with the House appropriately revised committee allocations and revised functional levels and aggregates. Considers such revised allocations and aggregates to be allocations and aggregates established by the concurrent resolution on the budget. Title III: Reserve Funds - (Sec. 301) Creates reserve funds, subject to specified conditions, for: (1) disposal of underutilized federal real property; (2) reauthorization of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act; (3) calendar year 2007 alternative minimum tax relief; (4) the National Flood Insurance Program; (5) revision of the regulation of government-sponsored enterprises; and (6) full offset of appropriations for the Departments of Labor (DOL), Health and Human Services (HHS), Education, and other domestic priorities. Title IV: Budget Enforcement - (Sec. 401) Sets forth prohibitions on advance appropriations in the House. Allows advance appropriations for FY2008 and FY2009 for specified accounts identified in the joint explanatory statement accompanying this resolution, but only in an aggregate of up to $23.565 billion in new budget authority. (Sec. 402) Declares that, if any legislation is reported making appropriations for FY2007 for contingency operations related to the global war on terrorism, and other unanticipated defense-related operations, then the resulting new budget authority, new entitlement authority, outlays, and receipts shall not count for certain purposes of the Congressional Budget Act (CBA). (Sec. 406) Requires the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any concurrent resolution on the budget to include in its allocations to the Committees on Appropriations in the House and Senate amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration (SSA). (Sec. 408) Authorizes the House Committee on Appropriations to make a separate suballocation for general appropriations for the legislative branch for the first fiscal year of this resolution. (Sec. 409) Requires the budgetary effects of legislation or recommendations containing certain National Flood Insurance Program reforms to be scored without regard to the obligations resulting from the enactment of the National Flood Insurance Program Enhanced Borrowing Authority Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-208). Requires such estimate to assume the liquidating of the National Flood Insurance Fund's remaining contractual obligations resulting from claims with respect to 2005 floods. (Sec. 410) Allows the Chairman to make appropriate adjustments in the allocations and aggregates of budget authority, outlays, and revenue set forth in this resolution to reflect the budgetary effects of any reported legislation extending expired federal tax policies, but only if such adjustments would not cause the level of revenue to be less than the level provided for in this resolution for FY2007-FY2011, nor cause the deficit to exceed the appropriate level of deficits provided for such fiscal years. Title V: Emergency Reserve Fund - (Sec. 501) Allows the Chairman to make adjustments to the allocations and aggregates set forth in this resolution for any reported legislation providing new discretionary budget authority and outlays, and designated an emergency requirement. Limits the sum of such adjustments to $6.450 billion for FY2007. Sets forth procedures for consideration of adjustments to such legislation if enactment would cause the total amount in the reserve fund for such fiscal year to be exceeded. (Sec. 502) Specifies criteria and guidelines with respect to designated emergency requirements. Title VI: Sense of Congress - (Sec. 601) Expresses the sense of Congress that the determination of the congressional budget for the federal government and the President's budget request should include consideration of the Financial Report of the United States Government, especially its information regarding the government's net operating cost, financial position, and long-term liabilities. (Sec. 602) Expresses the sense of Congress that any revenue increases achieved through recovery of taxes legally owed to the U.S. Treasury but not actually paid (the so-called "tax gap") shall be dedicated entirely to reducing the deficit and the accumulated debt, and not to financing additional spending. (Sec. 603) Declares that: (1) the House of Representatives recognizes the need to increase the President's FY2007 request for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies Appropriation bill by not less than $7.158 billion; and (2) there should be included in any offsets enacted to provide for such increases a rescission of at least $1 billion from available, unobligated funds previously appropriated for reconstruction activities in Iraq.</summary>
</bill>
