<bill session="113" type="s" number="1407" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Science Education and Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to strengthen elementary and secondary computer science education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Computer Science Education and Jobs Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to define "computer science" as the study of computers and algorithmic processes, including the study of computing principles, computer hardware, software design, computer applications, and the impact of computers on society. Makes computer science a core academic subject. Includes computer science teachers in professional development activities. Requires the Secretary of Education to give a priority in awarding advanced placement incentive program grants to entities focused on expanding access to advanced placement computer science programs. Requires state plans for school improvement to describe how the state will consider including computer science in its academic standards, accountability system, and assessments. Requires computer science teachers to be highly qualified by the end of the 2015-2016 school year. Includes computer science in the program awarding grants to partnerships between states, institutions of higher education (IHEs), and high-need local educational agencies to: (1) train and recruit mathematics and science teachers, and (2) develop more rigorous science and mathematics curricula. Authorizes the Secretary to award five-year grants to IHEs to: (1) develop courses that prepare undergraduate students to teach elementary and secondary school computer science, and (2) develop and fund teacher mentoring programs to support new computer science teachers. Amends the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 to include informatics and computer science majors and professionals in the Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship Program (the Program recruits and prepares science, technology, engineering, and mathematics majors and professionals to become mathematics and science teachers).</summary>
</bill>
