<bill session="112" type="hr" number="27" updated="2013-07-20T01:03:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-07T11:31:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-07T11:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Relating to the status of certain actions taken by Members-elect.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-07T11:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H118-120" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-07T11:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H.Res. 26, the House proceeded with four minutes of debate on H. Res. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-07T11:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H119" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-01-07T11:31:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="11" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 257 - 159, 3 Present (Roll no. 11).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H118" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-01-07T11:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2011--Passed House without amendment.
Requires specified rollcall votes recorded for Representative-elect Sessions and Representative-elect Fitzpatrick be deleted and the vote-totals for each of those rollcalls be adjusted accordingly, both in the Journal and in the Congressional Record. Ratifies the election of Representative-elect Sessions to a standing committee and his participation in its proceedings. Considers the measures delivered by him to the Speaker for referral as introduced. Retains the numbers assigned. Considers as valid: (1) any submissions to the Congressional Record by Representative-elect Sessions or Representative-elect Fitzpatrick; and (2) any cosponsor lists naming them. Ratifies any non-voting participation by them in floor proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
