<bill session="110" type="s" number="2241" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Land Fire Regulations Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide consistent enforcement authority to the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service to respond to violations of regulations regarding the management, use, and protection of public land under the jurisdiction of those agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13453-13454"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1484"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2007--Introduced.
Public Land Fire Regulations Enforcement Act - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, and other federal law to provide that: (1) any person who knowingly violates the provisions of such an Act concerning the management, use, and protection of covered lands shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor and subject to fine and/or imprisonment; and (2) any person who otherwise violates the provisions of such an Act concerning the management, use, and protection of such covered lands shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor and subject to fine and/or imprisonment. Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, and other federal law to set a minimum fine of $500 for certain fire usage violations on BLM, National Park System, and National Forest System land.</summary>
</bill>
