<bill session="109" type="h" number="3007" updated="2013-07-19T19:30:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combating Terrorism Financing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To combat terrorism financing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400168"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Underground economy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2005--Introduced.
Combating Terrorism Financing Act of 2005 - Amends the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to increase penalties for violating a license, order, or regulation under the Act. Amends the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act (RICO) to expand its scope to include offenses relating to the financing of terrorism and violations of the Social Security Act relating to obtaining funds through the misuse of a social security number. Authorizes the Department of Homeland Security to investigate violations of money laundering and related offenses. Directs that a transaction or transfer of funds be considered to involve the proceeds of specified unlawful activity if it is part of a set of parallel or dependent transactions involving such proceeds. Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) provide for civil forfeiture to the United States of the assets of any individual or organization engaged in planning or perpetrating an act of international terrorism against any international organization or against any foreign government; and (2) establish procedures for contesting the confiscation of assets of suspected international terrorists. Amends RICO to make receiving military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization a predicate offense to violation of money laundering provisions.</summary>
</bill>
