<bill session="111" type="h" number="1703" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Transform America Transaction Fee Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require a study and comprehensive analytical report on transforming America by reforming the Federal tax code through elimination of all Federal taxes on individuals and corporations and replacing the Federal tax code with a transaction fee-based system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400130"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Comprehensive Transform America Transaction Fee Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct an in-depth study on the implementation of a transaction fee in the United States to replace all existing federal taxes. Sets forth guidelines for such study, including: (1) an identification of the transactions to which such fee would apply; (2) exclusions from such fee; (3) the rate of such fee; (4) potential uses for revenue from such fee; (5) progressivity standards; and (6) general matters, including point of liability for such fee and responsibility for collection. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the results of such study within one year after the enactment of this Act with a comprehensive analysis of various aspects of the transaction fee, including revenue generation, impact on the national economy, and implementation.</summary>
</bill>
