<bill session="110" type="h" number="2172" updated="2013-07-19T21:22:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Amputee Veteran Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require that all Department of Veterans Affairs orthotic-prosthetic laboratories, clinics, and prosthesists are certified by either the American Board for Certification in Orthotics and Prosthetics or the Board of Orthotics and Prosthetic Certification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400337"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2007--Introduced.
Amputee Veteran Assistance Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that all Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) orthotic-prosthetic laboratories and clinics are certified by either the American Board for Certification in Orthotics and Prosthetics or the Board of Orthotics and Prosthetic Certification. Requires the Secretary to contract with a non-VA entity for the service and repair of prosthetic devices for a veteran if: (1) the Secretary determines that VA facilities are unable to perform such service or repair due to a lack of technology or any other reason; or (2) the veteran needing such service or repair resides more than 55 miles from the nearest VA facility capable of furnishing such service or repair. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop and carry out a plan to inform disabled veterans at least twice a year of technological advances in the field of prosthetics; (2) review all VA orthotic-prosthetic laboratories and clinics to ensure that the VA is capable of servicing and repairing the most technologically advanced prosthetic devices; and (3) review VA prosthetists and orthotists to determine the level and kinds of education required to ensure their qualification to provide the most technologically advanced prosthetic devices.</summary>
</bill>
