<bill session="109" type="s" number="3832" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reclamation Facility Title Transfer Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish criteria to transfer title to reclamation facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8846-8847"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S8847" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-781.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Reclamation Facility Title Transfer Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to: (1) establish criteria for the transfer of title to reclamation facilities from the United States to project beneficiaries (or an entity approved by such beneficiaries); and (2) recommend facilities that may be appropriate for transfer in accordance with such criteria. Requires that such criteria include: (1) requirements that beneficiaries be willing to have title transferred to them, be capable of assuming facility operations, maintenance, and rehabilitation, and be willing to assume liability for such facilities; (2) a requirement for an assessment by the Secretary of effects of the transfer on the government's ability to carry out its Indian tribal trust responsibility, costs savings to the United States, legal and environmental considerations, adverse impacts on stakeholders, and the beneficiaries' interest in owning the facility, ability to meet financial obligations, and willingness and ability to fulfill legal obligations; (3) procedures for soliciting stakeholder involvement and for involving appropriate federal, state, and local entities in evaluating and carrying out the transfer; (4) a requirement that the Secretary prepare a comprehensive list of items that need to be accomplished before the transfer; and (5) procedures to allow the Secretary to address real property and cultural and historic preservation issues in a more efficient manner. Directs the Secretary to incorporate any existing applicable criteria.</summary>
</bill>
