<bill session="111" type="h" number="4817" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to clarify that uncertified States and Indian tribes have the authority to use certain payments for certain noncoal reclamation projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412316"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="2830"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 with respect to the allocation of surface mining reclamation funds to states and Indian tribes, to modify limitations on the allocation of surface mining reclamation funds to states and Indian tribes to provide for payments for filling voids and sealing tunnels and entryways of non-coal mines as well as coal mines. Requires uncertified states or Indian tribes to use such allocated funds to fill voids and seal tunnels and entryways of non-coal as well as coal mines. ("Uncertified states and Indian tribes" are those which have not certified to the Secretary of the Interior that all priorities specified under the Act for eligible lands and waters have been achieved.)</summary>
</bill>
