<bill session="109" type="s" number="3969" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lead Poisoning Reduction Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to assess and reduce the levels of lead found in child-occupied facilities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10471-10472"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6222"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Lead Poisoning Reduction Act of 2006 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to establish a Select Group on Lead Exposure. Requires the Group to: (1) conduct a study of state, tribal, and local programs to protect children from exposure to lead at child-occupied facilities constructed before January 1, 1978; (2) develop baseline standards such programs must meet to receive a grant under this Act; and (3) develop a model program to protect children from exposure to lead at such facilities that can be adopted by state, local, and tribal governments. Requires the model program to meet or exceed standards that require facilities to be notified as soon as practicable after a child is diagnosed with lead poisoning and to be tested for the presence of lead upon receiving such notification. Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish a program to provide grants to assist such facilitites in carrying out activities to protect children from lead exposure; (2) promulgate regulations requiring such facilities to test applicable exposure pathways for lead, prohibiting states and Indian tribes from issuing a license to such facilities until the testing is complete and the exposure to lead is eliminated, and requiring all child-occupied facilities to eliminate the risk of exposure to lead through applicable exposure pathways; and (3) apply regulations governing lead-based paint activities to contractors and workers engaged in the renovation, remodeling, or painting of such facilitates and to establish a program to provide information and training about those activities to them.</summary>
</bill>
