<bill session="109" type="h" number="3812" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-06T14:25:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-06T14:25:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a feasibility study with respect to the Mokelumne River, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11043-11044" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3812.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-06T14:25:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11043" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2005--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, and in consultation with the Mokelumne River Water and Power Authority, to complete and submit to specified congressional committees a study in the area of the Mokelumne River (California) to determine the feasibility of constructing a project to provide additional water supply and improve water management reliability through the development of new water storage and conjunctive use programs. Instructs the Secretary: (1) in developing the Study, to use reports and any other relevant information supplied by the Mokelumne River Water and Power Authority, the East Bay Municipal Utility District, and other Mokelumne River Forum stakeholders; and (2) to accept in-kind contributions of goods or services from the Authority as will contribute to the conduct and completion of the Study. Limits the federal share of Study costs to 50% of the total cost. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out any provisions of this Act ten years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
