<bill session="112" type="s" number="1537" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National September 11 Memorial and Museum Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to accept from the Board of Directors of the National September 11 Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center Foundation, Inc., the donation of title to The National September 11 Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5477-5478"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5477-5478" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-224.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2882"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2011--Introduced.
National September 11 Memorial and Museum Act of 2011- Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to accept from the Board of Directors of the National September 11 Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center Foundation, Inc., the donation of title to the National September 11 Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center in New York City, New York. Requires approval of the donation by the governor of New York, the governor of New Jersey, and the mayor of New York City. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide technical and financial assistance to the Board that is related to the operation of the Memorial; and (2) consult with and seek technical assistance from the Secretaries of Defense (DOD), Education, Homeland Security (DHS), Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and the Administrator of General Services (GSA) in providing such technical and financial assistance to the Board.</summary>
</bill>
