<bill session="112" type="h" number="2623" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">9/11 Commission Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Commission to Review the National Response Since the Terrorist Attacks of September 11, 2001.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2011-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3116"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2011--Introduced.
9/11 Commission Review Act - Establishes in the legislative branch a National Commission to Review the National Response Since the Terrorist Attacks of September 11, 2001. Directs the Commission to conduct a comprehensive review of the implementation of the recommendations proposed in the report issued by the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States (9/11 Commission) and to: (1) assess the progress and challenges in carrying out such recommendations; (2) analyze the trends of domestic terror attacks since the attacks of September 11, 2001, including the growing influence of domestic radicalization and how federal, state, and local agencies can deter and mitigate it; (3) investigate whether there is evidence of any conduct, relationships, or other factors which served to contribute to, facilitate, support, or assist the hijackers who carried out the attacks that was not considered by the 9/11 Commission; and (4) provide additional recommendations with regard to U.S. homeland security protection, interagency intelligence sharing, and counterterrorism policy.</summary>
</bill>
