<bill session="109" type="h" number="1174" updated="2013-07-19T19:14:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sand Conservation and Taxpayer Savings Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve regional sediment management.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2005-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2005--Introduced.
Sand Conservation and Taxpayer Savings Act of 2005 - Amends the Water Resources Development Act (WRDA) of 1992 to replace provisions regarding beneficial uses of dredged material with provisions regarding regional sediment management. Directs the Secretary of the Army, in connection with sediment obtained in connection with an authorized Federal water resources project and acting through the Chief of Engineers, to develop regional sediment management plans and carry out projects for: (1) the protection of property; (2) the protection, restoration, and creation of aquatic and ecologically related habitats; and (3) the transport and placement of suitable sediment at specified locations. Authorizes projects to be undertaken where the Secretary finds that: (1) the environmental, economic, and social benefits of the project justify the cost; and (2) the project would not result in environmental degradation. Makes operation, maintenance, replacement, and rehabilitation costs associated with a project a non-Federal sponsor responsibility. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Chief, to develop at Federal expense plans and projects for regional management of sediment obtained in conjunction with projects, subject to specified limitations. Authorizes the Secretary, through the Chief, to cooperate with any State in preparing a comprehensive State or regional coastal sediment management plan within the State's boundaries and to encourage State participation in implementing it. Repeals provisions of the WRDA of 1976 regarding the placement on State beaches of sand dredged in constructing and maintaining navigation inlets and channels adjacent to such beaches.</summary>
</bill>
