<bill session="110" type="h" number="7065" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Workforce Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to address health workforce shortages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2008-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
Health Workforce Investment Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the National Health Workforce Advisory Council to make recommendations to relevant agencies and congressional committees on health workforce issues, including on: (1) the supply and distribution of the U.S. health workforce; (2) current and future shortages or excesses of health workforce professionals; (3) issues relating to foreign medical and nursing school graduates; and (4) deficiencies in existing databases concerning the supply and distribution of, and postgraduate training programs for, health workforce professionals. Requires the Council to encourage entities providing graduate medical education to conduct activities to voluntarily address health workforce issues.Establishes the National Center for Health Workforce Information and Analysis to conduct and support statistical and epidemiological activities for the purpose of assessing and improving the supply, distribution, diversity, and development of the health workforce in the United States. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to states for: (1) ensuring access to health services for all individuals, particularly those with low incomes or limited access to health services; (2) improving the supply, distribution, diversity, and development of the health workforce; and (3) creating state-specific health workforce goals and objectives consistent with health status goals and national health workforce objectives. Authorizes the Secretary to provide for research to identify best practices and innovative approaches to improving the health workforce.Requires the Secretary to develop national health workforce objectives.</summary>
</bill>
