<bill session="110" type="h" number="5993" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Signing Statements Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote congressional and public awareness, understanding, and political accountability of presidential signing statements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2008--Introduced.
Presidential Signing Statements Act of 2008 - Requires the President to transmit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the chairmen of the House and Senate Committees on the Judiciary, and to the Senate Majority Leader each signing statement that declares or insinuates the President's intention to disregard provisions of any bill he has signed into law because he believes it is unconstitutional. Requires the Attorney General, Deputy Attorney General, or White House Counsel to testify before such congressional committees at the behest of any single Member of either committee to explain the meaning and justification of every presidential signing statement covered by this Act. Prohibits executive privilege from being recognized as a valid basis for refusing to appear or refusing to answer a question pertinent to the legal reasoning behind a signing statement or its legal ramifications. Bars authorization or expenditure of federal funds to implement any law accompanied by a presidential signing statement noncompliant with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
