<bill session="113" type="h" number="285" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans, Women, Families with Children, Race, and Persons with Disabilities Housing Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize funds to prevent housing discrimination through the use of nationwide testing, to increase funds for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400653"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2013--Introduced.
Veterans, Women, Families with Children, Race, and Persons with Disabilities Housing Fairness Act of 2013 or Housing Fairness Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to conduct a nationwide testing program to: (1) detect and document differences in the treatment of persons seeking to rent or purchase housing or obtain or refinance a home mortgage loan; (2) measure patterns of adverse treatment because of the race, color, religion, sex, familial status, disability status, or national origin of a renter, home buyer, or borrower; and (3) measure the prevalence of such discriminatory practices across housing and mortgage lending markets. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 to require that only qualified private nonprofit fair housing enforcement organizations receive funds under the fair housing initiatives program for investigations of violations of the rights granted under the Civil Rights Act of 1968. Requires the design of the national education and outreach program to provide for the development and dissemination of websites and other media outlets among its fair housing media products. Requires private entities that formulate or carry out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices to be nonprofit in order to be eligible for contracts to establish or support education and outreach programs and to support community-based education and outreach activities. Requires the Secretary to establish minimum standards for the training of testers of organizations funded with any amounts made available under this Act. Directs the Secretary to implement a competitive matching grant program to assist public and private nonprofit organizations in: (1) conducting comprehensive studies of the causes and effects of housing discrimination and segregation on education, poverty, and economic development or on veterans and military personnel; and (2) implementing pilot projects that test solutions to help prevent or alleviate housing discrimination and segregation.</summary>
</bill>
