<bill session="111" type="h" number="2997" updated="2013-07-19T23:38:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-23T20:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-181, by Ms. DeLauro.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-23T20:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="98">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 98.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 609 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2997 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 609 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 609.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7799-7828" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7805" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7806, H7807, H7808-7810, H7810, H7811-7812" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7812" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7812-7814" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7814-7815" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7815" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7815, H7817" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7817-7819" label="text of Title VII as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2997 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 609 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Vic Snyder to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeLauro amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeLauro amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kingston demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Brady (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Capito amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Capito amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Capito demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fortenberry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T20:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Broun (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blackburn amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blackburn amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Blackburn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Campbell amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T21:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 609, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kingston amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:26:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kingston amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kingston demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T22:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2997 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7843-7855" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7852" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T11:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kingston moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7852-7854" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7852" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. The provisions of the motions to recommit constitute legislation in an appropriations bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kingston appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7853" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7853" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:25:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by recorded vote: 246 - 179 (Roll no. 509).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kingston moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7854" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7854" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kingston motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to redirect funds by transfer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to recommit with instructions withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-09T12:53:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="510" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 266 - 160 (Roll no. 510).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="105">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 105.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8534-8537" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8619-8623" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Cloture motion on the bill presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8620" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8620" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8647-8663" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8711-8713, S8714, S8715-8716, S8716-8719, S8720-8730" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Motion by Senator Coburn to commit to Senate Committee on Appropriations with instructions made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8724, S8726" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8724" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Motion by Senator Coburn to commit to Senate Committee on Appropriations with instructions rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 32 - 65. Record Vote Number: 259.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8726" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2009-08-04" how="roll" result="pass" roll="261" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 80 - 17. Record Vote Number: 261.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/5/2009 S8877-8887" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Kohl; Harkin; Dorgan; Feinstein; Durbin; Johnson; Nelson NE; Reed; Pryor; Specter; Inouye; Brownback; Bennett; Cochran; Bond; McConnell; Collins; Shelby.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10021-10023, H10041-10042" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kingston moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Kingston motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 2997. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to not record their approval of the final conference agreement (within the meaning of clause 12(a)(4) of House rule XXII) unless the text of such agreement has been available to the managers in an electronic, searchable, and downloadable form for at least 72 hours piror to the time described in such clause.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10023" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 359 - 41 (Roll no. 742).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10041-10042" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: DeLauro, Farr, Boyd, Bishop (GA), Davis (TN), Kaptur, Hinchey, Jackson (IL), Obey, Kingston, Latham, Emerson, Alexander, and Lewis (CA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 111-279 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10358-10402" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 799 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2997. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the conference report to its adoption without intervening motion except: (1)one hour of debate; and (2) one motion to recommit if applicable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 799 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro brought up conference report H. Rept. 111-279 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 799.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11061-11077" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11076" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2009-10-07T18:05:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="761" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 263 - 162 (Roll no. 761).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10280-10284" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2009-10-08" how="roll" result="pass" roll="318" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 76 - 22. Record Vote Number: 318.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2009-10-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2009-10-21" type="public" number="111-80">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-80.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="609"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="799"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1406"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1406"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1406"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3606"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Farm Credit Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General agriculture matters"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h293"/>
    <amendment number="h294"/>
    <amendment number="h295"/>
    <amendment number="h296"/>
    <amendment number="h297"/>
    <amendment number="h298"/>
    <amendment number="h299"/>
    <amendment number="h300"/>
    <amendment number="h301"/>
    <amendment number="h302"/>
    <amendment number="h303"/>
    <amendment number="h304"/>
    <amendment number="h305"/>
    <amendment number="s1908"/>
    <amendment number="s1909"/>
    <amendment number="s1910"/>
    <amendment number="s1911"/>
    <amendment number="s1912"/>
    <amendment number="s1913"/>
    <amendment number="s1914"/>
    <amendment number="s1915"/>
    <amendment number="s1916"/>
    <amendment number="s1917"/>
    <amendment number="s1918"/>
    <amendment number="s1919"/>
    <amendment number="s1920"/>
    <amendment number="s1921"/>
    <amendment number="s1922"/>
    <amendment number="s1923"/>
    <amendment number="s1924"/>
    <amendment number="s1925"/>
    <amendment number="s1926"/>
    <amendment number="s1927"/>
    <amendment number="s1928"/>
    <amendment number="s1929"/>
    <amendment number="s1930"/>
    <amendment number="s1931"/>
    <amendment number="s1932"/>
    <amendment number="s1933"/>
    <amendment number="s1934"/>
    <amendment number="s1935"/>
    <amendment number="s1936"/>
    <amendment number="s1937"/>
    <amendment number="s1938"/>
    <amendment number="s1939"/>
    <amendment number="s1940"/>
    <amendment number="s1941"/>
    <amendment number="s1942"/>
    <amendment number="s1943"/>
    <amendment number="s1944"/>
    <amendment number="s1945"/>
    <amendment number="s1946"/>
    <amendment number="s1947"/>
    <amendment number="s1948"/>
    <amendment number="s1949"/>
    <amendment number="s1950"/>
    <amendment number="s1951"/>
    <amendment number="s1952"/>
    <amendment number="s1953"/>
    <amendment number="s1954"/>
    <amendment number="s1955"/>
    <amendment number="s1956"/>
    <amendment number="s1957"/>
    <amendment number="s1958"/>
    <amendment number="s1959"/>
    <amendment number="s1960"/>
    <amendment number="s1961"/>
    <amendment number="s1962"/>
    <amendment number="s1963"/>
    <amendment number="s1964"/>
    <amendment number="s1965"/>
    <amendment number="s1966"/>
    <amendment number="s1967"/>
    <amendment number="s1968"/>
    <amendment number="s1969"/>
    <amendment number="s1970"/>
    <amendment number="s1971"/>
    <amendment number="s1972"/>
    <amendment number="s1973"/>
    <amendment number="s1974"/>
    <amendment number="s1975"/>
    <amendment number="s1976"/>
    <amendment number="s1977"/>
    <amendment number="s1978"/>
    <amendment number="s1979"/>
    <amendment number="s1980"/>
    <amendment number="s1981"/>
    <amendment number="s1982"/>
    <amendment number="s1983"/>
    <amendment number="s1984"/>
    <amendment number="s1985"/>
    <amendment number="s1986"/>
    <amendment number="s1987"/>
    <amendment number="s1988"/>
    <amendment number="s1989"/>
    <amendment number="s1990"/>
    <amendment number="s1991"/>
    <amendment number="s1992"/>
    <amendment number="s1993"/>
    <amendment number="s1994"/>
    <amendment number="s1995"/>
    <amendment number="s1996"/>
    <amendment number="s1997"/>
    <amendment number="s1998"/>
    <amendment number="s1999"/>
    <amendment number="s2000"/>
    <amendment number="s2001"/>
    <amendment number="s2002"/>
    <amendment number="s2003"/>
    <amendment number="s2004"/>
    <amendment number="s2005"/>
    <amendment number="s2006"/>
    <amendment number="s2007"/>
    <amendment number="s2008"/>
    <amendment number="s2009"/>
    <amendment number="s2010"/>
    <amendment number="s2011"/>
    <amendment number="s2012"/>
    <amendment number="s2013"/>
    <amendment number="s2014"/>
    <amendment number="s2015"/>
    <amendment number="s2016"/>
    <amendment number="s2017"/>
    <amendment number="s2018"/>
    <amendment number="s2019"/>
    <amendment number="s2020"/>
    <amendment number="s2021"/>
    <amendment number="s2022"/>
    <amendment number="s2023"/>
    <amendment number="s2024"/>
    <amendment number="s2025"/>
    <amendment number="s2026"/>
    <amendment number="s2027"/>
    <amendment number="s2028"/>
    <amendment number="s2029"/>
    <amendment number="s2030"/>
    <amendment number="s2031"/>
    <amendment number="s2032"/>
    <amendment number="s2033"/>
    <amendment number="s2034"/>
    <amendment number="s2035"/>
    <amendment number="s2036"/>
    <amendment number="s2037"/>
    <amendment number="s2038"/>
    <amendment number="s2039"/>
    <amendment number="s2040"/>
    <amendment number="s2041"/>
    <amendment number="s2042"/>
    <amendment number="s2043"/>
    <amendment number="s2044"/>
    <amendment number="s2045"/>
    <amendment number="s2046"/>
    <amendment number="s2047"/>
    <amendment number="s2048"/>
    <amendment number="s2049"/>
    <amendment number="s2050"/>
    <amendment number="s2051"/>
    <amendment number="s2052"/>
    <amendment number="s2053"/>
    <amendment number="s2054"/>
    <amendment number="s2055"/>
    <amendment number="s2056"/>
    <amendment number="s2057"/>
    <amendment number="s2058"/>
    <amendment number="s2059"/>
    <amendment number="s2060"/>
    <amendment number="s2061"/>
    <amendment number="s2062"/>
    <amendment number="s2063"/>
    <amendment number="s2064"/>
    <amendment number="s2065"/>
    <amendment number="s2066"/>
    <amendment number="s2067"/>
    <amendment number="s2068"/>
    <amendment number="s2069"/>
    <amendment number="s2070"/>
    <amendment number="s2071"/>
    <amendment number="s2072"/>
    <amendment number="s2073"/>
    <amendment number="s2074"/>
    <amendment number="s2075"/>
    <amendment number="s2076"/>
    <amendment number="s2077"/>
    <amendment number="s2078"/>
    <amendment number="s2079"/>
    <amendment number="s2080"/>
    <amendment number="s2081"/>
    <amendment number="s2082"/>
    <amendment number="s2083"/>
    <amendment number="s2084"/>
    <amendment number="s2085"/>
    <amendment number="s2086"/>
    <amendment number="s2087"/>
    <amendment number="s2088"/>
    <amendment number="s2089"/>
    <amendment number="s2090"/>
    <amendment number="s2091"/>
    <amendment number="s2092"/>
    <amendment number="s2093"/>
    <amendment number="s2094"/>
    <amendment number="s2095"/>
    <amendment number="s2096"/>
    <amendment number="s2097"/>
    <amendment number="s2098"/>
    <amendment number="s2099"/>
    <amendment number="s2100"/>
    <amendment number="s2101"/>
    <amendment number="s2102"/>
    <amendment number="s2103"/>
    <amendment number="s2104"/>
    <amendment number="s2105"/>
    <amendment number="s2106"/>
    <amendment number="s2107"/>
    <amendment number="s2108"/>
    <amendment number="s2109"/>
    <amendment number="s2110"/>
    <amendment number="s2111"/>
    <amendment number="s2112"/>
    <amendment number="s2113"/>
    <amendment number="s2114"/>
    <amendment number="s2115"/>
    <amendment number="s2116"/>
    <amendment number="s2117"/>
    <amendment number="s2118"/>
    <amendment number="s2119"/>
    <amendment number="s2120"/>
    <amendment number="s2121"/>
    <amendment number="s2122"/>
    <amendment number="s2123"/>
    <amendment number="s2124"/>
    <amendment number="s2125"/>
    <amendment number="s2126"/>
    <amendment number="s2127"/>
    <amendment number="s2128"/>
    <amendment number="s2129"/>
    <amendment number="s2130"/>
    <amendment number="s2131"/>
    <amendment number="s2132"/>
    <amendment number="s2133"/>
    <amendment number="s2134"/>
    <amendment number="s2135"/>
    <amendment number="s2136"/>
    <amendment number="s2137"/>
    <amendment number="s2138"/>
    <amendment number="s2139"/>
    <amendment number="s2140"/>
    <amendment number="s2141"/>
    <amendment number="s2142"/>
    <amendment number="s2143"/>
    <amendment number="s2144"/>
    <amendment number="s2145"/>
    <amendment number="s2146"/>
    <amendment number="s2147"/>
    <amendment number="s2148"/>
    <amendment number="s2149"/>
    <amendment number="s2150"/>
    <amendment number="s2151"/>
    <amendment number="s2152"/>
    <amendment number="s2153"/>
    <amendment number="s2154"/>
    <amendment number="s2155"/>
    <amendment number="s2156"/>
    <amendment number="s2157"/>
    <amendment number="s2158"/>
    <amendment number="s2159"/>
    <amendment number="s2160"/>
    <amendment number="s2161"/>
    <amendment number="s2162"/>
    <amendment number="s2163"/>
    <amendment number="s2164"/>
    <amendment number="s2165"/>
    <amendment number="s2166"/>
    <amendment number="s2167"/>
    <amendment number="s2168"/>
    <amendment number="s2169"/>
    <amendment number="s2170"/>
    <amendment number="s2171"/>
    <amendment number="s2172"/>
    <amendment number="s2173"/>
    <amendment number="s2174"/>
    <amendment number="s2175"/>
    <amendment number="s2176"/>
    <amendment number="s2177"/>
    <amendment number="s2178"/>
    <amendment number="s2179"/>
    <amendment number="s2180"/>
    <amendment number="s2181"/>
    <amendment number="s2182"/>
    <amendment number="s2183"/>
    <amendment number="s2184"/>
    <amendment number="s2185"/>
    <amendment number="s2186"/>
    <amendment number="s2187"/>
    <amendment number="s2188"/>
    <amendment number="s2189"/>
    <amendment number="s2190"/>
    <amendment number="s2191"/>
    <amendment number="s2192"/>
    <amendment number="s2193"/>
    <amendment number="s2194"/>
    <amendment number="s2195"/>
    <amendment number="s2196"/>
    <amendment number="s2197"/>
    <amendment number="s2198"/>
    <amendment number="s2199"/>
    <amendment number="s2200"/>
    <amendment number="s2201"/>
    <amendment number="s2202"/>
    <amendment number="s2203"/>
    <amendment number="s2204"/>
    <amendment number="s2205"/>
    <amendment number="s2206"/>
    <amendment number="s2207"/>
    <amendment number="s2208"/>
    <amendment number="s2209"/>
    <amendment number="s2210"/>
    <amendment number="s2211"/>
    <amendment number="s2212"/>
    <amendment number="s2213"/>
    <amendment number="s2214"/>
    <amendment number="s2215"/>
    <amendment number="s2216"/>
    <amendment number="s2217"/>
    <amendment number="s2218"/>
    <amendment number="s2219"/>
    <amendment number="s2220"/>
    <amendment number="s2221"/>
    <amendment number="s2224"/>
    <amendment number="s2225"/>
    <amendment number="s2226"/>
    <amendment number="s2227"/>
    <amendment number="s2229"/>
    <amendment number="s2230"/>
    <amendment number="s2231"/>
    <amendment number="s2232"/>
    <amendment number="s2233"/>
    <amendment number="s2234"/>
    <amendment number="s2235"/>
    <amendment number="s2236"/>
    <amendment number="s2237"/>
    <amendment number="s2238"/>
    <amendment number="s2239"/>
    <amendment number="s2240"/>
    <amendment number="s2241"/>
    <amendment number="s2242"/>
    <amendment number="s2243"/>
    <amendment number="s2244"/>
    <amendment number="s2245"/>
    <amendment number="s2246"/>
    <amendment number="s2247"/>
    <amendment number="s2248"/>
    <amendment number="s2249"/>
    <amendment number="s2250"/>
    <amendment number="s2251"/>
    <amendment number="s2252"/>
    <amendment number="s2253"/>
    <amendment number="s2254"/>
    <amendment number="s2255"/>
    <amendment number="s2256"/>
    <amendment number="s2257"/>
    <amendment number="s2258"/>
    <amendment number="s2259"/>
    <amendment number="s2260"/>
    <amendment number="s2261"/>
    <amendment number="s2262"/>
    <amendment number="s2263"/>
    <amendment number="s2264"/>
    <amendment number="s2265"/>
    <amendment number="s2266"/>
    <amendment number="s2267"/>
    <amendment number="s2268"/>
    <amendment number="s2269"/>
    <amendment number="s2270"/>
    <amendment number="s2271"/>
    <amendment number="s2272"/>
    <amendment number="s2273"/>
    <amendment number="s2274"/>
    <amendment number="s2275"/>
    <amendment number="s2276"/>
    <amendment number="s2277"/>
    <amendment number="s2278"/>
    <amendment number="s2279"/>
    <amendment number="s2280"/>
    <amendment number="s2281"/>
    <amendment number="s2282"/>
    <amendment number="s2283"/>
    <amendment number="s2284"/>
    <amendment number="s2285"/>
    <amendment number="s2286"/>
    <amendment number="s2287"/>
    <amendment number="s2288"/>
    <amendment number="s2289"/>
    <amendment number="s2290"/>
    <amendment number="s2291"/>
    <amendment number="s2292"/>
    <amendment number="s2293"/>
    <amendment number="s2294"/>
    <amendment number="s2295"/>
    <amendment number="s2296"/>
    <amendment number="s2297"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/21/2009--Public Law.
Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010 - Title I: Agricultural Programs - Appropriates FY2010 funds for the following Department of Agriculture (Department) programs and services: (1) Office of the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary); (2) Office of Tribal Relations; (3) Office of the Chief Economist; (4) National Appeals Division; (5) Office of Budget and Program Analysis; (6) Office of Homeland Security; (7) Office of Advocacy and Outreach; (8) Office of the Chief Information Officer; (9) Office of the Chief Financial Officer; (10) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights; (11) Office of Civil Rights; (12) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration; (13) agriculture buildings and facilities and rental payments; (14) hazardous materials management; (15) departmental administration; (16) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations; (17) Office of Communications; (18) Office of the Inspector General; (19) Office of the General Counsel; (20) Office of the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics; (21) Economic Research Service; (22) National Agricultural Statistics Service; (23) Agricultural Research Service; (24) National Institute of Food and Agriculture; (25) Native American Institutions Endowment Fund; (26) extension and integrated activities; (27) Office of the Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs; (28) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service; (29) Agricultural Marketing Service; (30) Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration; (31) Office of the Under Secretary for Food Safety; (32) Food Safety and Inspection Service; (33) Office of the Under Secretary for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services; (34) Farm Service Agency; (35) state mediation grants; (36) grassroots water protection; (37) dairy indemnity program; (38) Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund Program Account; (39) Risk Management Agency; (40) Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund; and (41) Commodity Credit Corporation Fund. Title II: Conservation Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment; and (2) Natural Resources Conservation Service. Title III: Rural Development Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Rural Development; (2) rural development salaries and expenses; (3) Rural Housing Service; (4) Rural Community Facilities Program Account (5) Rural Business-Cooperative Service; (6) rural development loans; (7) rural cooperative grants; (8) rural microenterprise; (9) Rural Energy for America Program; (10) Rural Utilities Service; (11) rural electrification and telecommunications loans; and (12) distance learning, telemedicine, and broadband. Title IV: Domestic Food Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition and Consumer Services; and (2) Food and Nutrition Service. Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Foreign Agricultural Service; (2) Public Law 480 (P.L. 480) program title I and title II grants; (3) Commodity Credit Corporation export loans program account; and (4) McGovern-Dole international food for education and child nutrition program grants. Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Food and Drug Administration (FDA); (2) Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC); and (3) Farm Credit Administration. Title VII: General Provisions - Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibitions against the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 703) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer unobligated balances to the Working Capital Fund for plant and capital equipment acquisition. (Sec. 704) Prohibits appropriations under this Act from remaining available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly provided for. (Sec. 705) Limits negotiated indirect costs on cooperative agreements between the Department and nonprofit organizations to 10%. (Sec. 708) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for the Safe Meat and Poultry Inspection Panel. (Sec. 709) Requires that Department agencies reimburse each other for employees detailed for longer than 30 days. (Sec. 712) Prohibits, without congressional notification, funds available under this Act or under previous appropriations Acts from being used through a reprogramming of funds to: (1) eliminate or create a new program; (2) relocate or reorganize an office or employees; (3) privatize federal employee functions; or (4) increase funds or personnel for a project for which funds have been denied or restricted. Prohibits, without congressional notification, funds available under this Act or under previous appropriations Acts from being used through a reprogramming of funds in excess of $500,000 or 10%, whichever is less: (1) to augment an existing program; (2) to reduce by 10% funding or personnel for any existing program; or (3) that results from a reduction in personnel which would result in a change in existing programs. (Sec. 713) Prohibits the use of funds for user fee proposals that fail to provide certain budget impact information. (Sec. 714) Prohibits the use of funds to close or relocate a Rural Development office unless the Secretary determines the cost effectiveness and/or enhancement of program delivery. (Sec. 715) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to close or relocate the FDA Division of Pharmaceutical Analysis in St. Louis, Missouri, outside the city or county limits. (Sec. 716) Appropriates funds for Rural Development program purposes in communities suffering from extreme outmigration that are in Empowerment Zone-designated areas. (Sec. 717) Limits funds made available in FY2010 or preceding fiscal years under P.L. 480 to reimburse the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) for the release of certain commodities under the Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act. (Sec. 718) Appropriates funds for a grant to the National Center for Natural Products Research for construction or renovation to carry out the research objectives of the natural products research grant issued by the FDA. (Sec. 719) Makes funds available in the current fiscal year for agricultural management assistance under the Federal Crop Insurance Act and for specified conservation programs under the Food Security Act of 1985 until expended for obligations made in the current fiscal year. (Sec. 720) Prohibits fund use under this Act by any executive branch entity to produce a prepackaged news story for U.S. broadcast or distribution unless it contains audio or text notice that it was produced or funded by such executive entity. (Sec. 721) Limits funds to carry out the environmental quality incentives program under the Food Security Act of 1985. Prohibits the use of CCC funds for dam rehabilitation under the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act. Reduces the maximum amount of FY2010 funds available for domestic food assistance programs under the Act of August 24, 1935, before amounts in excess of such maximum must be transferred to carry out the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act. Limits funds to carry out the fresh fruit and vegetable program until October 1, 2010. Rescinds specified unobligated amounts for domestic food assistance programs under the Act of August 24, 1935. (Sec. 722) Makes eligible for economic development and job creation assistance under the Rural Electrification Act in the same manner as a borrower under such Act any former Rural Utilities Service borrower that has repaid or prepaid an insured, direct or guaranteed loan under such Act, or any not-for-profit utility that is eligible to receive an insured or direct loan under such Act. (Sec. 723) Appropriates funds for an agricultural pest facility in Hawaii. (Sec. 724) Appropriates funds to develop and test new food products to improve the nutritional delivery of humanitarian food assistance under the McGovern-Dole and the P.L. 480 (title II) programs. (Sec. 725) Prohibits the Department from using funds under this Act to implement the risk-based inspection program in any location until the Office of Inspector General of the Department has reported to the Food Safety and Inspection Service and appropriate congressional committees regarding the data used in the program's development. (Sec. 726) Directs the Secretary, until receipt of the 2010 decennial Census, to consider: (1) the unincorporated area of Los Osos, California, Imperial, California, and the Harrisville Fire District, Rhode Island, eligible for rural water and waste disposal loans and grants; (2) the unincorporated community of Thermalito in Butte County, California, and Nogales, Arizona, eligible for rural housing loans and grants; and (3) Lumberton, North Carolina, and Sanford, North Carolina eligible for rural community facilities loans and grants. Authorizes the Secretary, until receipt of the 2010 decennial Census, to fund certain rural community facility projects for communities and municipal districts and areas in Connecticut, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island that applied for funding-eligible projects with the appropriate Rural Development field offices prior to August 1, 2009. (Sec. 727) Appropriates funds for the Bill Emerson National Hunger Fellowship Program and the Mickey Leland International Hunger Fellowship Program. (Sec. 728) Appropriates funds for: (1) the Wisconsin Department of Agriculture, Trade, and Consumer Protection; (2) the Vermont Agency of Agriculture, Foods, and Markets; (3) development of a national carbon inventory and accounting system prototype for forestry and agriculture; (4) the International Food Protection Training Institute; and (5) the Center for Foodborne Illness Research and Prevention. (Sec. 729) Directs the Natural Resources Conservation Service to provide financial and technical assistance through the Watershed and Flood Prevention Operations program to carry out: (1) the Alameda Creek Watershed Project in Alameda County, California; (2) the Hurricane Katrina-Related Watershed Restoration project in Jackson County, Mississippi; (3) the Pidcock-Mill Creeks Watershed project in Bucks County, Pennsylvania; (4) the Farmington River Restoration project in Litchfield County, Connecticut; (5) the Lake Oscawana Management and Restoration project in Putnam County, New York; (6) the Richland Creek Reservoir in Paulding County, Georgia; (7) the Pocasset River Floodplain Management Project in Rhode Island; (8) the East Locust Creek Watershed Plan Revision in Missouri; (9) the Little Otter Creek Watershed project in Missouri; (10) the DuPage County Watershed project in Illinois; (11) the Dunloup Creek Watershed Project in Fayette and Raleigh Counties, West Virginia; (12) the Dry Creek Watershed project in California; and (13) the Upper Clark Fork Watershed project in Montana. (Sec. 730) Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act regarding the program for at-risk school children to: (1) make Connecticut, Nevada, Wisconsin, and the District of Columbia program participants; and (2) increase the total number of program states from 10 to 13. (Sec. 731) Prohibits, regarding the specialty crop research initiative, funds from being used to prohibit the provision of certain in-kind support from nonfederal sources. (Sec. 732) Makes unobligated balances for salaries and expenses for the Farm Service Agency and the Rural Development mission area under this Act available for information technology expenses through September 30, 2011. (Sec. 733) Authorizes the Secretary to permit a state agency to use funds provided in this Act to exceed a specified maximum amount of liquid concentrate infant formula when issuing liquid infant formula to participants. (Sec. 734) Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to exclude combat pay from household income in calculating a child's eligibility for free or reduced price meals under the school lunch program. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to require states to exclude combat pay from family income in making eligibility determinations under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC). (Sec. 735) Appropriates funds to obtain and add to an anhydrous ammonia fertilizer nurse tank a substance to reduce the amount of methamphetamine produced from anhydrous ammonia removed from the nurse tank. (Sec. 736) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used for first-class travel by employees of agencies funded under this Act in contravention of the Federal Travel Regulation System. (Sec. 737) Requires certain agencies providing international food assistance to provide the appropriate congressional committees with specified cost-savings alternatives. (Sec. 738) Appropriates funds to the Kansas Farm Bureau Foundation for workforce development initiatives to address rural out-migration. (Sec. 739) Appropriates funds to the Farm Service Agency for a pilot program to demonstrate the use of new technologies that increase the growth rate of reforested hardwood trees on private non-industrial forests lands, enrolling lands on the coast of the Gulf of Mexico that were damaged by Hurricane Katrina in 2005. (Sec. 740) Directs the FDA Commissioner (Commissioner) to establish review groups to recommend solutions for the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of: (1) rare diseases; and (2) neglected diseases of the developing world. Directs the Commissioner to report to Congress regarding such groups' recommendations. (Sec. 741) Appropriates funds for: (1) direct reimbursement payments for geographically disadvantaged farmers or ranchers; and (2) compensation to durum wheat producers for fungicide costs to control Fusarium head blight (wheat scab). (Sec. 742) Rescinds unobligated amounts for training and education programs under the supplemental nutrition assistance program (formerly known as the food stamp program). (Sec. 743) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to establish or implement a rule allowing U.S. importation of processed poultry or processed poultry products from the People's Republic of China (PRC) unless the Secretary notifies Congress that the Department will: (1) not provide preferential consideration to PRC applications to export poultry or poultry products to the United States; (2) conduct audits of inspection systems and on-site reviews of slaughter and processing facilities, laboratories and other control operations before any Chinese facilities are certified as eligible to ship poultry or poultry products to the United States; (3) implement an increased level of port of entry re-inspection; (4) establish and conduct an information sharing program with other countries importing processed poultry or processed poultry products from the PRC; (5) make lists of certified export facilities in the PRC and sanitary on-site inspection information publicly available; and (6) report to the appropriate congressional committees. Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to promulgate any proposed or final rule allowing U.S. importation of poultry slaughtered or poultry products produced from poultry slaughtered in the PRC unless such rule is promulgated in accordance with Executive Order 12866. (Sec. 744) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to inspect horses for slaughter purposes. (Sec. 745) Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act and the Trade Act of 1974 to include multiyear assistance/multiyear production loss coverage under the supplemental agricultural disaster assistance programs. (Sec. 746) Provides that if a school is closed for at least five consecutive days during a pandemic influenza emergency in FY2010 each household containing at least one member who is an eligible child attending such school shall be eligible to receive specified assistance pursuant to a state-approved plan. (Sec. 747) Requires that certain projects intended for nonprofit entities be awarded under an open competition. (Sec. 748) Appropriates funds for purchases of cheese and other dairy products to assist dairy producers who have suffered economic losses. (Sec. 749) Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to: (1) extend the waiver of the use of weighted averages for nutrient analysis of menu items and foods under the school lunch or school breakfast programs through September 30, 2010; (2) extend state food safety inspection audit and reporting requirements, and the requirement that the Secretary audit such reports, through 2010; (3) extend funding for the summer food service program and other year-round feeding programs for children in California through FY2010; (4) extend funding for administrative training for, and related state supervision of, school meal programs through October 1, 2009; and (5) extend funding for the clearinghouse that provides information to nongovernmental groups that assist low-income individuals or communities regarding food assistance and self-help activities through FY2010. Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out demonstration projects to develop methods of providing access to food for children in urban and rural areas during the summer months; (2) provide for an independent evaluation of such projects; and (3) report annually to the appropriate congressional committees regarding such projects. Provides project funding as of October 1, 2009. Directs the Secretary to provide grants to state agencies administering the national school lunch program with the lowest rates of children certified for free: (1) to improve such rates; and (2) for related administrative assistance. Provides funding as of October 1, 2009. Directs the Secretary, in carrying out the WIC program, to provide performance bonus payments to state agencies that demonstrate: (1) the highest proportion of breastfed infants; or (2) the greatest improvement in proportion of breastfed infants. Provides funding as of October 1, 2009. Directs the Secretary to make payments to state educational agencies for grants to eligible school food authorities for equipment purchases. Provides funding as of October 1, 2009. Provides grants to state agencies administering the child and adult care food program to improve the health and nutrition of children in child care settings. Provides funding as of October 1, 2009.</summary>
</bill>
