<bill session="112" type="h" number="4108" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Energy Jobs Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase and extend the credit for qualifying advanced energy projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="258"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="940"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2204"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/29/2012--Introduced.
Clean Energy Jobs Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow additional allocations of credits under the qualifying advanced energy project (i.e., the project for the production of renewable and alternative energy resources) in 2012. Limits or repeals certain tax benefits for major integrated oil companies (defined as companies with annual gross receipts over $1 billion and an average daily worldwide production of crude oil of at least 500,000 barrels), including: (1) the foreign tax credit; (2) the tax deduction for income attributable to oil, natural gas, or primary products thereof; (3) the tax deduction for intangible drilling and development costs; (4) the percentage depletion allowance for oil and gas wells; and (5) the tax deduction for qualified tertiary injectant expenses. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal royalty relief (suspension of royalties) for: (1) natural gas production from deep wells in shallow waters of the Gulf of Mexico; and (2) deep water oil and gas production in the Western and Central Planning Area of the Gulf (including the portion of the Eastern Planning Area encompassing whole lease blocks lying west of 87 degrees, 30 minutes west longitude). Dedicates any increased revenue generated by this Act to the reduction of a federal budget deficit or the federal debt. Provides for compliance of the budgetary effects of this Act with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
