<bill session="109" type="s" number="865" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Price-Anderson Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Price-Anderson Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to reauthorize the Price-Anderson provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2005-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4036" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-99.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-07-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="153">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 153.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Price-Anderson Amendments Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Price-Anderson Act with respect to indemnification of the licensee of an industrial or commercial nuclear power utilization or production facility, and the limitation of liability arising from nuclear incidents in excess of the level of financial protection required of the licensee. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to consider, for primary financial protection purposes, a combination of utilization or production facilities to be a single facility having a rated capacity of 100,000 electrical kilowatts or more. Defines such combination to be two or more facilities located at a single site, each of which has a rated capacity of between 100,000 and 300,000 electrical kilowatts, with a combined rated capacity of not more than 1.3 million electrical kilowatts. (Sec. 3) Extends from December 31, 2003, through December 31, 2025, NRC authority to indemnify certain licenses issued between August 30, 1954, and such date. (Sec. 4) Extends until August 1, 2023, the requirement that the NRC and the Secretary of Energy report annually to Congress on the need to continue or modify the Price-Anderson Act. (Sec. 5) Increases from $63 million to $95.8 million (adjusted for inflation) the maximum amount of the standard deferred premium that may be charged a licensee following a nuclear incident. Increases from $10 million to $15 million the maximum amount of standard deferred premium that may be charged annually. Subjects such annual maximum to adjustment for inflation.</summary>
</bill>
