<bill session="109" type="s" number="383" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Localism in Broadcasting Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to shorten the term of broadcasting licenses under the Communications Act of 1934 from 8 to 3 years, to provide better public access to broadcasters' public interest issues and programs lists and children's programming reports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1424-1425"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1425" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1665"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2005--Introduced.
Localism in Broadcasting Reform Act of 2005 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to reduce from eight to three years the term for radio or television broadcasting licenses issued by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC). Requires full FCC review of at least five percent of the applications filed each year. Requires every broadcaster to file electronically with the FCC a copy of its public interest issues and programs list and its children's programming reports within ten days after the end of each quarter. Allows a waiver of such requirement for good cause shown. Requires such list and reports to be made available on publicly accessible websites of such stations. Requires the standards for a station's license renewal to include review of the licensee's other stations (if any). Requires the FCC, within nine months after the enactment of this Act, to complete action on two specified proceedings concerning disclosure requirements and public interest obligations of television broadcast licensees.</summary>
</bill>
