<bill session="112" type="h" number="3884" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Medic Transition Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EMT Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants to State emergency medical service departments to provide for the expedited training and licensing of veterans with prior medical training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2012-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4288"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2012--Introduced.
Emergency Medic Transition Act of 2012 or the EMT Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a program of awarding grants to states to assist veterans who received and completed military emergency medical training while serving in the United States Armed Forces to become, upon their discharge or release from active duty service, state-licensed or certified emergency medical technicians. Allows such funds to be used to: (1) provide such veterans required course work and training (that takes into account, and is not duplicative of, medical course work and training already received) to satisfy emergency medical services personnel certification requirements in the civilian sector; (2) provide reimbursement for costs associated with such course work and training and with applying for licensure or certification; (3) expedite the licensing or certification process; and (4) enter into an agreement with an educational institution to provide course work and training under this Act. Requires a state, to be eligible for a grant under this Act, to demonstrate that it has a shortage of emergency medical technicians. Directs the Comptroller General to: (1) study the barriers experienced by such veterans seeking to become licensed or certified in a state as civilian health professionals; and (2) report on the results of such study, including recommendations on whether the program under this Act should be expanded to assist veterans seeking to become licensed or certified in a state as health providers other than emergency medical technicians.</summary>
</bill>
