<bill session="112" type="h" number="3807" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Guaranteed Energy Assistance Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for funding of the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP) with a dedicated revenue source consisting of a tax on offshore oil production.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2012--Introduced.
Guaranteed Energy Assistance Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on each barrel of oil extracted pursuant to any lease of federal onshore lands under the Mineral Leasing Act, the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands, or any other federal law, or any lease under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. Establishes the amount of such tax at the lesser of 50 cents per barrel or such amount as the Secretary of the Treasury estimates would result in aggregate revenue for a fiscal year equal to the excess of $5.1 billion over the amount appropriated for such fiscal year for providing assistance under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981. Establishes in the Treasury the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program Trust Fund (LIHEAP Trust Fund) to provide assistance under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981. Limits the amount of such assistance to $5.1 billion in any fiscal year. Dedicates revenues from the tax on oil under this Act to such Fund.</summary>
</bill>
