<bill session="109" type="h" number="4968" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tupac Shakur Records Release Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the expeditious disclosure of records relevant to the life and death of Tupac Amaru Shakur.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Entertainers"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="House Government Reform"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential records"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2006--Introduced.
Tupac Amaru Shakur Records Release Act of 2006 - Directs the National Archives to commence establishment of a collection of records to be known as the "Tupac Amaru Shakur Records Collection" at the National Archives. Requires the Archivist of the United States to enter into an agreement with the Tupac Amaru Shakur Center for the Arts in Stone Mountain, Georgia, or another location agreed to by the family of Tupak Shakur, for the establishment of a secondary location for a complete copy of the appropriate part of the Collection, not including physical artifacts. Instructs the National Archives to ensure the security of the records in the Collection that qualify for postponement of public disclosure pursuant to this Act. Directs the National Archives to appoint an independent Citizens Advisory Committee. Sets forth provisions for the review, identification, transmission to the National Archives, and public disclosure of records related to the life and death of Tupac Amaru Shakur, by Government offices. Sets forth provisions for the postponement of public disclosure of related records or particular information in such records.. Sets forth requirements for the review of all related records for public disclosure or postponement of public disclosure by the Archivist. Grants Presidential authority over such disclosure or postponement of executive branch related records or information, or of any information in a related record obtained or developed solely within the executive branch. Requires the Archivist to: (1) provide written notice to the President and Congress of the Archivist's intention to terminate activities under this Act; and (2) upon completing activities required under this Act, to submit to the President and Congress a written certification that the activities of the Archivist are complete.</summary>
</bill>
