<bill session="113" type="h" number="1907" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nurse Staffing Standards for Patient Safety and Quality Care Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish direct care registered nurse-to-patient staffing ratio requirements in hospitals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Nurse Staffing Standards for Patient Safety and Quality Care Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require hospitals to implement a staffing plan that includes a minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratio by unit, adjustments above the minimum ratio under appropriate circumstances, and compliance with minimum licensed practical nurse staffing requirements. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a national acuity tool to establish nurse staffing requirements above minimum ratios. Directs the Secretary to adjust Medicare payments to hospitals to cover additional costs incurred in providing services to Medicare beneficiaries that are attributable to compliance with such ratios. Authorizes a nurse to object to, or refuse to participate in, any activity, policy, practice, assignment or task if in good faith it would violate minimum ratios under this Act or if the nurse is not prepared by education, training, or experience to fulfill the assignment without compromising the safety of any patient or jeopardizing the license of the nurse. Prohibits a hospital from: (1) taking specified actions against a nurse based on the nurse's refusal to accept an assignment for such a reason; or (2) discriminating against any patient, employee, or any other individual for good faith complaints or grievances relating to the care, services, or conditions of the hospital or of any affiliated or related facilities. Prohibits actions by hospitals to restrain such rights. Sets forth enforcement provisions. Applies provisions of this Act through federal health programs, including Medicare, Medicaid, and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health benefits programs. Includes stipends in the nurse workforce loan repayment and scholarship program. Expands the nurse retention grant program to authorize programs to implement nurse preceptorship and mentorship projects.</summary>
</bill>
