<bill session="109" type="h" number="4415" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Checking Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a fair order of posting checks and deposits to prevent unjust enrichment of financial institutions from fees that accrue only by virtue of the order used by the institution for posting checks and deposits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Consumer Checking Fairness Act - Amends the Expedited Funds Availability Act to require a depository institution to post checks presented for payment against a checking account used primarily for personal, family, or household purposes after the close of any business day in the numerical order of the checks, beginning with the lowest number. Requires customer notification and consent for a different posting order. Requires a depository institution to credit all deposits to such account after the close of any business day before debiting any check drawn on the account and presented for payment. Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to prescribe implementing regulations.</summary>
</bill>
