<bill session="109" type="h" number="4733" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stand Up for America Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Office of the Congressional Trade Enforcer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2006-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Currency devaluation"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Senate Finance"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Veto"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2006--Introduced.
Stand Up for America Act of 2006 - Establishes in the legislative branch an Office of the Congressional Trade Enforcer to ensure compliance by U.S. trading partners with international trade agreements to which the United States is a party. Establishes the Office of Market Access Assistance within such Office to provide technical and legal assistance and advice to eligible small businesses enabling them to prepare and file petitions (other than those that are frivolous) under the Trade Act of 1974. Amends the Act to extend indefinitely (currently, 1995 only) the Congressional Trade Enforcer's (currently, U.S. Trade Representative's) mandate to identify and report on trade expansion priorities. Requires the report to identify priority foreign country practices of currency manipulation. Requires the Trade Representative, before initiating an investigation (as under current law), to seek consultations with each foreign country identified in the report as engaging in priority foreign country practices, for the purpose of reaching a satisfactory resolution of such priority practices. Requires initiation of an investigation only if a satisfactory resolution of such practices has not been reached. Requires the Congressional Trade Enforcer: (1) to identify and report to Congress on priority foreign trade practices of the People's Republic of China (PRC), the Russian Federation, and the European Union; and (2) as part of the report's analysis, to consider violations by the PRC and the Russian Federation of World Trade Organization (WTO) rules regarding the protection of intellectual property rights, violations by the PRC of WTO rules regarding the manipulation of currency, and violations by the European Union of WTO rules regarding discriminatory regional trade agreements.</summary>
</bill>
