<bill session="113" type="h" number="2481" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28T17:25:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-28T17:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans G.I. Bill Enrollment Clarification Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Veterans Economic Opportunity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans Economic Opportunity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to codify and improve the election requirements for the receipt of educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To make certain improvements in the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-08-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-11T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 113-207.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-11T13:27:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="152">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 152.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6794-6800" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2481.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2013-10-28T17:25:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6794-6797" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28T17:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Introduced.
Veterans G.I. Bill Enrollment Clarification Act of 2013 - Allows individuals to elect to convert their educational assistance to the post-9/11 veterans' educational assistance program if, as of August 1, 2009, they meet specified conditions with respect to their entitlements and elections under the all-volunteer force educational assistance program or certain other educational programs for professional military, selected reserve, or reserve component members. Conditions such post-9/11 program eligibility on the individual meeting the requirements for the post-9/11 program as of the date of election. Sets forth transitional rules with respect the transfer or revocation of entitlements from a previous assistance program after an election to convert to the post-9/11 program. Requires certain assistance to remain available to individuals under their previous program if it is not available under the post-9/11 program. Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), if an individual submits an election that the Secretary determines is against the interests of the individual, to make an alternative election on the individual's behalf. Allows such individual, during a specified period, to modify or revoke the Secretary's alternative selection.</summary>
</bill>
