<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1509" updated="2013-07-19T23:09:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-14T13:38:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-14T13:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1722) to improve teleworking in executive agencies by developing a telework program that allows employees to telework at least 20 percent of the hours worked in every 2 administrative workweeks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-535, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. House Resolution 1496 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-13T18:57:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="213">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 213.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5567-5576" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1509.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 184 (Roll no. 437).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5575-5576" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-07-14T13:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="438" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 238 - 180 (Roll no. 438).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5567" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1496"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="1722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1722) to improve teleworking in executive agencies by developing a telework program that allows employees to telework at least 20 percent of the hours worked in every 2 administrative workweeks.</summary>
</bill>
