<bill session="112" type="s" number="2034" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to human rights abuses committed against the people of Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2101"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2012--Introduced.
Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 - Directs the President to submit, and update every 180 days and as new information becomes available, the following lists to Congress: (1) Syrian government officials or persons acting on behalf of that government who are responsible for or complicit in the commission of serious human rights abuses against Syrian citizens or their family members, regardless of whether such abuses occurred in Syria; (2) persons who knowingly transfer or facilitate the transfer of goods or technologies (weapons, surveillance technology, or sensitive technology) that are likely to be used by Syria to commit human rights abuses against the Syrian people; and (3) persons who engage in censorship that prohibits, limits, or penalizes the legitimate exercise of freedom of expression by Syrian citizens. Directs the President to impose specified property and finance-related sanctions on such listed persons and make them ineligible for U.S. entry. Authorizes the President to waive the listing of a person or the imposition of sanctions if in the U.S. national security interest. Prohibits the head of a federal agency from entering into or renewing a contract for the procurement of goods or services with a person (or a person owning or controlling such person) that exports sensitive technology to Syria. Authorizes the President to exempt certain products from such prohibition. Defines "sensitive technology" as hardware, software, telecommunications equipment, or any other technology that is used to: (1) restrict the free flow of unbiased information in Syria; or (2) disrupt, monitor, or otherwise restrict the speech of the Syrian people.</summary>
</bill>
