<bill session="109" type="h" number="3551" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GEAR UP &amp; GO Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 by strengthening and expanding the Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs (GEAR UP) in order to facilitate the transition of low-income high school students into post-secondary education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400130"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student enrollment"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
GEAR UP &amp; GO Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise specified requirements for Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs (GEAR UP) to facilitate the transition of low-income high school students into postsecondary education.Authorizes the Secretary of Education to carry out a GEAR UP &amp; GO grants program to provide low-income high school students participating in GEAR UP partnerships or state programs opportunities for dual/concurrent enrollment in college courses while still enrolled in high school. Provides that students in such program: (1) shall not be required to apply for admission to the institution of higher education; and (2) may receive college credit. Requires up to 25 percent of GEAR UP &amp; GO program funds to be reserved for grants to early/middle college high schools designed to provide 9th through 12th grade low-income and first-generation college students with a coherent course of study enabling them to earn simultaneously a high school diploma and college credit toward a postsecondary degree.</summary>
</bill>
