<bill session="112" type="sr" number="490" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-15">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution designating the week of September 16, 2012, as "Mitochondrial Disease Awareness Week", reaffirming the importance of an enhanced and coordinated research effort on mitochondrial diseases, and commending the National Institutes of Health for its efforts to improve the understanding of mitochondrial diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2012-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3982-3983" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-15">
      <text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6870-6871" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-11-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6870-6871" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Designates the week of September 16, 2012, as Mitochondrial Disease Awareness Week. Reaffirms the importance of an enhanced and coordinated research effort aimed at improving the understanding of primary mitochondrial diseases and the development of treatments and cures. Commends the National Institutes of Health (NIH) for its efforts to organize a symposium to improve the understanding of mitochondrial diseases and to enhance collaboration and chart a course for future mitochondrial disease research. Encourages NIH to place a greater priority on research into primary mitochondrial diseases, to continue to explore the connections between mitochondrial dysfunction and other systemic diseases, to promote collaboration and coordination among the Institutes of NIH and with other organizations, and to consider the recommendations and address research directions identified in the white paper developed from the symposium.</summary>
</bill>
