<bill session="113" type="s" number="1053" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:34-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hospice Evaluation and Legitimate Payment Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to strengthen and protect Medicare hospice programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3852" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Hospice Evaluation and Legitimate Payment Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to the face-to-face encounter framework in hospice care. Allows a clinical nurse specialist, physician assistant, or other health professional (in addition to a hospice physician or a nurse practitioner, as under current law) to conduct the face-to-face encounter with the individual to determine continued eligibility for hospice care before the first 60-day (currently 180-day) recertification period and each subsequent recertification. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Medicare Hospital Payment Reform demonstration program to test any revisions to the methodology for determining payment rates for routine home care and other hospice care services. Sets at every three years the frequency of surveys of certified hospice programs.</summary>
</bill>
