<bill session="109" type="h" number="2360" updated="2013-07-19T19:25:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2006, Homeland Security</title>
    <title type="popular">Homeland Security Department FY2006 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Homeland Security Grant Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-13T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-79, by Mr. Rogers (KY).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-13T14:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="38">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 38.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-16T20:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 278 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2360 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 278 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 278.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3346-3405" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3367, H3376, H3383-3384" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3384-3385, H3386-3387" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3387, H3388-3389" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3389, H3390" label="text of title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3390, H3391-3393" label="text of title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2360 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 278 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul E. Gillmor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2360.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hostetler amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T12:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Souder amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the LoBiondo amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>RESERVATION OF POINT OF ORDER WITHDRAWN - Mr. Rogers of Kentucky withdrew his reservation of a point of order and the Committee of the Whole continued with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committe of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Musgrave amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sabo amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Menendez amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Menendez amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Menendez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Menendez amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Mica raised a point of order against the language on page 17, beginning with the colon on line 2, through "intent" on line 11. Mr. Mica stated that the language sought to change existing law and violated clause 2 of rule XXI. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the LaTourette amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Shuster raised a point of order against the language on page 36, line 19, beginning with "and" through "funds" on line 22. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) asked unanimous consent that the bill through page 55, line 12 be considered read, printed in the Congressional Record and be open for amendment. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tancredo amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tancredo amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that theayes had prevailed. Mr. Sabo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Tancredo amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tom Davis (VA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Poe amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Poe demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Poe amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Meeks (NY) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Meeks (NY) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Meeks (NY) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Meeks (NY) amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tiahrt amendment under the five-minute rule pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>VACATING PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Poe asked unanimous consent to vacate his request for a recorded vote on his amendment and allow the voice vote, earlier called for the noes, to stand. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Obey amendment under the five-minute rule pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Obey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rogers (KY) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Obey amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of the amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2360.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3404" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-05-17T18:03:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="180" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 424 - 1 (Roll no. 180).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Gregg with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-83.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="129">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 129.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7947-7974, S7976-7980" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7948-7959" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-12">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8093-8110, S8111-8131" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8154, S8179, S8179-8204" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8248-8290" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2005-07-14" how="roll" result="pass" roll="189" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 1. Record Vote Number: 189.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Gregg; Cochran; Stevens; Specter; Domenici; Shelby; Craig; Bennett; Allard; Byrd; Inouye; Leahy; Mikulski; Kohl; Murray; Reid; Feinstein.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8290" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) moved that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8395-8401, H8405" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sabo moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8395" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8395" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Sabo motion to instruct conferees. Instructions seek to direct the managers on the part of the House to insist on the headings and appropriation accounts in Title III of the House-passed bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T11:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the Sabo motion to instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T11:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sabo motion to instruct conferees, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sabo demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 227 (Roll no. 497).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8405, H8406" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Rogers (KY), Wamp, Latham, Emerson, Sweeney, Kolbe, Istook, LaHood, Crenshaw, Carter, Lewis (CA), Sabo, Price (NC), Serrano, Roybal-Allard, Bishop (GA), Berry, Edwards, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 109-241 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8585-8626" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) brought up conference report H. Rept. 109-241 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 474.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8695-8706" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T19:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2360.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8705" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2005-10-06T20:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="512" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 347 - 70 (Roll no. 512).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-10-07" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11275-11279" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-10-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-10-18">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-10-18" type="public" number="109-90">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-90.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP14" subcommittee="Department of Homeland Security" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="278"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="474"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Allegiance"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Apples"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Chief information officers"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="College libraries"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Earth movements and building"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Landslides"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military advisers"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Oaths"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Patrol aircraft"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h128"/>
    <amendment number="h129"/>
    <amendment number="h130"/>
    <amendment number="h131"/>
    <amendment number="h132"/>
    <amendment number="h133"/>
    <amendment number="h134"/>
    <amendment number="h135"/>
    <amendment number="h136"/>
    <amendment number="h137"/>
    <amendment number="h138"/>
    <amendment number="h139"/>
    <amendment number="h140"/>
    <amendment number="h141"/>
    <amendment number="h142"/>
    <amendment number="h143"/>
    <amendment number="h144"/>
    <amendment number="h145"/>
    <amendment number="s1069"/>
    <amendment number="s1070"/>
    <amendment number="s1072"/>
    <amendment number="s1073"/>
    <amendment number="s1074"/>
    <amendment number="s1075"/>
    <amendment number="s1076"/>
    <amendment number="s1080"/>
    <amendment number="s1104"/>
    <amendment number="s1105"/>
    <amendment number="s1106"/>
    <amendment number="s1107"/>
    <amendment number="s1108"/>
    <amendment number="s1109"/>
    <amendment number="s1110"/>
    <amendment number="s1111"/>
    <amendment number="s1112"/>
    <amendment number="s1113"/>
    <amendment number="s1114"/>
    <amendment number="s1115"/>
    <amendment number="s1116"/>
    <amendment number="s1117"/>
    <amendment number="s1118"/>
    <amendment number="s1119"/>
    <amendment number="s1120"/>
    <amendment number="s1121"/>
    <amendment number="s1122"/>
    <amendment number="s1123"/>
    <amendment number="s1124"/>
    <amendment number="s1125"/>
    <amendment number="s1126"/>
    <amendment number="s1127"/>
    <amendment number="s1128"/>
    <amendment number="s1129"/>
    <amendment number="s1130"/>
    <amendment number="s1131"/>
    <amendment number="s1132"/>
    <amendment number="s1133"/>
    <amendment number="s1134"/>
    <amendment number="s1135"/>
    <amendment number="s1136"/>
    <amendment number="s1137"/>
    <amendment number="s1138"/>
    <amendment number="s1139"/>
    <amendment number="s1140"/>
    <amendment number="s1141"/>
    <amendment number="s1142"/>
    <amendment number="s1143"/>
    <amendment number="s1144"/>
    <amendment number="s1145"/>
    <amendment number="s1146"/>
    <amendment number="s1147"/>
    <amendment number="s1148"/>
    <amendment number="s1149"/>
    <amendment number="s1150"/>
    <amendment number="s1151"/>
    <amendment number="s1152"/>
    <amendment number="s1153"/>
    <amendment number="s1154"/>
    <amendment number="s1155"/>
    <amendment number="s1156"/>
    <amendment number="s1157"/>
    <amendment number="s1158"/>
    <amendment number="s1159"/>
    <amendment number="s1160"/>
    <amendment number="s1161"/>
    <amendment number="s1162"/>
    <amendment number="s1163"/>
    <amendment number="s1164"/>
    <amendment number="s1165"/>
    <amendment number="s1166"/>
    <amendment number="s1167"/>
    <amendment number="s1168"/>
    <amendment number="s1169"/>
    <amendment number="s1170"/>
    <amendment number="s1171"/>
    <amendment number="s1172"/>
    <amendment number="s1173"/>
    <amendment number="s1174"/>
    <amendment number="s1175"/>
    <amendment number="s1176"/>
    <amendment number="s1177"/>
    <amendment number="s1178"/>
    <amendment number="s1179"/>
    <amendment number="s1180"/>
    <amendment number="s1181"/>
    <amendment number="s1182"/>
    <amendment number="s1183"/>
    <amendment number="s1184"/>
    <amendment number="s1185"/>
    <amendment number="s1186"/>
    <amendment number="s1187"/>
    <amendment number="s1188"/>
    <amendment number="s1189"/>
    <amendment number="s1190"/>
    <amendment number="s1191"/>
    <amendment number="s1192"/>
    <amendment number="s1193"/>
    <amendment number="s1194"/>
    <amendment number="s1195"/>
    <amendment number="s1196"/>
    <amendment number="s1197"/>
    <amendment number="s1198"/>
    <amendment number="s1199"/>
    <amendment number="s1200"/>
    <amendment number="s1201"/>
    <amendment number="s1202"/>
    <amendment number="s1203"/>
    <amendment number="s1204"/>
    <amendment number="s1205"/>
    <amendment number="s1206"/>
    <amendment number="s1207"/>
    <amendment number="s1208"/>
    <amendment number="s1209"/>
    <amendment number="s1210"/>
    <amendment number="s1211"/>
    <amendment number="s1212"/>
    <amendment number="s1213"/>
    <amendment number="s1214"/>
    <amendment number="s1215"/>
    <amendment number="s1216"/>
    <amendment number="s1217"/>
    <amendment number="s1218"/>
    <amendment number="s1219"/>
    <amendment number="s1220"/>
    <amendment number="s1221"/>
    <amendment number="s1222"/>
    <amendment number="s1223"/>
    <amendment number="s1224"/>
    <amendment number="s1225"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/18/2005--Public Law.
Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006 - Title I: Departmental Management and Operations - Makes appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for FY2006 for: (1) the Office of the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) and executive management; (2) the Office of Screening Coordination and Operations; (3) Office of the Under Secretary for Management; (4) the Office of the Chief Financial Officer; (5) the Office of the Chief Information Officer; (6) analysis and operations; and (7) the Office of Inspector General. Title II: Security, Enforcement, and Investigations - Makes FY2006 appropriations for: (1) the U.S. Visitor and Immigrant Status Indicator Technology (U.S.-VISIT) project; (2) Customs and Border Protection (CBP), including customs and border protection automated systems, air and marine interdiction, and construction; (3) Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE); (4) the Federal Protective Service, including immigration and customs enforcement automated systems, and construction; (4) the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), including surface transportation security, transportation vetting and credentialing, transportation security support, and Federal Air Marshals; (5) the Coast Guard, including environmental compliance and restoration, Coast Guard Reserve training, acquisition, construction, and improvements, alteration of bridges, research, development, test, and evaluation, and retired pay; and (6) the U.S. Secret Service, including acquisition, construction, and improvements. Title III: Preparedness and Recovery - Makes FY2006 appropriations for: (1) the Office of the Under Secretary for Preparedness, the Office of the Chief Medical Officer, and the Office of National Capital Regional Coordination; (2) the Office for Domestic Preparedness, including grants to state and local governments for terrorism prevention activities, firefighter assistance grants, and emergency management performance grants, the U.S. Fire Administration and training, infrastructure protection and information security, and the Counterterrorism Fund; (3) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), including preparedness, mitigation, response, and recovery, public health programs, disaster relief, the disaster assistance direct loan program, the Flood Map Modernization Fund, the National Flood Insurance Fund, the National Flood Mitigation Fund, the National Pre-Disaster Mitigation Fund, and an emergency food and shelter program. States that the aggregate charges assessed during FY2006 for the Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program shall not be less than 100% of the necessary amounts anticipated by DHS. Title IV: Research and Development, Training, and Services - Makes FY2006 appropriations for: (1) U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services; (2) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, including acquisition, construction, and improvements; and (3) the Office of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, including science and technology research, development, acquisition, and operations. Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 504) Prohibits the use of appropriated funds to make payments to the Working Capital Fund, except for certain activities and amounts. (Sec. 506) Deems funds made available by this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY2006 until the enactment of an Act authorizing such activities for FY2006. (Sec. 507) Directs the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to lead the federal law enforcement training accreditation process, to include representatives from the federal law enforcement community and nonfederal accreditation experts involved in law enforcement training, to continue the implementation of measuring and assessing the quality and effectiveness of federal law enforcement training programs, facilities, and instructors. (Sec. 510) Requires the Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to schedule basic and/or advanced law enforcement training at all four training facilities under Center control to ensure that they are operated at the highest capacity throughout the fiscal year. (Sec. 512) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act in contravention of the Buy American Act. (Sec. 513) Directs the Secretary to ensure that DHS is in compliance with the requirement in the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005 that the Secretary amend Security Directives and programs to at least triple the percentage of cargo inspected on passenger aircraft. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees biweekly beginning on October 1, 2005, on any reason for noncompliance. Directs the Secretary to take all possible actions, including the procurement of certified systems to inspect and screen air cargo on passenger aircraft, to increase the level of air cargo inspected beyond that mandated. (Sec. 515) Applies TSA acquisition management system to the acquisition of services, as well as equipment, supplies, and materials. (Sec. 516) Transfers authority to conduct background investigations from the Office of Personnel Management to DHS. (Sec. 517) Exempts funds appropriated under the State and Local Programs heading under Title III of this Act from the Cash Management Improvement Act of 1990. (Sec. 518) Prohibits the obligation of funds for deployment or implementation of the Secure Flight program or other follow on or successor passenger prescreening program, on other than a test basis, until the Secretary has certified and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) has reported that specified requirements have been met. (Sec. 519) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act to amend the oath of allegiance required for naturalization under the Immigration and Nationality Act. (Sec. 520) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this Act to process or approve a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A-76 for services provided as of June 1, 2004, by employees of the DHS Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services who are known as Immigration Information Officers, Contact Representatives, or Investigative Assistants. (Sec. 521) Prohibits the availability of funds appropriated by this Act to maintain the U.S. Secret Service as anything but a distinct entity within DHS. Prohibits the use of such funds to merge the Secret Service with any other DHS function, cause any personnel and operational elements to report to an individual other than the Director of the U.S. Secret Service, or cause the Director to report directly to any individual other than the Secretary. (Sec. 522) Prohibits the availability of funds appropriated to the U.S. Secret Service for the protection of the head of a federal agency other than the Secretary, unless the Director is fully reimbursed. (Sec. 523) Names the DHS processing and data storage facilities at the John C. Stennis Space Center the National Center for Critical Information Processing and Storage. (Sec. 524) Directs the Secretary to develop standards and protocols for increasing the use of explosive detection equipment to screen air cargo when appropriate. (Sec. 525) Directs the TSA to utilize existing checked baggage explosive detection equipment and screeners to screen cargo carried on passenger aircraft to the greatest extent practicable at each airport. Directs TSA to report monthly to specified congressional committees on the amount of cargo carried on passenger aircraft that was screened. (Sec. 526) Prohibits the use of any funds available for the transportation worker identification credential program to develop a personalized system that is decentralized or a card production capability that does not utilize an existing government card production facility. (Sec. 527) Rescinds $78,630,689 for integrated Deepwater System 110-123-foot patrol boats conversion. Reappropriates such funds for the service life extension of the current Island Class patrol boat fleet and accelerated design and and production of the Fast Response Cutter. (Sec. 528) Requires the Secretary to utilize the Transportation Security Clearinghouse as the central identity management system for the deployment and operation of the registered traveler program and the transportation worker identification credential program for the purposes of collecting and aggregating biometric data necessary for background vetting. (Sec. 529) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act by any person but the privacy officer appointed under the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to alter, direct that changes be made to, delay, or prohibit the transmission of a privacy officer report to Congress. (Sec. 530) Prohibits the availability of any funds to pay the salary of any employee serving as a contracting officer's technical representative (COTR), or anyone acting in a similar or like capacity, who has not received COTR training. (Sec. 531) Makes any funds appropriated or transferred to TSA "Aviation Security" and "Administration" in FY2004 and 2005, which are recovered or deobligated, available only for procurement and installation of explosive detection systems for air cargo, baggage, and checkpoint screening systems. (Sec. 532) Requires the Secretary to survey all ports of entry in the United States and designate an airport as a port of entry in each state that does not have one. (Sec. 533) Directs the Secretary to consider eligible under the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Public Assistance Program the costs sufficient to enable the City of Paso Robles, California, to repair and upgrade all elements of the Carnegie Library damaged (or undamaged) by the 2003 San Simeon earthquake so that the library is brought into conformance with all local code requirements for new construction. (Sec. 534) Directs the Secretary to consider eligible under the FEMA Public Assistance Program costs for the damage to canals and wooden flumes, incurred during a 1996 storm and subsequent mudslide in El Dorado County, California, to the El Dorado Irrigation District, based on 50% of the costs of the Improved Project for the Mill Creek to Bull Creek tunnel proposed in a November 2001 Carleton Engineering Report. (Sec. 535) Directs the Secretary to consider eligible under the FEMA Public Assistance Program the costs sufficient to enable replacement of research and education materials and library collections, and for other non-covered losses, at the University of Hawaii Manoa campus, Hawaii, resulting from an October 30, 2004, flood event. (Sec. 536) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize H2A visas to nonimmigrant aliens coming temporarily to the United States to perform the pressing of apples for cider on a farm. (Sec. 537) Directs the Secretary to provide that each office within DHS that handles documents marked as Sensitive Security Information (SSI) has at least one employee with authority to coordinate and make determinations on the agency's behalf that such documents meet the criteria for marking as SSI. Requires reports to Congress of DHS SSI policies, auditing, and accountability. (Sec. 538) Appropriates $40 million for discretionary grants to states to implement the REAL ID Act of 2005, subject to congressional approval of the implementation plan. Earmarks a portion of such funds for availability to states for pilot projects on integrating hardware, software, and information management systems. (Sec. 539) Extends the authorization of the Working Capital Fund through FY2006. (Sec. 540) Directs the Secretary to impose a fee for the registered traveler program. (Sec. 541) Extends liability protection to certain persons who report a situation, activity or incident, if they have completed a security awareness training course approved by or operating under a cooperative agreement with DHS, and are enrolled in a program recognized or acknowledged by an Information Sharing and Analysis Center. (Sec. 542) Rescinds $15 million from the unobligated balances available in the DHS Working Capital Fund. (Sec. 543) Rescinds $5.5 million from unobligated balances previously appropriated for TSA "Aviation Security." (Sec. 544) Rescinds $6,369,118 in appropriations for the Coast Guard. (Sec. 545) Rescinds $8 million from unobligated balances previously appropriated to the Counterterrorism Fund. (Sec. 546) Rescinds $20 million from unobligated balances previously appropriated to Science and Technology for research, development, acquisition, and operations. (Sec. 547) Declares that an airport operator shall not be liable for any claims for damages filed in state or federal court relating to: (1) its decision to apply or not to apply for the security screening pilot program; and (2) any act of negligence, gross negligence, or intentional wrongdoing by a qualified private screening company (or its employees) while acting under a DHS contract, or by federal employees providing passenger and property security screening services at the airport. States that an airport operator shall not be relieved from liability for its own acts or omissions related to its security responsibilities. Prohibits an airport operator from relieving any qualified private screening company or its employees from any liability related to its own acts of negligence, gross negligence, or intentional wrongdoing. (Sec. 548) Requires the weekly disaster relief report required by the Second Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act to Meet Immediate Needs Arising From the Consequences of Hurricane Katrina, 2005 to include specified details on certain allocations, obligations, expenditures, and credit card purchases.</summary>
</bill>
