<bill session="110" type="s" number="3466" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Job Access and Reverse Commute Program Improvements Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the job access and reverse commute program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8278-8279"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the aged"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2008--Introduced.
Job Access and Reverse Commute Program Improvements Act of 2008 - Revises the job access and reverse commute (JARC) program to authorize a state to accept a single combined application for a project funded from at least two of the following programs that provide individuals with transportation to and from a job: (1) the JARC program; (2) the elderly and disabled specialized transit program; (3) the new freedom program (for disabled workers); and (4) any other program the Secretary deems appropriate. Makes eligible for JARC formula grant funding the subsidizing of costs associated with the transportation of low income high school students and young adults to career or technical education, job training, or apprenticeship programs. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation, at state request, to waive or streamline JARC program reporting and certification requirements, provided program goals are met. Directs the Secretary to study the feasibility of eliminating, revising, or reducing frequency of collection for any reporting or certification requirements relating to the JARC formula grant program, particularly examining the burden on and needs of nonprofit organizations that receive funding and are unaccustomed to Federal Transit Administration (FTA) regulations. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out a grant pilot program to: (1) improve education and employment related transportation activities for eligible teens and young adults; (2) evaluate streamlined reporting and certification requirements; and (3) support more comprehensive projects integrated with other federal, state, and local transportation and human service programs, while ensuring the paperwork burden is minimized. Requires the Secretary to continue and expand JARC technical assistance activities so that the Department of Transportation supports various specified efforts, including those that act as an information clearinghouse and information network.</summary>
</bill>
