<bill session="113" type="h" number="707" updated="2013-11-02T06:24:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Short Term Retention for Agricultural Workers Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to simplify and rename the H-2C worker program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
Short Term Retention for Agricultural Workers Act of 2013 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to rename H-2A nonimmigrant temporary agricultural workers as STRAW workers. Includes dairy or ranch workers in such category. Eliminates the 50% rule requiring employers to agree to accept all qualified U.S. workers until 50% of the certified employment period has been completed. Provides that an employer shall not be required to pay a wage rate greater than the greatest of the federal, state, and local minimum wage rates. Prohibits the Legal Services Corporation from providing legal assistance for any alien and prohibits providing financial assistance to any person or entity that provides legal assistance for any alien, unless: (1) the alien is present in the United States when the legal assistance is provided, and (2) the parties to the dispute have attempted mediation or other non-binding dispute resolution of all issues. Sets forth STRAW worker provisions regarding housing and length of U.S. stay. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide each nonimmigrant agricultural worker with an identification card that contains: (1) an encrypted, machine-readable, electronic identification strip that is unique to such alien; (2) biometric identifiers, including fingerprints and a digital photograph; and (3) physical security features designed to prevent tampering, counterfeiting, or duplication. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a trust fund to pay for: (1) program administration and enforcement, (2) identification card costs, (3) monetary incentives for nonimmigrant agricultural workers to return to their country of origin, and (4) emergency medical services furnished to such workers. Provides for the payment of specified funds into the trust fund from employers and worker wage deductions.</summary>
</bill>
