<bill session="113" type="h" number="407" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Vehicles Incentive Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a business credit relating to the use of clean-fuel and fuel efficient vehicles by businesses within areas designated as nonattainment areas under the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2013-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Clean Vehicles Incentive Act of&#160;2013 - &#160;Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow certain businesses located in areas designated as nonattainment areas under the Clean Air Act a general business tax credit for the cost of certain clean-fuel vehicle property and the use of clean-burning fuel. Allows the credit to be taken against regular and alternative minimum tax liabilities. Allows a tax deduction for any unused clean fuel credit amounts. Allows a new qualified hybrid motor vehicle tax credit for any taxable year after 2012 only for such a vehicle which is placed in service after December 31, 2012, by an eligible business and substantially all of the use of which is in a nonattainment area. Extends such credit to new hybrid vehicles purchased after: (1) December 31, 2009, and before January 1, 2013, or (2) December 31, 2012, and before January 1, 2018.</summary>
</bill>
