<bill session="113" type="h" number="2801" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Access to Rural Therapy Services (PARTS) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to physician supervision of therapeutic hospital outpatient services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412475"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412488" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2013-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1143"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Access to Rural Therapy Services (PARTS) Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to state that, except with respect to high-risk or complex medical services requiring direct levels of supervision, if the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) requires supervision by a physician or non-physician practitioner for Medicare payment for therapeutic hospital outpatient services, that requirement is met if such services are furnished under the physician's or non-physician practitioner's general supervision. Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish a process for designating therapeutic hospital outpatient services for which direct supervision may be required for the entire service or direct supervision during the initiation of the service followed by general supervision for the remainder of the service. Declares without force or effect in law regarding Medicare requirements for direct supervision by physicians for therapeutic hospital outpatient services a specified restatement and clarification under the final rulemaking changes to the Medicare hospital outpatient prospective payment system and calendar year 2009 payment rates, which was published in the Federal Register on November 18, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
