<bill session="109" type="h" number="2740" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prompt Payment Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to require the provision of a written prompt payment policy to each subcontractor under a Federal contract and to require a clause in each subcontract under a Federal contract that outlines the provisions of the prompt payment statute and other related information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2005-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Prompt Payment Improvement Act of 2005 - Requires: (1) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to set forth in writing the prompt payment policy applicable to subcontractors under Federal contracts; and (2) the head of each Federal agency to provide a copy of such policy to each contractor and to require each contractor to provide a copy to each subcontractor. Directs each agency head to require contractors to include in each subcontract a clause containing: (1) the requirements and penalties relating to the timely payment obligations of the Government and prime contractors; (2) the name and number of a senior employee with authority to resolve progress payment questions; and (3) the obligations of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization in assisting small business contractors and subcontractors in receiving prompt payments.</summary>
</bill>
