<bill session="109" type="s" number="2573" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reverse the Raid on Student Aid Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide interest rate reductions, to authorize and appropriate amounts for the Federal Pell Grant program, to allow for in-school consolidation, to provide the administrative account for the Federal Direct Loan Program as a mandatory program, to strike the single holder rule, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3201-3203"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3234-3235" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6552-6553"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5150"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Reverse the Raid on Student Aid Act of 2006 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to cut student loan interest rates to 3.4% for student borrowers and 4.25% for parent borrowers under the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) and William D. Ford Direct Loan programs for loans whose first disbursement is made on or after July 1, 2006. Maintains the current 6.8% interest rate, however, for unsubsidized Stafford loans for middle-income borrowers under such programs. Authorizes and appropriates the funds necessary to award eligible students with Pell Grants up to specified maximum increasing amounts from academic year 2007 to 2012, with increases thereafter gauged to the Consumer Price Index. Allows students to consolidate loans under the FFEL program while still in school. Sets limits on funds available for administrative expenses under the FFEL and Direct Loan programs for FY2007-2012. Eliminates the current FY2007-2011 authorization of appropriations for the administrative costs of such programs. Repeals the single holder rule which requires borrowers to apply to their current lenders for FFEL consolidation loans.</summary>
</bill>
