<bill session="110" type="h" number="152" updated="2013-07-19T21:05:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Insurance Coverage of Childhood Immunization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act and title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require that group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans provide comprehensive coverage for childhood immunization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Comprehensive Insurance Coverage of Childhood Immunization Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require a group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage to provide comprehensive coverage for routine immunizations for each individual under 19 years of age who is a dependent of a participant or beneficiary under the plan. Requires coverage of routine immunizations without deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing in accordance with the most recent version of the Recommended Childhood Immunization Schedule issued by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Applies such requirement to coverage offered in the individual market. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor to ensure that: (1) such requirement has the same effect at all times; and (2) such Secretaries have a coordinated enforcement strategy.</summary>
</bill>
