<bill session="110" type="s" number="1389" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Climate Change Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the National Science Foundation to establish a Climate Change Education Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6070-6071"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1728"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2007--Introduced.
Climate Change Education Act - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation to establish a Climate Change Education Program to: (1) broaden the understanding of climate change, possible long and short-term consequences, and potential solutions; (2) apply the latest scientific and technological discoveries to provide learning opportunities to people; and (3) emphasize actionable information to help people understand and to promote implementation of new technologies, programs, and incentives related to energy conservation, renewable energy, and greenhouse gas reduction.Requires such Program to include: (1) a national information campaign to disseminate information on and promote implementation of the new technologies, programs, and incentives; and (2) a competitive grant program to provide grants to states, municipalities, educational institutions, and other organizations to create materials relevant to climate change and climate science, develop climate science kindergarten through grade 12 curriculum and supplementary educational materials, or publish climate change and climate science information.</summary>
</bill>
