<bill session="109" type="h" number="664" updated="2013-07-19T19:10:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Sexual Assault Crimes Revision Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Uniform Code of Military Justice to bring sexual assault crimes under military law into parallel with sexual assault crimes under Federal law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400356"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2005-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E199"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Military and naval offenses"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Prison violence"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Military Sexual Assault Crimes Revision Act of 2005 - Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice to define as the crime of aggravated sexual abuse engaging in a sexual act: (1) through the use of force; (2) by threatening or placing a person in fear that any person will be subjected to death, grievous bodily harm, or kidnapping; (3) by rendering another person unconscious; (4) by administering to another person an impairing drug or intoxicant; or (5) with a person under 12 years of age whether or not the accused knew the person's age. Defines as the crime of sexual abuse engaging in a sexual act: (1) by threatening or placing a person in fear (other than in a manner that would constitute aggravated sexual abuse); (2) with a person who is incapable of either appraising the nature of the conduct or physically incapable of declining; or (3) with a person who is at least 12 but under 16 who is not the spouse of the accused whether or not the accused knew the person's age. Establishes as an affirmative defense the accused's reasonable belief that the person was at least 16. Defines sexual abuse of a prisoner as knowingly engaging in a sexual act with a person who is: (1) in official detention or confinement; (2) under the custodial, supervisory, or disciplinary authority of the accused; and (3) is not the accused's spouse. Makes the above crimes punishable by court-martial and sets forth interim maximum punishments for each.</summary>
</bill>
