<bill session="113" type="s" number="648" updated="2013-11-02T06:57:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Educators Support All Students Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to support teacher and school professional training on awareness of student mental health conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Helping Educators Support All Students Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local educational agencies to support or develop programs that will train teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel regarding mental health conditions in children. Requires grant and subgrant recipients to partner with a mental health organization, family advocacy organization, or community nonprofit organization. Requires subgrantees to utilize school counselors, school psychologists, school social workers, or community organizations with experience in mental illness in developing and conducting the training. Requires the training program to include an annual in-service training component that enables teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel to: (1) better understand mental health conditions and the early warning signs in children and adolescents; (2) effectively communicate their mental health concerns with families and consider family perspectives; (3) identify classroom strategies for working effectively with troubled children; and (4) understand school specific information, including links to mental health services and supports in the school and community. Directs the Secretary to develop outcome measures that the Secretary is to use to conduct an in-depth evaluation of the effectiveness of the training programs.</summary>
</bill>
