<bill session="111" type="s" number="2806" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BE WELL Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Building Efforts for Wellness and Encouraging Longer Lives Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to codify and enhance existing regulations designed to encourage individuals to adopt healthy behaviors through voluntary participation in programs of health promotion and disease prevention.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Building Efforts for Wellness and Encouraging Longer Lives Act or the BE WELL Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish standards for programs of health promotion and disease prevention (wellness programs), including a system of rewards and reimbursements for voluntarily adopting healthy behaviors, including participation in fitness and smoking cessation programs. Applies such standards to group plans under the Public Health Service Act and federal employee health benefit plans. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a 10-state demonstration project to apply wellness program standards to state health insurance plans.</summary>
</bill>
