<bill session="112" type="h" number="3480" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End Pensions in Congress Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EPIC Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the termination of further retirement benefits for Members of Congress, except the right to continue participating in the Thrift Savings Plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412398" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412394" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412430" joined="2012-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2913"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2011--Introduced.
End Pensions in Congress Act or EPIC Act - Amends the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) and the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) to exclude Members of Congress, except the Vice President, from further CSRS and FERS retirement coverage. Prohibits further government contributions or deductions from such Member's basic pay for deposit in the Treasury to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund. States that nothing in this Act shall: (1) be considered to nullify, modify, or otherwise affect any right, entitlement, or benefit under CSRS for any Member covering any period before the enactment of this Act; or (2) affect the eligibility of a Member to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP) in accordance with otherwise applicable law. Allows Members covered by such exclusion, within 90 days after enactment of this Act, to elect to remain subject to CSRS or FERS, as the case may be.</summary>
</bill>
