<bill session="110" type="h" number="4142" updated="2013-07-19T21:40:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Medication Access for Veterans Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to permit medicare-eligible veterans to receive an out-patient medication benefit, to provide that certain veterans who receive such benefit are not otherwise eligible for medical care and services from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2007--Introduced.
Improving Medication Access for Veterans Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish certain prescribed drugs and medicines (i.e., only drugs and medicines included on the National Prescription Drug Formulary of the Department of Veterans Affairs) as specific therapy in the treatment of any illness or injury suffered by each veteran who is receiving additional compensation or allowance due to a service-connected disability, or an increased pension as a veteran of a period of war, by reason of being permanently housebound or in need of regular aid and attendance. Allows any Medicare-eligible veteran to elect to be furnished by the Secretary, on an outpatient basis, such drugs and medicines as specific therapy for any illness or injury suffered by the veteran. Requires such election to last for a calendar year and be irrevocable. Allows for election renewal. Requires appropriate information to be furnished to each veteran prior to making an election. Authorizes the Secretary to administer immunizations to veterans who voluntarily request such immunizations in connection with care for a disability in a Department of Veterans Affairs health care facility. Provides for appropriate copayments for the drugs and medicines received by veterans under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
