<bill session="109" type="s" number="2563" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pharmacist Access and Recognition in Medicare (PHARM) Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require prompt payment to pharmacies under part D, to restrict pharmacy co-branding on prescription drug cards issued under such part, and to provide guidelines for Medication Therapy Management Services programs offered by prescription drug plans and MA-PD plans under such part.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2006-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2006-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2006-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2006-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2006-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2006-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2006-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3220"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3220-3221" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5182"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5307"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2664"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Pharmacist Access and Recognition in Medicare (PhARM) Act of 2006 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require prompt payment of clean claims to pharmacies by prescription drug plans and Medicare Advantage prescription drug plans. Defines prompt payment as within 14 days from submission for claims submitted electronically, and within 30 days for claims submitted otherwise. Requires payment of interest, also, if a payment is not issued, mailed, or otherwise transmitted within the applicable number of calendar days. Prohibits a Medicare prescription drug card issued by a prescription drug plan sponsor from displaying the name, brand, or trademark (co-branding) of any pharmacy. Revises requirements for a covered medication therapy management program, allowing it to be furnished by a health care provider, other than a pharmacist, with advanced training in medication management. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to specify: (1) the population of part D eligible individuals appropriate for services under a medication therapy management program, based on certain characteristics; and (2) a minimum defined package of medication therapy management services that shall be provided to each enrollee. Revises requirements for pharmacy fees. Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a two-year demonstration program to examine the impact of medication therapy management furnished by a pharmacist in a community-based or ambulatory-based setting on quality of care, spending, and patient health; and (2) a Best Practices Commission to develop a best practices model for medication therapy management.</summary>
</bill>
