<bill session="111" type="s" number="1111" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Special Disability Workload Liability Resolution Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into agreements with States to resolve outstanding claims for reimbursement under the Medicare program relating to the Special Disability Workload project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5727"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5727-5728" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2849"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Special Disability Workload Liability Resolution Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to work with each state to reach an agreement on the amount of a payment for the state related to the Medicare program liability under title XVIII of the Social Security Act as a result of the Special Disability Workload project. (The special workload was the result of discovering a substantial number of recipients of Supplemental Security Income [SSI] benefits whose disability insured status under the title II [OASDI] Disability Insurance program was not previously recognized.) Prohibits any such payment to a state unless it: (1) waives the right to file a civil action (or to be a party to any action) in federal or state court in which the relief sought includes a payment to the state from the United States related to such Medicare liability; and (2) releases the United States from any further claims for reimbursement of state expenditures as a result of the Special Disability Workload project.</summary>
</bill>
