<bill session="109" type="sr" number="339" updated="2013-07-19T20:09:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution urging the Government of the Russian Federation to withdraw the first draft of the proposed legislation as passed in its first reading in the State Duma that would have the effect of severely restricting the establishment, operations, and activities of domestic, international, and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the Russian Federation, or to modify the proposed legislation to entirely remove these restrictions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-12-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13942-13943" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13942-13943" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13856" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hc" number="312"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="sc" number="70"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Urges: (1) the government of the Russian Federation to withdraw the first draft of the proposed legislation that would restrict the establishment and activities of domestic, international, and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the Russian Federation, or to modify the proposed legislation to remove such restrictions; and (2) in the event that the first draft of such proposed legislation is not withdrawn, the State Duma and the Federation Council of the Federal Assembly to amend the legislation to ensure the establishment and autonomous operations of such nongovernmental organizations in accordance with the practices universally adopted by democracies, including the provisions regarding foreign assistance.</summary>
</bill>
