<bill session="110" type="s" number="1428" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Durable Medical Equipment Access Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to assure access to durable medical equipment under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6308-6309"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1845"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2007--Introduced.
Medicare Durable Medical Equipment Access Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from awarding any contracts under the competitive durable medical equipment items and services acquisition program unless: (1) the quality standards have been implemented; and (2) the Secretary has received advice from the program oversight committee. Requires the Secretary (who currently is authorized), in carrying out competitive acquisition programs, to exempt: (1) rural areas and areas with low population density within urban areas that are not competitive, unless there is a significant national market through mail order for a particular item or service; and (2) items and services for which the application of competitive acquisition is not likely to result in significant savings. Adds to such exemptions smaller metropolitan statistical areas. Modifies requirements for the protection of small suppliers in bidding and contracting. Requires the Secretary to permit suppliers classified as small businesses to continue to participate as suppliers at the single payment amount so long as they submit bids at less than the fee schedule amount otherwise applicable to the items and they otherwise comply with applicable program requirements. Provides for appeal rights (currently denied). Requires the Secretary to exempt from competitive acquisition requirements items and services for which the application of competitive acquisition is not likely to result in significant savings of at least 10%. Prohibits the Secretary from implementing a program with respect to an item or service unless the Secretary demonstrates a probability of achieving significant savings of at least 10%, compared to the fee schedule in effect on January 1, 2006, by including the item or service in the program. Prohibits the Secretary from implementing certain requirements for the payment basis for covered items furnished after January 1, 2009, with respect to the application of rates in an area that is not a competitive acquisition area, unless the Secretary has completed and published in the Federal Register a comparability analysis to ensure the application is appropriate. Requires application of the comparability analysis requirement to certain other part B items and services.</summary>
</bill>
