<bill session="109" type="s" number="1918" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Immigration Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Workforce Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to address the demand for foreign workers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11825-11826"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wage surveys"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2005--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Workforce Act of 2005 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) amend the definition of H-2B nonimmigrant worker; and (2) add a new H-2C nonimmigrant worker category (willing worker program). Requires employers seeking to hire H-2B or H-2C workers to undertake specified recruitment efforts for U.S. workers, and to submit specified labor attestations. Provides worker protections. Addresses portability. Provides derivative status for spouses and children of H-2B and H-2C workers. Establishes annual numerical limitations on the number of aliens who may receive H-2B and H-2C status. Specifies authorized periods of admission for each category. Establishes the Immigration Study Commission to review the impact of this Act on national security and the economy and families. Sets forth H-2B and H-2C alien provisions respecting: (1) nonimmigrant status change and permanent immigrant status adjustment; (2) exemption from certain grounds for inadmissibility; (3) employer petition fees; (4) collective bargaining coverage; and (5) status ineligibility. Provides for stays of removal for aliens involved in workplace claims. Prohibits disclosure to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) by a federal or state agency of information concerning the immigration status of any worker. Triples civil penalties for a commercial enterprise that commits immigration-related document fraud for commercial or financial advantage. Exempts from fiscal year admission limits foreign students who have earned an advanced degree in science, technology, engineering or math from a U.S. university or who are employed. Exempts from direct numerical limitations: (1) aliens with an advanced degree in science, technology, engineering, or math who have been working in a related field in the United States during the three-year period preceding their application for an employment-based immigrant visa; (2) certain aliens who are priority workers or who have received a national interest waiver; and (3) immediate relatives of an employment-based immigrant. Authorizes full-time foreign students to work part-time off campus. Requires employer attestation respecting: (1) wages; (2) hours; and (3) U.S. citizen recruitment.</summary>
</bill>
