<bill session="109" type="s" number="99" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to contract with the city of Cheyenne, Wyoming, for the storage of the city's water in the Kendrick Project, Wyoming.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici without amendment. With written report No. 109-27.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="40">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 40.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1046"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1046"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2005--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to enter into one or more contracts with the City of Cheyenne, Wyoming, for the annual storage of the city's water for municipal and industrial use in the Seminoe Dam and Reservoir of the Kendrick Project (the Bureau of Reclamation project on the North Platte River that was authorized by a finding of feasibility approved by the President on August 30, 1935, and constructed for irrigation and electric power generation, the major features of which include Seminoe Dam, Reservoir, and Powerplant and Alcova Dam and Powerplant). Limits a contract to a term of not more than 40 years, which may be renewed on terms agreeable to the Secretary and the city, for successive terms of not more than 40 years per term. Directs that: (1) any operation and maintenance charges received under such a contract be credited against applicable operation and maintenance costs of the Project; and (2) any other revenues received under such a contract be credited to the Reclamation Fund as a credit to the construction costs of the Project.</summary>
</bill>
