<bill session="111" type="s" number="3335" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Earmark Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Earmark Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require Congress to establish a unified and searchable database on a public website for congressional earmarks as called for by the President in his 2010 State of the Union Address to Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-365. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="692">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 692.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5258"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Earmark Transparency Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Secretary of the Senate, the Senate Sergeant of Arms, and the Clerk of the House of Representatives to begin the development of a single free public searchable website that specifies certain identifying information relating to each request by Members of Congress for congressionally directed spending items or limited tax or tariff benefits (congressional earmarks). Requires a request for a congressional earmark from a Member of Congress to be made available on the website within five days after its submission to a congressional committee. Places on the requesting Member the burden of providing the required information in a timely manner and in compliance with this Act to the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House. Places on the chair of each committee to which the request is made, however, the burden of providing: (1) the amount approved by the committee; (2) the amount approved in the final legislation (if approved); and (3) the name of the federal department or agency through which the entity will receive the funding. Allows transfer to the office of the Secretary of the Senate, to pay for costs associated with the website, of any unobligated or unspent funds remaining at the end of FY2010 or FY2011 from the Official Personnel and Office Expense Account of any Senator who agrees to the transfer.</summary>
</bill>
