<bill session="111" type="h" number="5285" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Educational Success for Children and Youth Without Homes Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend subtitle B of title VII of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to provide education for homeless children and youths, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2800"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2010--Introduced.
Educational Success for Children and Youth Without Homes Act of 2010 - Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act's program of grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for the education of homeless youths to: (1) raise the minimum allotment for each state; (2) elaborate on the functions of each state's Office of the Coordinator for Education of Homeless Children and Youths; (3) elaborate on required state procedures for resolving disputes regarding the educational placement of homeless youth; (4) ensure that homeless youth do not lose credits earned in other schools and are not segregated into separate schools or programs within schools; (5) require states, LEAs, and schools to promote success for homeless youth by holding them to the same achievement standards as other students and removing barriers to their full participation in all classes and school activities; (6) list student-centered factors to be considered before an LEA places a homeless youth in a school; (7) require such schools to immediately enroll homeless youth despite unpaid fees or missed application or enrollment deadlines; (8) protect the privacy of information about a homeless youth's living situation; (9) require LEAs to coordinate services provided to homeless and disabled youth; (10) add to the duties of, and funding available to, LEA liaisons for homeless youth; (11) provide for the enrollment of homeless children in preschool programs; (12) require the Secretary of Education to establish or designate a Federal Office of the Coordinator for Education of Homeless Children and Youths; (13) authorize the Secretary to award grants or enter into contracts for evaluation, dissemination, and technical assistance activities for educational programs for homeless youth; and (14) triple authorized FY2010 appropriations from those authorized for FY2009. Establishes a separately funded Emergency Disaster Grant program which distributes funds to LEAs directly or through states to increase LEAs' capacity to respond to major disasters.</summary>
</bill>
