<bill session="112" type="h" number="1393" updated="2013-07-20T01:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Regulation and Enforcement and offshore drilling for oil and gas, to repeal the limitation of liability of a responsible party for discharge of oil from an offshore facility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2011--Introduced.
Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations that require each Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Regulation and Enforcement (BOEMRE) employee to be subject to random testing for the prohibited use of a controlled substance at least twice a year. Prohibits an individual from being employed by any person conducting any activity under a lease or permit issued by BOEMRE&#160; or subject to BOEMRE&#160; regulation for two years after leaving employment with BOEMR. Directs the Secretary, acting through BOEMRE, to conduct monthly inspections of each vessel and facility used for Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) oil or gas drilling. Prohibits the Secretary from exempting any category of activity of a vessel or facility engaged in OCS oil or gas drilling in waters deeper than 1,000 feet from any federal requirement or restriction that applies to such activity. Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to repeal the liability limits applicable to a responsible party for discharge of oil from an offshore facility.</summary>
</bill>
