<bill session="112" type="s" number="238" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FISH Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fishing Impact Statement Honesty Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require that fishery impact statements be updated each year and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2011--Introduced.
Fishing Impact Statement Honesty Act of 2011 or the FISH Act of 2011 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require a yearly update of each fishery impact statement (FIS) included with specified fishery management plans or amendments. Requires such FISs to: (1) be prepared by an objective person (prohibits U.S. government officers, employees, or entities) selected by the Comptroller General; and (2) determine if the fishery management plan or amendment is consistent with specified national standards for fishery conservation and management, including whether the relevant measures provide for the sustained participation of fishing communities and minimize adverse economic impacts on such communities. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, after an updated FIS is published, to prepare and begin implementing a comprehensive mitigation plan to: (1) address any identified negative economic or social impacts, and (2) correct specified inconsistencies.</summary>
</bill>
