<bill session="111" type="h" number="4059" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Online Age Verification and Child Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance Internet safety and security and to prevent exploitation of children online through the use of technology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications, Technology, and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2009--Introduced.
Online Age Verification and Child Safety Act - Makes it unlawful for an operator of a pornographic website to display any pornographic material without first verifying that any user is at least 18 years old. Makes it unlawful for an operator of a website to carry out any financial transaction involving any product or service whose sale or access to persons under a legally specified age is prohibited by federal or state law without first verifying that any user meets the age requirement. Imposes criminal penalties. Requires any Internet payment service provider or business performing financial transactions relating to pornographic material or to age-restricted products or services only process age-verified transactions. Establishes safe harbors. Requires: (1) violations to be treated as violations of a rule regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices; and (2) the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce this title. Prohibits construing this Act as providing a private right of action, including a class action. Prohibits any financial institution from processing a financial transaction denominated in or otherwise involving an electronic currency not backed by the full faith and credit of a United Nations (UN) member state.</summary>
</bill>
