<bill session="112" type="h" number="6139" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a Federal charter for National Consumer Credit Corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2012-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2012--Introduced.
Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act - Directs the Comptroller of the Currency to charter qualified nondepository creditors known as National Consumer Credit Corporations (Credit Corporations) to offer financial products or services. Requires a qualified nondepository creditor seeking a federal charter to submit an application which includes in part: (1) a business plan for at least a three-year period with its primary business activities serving underserved consumers and small businesses; (2) a market demand forecast, the intended customer base, competition, economic conditions, financial projections, and business risks; (3) a marketing plan that describes the types of financial products or services such creditor intends to offer; and (4) adequate capital structure. Directs the Comptroller to: (1) ensure that Credit Corporations focus their business operations primarily on providing underserved consumers a variety of affordable and commercially viable financial products or services, including some that facilitate personal savings and enhance the credit record of such consumers; (2) facilitate business partnerships among Credit Corporations, insured depository institutions, other nondepository creditors, third-party service providers and vendors, and nonprofit organizations in order to ensure greater credit access for underserved consumers and small businesses; and (3) examine and supervise the Credit Corporations. Requires Credit Corporations to make available to each consumer to whom a financial product or service is being offered: (1) information on how a consumer may obtain financial counseling services, the benefits of following a regular personal savings program, and how consumers can improve their credit ratings; (2) disclose clearly and conspicuously in the loan agreement the true cost of the loan, including all interest, fees, and loan related charges; and (3) offer an underserved consumer who is unable to repay an extension of credit with a loan repayment term of less than 120 days, an extended repayment plan, at no cost to the consumer, at least once in a 12-month period. Prohibits specified practices. Prescribes: (1) a national consumer credit corporation regulatory fee, (2) a usury limit, and (3) civil penalties. Grants enforcement powers to the Comptroller and state attorneys general.</summary>
</bill>
