<bill session="113" type="h" number="2587" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Planting STEM in the Classroom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Federal agencies and employees to support science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) activities in classrooms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2013-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2013--Introduced.
Planting STEM in the Classroom Act - Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to develop a policy to: (1) encourage federal employees engaged in STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) activities to volunteer in STEM education activities by providing them with the administrative leave and support they need to do so; and (2) support increased communication and partnerships between federal scientists and engineers and elementary and secondary schools and teachers through volunteerism in STEM education activities. Requires each federal science agency to report to Congress on efforts it will make to promote widespread public understanding of career opportunities in the STEM fields specific to the workforce needs of that agency.</summary>
</bill>
