<bill session="111" type="s" number="3734" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Czar Accountability Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the President to submit reports and certifications to Congress on the duties of certain employees who are appointed without the advice and consent of the Senate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Czar Accountability Act of 2010 - Directs the President, by January 1, 2011, and every six months thereafter, to submit a report to specified congressional committees that: (1) identifies each employee of the Executive Office of the President who is not appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate and who reports directly to the President and each employee of the Department of State who is not appointed by and with such advice and consent and who is an envoy or special representative; (2) describes the duties of each such employee; and (3) includes a certification that each such employee of Executive Office of the President is not exercising significant authority under U.S. law, that each such employee of the State Department is not an ambassador, other public minister, or consul, and that each such employee is not exercising any power that has been expressly delegated to the President by the Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
