<bill session="109" type="s" number="778" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to require a pharmacy that receives payments or has contracts under the medicare and medicaid programs to ensure that all valid prescriptions are filled without unnecessary delay or interference.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3564"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2005--Introduced.
Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to prohibit any payment to a pharmacy unless it ensures: (1) that each valid prescription is filled without unnecessary delay or other interference, consistent with the normal timeframe for filling prescriptions; and (2) that, if the prescribed item is not in the pharmacy's stock, the pharmacy will order such item without unnecessary delay or, if the patient prefers, will transfer the prescription to a local pharmacy of the patient's choice or return the prescription to the patient, at the patient's request. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to require any pharmacy that provides services to any individual eligible for medical assistance to comply with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
