<bill session="111" type="h" number="4392" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">African Higher Education Expansion and Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance to expand, improve, support, and promote higher education in the countries of sub-Saharan Africa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2009--Introduced.
African Higher Education Expansion and Improvement Act of 2009 - Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the importance to the development of sub-Saharan Africa of support for the improvement of primary, secondary, and higher education in that region. States that it is this country's policy to provide Africa with long-term assistance to improve the capacity of its institutions of higher education (IHEs) through partnerships with our IHEs. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to provide long-term assistance to sub-Saharan Africa that improves higher education by: (1) building the capacity of IHEs in sub-Saharan Africa; (2) building linkages and partnerships between sub-Saharan IHEs and our IHEs; (3) assisting efforts to recruit and retain women as students, faculty, and administrators; and (4) establishing an American University in West Africa. Requires the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to designate a Director of Assistance to Support and Promote Higher Education in Sub-Saharan Africa, who is to carry out such activities. Establishes a Sub-Saharan African Higher Education Advisory Board within USAID, which is appointed by the Administrator and composed of individuals from the private sector who have the requisite experience with Africa and higher education to assist the Director. Urges the Director and the Board to make every effort to leverage resources from the private sector in carrying out their responsibilities.</summary>
</bill>
