<bill session="111" type="s" number="4022" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Don't Ask, Don't Tell Repeal Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the repeal of the Department of Defense policy concerning homosexuality in the Armed Forces known as "Don't Ask, Don't Tell".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2965"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6520"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="4023"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2010--Introduced.
Don't Ask, Don't Tell Repeal Act of 2010 - Provides for repeal of the current Department of Defense (DOD) policy concerning homosexuality in the Armed Forces, to be effective 60 days after the Secretary of Defense has received DOD's comprehensive review on the implementation of such repeal, and the President, Secretary, and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (JCS) certify to the congressional defense committees that they have considered the report and proposed plan of action, that DOD has prepared the necessary policies and regulations to exercise the discretion provided by such repeal, and that implementation of such policies and regulations is consistent with the standards of military readiness and effectiveness, unit cohesion, and military recruiting and retention. Provides that, until such time as the above conditions are met, the current policy shall remain in effect.</summary>
</bill>
