<bill session="111" type="h" number="5220" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-19T11:50:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-19T11:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eunice Kennedy Shriver Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Eunice Kennedy Shriver Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Special Olympics Sport and Empowerment Act of 2004, to provide assistance to Best Buddies to support the expansion and development of mentoring programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412274" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412257" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2010-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Fudge moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3583-3589" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5220.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-05-19T11:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3583-3585" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5190"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2010--Passed House amended.
Eunice Kennedy Shriver Act - Title I: Reauthorization of Special Olympics Act - (Sec. 101) Reauthorizes the Special Olympics Sport and Empowerment Act of 2004 for FY2011-FY2015. Directs the Secretary of State to act through the Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs in awarding grants or entering agreements with Special Olympics for activities outside the United States. Includes community-based prevention among the activities for which the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) may award grants or enter into agreements with Special Olympics. Requires grant or agreement applications to include a description of specific measurable annual benchmarks, long-term goals and objectives, and outcomes to be achieved through specified activities, which must include: (1) activities to increase the full participation of people with intellectual disabilities in inclusive school and community activities with nondisabled people; and (2) education programs that dispel negative stereotypes about people with intellectual disabilities, activities to increase the participation of people with intellectual disabilities in Special Olympics outside of the United States, and health-related activities (including on-site health assessments, screening for health problems, health education, community-based prevention, data collection, and referrals to direct health care services). Requires annual reports by Special Olympics to describe demographic data about Special Olympics participants. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Best Buddies - (Sec. 202) Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements to promote the expansion of Best Buddies, including activities to increase the participation of people with intellectual disabilities in social relationships and other aspects of community life, including education and employment, within the United States. (Sec. 203) Conditions the receipt of funds on Best Buddies submitting to the Secretary an annual report that describes the degree to which progress has been made toward meeting the specific measurable goals, objectives, and outcomes described in its grant or contract application. (Sec. 204) Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Establishment of Eunice Kennedy Shriver Institutes for Sport and Social Impact - (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education to establish Eunice Kennedy Shriver Institutes for Sport and Social Impact. (Sec. 303) Requires recipients to use grant funds to advance the quality of life and inclusion of people with intellectual disabilities through research and evaluation, technical assistance, training, data collection, evaluation, collaboration, and dissemination of evidence-based best practices. (Sec. 304) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
