<bill session="109" type="s" number="2620" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community-Based Choices for Older Americans Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to authorize the Assistant Secretary for Aging to provide older individuals with financial assistance to select a flexible range of home and community-based long-term care services or supplies, provided in a manner that respects the individuals' choices and preferences.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3390-3391"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3391-3394" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Respite care"/>
    <term name="Retirement communities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2006--Introduced.
Community-Based Choices for Older Americans Act of 2006 - Requires the Assistant Secretary for Aging to provide allotments to enable states whose plans are approved to execute a program that pays for the federal share of costs of covered long-term care service and supplies for individuals who: (1) are 60 years or older; (2) are not eligible for Medicaid assistance; (3) meet state income eligibility and total asset criteria; (4) are unable to perform a certain number of daily living activities (such as eating, bathing, and dressing) without substantial assistance, have a certain level of disability, or require substantial supervision due to cognitive or mental impairment; and (5) satisfy other state eligibility criteria. Bases state allotments on the number of individuals age 60 or older whose income does not exceed the poverty line residing in a state relative to the total number residing in all states. Stipulates that allotments are to supplement and not to supplant other federal or state payments for long-term care services. Sets forth: (1) program plan requirements, including descriptions of eligibility criteria, services and supplies to be provided, and methodologies for individual cost-sharing, coordinating with other assistance programs, coordinating service, and outreach; and (2) responsibilities of state service coordinators, including assisting with the development and coordination of individual care plans. Requires states to establish annual assistance amounts for each enrolled individual and to make payments to individuals in accordance with their care plans. Limits the annual assistance amount per individual.</summary>
</bill>
