<bill session="112" type="s" number="3638" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TEAM Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Today's Entrepreneurs are Advancing Mentorship Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an Office of Entrepreneurial Support within the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-11-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2012-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-29">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/26/2012--Introduced.
Today's Entrepreneurs are Advancing Mentorship Act of 2012 or TEAM Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to establish within the Small Business Administration (SBA) an Office of Entrepreneurial Support, headed by a Director, to develop and provide innovative entrepreneurial information, education, and resources to promote both prospective entrepreneurs and successful small businesses. Requires: (1) the SBA's Associate Administrator for Entrepreneurial Development to establish a program of technical assistance grants for the development and implementation of curricula and mentoring programs designed to promote entrepreneurship, and (2) the Director to report to the congressional small business committees on best practices of U.S. entrepreneurial education and training programs. Directs the SBA Administrator to establish an Emerging Leaders Program of specialized training and executive-level mentoring to certain small businesses, with an emphasis on small businesses in emerging, underserved, rural, and urban markets. Requires: (1) the Administrator to develop performance measures for the Emerging Leaders and Entrepreneurial Support Programs, and (2) the Comptroller General to submit to the small business committees a comprehensive analysis of the economic impact of such Programs.</summary>
</bill>
