<bill session="109" type="h" number="6091" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To secure the borders of the United States, and to ensure the removal of deportable criminal aliens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2006--Introduced.
Border Security Enhancement Act of 2006 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Attorney General should adopt uniform guidelines for the prosecution of smuggling offenses. Directs the Attorney General, subject to the availability of appropriations, to increase the number of U.S. attorneys employed to prosecute alien smuggling cases by at least 20 in each of FY2008-FY2013. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to determine inadmissibility based on criminal grounds under an expedited removal process for an alien who: (1) has not been admitted or paroled; (2) has not been found to have a credible fear of persecution; and (3) is not eligible for a waiver of inadmissibility or relief from removal. Authorizes the Secretary to execute an order of removal seven days (currently, 14 days) after it's issuance. Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the knowing construction or financing of an unauthorized tunnel or subterranean passage that crosses the international border between the United States and another country. Imposes a 20-year maximum prison term for such offense. Imposes a 10-year maximum prison term on any person who recklessly permits the construction or use of such a tunnel or passage on land that such person owns or controls. Doubles penalties for persons who use such a tunnel or passage to unlawfully smuggle an alien, illegal goods, controlled substances, weapons of mass destruction, or members of a terrorist organization. Subjects to forfeiture any property involved in, or traceable to, the construction or financing of such a tunnel or passage. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promulgate or amend sentencing guidelines to provide for increased penalties for persons convicted of criminal offenses related to the construction or financing of such a tunnel or passage.</summary>
</bill>
