<bill session="110" type="s" number="3402" updated="2013-07-19T22:51:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Health Education and Transparency Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide information and education to consumers concerning health care services and health insurance coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Consumer Health Education and Transparency Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the Office of Consumer Health Education and Information to provide consumers of health care services and health insurance with information concerning personal health and wellness and health insurance coverage. Requires the Secretary to: (1) require the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to develop standards for use by health insurance issuers in compiling and providing to enrollees a summary of benefits explanation that accurately represents the benefits and coverage provided by the issuer under the applicable health insurance plan; and (2) promulgate regulations to apply such standards.Directs health insurance issuers and federal health care programs to provide such a summary of benefits explanation to individuals prior to the effective date of coverage.Provides that such standards preempt related state standards that provide less information to consumers.Subjects entities that willfully fail to provide such information to fines.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office, to establish and implement a consumer health education and outreach initiative.Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct a comprehensive study of matters related to improved consumer education on end-of-life care decisions and spending; and (2) award grants to local education agencies to develop and implement a personal health and nutrition curriculum in elementary or secondary schools.</summary>
</bill>
