<bill session="109" type="s" number="3905" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bainbridge Island Japanese American Monument Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to adjust the boundary of the Minidoka Internment National Monument to include the Nidoto Nai Yoni Memorial in Bainbridge Island, Washington, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2006-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5817"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Japanese Americans"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2006--Introduced.
Bainbridge Island Japanese American Monument Act of 2006 - Adjusts the boundary of the Minidoka Internment National Monument located in Idaho to include the Nidoto Nai Yoni ("Let it not happen again") memorial that commemorates the Japanese Americans of Bainbridge Island, Washington, who were the first to be forcibly removed from their homes and relocated to internment camps during World War II . Authorizes the Secretary, for the purposes of developing the Nidoto Nai Yoni Memorial, to enter into agreements with: (1) the city of Bainbridge Island; (2) the Bainbridge Island Metropolitan Park Camp Recreational District; (3) the Bainbridge Island Japanese American Community Memorial Committee; (4) the Bainbridge Island Historical Society; and (5) successor and other appropriate individuals or entities. Requires the Secretary to coordinate the development of interpretive and educational materials and programs for the Memorial and the Monument with the Manzanar National Historic Site in California.</summary>
</bill>
