<bill session="109" type="hr" number="1070" updated="2013-07-19T19:03:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-05T14:35:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-05T14:35:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Members of the House should actively engage with employers and the American public at large to encourage the hiring of members and former members of the Armed Forces who were wounded in service and are facing a transition to civilian life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2006-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2006-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05T10:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hunter moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8679-8681, H8702" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1070.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05T10:40:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05T14:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-12-05T14:35:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="524" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 403 - 0 (Roll no. 524).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8679" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05T14:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2006--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) Members of the House should actively engage with employers and the American public at large to encourage the hiring of members and former members of the Armed Forces who were wounded in service and are facing a transition to civilian life; (2) a strong relationship should be forged between Congress, local businesses, and such members and former members towards the goal of finding employment for those who have sacrificed so much; and (3) Members should carry out the types of activities described in this resolution in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and the Committee on House Administration.</summary>
</bill>
