<bill session="109" type="s" number="457" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Purchase Card Waste Elimination Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Purchase Card Waste Elimination Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Purchase Card Waste Elimination Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to issue guidance for, and provide oversight of, the management of micropurchases made with Governmentwide commercial purchase cards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1718-1719"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="438">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 438.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5513-5514" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5513-5514" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-06-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5514" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06T20:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4191"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/6/2006--Passed Senate amended.
Purchase Card Waste Elimination Act of 2006 - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue guidelines to assist executive agencies in improving the management of the use of the governmentwide commercial purchase card for making micropurchases. Requires such guidelines to cover an analysis of purchase card expenditures to identify opportunities for achieving and accurately measuring: (1) fair participation of small business concerns in micro-purchases, consistent with the national policy on small business participation in federal procurements set forth in the Small Business Act; and (2) dissemination of best practices for participation of small business concerns in micro-purchases. Requires the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to continue efforts to improve reporting by financial institutions that issue such a card so that GSA has the data needed to: (1) identify opportunities for achieving savings; and (2) actively pursue point-of-sale discounts with major vendors accepting it so that any federal government purchaser using it can benefit from such discounts. Requires the senior procurement executive for each executive agency, as directed by OMB, to report periodically to OMB on the actions taken in the agency pursuant to the guidelines. Requires OMB to report annually to specified congressional committees on the progress made in: (1) improving management of the use of the purchase card; and (2) achieving certain savings in micropurchases made with it. Requires GSA, in conjunction with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and the Financial Management Service, to develop procedures to subject to the Federal Payment Levy program any purchase card payments to federal contractors. Requires GSA to report annually to specified congressional committees on all first class and business class travel by executive agency employees undertaken at federal expense.</summary>
</bill>
