<bill session="110" type="s" number="2243" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Saudi Arabia Accountability Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to strongly encourage the Government of Saudi Arabia to end its support for institutions that fund, train, incite, encourage, or in any other way aid and abet terrorism, to secure full Saudi cooperation in the investigation of terrorist incidents, to denounce Saudi sponsorship of extremist Wahhabi ideology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13454-13455"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13455-13456" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2976"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Extremist movements in politics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious education"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2007--Introduced.
Saudi Arabia Accountability Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the government of Saudi Arabia must: (1) close permanently all organizations in Saudi Arabia that fund, train, encourage, or aid terrorism anywhere in the world; (2) end funding for terror organizations outside Saudi Arabia; (3) block funding from private Saudi citizens and entities to Saudi-based or offshore terror organizations; and (4) cooperate fully with the United States in investigating terror groups and individuals. Directs the President to certify to the appropriate congressional committees when the government of Saudi Arabia: (1) is fully cooperating with the United States in investigating and preventing terrorist attacks; (2) has permanently closed all Saudi-based Wahhabbist organizations that fund Islamic extremism; (3) has exercised maximum efforts to block all funding from private Saudi citizens, corporations, and entities to foreign Islamic extremist and terrorist movements; and (4) has stopped financing and disseminating materials and other forms of support that encourage the spread of radical Wahhabi ideology. Directs the President to report annually to the committees until such certification is made.</summary>
</bill>
