<bill session="112" type="s" number="3567" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Women's History Museum Commission Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Women's History Museum, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2012-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2012-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6461"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6421"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Introduced.
National Women's History Museum Commission Act of 2012 - Establishes the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Women's History Museum to submit to the President and Congress a report containing recommendations with respect to a plan of action for the establishment and maintenance of a National Women's History Museum in Washington, D.C. Requires the Commission to be composed of eight members. Directs the Senate Majority Leader, Speaker of the House of Representatives, Senate Minority Leader, and House Minority Leader to each appoint two Commission members. Directs the Commission to: (1) report on issues including potential locations for the Museum and whether it should be part of the Smithsonian Institution, and (2) develop a fundraising plan to support the establishment and maintenance of the Museum through contributions from the public. Authorizes the Commission to employ and compensate an executive director and other necessary personnel. Terminates the Commission within a specified period after it has submitted its final reports pursuant to this Act. Prohibits federal funds from being obligated to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
