<bill session="113" type="s" number="1507" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal General Welfare Exclusion Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the treatment of general welfare benefits provided by Indian tribes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2013--Introduced.
Tribal General Welfare Exclusion Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income, for income tax purposes, the value of an Indian general welfare benefit. Defines "Indian general welfare benefit" as any payment made or services provided to or on behalf of a member of an Indian tribe under an Indian tribal government program if: (1) such program is administered under specified guidelines and does not discriminate in favor of members of the governing body of the Indian tribe; and (2) the program benefits are available to any tribal member, are for the promotion of general welfare, are not lavish or extravagant, and are not compensation for services. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) establish a Tribal Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary on the taxation of Indians, (2) establish and require training and education for Internal Revenue Service (IRS) field agents on federal Indian law and the implementation of this Act, and (3) suspend audits and examinations of Indian tribal governments and members of Indian tribes and waive any interest or tax penalties related to the exclusion from gross income of Indian general welfare benefits.</summary>
</bill>
