<bill session="109" type="hr" number="855" updated="2013-07-19T19:01:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commending the cooperation of important allies in counterterrorist operations, condemning the criticism of such cooperation by the European Parliament, and commending the counterterrorism efforts of the Central Intelligence Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Prison administration"/>
    <term name="Sweden"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2006--Introduced.
Commends: (1) the counterterrorism cooperation of Italy, Sweden, and Bosnia-Herzegovina; and (2) the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) for increasing U.S. and European security through counterterrorism operations and for decreasing the likelihood of terrorist attacks. Condemns the European Parliament for criticizing CIA and allied counterterrorism efforts. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the Temporary Committee of the European Parliament's declarations on the alleged CIA use of European countries for transport and illegal detention of prisoners decrease the security of European and American citizens and increase the likelihood of terrorist acts.</summary>
</bill>
