<bill session="111" type="s" number="1278" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumers Health Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Consumers Choice Health Plan, a public health insurance plan that provides an affordable and accountable health insurance option for consumers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6722-6723"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6723-6727" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2009--Introduced.
Consumers Health Care Act of 2009 - Establishes within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) an Office of Health Plan Management to establish and administer the Consumer Choice Health Plan to provide for health insurance coverage that is made available to all eligible individuals in the United States and its territories. Requires the Plan to comply with all regulations and requirements that are applicable with respect to other health insurance plans offered through the National Health Insurance Exchange. (The National Health Insurance Exchange has not been established.) Makes an individual or employer who is eligible to purchase coverage from a health insurance plan through the Exchange eligible to enroll in the Plan or purchase coverage for their employees from the Plan. Treats an individual's enrollment with the Plan as satisfying any requirement under federal law for such individual to demonstrate enrollment in health insurance or benefits coverage. Requires Medicare, Medicaid, and Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) providers to provide services to any individual enrolled in the Plan for three years following establishment of the Plan, after which the provider may opt-out. Sets forth provisions governing payment rates. Requires repayment of funds necessary for the establishment of the Plan. Requires the Plan to be financially self-sustaining. Authorizes the establishment of the America's Health Insurance Trust as a nonprofit corporation, to provide information on, and oversight of, health insurance plans provided through the Exchange. Establishes in the Treasury the America's Health Insurance Trust Fund. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a fee on accident and health insurance policies and self-insured health plans.</summary>
</bill>
