<bill session="109" type="sr" number="457" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-01">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the citizens of the United States and the United States Government have serious concerns regarding the release of convicted terrorist and murderer Mohammad Ali Hammadi by the Government of Germany.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2006-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-05-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3846-3847" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S346-3847" label="text as passed Senated"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S3804-3805" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the government of Germany's unfortunate early release of Mohammad Ali Hammadi has undermined joint U.S.-German efforts to combat international terrorism, and sends a signal of weakness to terrorist groups such as Hezbollah and could increase the likelihood of further terrorist attacks against citizens worldwide; (2) the U.S. government should continue to call on the government of Lebanon to hand over Mr. Hammadi and other known terrorists so that they may face trial in the United States; (3) the U.S. government should take all appropriate steps to secure the arrest of Mr. Hammadi and his fellow hijackers and their transfer to the United States; and (4) the murderers of U.S. Navy Petty Officer Robert Dean Stethem must be brought to justice, and a clear message must be sent to the international community that the murder of U.S. service members or civilians will neither be tolerated nor forgotten.</summary>
</bill>
