<bill session="111" type="s" number="496" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Afghanistan and Pakistan Reconstruction Opportunity Zones Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide duty-free treatment for certain goods from designated Reconstruction Opportunity Zones in Afghanistan and Pakistan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2009--Introduced.
Afghanistan and Pakistan Reconstruction Opportunity Zones Act of 2009 - Declares the purposes of this Act, including to stimulate economic activity and development in Afghanistan and the border region of Pakistan in an effort to combat violent extremism. Authorizes the President to: (1) designate an area within Afghanistan or Pakistan as a Reconstruction Opportunity Zone, provided such country meets certain eligibility requirements; and (2) proclaim duty-free treatment for certain articles (including certain textile and apparel articles as well as non-textile or non-apparel articles) that are imported into the United States from a designated zone within such country, provided certain requirements are met. Specifies rules of origin for such articles.Prohibits duty-free treatment for any such articles unless the country in question adopts certain enforcement measures to prevent their unlawful transshipment and the use of false documents relating to importation into the United States.Authorizes the President to: (1) waive duty-free treatment for such articles if it is inconsistent with the national interests of the United States; and (2) withdraw, suspend, or limit such treatment.</summary>
</bill>
