<bill session="111" type="h" number="5517" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Every Veteran Counts Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 13, United States Code, to require that the questionnaire used in a decennial census of population shall include an inquiry regarding an individual's status as a veteran, a spouse of a veteran, or a dependent of a veteran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO23" subcommittee="Information Policy, Census, and National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2010--Introduced.
Every Veteran Counts Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to include on each questionnaire used in a decennial census a question regarding whether an individual is a veteran, a spouse of a veteran, or the dependent of a veteran. Authorizes the Secretary to include such a question in any survey conducted during the interval between each census of population. Directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to report to Congress identifying the laws or programs administered by the VA for which population data or any other information obtained from any census or survey: (1) was used by the VA during the year most recently ended; and (2) will be used by the VA after the close of such year and before the date data from the next decennial census is obtained.</summary>
</bill>
