<bill session="109" type="h" number="3094" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secure America's Vote Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to improve the fairness and accuracy of voter registration in elections for Federal office, establish a uniform standard for the treatment of provisional ballots cast at an incorrect polling place, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2005--Introduced.
Secure America's Vote Act of 2005 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to direct the Election Assistance Commission to revise the mail voter registration form to emphasize more prominently the requirement that an individual be a U.S. citizen to register to vote in federal elections. Prohibits a state from: (1) rejecting an application for voter registration for federal office soley for the individual's failure to provide required information or error in providing such information, if with reasonable effort the state would be able to correct it; or (2) removing an individual from the official list of eligible voters for federal elections by reason of felony status or death unless the applicable database meets accuracy standards established by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology. Requires a state to notify the public, within 45 days before any federal election, by posting on the chief state election official's public website, and through other appropriate methods, of: (1) all names removed from the computerized list since the later of the most recent election for federal office held in the state or the day of the most recent previous public notice; (2) the criteria, processes, and procedures used to determine which names were removed; and (3) information on the steps an individual may take to appeal such removal and reinstate himself or herself before the election. Establishes a uniform standard for the treatment of provisional ballots cast at an incorrect polling place. Provides for additional security requirements for voting systems used in federal elections. Requires states to make election laws available to the public. Establishes criminal penalties for voter suppression. Directs the Election Assistance Commission to establish best practice guidelines for the treatment of absentee ballots of uniformed services voters and overseas voters to ensure their timely delivery and return.</summary>
</bill>
