<bill session="111" type="h" number="2461" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Small Business Verification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the responsibility of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to verify the veteran status of the owners of small business concerns listed in the database maintained by the Secretary.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400443"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Provisions of measure incorporated into H.R. 3949.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2009--Introduced.
Veterans Small Business Verification Act - Provides that application by a veteran small business owner for inclusion in a database of veteran-owned small businesses maintained by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall constitute permission for the Secretary to verify information included in the application. Provides that, if the Secretary receives an application from an individual whose status as a veteran cannot be verified, the Secretary may not include that small business in the database until the Secretary receives sufficient information to verify such status. Prohibits a small business from being listed in the database until the Secretary has verified that: (1) the small business is owned and controlled by veterans; and (2) when an owner indicates that the small business is owned and controlled by a veteran with a service-connected disability, the person is a veteran with a service-connected disability.</summary>
</bill>
