<bill session="111" type="s" number="2864" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defense Against Infectious Diseases Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the enhancement of United States preparedness for outbreaks of infectious disease to protect homeland security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12911-12912"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/10/2009--Introduced.
Defense Against Infectious Diseases Act of 2009 - Directs the President: (1) to convene a consortium of representatives of state, local, and tribal governments to assess the adequacy of guidance for state and local government planning in the National Strategy for Pandemic Flu and the National Strategy for Pandemic Influenza Implementation Plan; and (2) within one year after convening such consortium and every four years thereafter, to convene another consortium to review and update such Strategy and Plan. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), to conduct a survey to identify appropriate alternative medical care facilities capable of meeting medical surge capacity needs for the prophylaxis for, and treatment of, infectious diseases outbreaks. Directs the Secretary of DHS to identify specific resources, including subsistence supplies and personnel, that may be required to support the implementation of strategies for social distancing and medical surge during a federally declared emergency or major disaster to prevent the introduction, transmission, and spread of communicable disease and ensure the proper delivery of crisis and medical care. Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to the appropriate Senate and House committees describing the roles and responsibilities, capabilities, and coordination of federal assets for medical response to infectious disease outbreaks or biological attacks.</summary>
</bill>
