<bill session="111" type="s" number="648" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Access to Community Health Centers (MATCH) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a prospective payment system instead of the reasonable cost-based reimbursement method for Medicare-covered services provided by Federally qualified health centers and to expand the scope of such covered services to account for expansions in the scope of services provided by Federally qualified health centers since the inclusion of such services for coverage under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3556"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3556-3557" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Access to Community Health Centers (MATCH) Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise the definition of "federally qualified health center services" to include ambulatory services furnished by a federally qualified health center (FQHC) for which payment may otherwise be made under Medicare if such services were furnished by a non-FQHC health care provider or health care professional employed by or under contract with an FQHC. Permits payment for hospital-based services. Provides for a Medicare prospective payment system (PPS) for Medicare-covered services provided by FQHCs.</summary>
</bill>
