<bill session="113" type="h" number="3187" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Pay Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To appropriate such funds as may be necessary to ensure that members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components thereof, and supporting civilian and contractor personnel continue to receive pay and allowances for active service performed when a Governmentwide shutdown occurs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412509"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2013-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="171"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1541"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1543"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2013--Introduced.
Military Pay Protection Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, during a government-wide shutdown, to make available to the Secretary of Defense (DOD), and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) in the case of the Coast Guard, out of any amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as necessary to continue to provide pay and allowances to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components, who perform active service during the shutdown. Allows for the provision of such pay and allowances, at the discretion of the DOD Secretary, to: (1) DOD civilian personnel providing support to such members, and (2) DOD contractor personnel providing direct support to such members. Makes additional funding available as necessary to prevent interruptions or delays in the performance of domestic disaster relief and recovery operations during the shutdown. Defines "government-wide shutdown" as any portion of a fiscal year during which none of the appropriation bills for the fiscal year have become law and an Act or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year is not in effect.</summary>
</bill>
