<bill session="112" type="hc" number="141" updated="2013-07-20T02:10:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Harming Our Kids Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress efforts by mental health practitioners to change an individual's sexual orientation and gender identity or expression are dangerous and harmful and should be prohibited from being practiced on minors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2012-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/28/2012--Introduced.
Stop Harming Our Kids Resolution - Expresses the sense of Congress that sexual orientation and gender identity or expression change efforts directed at minors are discredited and ineffective, have no legitimate therapeutic purpose, and are dangerous and harmful. Encourages states to protect minors from efforts that promote or promise to change sexual orientation or gender identity or expression, based on the premise that homosexuality or transgender identity is a mental illness or developmental disorder that can or should be cured. Defines "sexual orientation and gender identity or expression change efforts" as any practice by a licensed mental health provider, health care provider, or counselor seeking or purporting to impose change of an individual's sexual orientation or gender identity or expression, including efforts to change such behavioral expression or eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same sex. Excludes culturally competent, affirmative therapy providing: (1) acceptance, support, and understanding of an individual's sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression and the facilitation of an individual's coping, social support, and identity exploration and development, including interventions to prevent or address unlawful conduct or unsafe sexual practices; or (2) acceptance, support, or understanding of an individual's gender expression or the facilitation of an individual's coping, social support, and identity exploration and development.</summary>
</bill>
