<bill session="112" type="s" number="2062" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom from Over-Criminalization and Unjust Seizures Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to repeal certain provisions relating to criminal penalties and violations of foreign laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2012-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="4171"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2012--Introduced.
Freedom from Over-Criminalization and Unjust Seizures Act of 2012 - Amends the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to repeal the prohibition on importing, exporting, transporting, selling, receiving, acquiring, or purchasing in interstate or foreign commerce: (1) fish or wildlife taken, possessed, transported, or sold in violation of foreign law; or (2) plants taken, possessed, transported, or sold in violation of foreign law, without the payment of appropriate royalties, taxes, or stumpage fees required by foreign law, or in violation of any limitation under foreign law that governs the export or transshipment of plants. Repeals the prohibition on possessing such fish, wildlife, or plants within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States. Establishes a $200,000 maximum limit on a civil penalty for a knowing violation of such Act that involves fish, wildlife, or plants with a market value of $350 or more. Repeals: (1) criminal penalties under such Act, and (2) the authorization to suspend, modify, or cancel specified licenses or permits issued to any person who is convicted of a criminal violation of such Act.</summary>
</bill>
