<bill session="112" type="s" number="291" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to repeal the sunset provisions in the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 and other related provisions and permanently reauthorize the USA PATRIOT Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S550" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-02-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="9">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="290"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1038"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2011--Introduced.
USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act of 2011 - Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to repeal the termination date of provisions of the USA PATRIOT Act: (1) authorizing roving surveillance of a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, (2) authorizing the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to apply for an order requiring the production of any tangible things for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations, and (3) requiring the Attorney General to inform specified congressional committess annually concerning all such requests for the production of tangible things. Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to repeal the termination date of provisions including in the definition of an "agent of a foreign power" any non-U.S. person who engages in international terrorism or preparatory activities ("lone wolf" provision).</summary>
</bill>
