<bill session="111" type="s" number="674" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 41 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the establishment and authorization of funding for certain training programs for supervisors of Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3659-3660"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3660-3661" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-364.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="691">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 691.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5522"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2010 - Revises provisions concerning training programs for federal agency managers. Requires the head of each federal agency to establish: (1) a training program for supervisors that includes developing and discussing relevant goals and objectives with employees, motivating employees, fostering a work environment characterized by fairness, respect, equal opportunity, and attention paid to the merit of the work of employees, effectively managing employees with unacceptable performance, addressing reports of a hostile work environment, and meeting supervisor competencies established by the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) or the supervisor's employing agency; (2) a training program on prohibited personnel practices, employee collective bargaining and union participation rights, and processes to enforce employee rights; and (3) a mentoring program for new supervisors. Requires: (1) new supervisors to complete such programs within one year after appointment, and (2) supervisors to complete the training programs every three years. Requires: (1) the Director of OPM to issue guidance to federal agencies on competencies supervisors are expected to meet in order to effectively manage, and be accountable for managing, the performance of employees; and (2) agencies to use such guidance to assess the performance and overall capacity of its supervisors.</summary>
</bill>
