<bill session="109" type="h" number="2731" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Care Liability Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the liability of hospitals and emergency departments for noneconomic and punitive damages when providing uncompensated care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Group medical practice"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Emergency Care Liability Relief Act - Limits noneconomic and punitive damages for injuries arising from the provision of uncompensated care by emergency care providers. Authorizes the award of attorney's fees and costs in actions in which a party's liability or such damages are contested. Requires liability for such awards to be allocated to the nonprevailing party personally, the attorney or law firm representing such party if representation was on a contingent fee basis, or both, taking into account specified factors. Requires the court, in actions in which liability or noneconomic or punitive damages described in this Act are contested, to instruct the jury that it must take into account the effect of the amount to be awarded in damages on the price and availability of health care liability insurance.</summary>
</bill>
