<bill session="110" type="s" number="3119" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Economic Recovery Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Commercial Truck Fuel Savings Demonstration Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to stimulate the economy by encouraging energy efficiency, infrastructure and workforce investment, and homeownership retention, and by amending the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide certain business tax relief and incentives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5594-5595"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2008--Introduced.
Economic Recovery Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a tax credit for up to $500 of the cost of replacing wood stoves in residences with stoves that meet certain energy efficiency standards; (2) extend through 2011 the tax credit for producing electricity from certain renewable resources; (3) extend through 2012 the tax credit for residential energy efficient property expenditures; (4) increase and make permanent the expensing allowance for depreciable business property; (5) extend through 2009 the accelerated depreciation of qualified restaurant property; and (6) allow a tax credit for investment in Build America bonds.Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to increase funding for the weatherization program in FY2009-FY2011. Authorizes appropriations for the Energy Star program.Authorizes the establishment of the Transportation Finance Corporation to issue Build America bonds and finance transportation infrastructure projects. Commercial Truck Fuel Savings Demonstration Act of 2008 - Establishes a two-year program to allow certain heavy trucks to travel on the federal interstate highway system when diesel fuel prices are $3.50 or more per gallon without a reduction of federal highway funds to states.Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize appropriations for FY2009-FY2010 for: (1) youth activities; (2) adult employment and training activities; and (3) dislocated worker employment and training activities. Amends the National Housing Act to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to insure any homeownership retention mortgage covering a one- to four-family residence made to pay or prepay outstanding obligations under an existing mortgage.</summary>
</bill>
