<bill session="112" type="h" number="1158" updated="2013-07-20T01:20:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Montana Mineral Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Montana Mineral Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the conveyance of mineral rights by the Secretary of the Interior in the State of Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400335"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01T18:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-299.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-12-01T18:15:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="199">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 199.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="647"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2110"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2011--Reported to House amended.
Montana Mineral Conveyance Act - (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary of the Interior, if Great Northern Properties Limited Partnership (the Great Northern Properties) conveys to the Northern Cheyenne Indian Tribe all its mineral interests underlying specified aggregate tracts of land in Montana within the Tribe's reservation (the Cheyenne tracts), to convey to Great Northern Properties all interest of the United States in and to the coal underlying specified unleased federal tracts in Montana outside of the Tribe's reservation. Prohibits the mineral interests underlying the Cheyenne tracts conveyed to the Tribe from being subject to taxation by the state of Montana. (Sec. 5) Requires the Northern Cheyenne Tribe to waive all legal claims arising from the continuing failure of the United States to acquire for the Tribe the mineral rights underlying the Cheyenne tracts as part of the Tribe's reservation as directed by Congress in 1900. Instructs the Northern Cheyenne Tribe and Great Northern Properties to jointly notify the Secretary in writing when they have agreed on a formula for the sharing of revenue from the coal produced from the federal tracts. Requires, after such condition is satisfied and within 90 days of the Secretary receiving such written notification, the completion of the mineral conveyances under this Act in a single transaction. Allows the Secretary or Great Northern Properties, if any part of such conveyances is invalidated by a federal district court and the court's judgment is not vacated or reversed on appeal, to rescind each such conveyance. Requires, if such a rescission is carried out, the Tribe's waiver to be considered as being rescinded. (Sec. 6) Specifies this Act's effect on the eligibility of the Tribe or its members to receive other federal benefits or services.</summary>
</bill>
