<bill session="113" type="h" number="953" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Courthouse Safety Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve security at State and local courthouses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412276"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="445"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2013--Introduced.
Local Courthouse Safety Act of 2013 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to permit the Director of the Department of Justice's (DOJ) Bureau of Justice Assistance to carry out a training and technical assistance program to teach employees of state, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies how to anticipate, survive, and respond to violent encounters during the course of their duties, including duties relating to security at state, county, and tribal courthouses. Amends the State Justice Institute Act of 1984 to require the State Justice Institute (a private nonprofit organization established to improve judicial administration in state courts) to include the improvement of the safety and security of state and local courts as a factor in the national assistance program under which it provides funding to state courts and related national and nonprofit organizations. Requires state or local courts that do not have magnetometers available for use to use grant matching funds to acquire magnetometers. Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to ensure that state or local courthouses having less security equipment than such courthouses require have an opportunity to request surplus security equipment (metal detectors, wands, baggage screening devices) before such equipment is made available to any other individual or entity. Requires that priority be given to courthouses that have no security equipment.</summary>
</bill>
