<bill session="109" type="h" number="2618" updated="2013-07-19T19:27:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize and direct the exchange and conveyance of certain National Forest land and other land in southeast Arizona.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400336"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2005-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1093"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1122"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2466"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2005--Introduced.
Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) to convey to Resolution Copper Mining, LLC, all, right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified federal land in Pinal county, Arizona, in exchange for Resolution Copper conveying to the United States title to: (1) the Secretary to specified non-federal land in Gila, Yavapai, Maricopa, and Pinal counties, Arizona, and (2) the Secretary of the Interior to specified non-federal land in Pinal and Santa Cruz counties, Arizona. Directs the Secretary to convey specified land in Pinal county to the town of Superior, Arizona. Instructs Resolution Copper to deliver to the Secretary an executed document granting a permanent conservation easement to an entity that is: (1) a qualified unit of government; or (2) a land trust or other qualified organization. Requires Resolution Copper and the grantee, in consultation with the town and other interested parties, to determine whether the area covered by the easement should be used to establish additional public access routes, trails, and trailheads to Apache Leap. Directs the Secretary, in consultation with Resolution Copper, the town, and other interested parties, to: (1) construct in the Global Ranger District of the Tonto National Forest a replacement campground or campgrounds for the Oak Flat Campground; and (2) provide a replacement rock climbing area or areas on National Forest or public land.</summary>
</bill>
