<bill session="110" type="h" number="3957" updated="2013-07-19T21:38:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30T20:44:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-30T20:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Use Efficiency and Conservation Research Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Water Use Efficiency and Conservation Research Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Water Use Efficiency and Conservation Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase research, development, education, and technology transfer activities related to water use efficiency and conservation technologies and practices at the Environmental Protection Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-802.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-30T11:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="519">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 519.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Matheson moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7604-7606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3957.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-07-30T20:44:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7605" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2008--Passed House amended.
Water Use Efficiency and Conservation Research Act - Requires the Environmental Protection Agency's (EPA) Assistant Administrator for Research and Development to establish a research and development program to promote water use efficiency and conservation, including: (1) technologies and processes that enable the collection, storage, treatment, and reuse of rainwater, stormwater, and greywater; (2) water storage and distribution systems; and (3) behavioral, social, and economic barriers to achieving greater water use efficiency.Requires the Assistant Administrator to coordinate the development of a strategic research plan for the water use efficiency and conservation research and development program established by this Act with all other EPA research and development strategic plans.Requires the Assistant Administrator to: (1) facilitate the adoption of technology and processes to promote water use efficiency and conservation; and (2) collect and disseminate information on technologies and processes to promote water use efficiency and conservation, including information on incentives and impediments to development and commercialization, best practices, and anticipated increases in water use efficiency and conservation resulting from the implementation of specific technologies and processes.Requires at least four projects under which funding is provided for the incorporation into a building (at least one residential and one commercial building) of the latest water use efficiency and conservation technologies and designs.Requires biennial reports to Congress on research and development projects initiated under this Act, outreach and communication activities concerning water use efficiency and conservation, and development and implementation of the strategic research plan.Directs the EPA Administrator to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences for completion of a study of "low impact" (mimicking predevelopment hydrology) and "soft path" (using natural capacities of ecosystems) strategies for management of water supply, wastewater, and stormwater.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
