<bill session="109" type="h" number="4860" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Childhood Obesity Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce and prevent childhood obesity by encouraging schools and school districts to develop and implement local, school-based programs designed to reduce and prevent childhood obesity, promote increased physical activity, and improve nutritional choices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2006-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2006-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2006-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2006-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1324"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Exercise"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Obesity"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2006--Introduced.
Childhood Obesity Reduction Act - Establishes a Congressional Council on Childhood Obesity to engage in the following activities to encourage every U.S. elementary and middle school to develop and implement a plan to reduce and prevent obesity, promote improved nutritional choices, and promote increased physical activity: (1) work with outside experts to develop the Congressional Challenge to Reduce and Prevent Childhood Obesity; (2) develop and maintain a website on best practices for reducing and preventing childhood obesity; (3) assist schools in establishing goals for the healthy reduction and prevention of childhood obesity; (4) consult and coordinate with the President's Council on Physical Fitness and other federal initiatives that are conducting activities to reduce and prevent childhood obesity; (5) reward elementary schools, middle schools, and local educational agencies promoting innovative, successful strategies; (6) provide information to secondary schools; and (7) designate model plans for reducing and preventing childhood obesity that are submitted by schools as Congressional Challenge winners. Establishes the National Foundation for the Prevention and Reduction of Childhood Obesity as a nonprofit private corporation to support and carry out activities to prevent and reduce childhood obesity, including by: (1) establishing a fund to provide endowments for positions within the Council and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) associated with reducing childhood obesity; (2) evaluating model plans used by schools; and (3) making Challenge awards to schools and local agencies for developing and implementing such plans. Requires creation of a committee to incorporate the Foundation under state laws, establish its policies and bylaws, provide for its initial operation, and appoint members of its board of directors.</summary>
</bill>
