<bill session="110" type="s" number="1790" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communities of Color Teen Pregnancy Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make grants to carry out activities to prevent the incidence of unintended pregnancies and sexually transmitted infections among teens in racial or ethnic minority or immigrant communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="468"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Ethics"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sex education"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2007--Introduced.
Communities of Color Teen Pregnancy Prevention Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for projects to prevent teen pregnancies in racial, ethnic minority, or immigrant communities with a substantial incidence or prevalence of cases of teen pregnancy compared to the average number in communities in the state.Allows the Secretary to make grants to: (1) carry out activities to prevent unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections among teens; (2) provide necessary social and cultural support services regarding teen pregnancy; (3) provide health and educational services related to the prevention of unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections among teens; (4) promote better health and educational outcomes among pregnant teens; and (5) provide relevant training for individuals who plan to work in school-based support programs.Requires the Secretary to make grants to: (1) provide public education and increase awareness with respect to the issue of reducing the rates of unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections among teens and related social and emotional issues; and (2) establish and operate a National Clearinghouse for Teen Pregnancy Prevention.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to make grants for research on the prevention of unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections among teens in such communities.Allows a grant to be made under this Act only if the applicant agrees that: (1) all information provided pursuant to the Act will be age-appropriate, factually and medically accurate and complete, and scientifically based; and (2) information, activities, and services under the grant will be provided in the language and cultural context that is most appropriate for individual groups.</summary>
</bill>
