<bill session="111" type="hr" number="443" updated="2013-07-19T22:59:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the support of the House of Representatives for members of the Armed Forces and veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder and their families and urging the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense to improve the services and support available to such members, veterans, and families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400661"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2009-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
Supports increased efforts to allow spouses and family members of veterans, including those killed in combat in Iraq and Afghanistan, to receive needed counseling services at Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities. Encourages the Secretaries of Veterans Affairs and Defense to develop programs for veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) that include and treat the entire family. Calls on the Secretaries and the heads of other appropriate federal agencies to increase resources available for family and friends of veterans suffering from PTSD. Urges the Secretaries to increase access to counseling and other mental health services to family members of veterans as part of the comprehensive plan for the treatment of mental health conditions of members of the Armed Forces required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008. Urges the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to collaborate with the Department of Defense (DOD) center of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of PTSD and other mental health conditions with respect to the education, treatment, and support of family members of veterans with such conditions. Requests the Secretaries to submit to Congress a list of statutory barriers that prevent each department from expanding access to mental health counseling services to family members of veterans. Urges the Secretary to aggressively work with Congress, veterans service organizations, and others to determine how to best meet the needs of veterans and their family members.</summary>
</bill>
