<bill session="110" type="h" number="3243" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Poverty Measurement Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Bureau of the Census to publish improved annual measures of family income for use in more accurately determining the extent of poverty in the United States and the anti-poverty effectiveness of means-tested benefit and tax programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400429"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1675-1676"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO23" subcommittee="Information Policy, Census, and National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Income statistics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2007--Introduced.
Poverty Measurement Improvement Act - Requires the Bureau of the Census to publish, annually, statistics on levels of family income in the United States in order to more accurately determine the extent of poverty and the antipoverty effectiveness of means-tested benefit and tax programs. Requires such statistics to be based on the following measures of income: (1) full benefits poverty income (equal to the sum of partial benefits poverty income and noncash benefits attributable to the members of a household); and (2) full benefits and taxes poverty income (equal to full benefits poverty income increased by state and federal earned income tax credits, refundable child credits, and any other refundable tax credit and decreased by state and federal income and payroll taxes attributable to the members of a household).Requires the Bureau to use such measures to produce corresponding tables and graphs showing for each year: (1) the partial benefits poverty rate; (2) the full benefits poverty rate; and (3) the full benefits and taxes poverty rate.</summary>
</bill>
