<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1109" updated="2013-07-19T23:05:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-25T12:01:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-25T12:01:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 3961) to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to reform the Medicare SGR payment system for physicians and to reinstitute and update the Pay-As-You-Go requirement of budget neutrality on new tax and mandatory spending legislation, enforced by the threat of annual, automatic sequestration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T10:38:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-420, by Mr. Perlmutter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T10:38:00-05:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for the consideration of the Senate amendments to H.R. 3961. The resolution makes in order a single motion by the Chair of the Committee on the Judiciary to concur in the Senate amendments. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the motion except clause 10 of Rule XXI and provides that the Senate amendments shall be considered as read. Finally, the resolution provides one hour of debate on the motion equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-02-25T10:38:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="164">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 164.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Perlmutter moved that the House now consider the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H845-848" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T11:36:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1109.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T12:01:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H848" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-02-25T12:01:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H845" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T12:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 3961) to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to reform the Medicare SGR payment system for physicians and to reinstitute and update the Pay-As-You-Go requirement of budget neutrality on new tax and mandatory spending legislation, enforced by the threat of annual, automatic sequestration.</summary>
</bill>
