<bill session="111" type="s" number="651" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Compensation Fairness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose an excise tax on excessive bonuses paid by, and received from, companies receiving Federal emergency economic assistance, to limit the amount of nonqualified deferred compensation that employees of such companies may defer from taxation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3563-3564"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-03-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="37">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 37.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
Compensation Fairness Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on excessive bonuses paid by federal emergency economic assistance recipients to their employees (including directors or officers). Sets the overall rate of such tax at 70% of the amount of such bonuses, 35% payable by federal emergency economic assistance recipients and 35% payable by the employees of such recipients. Exempts bonus recipients who repay bonus amounts to the federal government. Defines "excessive bonus" as any retention bonus or other bonus that exceeds $50,000 paid by a federal emergency economic assistance recipient after December 31, 2008. Defines "federal emergency economic assistance recipient" as: (1) an entity and its affiliates to which the federal government has paid an aggregate of more than $100 million of assistance and in which the federal government has acquired an equity interest under a program authorized by the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 or the Federal Reserve Act; and (2) the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac). Limits to $1 million the amount of compensation which a participant in a nonqualified deferred compensation plan maintained by a federal emergency economic assistance recipient may defer in any 12-month period.</summary>
</bill>
