<bill session="111" type="h" number="3478" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient-Controlled Healthcare Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify rules relating to health savings accounts, to provide payments for a health savings account and for a high deductible health plan instead of entitlement to benefits under Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP, to give more control and coverage to patients, to lower health care costs through increased price transparency, and to require immigrants to have a health savings account and high deductible health coverage at time of admission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400651"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Patient-Controlled Healthcare Protection Act of 2009 - Establishes an Advantage HSA (health savings account) program to provide payments to individuals in lieu of benefits under the Medicare, Medicaid, and Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) of the Social Security Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income payments made to an Advantage HSA and premium payments for a high deductible health plan under an Advantage HSA. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for payment by debit card of HSA medical expenses. Establishes the HSA Healthcare Panel to review information relating to treatments, services, and products treatable as medical expenses under an HSA. Requires health care providers to disclose to patients the actual price to be charged for services or treatment and different payment rates applicable to other health care entities. Prohibits the issuance or renewal of an immigrant visa to an alien unless such alien presents evidence of coverage under a high deductible health plan and an HSA. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to impose criminal penalties on an alien who reenters the United States after receiving emergency medical assistance prior to removal.</summary>
</bill>
