<bill session="110" type="h" number="7316" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Limitation on Nuclear Cooperation with the United Arab Emirates Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restrict nuclear cooperation with the United Arab Emirates, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="United Arab Emirates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2008--Introduced.
Limitation on Nuclear Cooperation with the United Arab Emirates Act of 2008 - Prohibits any agreement for cooperation to enter into force or any license to be issued for the export of nuclear material, equipment, or technology between the United States and the United Arab Emirates (UAE) pursuant to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 unless the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the government of the UAE has: (1) taken actions to prohibit the transfer of goods, services, or technology to the government of Iran, including fully implementing U.N. Security Council sanctions against Iran; (2) implemented an export control regime in accordance with international standards and has implemented legislative and functional actions to target the logistical and financial networks that support terrorist organizations; (3) terminated all related cooperation between any UAE national and the government of Iran, any Iranian national, or any Iranian-controlled entity, and has prosecuted any such UAE national, and (4) not engaged in or condoned activities that violate the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act, and other applicable U.S. law. Amends the the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require congressional approval of an agreement for peaceful nuclear cooperation (section 123 agreement). (Under current law such an agreement become effective unless Congress disapproves it within a specified time period.) Directs the President to keep the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations fully informed of any initiative or negotiations relating to a new or amended section 123 agreement.</summary>
</bill>
