<bill session="113" type="h" number="2279" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Excessive Deadline Obligations Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Reducing Excessive Deadline Obligations Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act relating to review of regulations under such Act and to amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 relating to financial responsibility for classes of facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412406"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Consideration and Mark-up Session Held by the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy Prior to Introduction.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 18.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-179, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 1, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-01T13:58:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="183">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 183.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2013--Introduced.
Reducing Excessive Deadline Obligations Act of 2013 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to remove a requirement that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) review and revise regulations promulgated under such Act at least every three years. Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to prohibit the President from promulgating any financial responsibility requirement under such Act without first reporting on: each facility or class of facilities to be covered by such requirement; the development of such requirement, including why the facility or class proposed to be covered by such requirement presents the highest level of risk of injury and why they are not already covered by adequate financial responsibility requirements; financial responsibility requirements promulgated by state or other federal agencies for the facility or class to be covered by such proposed requirement; the exposure to the Hazardous Substances Superfund for response costs resulting from such proposed covered facilities; and the capacity of the financial and credit markets to provide instruments of financial responsibility necessary to meet such requirement. Requires the President to update such report to reflect any revision of the facilities or classes of facilities to be covered by a financial responsibility requirement. Requires an owner or operator of a facility or vessel that has already established evidence of financial responsibility associated with the production, transportation, treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous substances under state law or any other federal law to establish evidence of financial responsibility under CERCLA only if the President determines that, in the event of a non-permitted release of hazardous substances, the existing financial responsibility requirements will not be sufficient to cover likely response costs.</summary>
</bill>
