<bill session="112" type="s" number="3598" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Robert Matava Exploitation Protection for Elder Adults Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect elder adults from exploitation and financial crime, to prevent elder adult abuse and financial exploitation, and to promote safety for elder adults.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="462"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2012--Introduced.
Robert Matava Exploitation Protection for Elder Adults Act of 2012 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) expand the prohibition against telemarketing fraud to cover e-mail marketing fraud; (2) include within the definition of "telemarketing or e-mail marketing" any plan to induce investment for financial profit, participation in a business opportunity, commitment to a loan, or participation in a fraudulent medical study, research study, or pilot study; and (3) apply enhanced penalties to telemarketing or e-mail marketing in connection with health care fraud offenses. Directs the Attorney General to annually: (1) collect from law enforcement agencies and prosecutor offices statistical data relating to the incidence of elder abuse, (2) identify common data points that would permit the collection of uniform national data, (3) publish a summary of the data collected, (4) identify the types of data that should be collected and what entity is most capable of collecting it, and (5) develop recommendations for collecting additional data. Requires the Attorney General to: (1) provide information, training, and technical assistance to assist states and local governments in investigating, prosecuting, preventing, and mitigating the impact of elder abuse, exploitation, and neglect; (2) carry out other specified duties in connection with enhancing the understanding, prevention, detection, and response to elder abuse; and (3) in cooperation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the Legal Services Corporation, to establish a demonstration program to provide grants annually to not more than six civil legal services entities that could prevent or provide remedies for abuse, neglect, and exploitation, and collaborate with other organizations seeking to prevent, detect, and respond to elder abuse. Grants congressional consent to any two or more states to enter into agreements or compacts for cooperative effort and mutual assistance in: (1) promoting the safety and well-being of elders, and (2) enforcing their respective laws and policies to promote such safety and well-being. Directs the Executive Director of the State Justice Institute to submit legislative proposals relating to the facilitation of interstate agreements and compacts. Requires the Comptroller General to publish a report reviewing any findings on the financial cost to the federal government from the abuse and exploitation of elders.</summary>
</bill>
