<bill session="111" type="s" number="1320" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy-Efficient Manufactured Housing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Energy-Efficient Manufactured Housing Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide assistance to owners of manufactured homes constructed before January 1, 1976, to purchase Energy Star-qualified manufactured homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2010-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2010-01-27" withdrawn="2010-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-307.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="593">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 593.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Energy-Efficient Manufactured Housing Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to provide grants to each state agency responsible for developing state energy conservation plans under the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide to owners of dated manufactured homes (manufactured homes constructed before January 1, 1976): (1) grants or loans to use toward the purchase of new Energy Star qualified manufactured homes, including single- and multi-section manufactured homes; and (2) rebates or grants for the decommission of such homes. Requires the Secretary, in providing such grants, to give priority to states that: (1) have a high percentage of dated manufactured homes relative to the existing manufactured housing stock of the state; (2) would experience substantial energy gains and returns on investment from replacement of dated manufactured homes; (3) have a high percentage of counties with fewer than six residents per square mile; (4) have the infrastructure or planned infrastructure necessary to replace dated manufactured homes; or (5) act in partnership with providers of affordable lending products that enable buyers to build wealth. Restricts rebates to owners of dated manufactured homes that are used on a year-round basis as a primary residence that will be destroyed (including appropriate recycling) and replaced in an appropriate area with an Energy Star qualified manufactured home. Limits rebates to: (1) one owner per household; (2) households with total incomes not exceeding 200% of the federal poverty level in the applicable area; and (3) $7,500 per manufactured home. Limits the amount of a decommission assistance rebate or grant to $2,500 per home. Allows a state agency to supplement the amount of the rebate using state or other funds. Permits a state agency conducting a program to replace dated manufactured homes with Energy Star qualified manufactured homes to use the amounts provided under this Act to support the program. Requires a homeowner that receives a grant or loan to: (1) assume a mortgage or personal property loan that maximizes the ability of the homeowner to stay in the new manufactured home, minimize default, and build equity; and (2) own or have a land-lease of not less than the longer of 10 years or the length of the mortgage term on the land on which the manufactured home is sited. Directs the Secretary to seek to achieve the purpose of this Act through similar federal programs, including the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009. Authorizes any amount made available under this Act for the Weatherization Assistance Program for Low-Income Persons to be used for the replacement of pre-1976 substandard manufactured homes with Energy Star-qualified manufactured homes. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
