<bill session="113" type="h" number="2217" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-06T11:13:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-06T11:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-29T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-91, by Mr. Carter.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-29T12:36:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="64">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 64.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T20:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 243 Reported to House. Resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 243.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3110-3161" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3131" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3132, H3135, H3139" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3139, H3140, H3141-3142, H3146, H3154-3156" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3156, H3156-3157, H3159" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2216 and H.R. 2217. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on each bill. The resolution provides that each bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. The resolution provides that the Chair may accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record. The resolution provides one motion to recommit for each bill with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 243 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable David P. Roe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2217.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Moore amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moore amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Moore demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Reichert amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T13:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Polis amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe (TX) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Heck (NV) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Heck (NV) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Heck (NV) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Runyan amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Grimm amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lynch amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garcia amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garcia amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garcia demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tipton amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Deutch amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Deutch amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Deutch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Broun (GA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tipton amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hudson amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Mica amendment No. 8 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Mica amendment No. 6 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Brownley amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Swalwell amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Fincher moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2217 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3162-3214" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3165-3166" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3166, H3168" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3168-3170, H3173-3174, H3176" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair recognized Members for the purpose of conducting colloquys.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T17:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bishop (NY) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bishop(NY) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (NY) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Moran amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T18:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moran amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Moran demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T18:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Goodlatte stated that section 563 changes existing law in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Pierluisi amendment No. 12 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Grimm amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Ryan (OH) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ryan (OH) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ryan (OH) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cassidy amendment No. 1 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T20:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cassidy amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Westmoreland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T20:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bustos amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Meadows amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Meadows amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Meadows demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T20:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Grayson amendments en bloc under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Murphy (FL) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Collins (GA) amendment No. 2 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Thompson (MS) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Thompson (MS) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Thompson (MS) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Salmon amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Runyan amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Runyan amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Runyan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson Lee amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T21:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gingrey amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T22:02:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T23:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Flores amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T23:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Meehan amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T23:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Ben Ray Lujan amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T23:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ben Ray Lujan amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Carter demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T23:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Engel amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05T23:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Ellison amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Blackburn amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:26:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blackburn amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Blackburn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Barletta amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carter moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:30:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T00:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2217 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T09:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3220" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T09:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T09:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carter moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T09:20:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T09:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2217 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3221-3225" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:04:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2217.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3223" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Murphy (FL) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3223-3225" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3223" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House prodeeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy (FL) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back forthwith with an amendment to increase funds for the Federal Emergency Management Agency Salaries and Expenses by $7,500,000 and the National Predisaster Mitigation Fund by $2,500,000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3224" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 226 (Roll no. 210).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="211" datetime="2013-06-06T11:13:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 245 - 182 (Roll no. 211).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>House requested return of papers pursuant to H. Res. 255.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Senate Committee on Appropriations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Senate returned papers to House, per House request of June 11, 2013, by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4403-4404" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations pursuant to the order of 6/12/13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-77.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="140">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 140.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Discharged, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="243"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="243"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="933"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="United Arab Emirates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h97"/>
    <amendment number="h98"/>
    <amendment number="h99"/>
    <amendment number="h100"/>
    <amendment number="h101"/>
    <amendment number="h102"/>
    <amendment number="h103"/>
    <amendment number="h104"/>
    <amendment number="h105"/>
    <amendment number="h106"/>
    <amendment number="h107"/>
    <amendment number="h108"/>
    <amendment number="h109"/>
    <amendment number="h110"/>
    <amendment number="h111"/>
    <amendment number="h112"/>
    <amendment number="h113"/>
    <amendment number="h114"/>
    <amendment number="h115"/>
    <amendment number="h116"/>
    <amendment number="h117"/>
    <amendment number="h118"/>
    <amendment number="h119"/>
    <amendment number="h120"/>
    <amendment number="h121"/>
    <amendment number="h122"/>
    <amendment number="h123"/>
    <amendment number="h124"/>
    <amendment number="h125"/>
    <amendment number="h126"/>
    <amendment number="h127"/>
    <amendment number="h128"/>
    <amendment number="h129"/>
    <amendment number="h130"/>
    <amendment number="h131"/>
    <amendment number="h132"/>
    <amendment number="h133"/>
    <amendment number="h134"/>
    <amendment number="h135"/>
    <amendment number="h136"/>
    <amendment number="h137"/>
    <amendment number="h138"/>
    <amendment number="h139"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2014 - Makes appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for FY2014.Title I: Departmental Management and Operations - Makes appropriations for: (1) the Office of the Secretary of Homeland Security and executive management, (2) the Office of the Under Secretary for Management, (3) the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, (4) the Office of the Chief Information Officer, (5) intelligence analysis and operations coordination activities, and (6) the Office of the Inspector General. Title II: Security, Enforcement, and Investigations - Makes appropriations for: (1) U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), including for border security fencing, infrastructure, and technology; (2) U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), including to reimburse other federal agencies for the costs associated with the care, maintenance, and repatriation of smuggled aliens unlawfully present in the United States, to identify and remove from the United States aliens convicted of a crime once they are judged deportable, and for detention and removal operations; (3) the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), including for aviation security (including explosives detection systems), surface transportation security, the development and implementation of vetting and credentialing activities of the Office of Transportation Threat Assessment and Credentialing, transportation security support and intelligence, and the Federal Air Marshals; (4) the Coast Guard, including funding designated by the Congress for Overseas Contingency Operations/Global War on Terrorism, funding derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund for prevention, removal, and enforcement related to oil discharges, funding for environmental compliance and restoration functions, and funding for the Coast Guard Reserve; and (5) the U.S. Secret Service. Requires the Border Patrol to maintain an active duty presence of not less than 21,370 full-time equivalent agents protecting U.S. borders in FY2014. Prohibits the use of funds appropriated for border fencing for concurrent deployment of technology associated with integrated fixed towers until the Commissioner of CBP certifies that operational testing has been completed on the first deployment. Requires ICE funding to maintain a level of not less than 31,800 detention beds through September 30, 2014. Requires the TSA Administrator to submit a report, by December 31, 2013, that: (1) certifies that one in four air passengers that require security screening by TSA is eligible for expedited screening without lowering security standards; and (2) outlines a strategy to increase the number of air passengers eligible for expedited screening to 50% by the end of calendar year 2014. Title III: Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery - Makes appropriations for FY2014 for: (1) the Office of the Under Secretary for the National Protection and Programs Directorate, including for the Federal Protective Service (FPS) and the Office of Biometric Identity Management; (2) the Office of Health Affairs, including for BioWatch operations; and (3) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), including for grants for state and local programs (including the Urban Area Security Initiative), firefighter assistance grants, emergency management performance grants, the U.S. Fire Administration, disaster relief, the flood hazard mapping and risk analysis program, the National Flood Insurance Fund, the predisaster mitigation grant program, and the emergency food and shelter program. Requires the revenues and collections of security fees credited to the account of FPS to be available until expended for necessary expenses related to the protection of federally owned and leased buildings and for the operations of FPS, provided that the Secretary of DHS and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) shall certify by December 31, 2013, that FPS operations will be fully funded in FY2014 through revenues and collection of security fees and shall adjust the fees to ensure fee collections are sufficient to ensure that FPS maintains not fewer than 1,371 full-time equivalent staff and 1,007 full-time equivalent Police Officers, Inspectors, Area Commanders, and Special Agents who, while working, are directly engaged on a daily basis protecting and enforcing laws at federal buildings. Requires the Director of FPS to include with the submission of the President's FY2015 budget a strategic human capital plan that aligns fee collections to personnel requirements based on a current threat assessment. Title IV: Research and Development, Training, and Services - Makes appropriations for FY2014 for: (1) U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (CIS), including for the E-Verify program; (2) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center; (3) the Office of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology; and (4) the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office. Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act for grants for immigrant integration to provide services to aliens who have not been lawfully admitted for permanent residence. Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 501) Sets forth limitations and prohibitions on the availability, use, reprogramming, or transfer of funds for specified programs and activities under this Act. (Sec. 513) Prohibits the use of funds available in this Act to amend the oath of allegiance required under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA). (Sec. 523) Prohibits the use of funds by CIS to grant an immigration benefit unless the results of required background checks have been received and do not preclude granting the benefit. (Sec. 526) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this or any other Act to approve a waiver of the navigation and vessel-inspection laws for the transportation of crude oil distributed from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve until the Secretary of DHS takes adequate measures to ensure the use of U.S. flag vessels. (Sec. 527) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act to reduce the Coast Guard's Operations Systems Center mission or its government-employed or contract staff levels. (Sec. 528) Prohibits the use of funds for CBP to prevent an individual from importing a prescription drug from Canada if: (1) such individual is not in the business of importing a prescription drug; and (2) such drug complies with specified provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and is not a controlled substance or a biological product. Makes this section applicable only to individuals transporting on their person a personal-use quantity of the prescription drug, not exceeding a 90-day supply. (Sec. 531) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act: (1) for planning, testing, piloting, or developing a national identification card; (2) to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions, of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the U.S. Armed Forces, or who is or was held on or after June 24, 2009, at the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, by the Department of Defense (DOD); or (3) to employ unauthorized aliens. (Sec. 539) Requires any company that collects or retains personal information directly from any individual who participates in TSA's Registered Traveler or successor program to safeguard and dispose of such information in accordance with specified requirements. (Sec. 541) Requires the TSA Administrator to: (1) submit to the House and Senate Appropriations Committees a report that either certifies that the requirement for screening all air cargo on passenger aircraft by the deadline has been met or includes a strategy to comply with such requirements, and (2) continue to submit such reports every 180 days until the Administrator has achieved screening of 100% of such air cargo. (Sec. 550) Prohibits funds made available under this Act or any prior appropriations Act from being provided to the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN) or any of its affiliates, subsidiaries, or allied organizations. (Sec. 552) Requires the DHS Secretary to ensure enforcement of immigration laws. (Sec. 556) Prohibits funds made available under this Act from being used by a federal law enforcement officer to facilitate the transfer of an operable firearm to an individual if the officer knows or suspects that the individual is an agent of a drug cartel unless U.S. law enforcement personnel continuously monitor or control the firearm at all times. (Sec. 559) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to pay for the travel to or attendance of more than 50 employees of a single component of DHS, who are stationed in the United States, at a single international conference unless the Deputy Secretary determines that such attendance is in the national interest and notifies the Senate and House Appropriations Committees within at least 10 days of that determination and its basis. (Sec. 560) Directs the Secretary to submit an annual report to the Inspector General regarding the costs and contracting procedures related to each conference held by any departmental component, agency, board, commission, or office during FY2014 for which the cost to the U.S. government was more than $100,000. Requires the head of any departmental component, agency, board, commission, or office, within 15 days after holding a conference during FY2014 for which the cost to the U.S. government was more than $20,000, to notify the Inspector General of the date, location, and number of employees attending such conference. (Sec. 561) Prohibits the use of funds to administer or enforce provisions regarding adjusted premium rates under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968. (Sec. 562) Directs the FEMA Administrator, in administering the funds made available to address any major disaster declared on or after August 27, 2011, to establish a pilot program for the relocation of state facilities under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. (Sec. 565) Amends: (1) the Department of Justice Appropriations Act of 2002 to increase from $7 to $9 the fee charged by the Attorney General for the immigration inspection of each passenger arriving at a U.S. port of entry, or for the preinspection of a passenger in a place outside of the United States prior to such arrival, aboard a commercial aircraft or commercial vessel; and (2) the Consolidated Appropriations Resolution, 2003 to increase from $3 to $5 the amount charged by the Attorney General per individual for the immigration inspection or pre-inspection of each commercial vessel passenger, with an exception for designated ports of entry passengers arriving by ferry or by Great Lakes and connecting waterways when operating on a regular schedule. (Sec. 566) Authorizes the Secretary to accept donations of real and personal property (including monetary donations) and nonpersonal services from private parties and state and local governments for purposes of constructing, altering, operating, or maintaining a new or existing land port of entry facility. (Sec. 567) Prohibits the Secretary from: (1) imposing any new border crossing fee on individuals crossing the southern U.S. border or the northern border at a land port of entry, or (2) conducting any study relating to the imposition of a border crossing fee. (Sec. 568) Revises the visa waiver program under the INA to authorize the Secretary (in lieu of the Attorney General) to designate any country as a program country if such country provides machine-readable passports and the visa refusal rate and overstay rate for nationals of that country were both not more than 3% in the previous fiscal year. Revises probationary and termination provisions. Provides for the consultative role of the Secretary of State. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to conduct a review of the methods used by the Secretary to: (1) track aliens entering and exiting the United States, and (2) detect any such alien who stays longer than such alien's period of authorized admission. Directs the Secretary to submit: (1) an evaluation of the security risks of aliens who enter the United States without an approved Electronic System for Travel Authorization verification, and (2) a description of any improvements needed to minimize the number of aliens who enter the United States without such verification. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary, in the process of conducting evaluations of countries participating in the visa waiver program, to prioritize the reviews of countries in which circumstances indicate that such a review is necessary or desirable. (Sec. 570) Rescinds specified funds for: (1) the Coast Guard for acquisition, construction, and improvements; (2) TSA for aviation security and research and development; and (3) CBP unobligated prior year balances for border security, fencing, infrastructure, and technology. (Sec. 571) Rescinds specified amounts of funds transferred to DHS when it was created in 2003 for: (1) CBP for salaries and expenses; (2) ICE for a Violent Crime Reduction Program; (3) TSA; (4) the Coast Guard for acquisition, construction, and improvements; (5) FEMA for the Office of Domestic Preparedness and the National Predisaster Mitigation Fund; and (6) the Working Capital Fund. (Sec. 572) Rescinds specified funds from unobligated balances made available in the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund.</summary>
</bill>
