<bill session="113" type="h" number="1583" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAST Redress Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an appeal and redress process for individuals who are screened against the terrorist watchlist and wrongly delayed or prohibited from boarding a flight, or denied a right, benefit, or privilege, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2013--Introduced.
Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2013 or the FAST Redress Act of 2013 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish an Office of Appeals and Redress to implement a redress process for individuals who believe they were wrongly delayed or prohibited from boarding a commercial aircraft or denied a right, benefit, or privilege by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) because they were wrongly identified as a threat when screened against the terrorist watchlist used by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), Customs and Border Protection (CBP), or any component of DHS. Requires the Director of such Office to: (1) maintain such redress process, which shall include an information technology system that addresses case management, workflow, document management, recordkeeping, and interoperability issues identified by audits of the process in effect before enactment of this Act; (2) review, adjudicate, and respond in writing, within 30 days, to an individual who files an appeal and redress request; and (3) maintain a Comprehensive Cleared List of individuals who are determined by the Director to have been misidentified. Directs the Secretary: (1) to ensure that such Cleared List is electronically integrated into the systems for screening individuals against the terrorist watchlist, (2) to transmit to government entities that use such watchlist such Cleared List and any other information necessary to resolve misidentifications, (3) to work with such entities to ensure that the Cleared List is considered when assessing the security risk of an individual, and (4) in conjunction with DHS's Chief Privacy Officer, to take specified steps to protect or limit the use of personally identifiable information, including requiring DHS employees to complete mandatory privacy and security training before being authorized to handle such information. Requires the Office to: (1) provide, at each airport at which DHS has a presence, written information to individuals about how to begin the appeal and redress process; and (2) ensure the availability, at each airport at which DHS has a significant presence, of a TSA or CBP supervisor to provide support to individuals in need of guidance in such process. Requires the DHS Inspector General to report on the implementation and impact of this Act. Incorporates the appeals and redress process into the Secure Flight Program.</summary>
</bill>
