<bill session="109" type="h" number="4564" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing Useful and Responsive Giving in Emergencies (SURGE) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make improvements in the administration of charitable donations made in the aftermath of disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2005--Introduced.
Securing Useful and Responsive Giving in Emergencies (SURGE) Act - Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to report to specified congressional committees on the feasibility of establishing a publicly accessible disaster charities database of nongovernmental, private donor, private sector, and volunteer organizations that provide relief services following Incidents of National Significance and other disasters and emergencies, including organizations specializing in immediate relief and those specializing in longer-term community redevelopment.Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the FEMA Director, after the Secretary of Homeland Security declares an Incident of National Significance, to submit to such congressional committees initial, interim, and final immediate relief estimates of the money needed for immediate relief for Incident victims, and the portion of that total that private charities and nonprofit organizations should be reasonably expected to provide.Requires the Comptroller General to report to such congressional committees on the use by hurricane-relief charities of nongovernment funds donated for relief for the victims of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) assess the performance of the American National Red Cross after the hurricanes with respect to its DHS partnership and related responsibilities pursuant to Emergency Support Function 6 of the National Response Plan under the Homeland Security Act of 2002; and (2) report on its designation as the only nongovernmental organization with primary agency responsibility under such Emergency Support Function.Directs the Secretary to establish a disaster call center network to facilitate responses to Incidents of National Significance, disasters, and emergencies.Amends the federal charter of the American Red Cross with respect to its annual report to the Secretary of Defense, its purpose, and mandatory management staff, partnership, and business enterprise initiative diversity.Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to amend the National Response Plan to include a similar diversity requirement.</summary>
</bill>
