<bill session="111" type="h" number="3046" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hunting Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recognize the heritage of hunting and provide opportunities for continued hunting on Federal public land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400335"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2009-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2010-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1348"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Hunting Heritage Protection Act - Requires that federal public land be open to access and use for hunting except as limited by: (1) the federal agency with jurisdiction over the land for national security or public safety reasons or for other reasons authorized by applicable federal law for limiting access; and (2) any law of the state in which the land is located that is applicable to hunting. Directs the head of each federal agency with authority to manage a natural resource or federal public land to exercise that authority in a manner so as to support, promote, and enhance access to hunting. Instructs the head of each federal agency to ensure that federal land management decisions and actions result in no net loss of land area accessible for hunting on federal public land. Requires the heads of federal agencies with authority to manage federal public land on which hunting occurs to report annually on areas administered in which access for hunting was limited and the reasons for the limitations and on areas that were opened to hunting to compensate for areas in which there were such limitations. Prohibits a withdrawal, change of classification, or change of management status that effectively closes or limits access to 5,000 or more acres of federal public land for hunting from occurring unless the head of the federal agency that has jurisdiction over the land has submitted written notice of the action to specified congressional committees. Grants states the right to file civil actions in district courts in cases where federal agencies fail to comply with state authority to manage or regulate fish and wildlife.</summary>
</bill>
