<bill session="112" type="sj" number="20" updated="2013-07-20T02:10:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A joint resolution authorizing the limited use of the United States Armed Forces in support of the NATO mission in Libya.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2011-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with amendments and with a preamble. With written report No. 112-27. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="88">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure (S.J.Res. 20) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4305" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure (S. J. Res. 20) presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4305" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4305" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4313-4319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Cloture motion to the motion to proceed to the bill withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="hj" number="67"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="68"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="68"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="74"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. Armed Forces and coalition partners who are engaged in military operations to protect the people of Libya have demonstrated extraordinary bravery and should be commended; (2) the U.S. government should continue to support the aspirations of the people of Libya for political reform and self-government based on democratic and human rights; (3) the military goals of U.S. policy in Libya are to protect civilians and enforce U.N. Security Council Resolution 1973; (4) U.S. political goals are to achieve the departure from power of Muammar Qaddafi and his family, including through the use of diplomatic and economic pressure, so that a peaceful transition can begin to an inclusive government that ensures freedom, opportunity, and justice for the people of Libya; (5) funds of the Qaddafi regime that have been frozen by the United States should be used to reimburse the United States for expenses incurred in connection with Operation Odyssey Dawn and Operation Unified Protector, for humanitarian and reconstruction assistance, and to ensure full payment of Foreign Claims Settlement Commission awards; and (6) the costs associated with the post-conflict reconstruction and stabilization of Libya should be borne primarily by the people of Libya and by the members of the League of Arab States. Authorizes the President to continue the limited use of the U.S. Armed Forces in Libya in support of U.S. security policy interests as part of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) mission to enforce U.N. Security Council Resolution 1973, as requested by the Transitional National Council, the Gulf Cooperation Council, and the Arab League. Terminates such authorization on the date that NATO operations end or one year after the date of the enactment of this joint resolution, whichever comes first. Declares that the authority for the limited use of the U.S. Armed Forces is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization under the War Powers Resolution (WPR). States that U.S. military operations in Libya since April 4, 2011, constitute hostilities within the meaning of the WPR and may be carried out only under WPR provisions regarding termination of the use of U.S. Armed Forces, exceptions, and extension. Prohibits funds from being used to: (1) deploy units or members of the U.S. Armed Forces in Libya in ground combat operations or participating in stabilization or international peacekeeping operations following Muammar Qaddafi's removal from government and during the transition to a new government, (2) award a contract to a private security contractor to conduct ground activity in Libya, or (3) otherwise establish or maintain units or members of the U.S. Armed Forces or private security contractors on the ground in Libya. Permits the obligation or expenditure of funds: (1) for the immediate personal defense of U.S. government officials or for rescuing members of NATO forces from imminent danger, or (2) if the President first certifies to Congress that the action is necessary and legislation is enacted specifically authorizing such action. States that Congress does not support deploying, establishing, or maintaining the presence of units and members of the U.S. Armed Forces on the ground in Libya unless the purpose of the presence is limited to the immediate personal defense of U.S. government officials or to rescuing members of NATO forces from imminent danger. Directs the President to consult frequently with Congress regarding U.S. efforts in Libya, including by providing regular briefings and reports to Congress not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this joint resolution and every 30 days thereafter. Includes as elements in such briefings and reports: (1) an updated description of U.S. national security interests and policy objectives in Libya; (2) an updated list of U.S. Armed Forces activities in Libya; (3) an updated assessment of the opposition groups in Libya, including potential successor governments; and (4) a full explanation of the President's legal and constitutional rationale for conducting military operations in Libya consistent with the WPR. Directs the President to report to Congress not later than 15 days after enactment of this joint resolution and every 30 days thereafter regarding: (1) the total cost to the U.S. government of military operations in Libya since their commencement on March 19, 2011; (2) the total cost to the U.S. government of military operations in Libya during the preceding 30 days; (3) sources and amounts of any reimbursements the United States has received from other countries for costs of military operations in Libya since their commencement; (4) a list of U.S. government direct spending programs whose budgetary resources will be reduced to pay for any unreimbursed costs associated with U.S. military operations in Libya since their commencement and the amount of such reductions; (5) the impact of U.S. military operations in Libya on the capacity of the United States to carry out military operations against al Qaeda and the Taliban; and (6) the impact of NATO military operations in Libya on the capacity of NATO countries to participate in other NATO operations, including in Afghanistan. Terminates such reporting requirement 30 days after the President notifies Congress that U.S. military operations in Libya have ended. Directs the President to continue any federal investigative activities regarding the bombing of Pan Am flight 103 and any other terrorist attacks attributable to the government of Muammar Qaddafi against U.S. citizens with the goal of bringing those responsible to justice.</summary>
</bill>
