<bill session="111" type="s" number="3393" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">COBRA Health Benefits Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for extension of COBRA continuation coverage until coverage is available otherwise under either an employment-based health plan or through an American Health Benefit Exchange under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5324"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2010--Introduced.
COBRA Health Benefits Extension Act of 2010 - Extends COBRA coverage (health insurance continuation benefits) until the earlier of: (1) the first date in which an individual is eligible for coverage under an employment-based health plan; or (2) the date on which such individual becomes eligible for health insurance coverage through an American Health Benefit Exchange under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA). Directs the Secretary of Labor to provide rules setting forth the form and manner in which prompt notice to individuals of such continued coverage shall be made. Allows a state to enforce the provisions of this Act with respect to COBRA continuation coverage provided under a state program. Provides that this Act has no effect on termination of continuation coverage for any reason other than expiration of a period of a specified number of months.</summary>
</bill>
