<bill session="110" type="h" number="3241" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03T23:55:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-08-03T23:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the amount of loans to be guaranteed under title XVII of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03T23:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 110-309, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03T23:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Science and Technology discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-08-03T23:55:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="196">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 196.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-08-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Reported to House without amendment, Part I.
Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) prohibit loan guarantees for innovative technologies from being less than the minimum amount determined by the Secretary of Energy to be likely to attract nonguaranteed investment adequate to capitalize the project; (2) authorize the Secretary to guarantee up to 100 % of any debt obligation of the borrower to fund an eligible project; and (3) prohibit the Secretary from issuing a rule or regulation establishing a lower percentage limit. Conditions such loan guarantee upon reasonable assurances by the borrower that all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction work financed in whole or in part with the loan will be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor. Prohibits any appropriation authorized pursuant to the Act from excluding any category of specified eligible projects.</summary>
</bill>
