<bill session="110" type="s" number="3523" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eight Steps to Energy Sufficiency Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Energy Security and Climate Enhancement Through Clean Coal Technology Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide 8 steps for energy sufficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9034"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Introduced.
Eight Steps to Energy Sufficiency Act of 2008 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) take designated actions to promote advanced batteries research and development for (plug-in) electric drive vehicles, including a direct loan program for domestic production. Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to prescribe procedures for oil and natural gas preleasing and leasing activities in certain new producing areas of the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS). Amends the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008, to repeal the prohibition against final regulations for a commercial leasing program for oil shale resources on public land. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) enter into a streamlined refinery permitting process (upon request of a state governor or Indian tribe); and (2) report to certain congressional committees regarding additional federal incentives to increase production of cellulosic ethanol. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to report to Congress regarding actions to limit litigation under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a tax credit for hydrogen installation, infrastructure, and fuel costs; and (2) extend and modify tax credits for renewable energy production, solar energy and fuel cell investment, residential energy efficient property, renewable energy bonds, energy efficient new and existing homes, and energy efficient appliances produced after 2007. Extends and modifies the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial buildings. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to declare certain large-scale coal-to-liquid facilities eligible for the federal loan guarantee program. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a loan program for coal-to-liquid facilities. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to permit the Secretary of Energy to construct storage facilities near pipeline infrastructure and a military base and store coal-to-liquid products in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR). Authorizes specified funds for the Air Force Research Laboratory to continue support efforts to test and procure coal-derived synthetic fuels for aviation jet use. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow specified tax incentives for coal-to-liquid production. Energy Security and Climate Enhancement Through Clean Coal Technology Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe specified clean coal technology incentives, including: (1) an investment credit for carbon dioxide capture, transport, and storage equipment; and (2) a credit for carbon dioxide sequestration in the generation of electricity. Provides for the issuance of clean energy coal bonds.Withdraws specified lands from certain leasing, mining and materials sales laws, and places them under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Energy for nuclear waste access to Yucca Mountain. Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to prescribe infrastructure activities related to a facility licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) at the Yucca Mountain site. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish: (1) a nuclear power facility construction credit; and (2) a five-year accelerated depreciation for new nuclear power facilities. Prescribes a leasing program for oil and gas exploration, development and production within the Coastal Plain of Alaska (known as the 1002 Coastal Plain Area). Establishes the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund. Prohibits exportation of oil or gas produced under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
