<bill session="111" type="s" number="3337" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Spill Claims Assistance and Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Works and Economic Development Administration Act of 1965 to establish a program to provide technical assistance grants for use by organizations in assisting individuals and businesses affected by the Deepwater Horizon oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2010--Introduced.
Oil Spill Claims Assistance and Recovery Act - Amends the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program to provide technical assistance grants within 60 days after this Act's enactment to eligible organizations for use in assisting individuals and businesses affected by the Deepwater Horizon oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico. Authorizes the use of grant funds to: (1) support education, outreach, intake, language services, accounting services, pro bono legal services, damage assessments, economic loss analysis, collecting and preparing documentation, and assistance in the preparation and filing of claims or appeals; (2) provide assistance to individuals or businesses seeking assistance from a party responsible for the oil spill, the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund, an insurance policy, or any other federal, state, or local government program; (3) pay salaries, training, and appropriate expenses relating to the purchase or lease of property to support operations, equipment, and travel expenses; (4) assist other organizations in assisting specific business sectors, providing services, assisting specific jurisdictions, or otherwise supporting operations; and (5) establish an advisory board of service providers and technical experts to monitor the claims process relating to the oil spill and to provide recommendations to the parties responsible for the oil spill, the National Pollution Funds Center, other appropriate agencies, and Congress to improve fairness and efficiency in the claims process. Prohibits the use of grant funds to provide compensation for damages or removal costs relating to the oil spill. Encourages the Secretary to consider grant applications from organizations that have established networks with affected business sectors, including the fishery and aquaculture industries, the restaurant, grocery, food processing, and food delivery industries, and the hotel and tourism industries. Requires the Director of the National Pollution Funds Center and the parties responsible for the oil spill to provide training to such an organization regarding the claims process. Makes grant funds available until the later of: (1) six years after the date of the oil spill; and (2) the date on which all claims relating to the oil spill have been satisfied.</summary>
</bill>
