<bill session="111" type="s" number="1580" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting America's Workers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to expand coverage under the Act, to increase protections for whistleblowers, to increase penalties for certain violators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8867"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2067"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2009--Introduced.
Protecting America's Workers Act - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA) to expand its coverage to federal, state, and local government employees. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor, under specified conditions, to cede OSHA jurisdiction to another federal agency with respect to certain occupational standards or regulations for such agency's employees. Declares OSHA inapplicable to working conditions covered by the Federal Mine Safety and Heath Act of 1977. Sets forth increased protections for whistle blowers under OSHA. Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) the posting of employee rights; (2) a prohibition against the adoption or implementation of policies or practices by employers that discourage the reporting of work-related injuries or illnesses or that discriminate or provide for adverse action against any employee for reporting such injury or illness; (3) a prohibition against the loss of wages or employee benefits as a result of an employee participating in or aiding workplace inspections; (4) investigations of incidents in a place of employment resulting in a death or the hospitalization of two or more employees; (5) a prohibition against designating a citation for an occupational health and safety standard violation as an unclassified citation; (6) the rights of an employee who has sustained a work-related injury or illness that is the subject of an investigation; (7) an employer's right to contest citations and penalties; (8) the Secretary's assertion of an employer's failure to correct a serious hazard during an employer's contest to a citation; and (9) employee objections to modifications of citations. Increases civil and criminal penalties for certain OSHA violators. Requires a state that has an approved plan for the development and enforcement of occupational safety and health standards to amend its plan to conform to the requirements of this Act within 12 months after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
