<bill session="110" type="s" number="1367" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Treatment and Prevention of Methamphetamine Abuse Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Services Act to provide methamphetamine prevention and treatement services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5948-5949"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and women"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2007--Introduced.
Treatment and Prevention of Methamphetamine Abuse Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary), acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (the Administrator), to award grants to provide residential substance abuse treatment to pregnant and postpartum women. Directs the Secretary to award grants to states to provide recovery support services for parents and families transitioning out of treatment. Requires the Secretary, jointly with the Attorney General, to assist local jails and detention facilities in providing substance abuse treatment services as alternatives to incarceration for nonviolent offenses. Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide for recovery-based housing support activities. Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to require the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to provide for the establishment of a National Court Teams Resource Center to promote the well-being of maltreated infants and toddlers and their families. Requires the Secretary to award scholarships to individuals who agree to provide substance abuse treatment services in rural or underserved areas. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to provide for methamphetamine prevention activities in schools and communities. Requires the Secretary to provide for a national telephone helpline and online resource center to assist parents and family members in receiving support, information about preventing drug abuse, and treatment referral information. Provides for: (1) examinations of the long-term effects of methamphetamine use on drug endangered children; and (2) evaluations to determine the effectiveness of methamphetamine prevention programs.</summary>
</bill>
