<bill session="113" type="h" number="899" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for additional safeguards with respect to imposing Federal mandates, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400643"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2013-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, Rules, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H819"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 17.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2013--Introduced.
Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2013 - States as the purposes of this Act to: (1) improve the quality of the deliberations of Congress with respect to proposed federal mandates by providing Congress and the public with more complete information about the effects of such mandates and by ensuring that Congress acts on such mandates only after focused deliberation on their effects; and (2) enhance the ability of Congress and the public to identify federal mandates that may impose undue harm on consumers, workers, employers, small businesses, and state, local, and tribal governments. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to: (1) require the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), at the request of the chairman or ranking member of a congressional committee, to conduct an assessment comparing the authorized level of funding in legislation to the prospective costs of carrying out any changes to a condition of federal assistance being imposed on state, local, or tribal governments participating in the federal assistance program; (2) modify the definition of "direct costs" to require CBO to consider, in accounting for the costs of federal mandates, forgone business profits, costs passed onto consumers and other entities, and behavioral changes; (3) eliminate the exemption of independent regulatory agencies (except the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee) from reporting requirements under the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (UMRA); and (4) make the raising of points of order in the consideration of congressional legislation applicable to legislation that would increase the direct cost of private sector mandates beyond limits established by UMRA. Amends UMRA to: (1) transfer certain responsibilities under such Act from the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs; (2) set forth detailed criteria to guide agencies in assessing the effects of federal regulatory actions on state, local, and tribal governments and the private sector; (3) revise requirements for agency statements accompanying significant regulatory actions to require an analysis of the annual effect of a proposed final rule on state, local, or tribal governments or the private sector and to require all statements and summaries under UMRA to be detailed; and (4) extend to the the private sector (including small business) the requirement for consultation with agencies in the development of regulatory proposals containing significant federal mandates and set forth detailed guidelines for such consultation. Revises UMRA reporting requirements to require: (1) the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs to provide guidance and oversight so that agency regulations are consistent with the principles and policies of UMRA and do not conflict with the policies or actions of another agency; and (2) agencies to include in their annual compliance statements an appendix detailing consultation activities with state, local, and tribal governments and the private sector. Amends UMRA to require an agency, at the request of the chairman or ranking member of a standing or select House or Senate Committee, to conduct a retrospective analysis of an existing regulation promulgated by such agency and submit to the chairman of the relevant committee, Congress, and the Comptroller General (GAO) a report on such regulation. Expands judicial review under UMRA to include review of provisions of such Act relating to agency assessment of the effects of the regulatory process and agency selection of the least costly or least burdensome alternative to a regulatory mandate. Grants courts expanded powers to compel agencies to comply with UMRA reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
