<bill session="112" type="h" number="6303" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Science Program for Security, Competitiveness, and Diplomacy Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Global Science Program for Security, Competitiveness, and Diplomacy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400638"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research and Science Education" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Global Science Program for Security, Competitiveness, and Diplomacy Act of 2012 - Authorizes the Secretary of State to establish the Global Science Program for Security, Competitiveness, and Diplomacy, which shall provide for: (1) global, regional, or country-specific research competitions to address global challenges and collaborative research, including programs to employ scientists in research for peaceful purposes; (2) science and engineering institutional capacity building; (3) nonproliferation research and training; and (4) online access to worldwide science journals. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the Advisory Panel on International Scientific Cooperation to facilitate Program implementation. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the Embassy Science Fellows Program to: (1) pay for the costs of federal scientists to serve in the Department of State, and (2) enhance scientists' role in U.S. diplomatic efforts. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the Jefferson Science Fellows Program to: (1) provide an opportunity for tenured research-active scientists and engineers from the U.S academic community to serve in the Department of State for one year, and (2) enhance the availability at the Department of up-to-date scientific knowledge relevant to foreign policy and international relations. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the Scientific Envoys Program under which the Secretary shall appoint scientists and engineers to serve as envoys on behalf of the United States to: (1) represent the U.S. commitment to promote, in collaboration with other countries, the advancement of science and technology; and (2) facilitate partnerships with eligible countries. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Office of the Science and Technology Advisor should be further integrated into Department activities, and (2) relevant federal agencies should work to improve the visa process to ensure that the United States remains a central destination for scientific conferences and programs.</summary>
</bill>
