<bill session="109" type="h" number="6390" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Parents' Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a civil action for a minor injured by exposure to an entertainment product containing material that is harmful to minors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Sex-oriented businesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2006--Introduced.
Parents' Empowerment Act - Authorizes a minor, through a person acting on his or her behalf under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, to bring a civil action in U.S. district court for compensatory and punitive damages for the knowing sale or distribution in interstate or foreign commerce of an entertainment product containing material harmful to minors, if: (1) a reasonable person would expect a substantial number of minors to be exposed to the material; and (2) the minor as a result of such exposure is likely to suffer personal or emotional injury or injury to mental or moral welfare.Makes it an affirmative defense to such an action that: (1) a parent or guardian of the minor owned or possessed the entertainment product containing the material to which the minor was exposed; and (2) an act of that parent or guardian was the proximate cause of the minor&#146;s exposure.</summary>
</bill>
