<bill session="110" type="h" number="6261" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Midwest Storm Victim Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the maximum amount of financial assistance that an individual or household is eligible to receive under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act in connection with recent storm damage and flooding in the Midwest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2008-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2008-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2008--Introduced.
Midwest Storm Victim Relief Act of 2008 - Directs the President, in providing financial assistance to individuals and households in connection with major disasters declared for storm damage and flooding in Indiana, Iowa, Minnesota, and Wisconsin from May 26-June 15, 2008, to double the maximum assistance available under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to suspend certain limitations on personal casualty losses attributable to major disasters declared for such storm damage and flooding. Excludes from gross income, for purposes of the Code, any amount received as compensation for a loss for which a deduction is allowed by reason of such a declaration if such compensation is received in a subsequent taxable year.</summary>
</bill>
