<bill session="110" type="h" number="7200" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Information and Treatment Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish programs that use the Internet to provide to patients and health care practitioners coordinated information on diseases and other conditions, to establish authorities that provide patients and health care practitioners freedom in the choice of medical treatments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2008--Introduced.
Medical Information and Treatment Access Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to utilize an Internet site to consolidate and translate federal health care information for the public.Authorizes health care practitioners to provide unapproved treatments to their patients under specified conditions, including that: (1) the drug used must be an active ingredient in an approved drug or an unapproved drug that is approved for commercial distribution in a foreign country; (2) the practitioner receives informed consent from the patient; (3) the practitioner submits a registration to the Secretary before providing the treatment; and (4) the Secretary determines that there is no clear and convincing evidence that the treatment is unsafe. Deems the registration to be cleared if the Secretary fails to act within 90 days.Requires the Secretary to establish a program to maintain information regarding registrations under this Act.Directs the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to establish a program to gather information from practitioners regarding surgical procedures and make such information publicly available.Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Center for Complementary and Alternative Medicine to establish a program to gather information from health care practitioners regarding alternative medicine and make such information publicly available.Gives a drug or device company immunity from federal and state liability claims for: (1) the use of a relevant unapproved treatment by a practitioner under a cleared registration; and (2) the provision by the company of information upon the request of a practitioner if the company reasonably believes the information to be accurate.</summary>
</bill>
