<bill session="112" type="h" number="6205" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect and Save Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent identity theft and tax fraud, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3215"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3482"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1534"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2012--Introduced.
Protect and Save Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose tax return information to federal and state law enforcement agencies to assist in the investigation of the misuse of the identity of another person for purposes of filing a false or fraudulent tax return,&#160;(2) direct the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to establish within the Criminal Investigation Division of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) the position of Local Law Enforcement Liaison to coordinate the investigation of tax fraud with state and local law enforcement agencies,&#160;and (3) make permanent the authority of the Secretary to disclose tax return information to federal and state prison officials to prevent the filing of false or fraudulent tax returns by prison inmates. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1)&#160;implement an identity theft tax fraud prevention program; and (2) review whether current tax laws and regulations related to the confidentiality and disclosure of tax return information prevent the effective enforcement of federal, state, and local identity theft statutes. Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to conduct a study and report&#160;on: (1) the role of prepaid debit cards and commercial tax preparation software in facilitating fraudulent tax returns through identity theft, and (2) the role e-filing and electronic tax returns play in either facilitating or preventing fraudulent tax returns through identity theft. Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from disclosing information contained&#160;on the Death Master File relating to a deceased individual to persons who are not certified to access such information. Requires the head of the Federal Bureau of Prisons to submit a detailed plan to Congress on how information obtained from the IRS will be used to reduce prison tax fraud.</summary>
</bill>
