<bill session="112" type="h" number="2839" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Piracy Suppression Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Piracy Suppression Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To suppress the threat of piracy on the high seas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2011-09-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10T15:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 112-273, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10T15:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-11-10T15:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="183">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 183.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2011--Reported to House without amendment, Part I.
Piracy Suppression Act of 2011 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Revised Statutes to subject any person who commits an act of piracy to the penalty of death or imprisonment for life. Defines "act of piracy" to mean any: (1) illegal act of violence, detention, or depredation, committed by the crew or passengers of a vessel against a vessel, person, or property on the high seas or in any other place outside the jurisdiction of a state (including inciting or facilitating such an act of piracy); and (2) any voluntary act of participation in the operation of a vessel with knowledge that it is a pirate ship. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to seek reimbursement from a foreign country for the cost of U.S. action to protect or defend foreign-flagged vessels of the country from a pirate attack, including the cost of U.S. action to deter the attack. Authorizes the waiver of such costs under certain circumstances. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish a training program for U.S. mariners on the use of force against pirates. (Sec. 5) Directs the DOT Secretary to require each federal agency responsible for the transport of equipment, materials, or commodities (government-impelled cargo) by U.S. vessels to provide armed personnel aboard such vessels while transiting high-risk waters. Requires each agency to reimburse vessel owners or operators for the cost of providing armed personnel. (Sec. 6) Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on efforts to track ransom payments paid to pirates operating in the waters off Somalia and improve their prosecution.</summary>
</bill>
