<bill session="111" type="s" number="1200" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Short Term Accelerated Retirement of Inefficient Vehicles Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a temporary vehicle trade-in program through which the Secretary of Transportation shall provide financial incentives for consumers to replace fuel inefficient vehicles with vehicles that have above average fuel efficiency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6260-6262"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6262-6265" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1550"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1550"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1606"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2640"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2751"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="247"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1135"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1248"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Introduced.
Short Term Accelerated Retirement of Inefficient Vehicles Act of 2009 - Establishes in the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) a Cash for Clunkers Temporary Vehicle Trade-In Program through which the Secretary of Transportation, acting through NHTSA, shall: (1) authorize the issuance of a voucher to offset the purchase or lease price for a fuel efficient automobile upon the transfer of the eligible trade-in vehicle title to a participating dealer; (2) register dealers for Program participation; (3) make payments to them for eligible transactions they accept between specified dates; and (4) establish and provide for the enforcement of measures to prevent and penalize fraud under the Program. Prescribes requirements, including combined fuel economy, for $1,000, $2,500, $3,500, and $4,500 vouchers to offset the purchase or lease price for a previously owned (model year 2004 or after) or new fuel efficient passenger automobile or truck. Limits the number of vouchers to one per customer, including joint registered owners of a single eligible trade-in vehicle. Requires a dealer to certify that each eligible trade-in vehicle: (1) has been or will be crushed or shredded, or transferred to an entity that will ensure it will be crushed or shredded, within the period of the Program; and (2) has not been, and will not be, sold, leased, exchanged, or otherwise disposed of for use as an automobile in the United States or in any other country. Makes it unlawful for any person to violate this Act or any regulations issued under it, particularly by fraud. Prescribes civil penalties for any such violation. Directs the Secretary to make Program information available on an Internet website and through other means. Sets forth procedures for expedited congressional consideration of any proposed presidential rescission of discretionary budget authority under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act.</summary>
</bill>
