<bill session="109" type="h" number="3665" updated="2013-07-19T19:36:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-10T16:21:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-10T16:21:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Housing Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans Housing and Employment Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Housing and Employment Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide adaptive housing assistance to disabled veterans residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member and to make direct housing loans to Native American veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To provide adaptive housing assistance to disabled veterans residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member, to make certain improvements in veterans employment assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2005-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2005-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Provisions of H.R.1773 Incorporated in This Measure, Sections 3 and 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Provisions of H.R. 419 Incorporated in This Measure, Title II.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Provisions of H.R. 1773 Incorporated in This Measure, Title I, Section 102.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Provisions of H.R. 3279 Incorporated in This Measure, Title III.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-01T19:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 109-263.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-01T19:19:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="144">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boozman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10074-10081" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3665.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:28:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10T16:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10151" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-11-10T16:21:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/9/2005 H10074-10078" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10T16:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10T16:21:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1235"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2005--Passed House amended.
Veterans Housing and Employment Improvement Act of 2005 - Title I: Housing Assistance - (Sec. 101) Amends federal veterans' benefits provisions to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to assist certain disabled veterans who are residing temporarily in housing owned by the veteran's family member in acquiring adaptations necessitated by such disability. Provides assistance limits. Terminates such assistance five years after the enactment of this Act. Requires the Secretary to provide for the coordination of adapted housing assistance programs administered by the Under Secretary for Health and the Under Secretary for Benefits within the Department of Veterans Affairs. Directs the Comptroller General to submit to Congress an interim and final report on implementation of the assistance program. (Sec. 102) Makes permanent (currently, a pilot program prohibiting loans after December 31, 2008) a Department program to make direct housing loans to Native American veterans. Requires information concerning the cost and number of such loans to be included in certain annual reports of the Secretary and the Veterans Benefits Administration. (Sec. 103) Extends eligibility for such loans to a non-Native American veteran who is the spouse of a Native American. Title II: Employment Assistance Programs - (Sec. 201) Amends the Jobs for Veterans Act to: (1) extend through December 31, 2008, the operation of the President's National Hire Veterans Committee; (2) provide additional funding to cover such extension; and (3) extend required reports concerning Committee activities. (Sec. 202) Directs the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans' Employment and Training to furnish information to employers with respect to the training and skills of veterans and disabled veterans, and the advantages of hiring such veterans. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) develop a plan for the transition to such Assistant Secretary of certain duties and functions of the National Hire Veterans Committee; and (2) submit such plan to the congressional veterans' committees. (Sec. 203) Renames the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment and Training the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach. Adds employer outreach activities to the duties of the Advisory Committee. Modifies Advisory Committee membership. Reinstates (with modifications) annual Advisory Committee reporting requirements. Title III: Homeless Veterans Reintegration Program - (Sec. 301) Reauthorizes appropriations for the homeless veterans reintegration program (to expedite the reintegration of homeless veterans into the labor force) for FY2007-FY2009. Title IV: Technical, Clarifying, and Clerical Amendments - (Sec. 401) Makes: (1) technical, clarifying, and clerical amendments concerning new traumatic injury protection coverage for veterans under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance Program; and (2) technical and clerical amendments to various other federal veterans' benefits provisions.</summary>
</bill>
