<bill session="111" type="h" number="3312" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preventing Unintended Pregnancies, Reducing the Need for Abortion, and Supporting Parents Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Title X Family Planning Services Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for programs that reduce the number of unplanned pregnancies, reduce the need for abortion, help women bear healthy children, and support new parents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400442" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400300" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2009--Introduced.
Preventing Unintended Pregnancies, Reducing the Need for Abortion, and Supporting Parents Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services ( HHS) to make matching grants for projects to provide comprehensive education on preventing teen pregnancies. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to reauthorize appropriations for the 21st Century Community Learning Centers and the Carol M. White Physical Education Program. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reauthorize appropriations for Federal TRIO Programs and Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs (GEARUP). Amends part A of title IV (Temporary Assistance to Needy Families) (TANF) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to award grants to states for reducing teen pregnancy and teen births. Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to require the Secretary to establish a national goal of reducing teen pregnancy by at least one-third over ten years. Authorizes the Secretary to make matching grants to assist entities in demonstrating innovative approaches to teen pregnancies, such as facilitating communication between parents and children. Requires the Secretary to award grants to organizations to establish and operate a national initiative for parents of adolescents to reduce teen pregnancy. Directs the Secretary of Education to award demonstration grants to community colleges for the purpose of developing and implementing innovative approaches to prevent unplanned pregnancy and promote healthy relationships among women and men in community colleges. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of SSA to expand coverage of family planning services. Expands and extends postpartum health care coverage for women under Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP). Expands the definition of "low-income child" under CHIP. Title X Family Planning Services Act of 2009 - Authorizes appropriations for the establishment and operation of voluntary family planning projects. Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit individual health insurance issuers from imposing any preexisting condition exclusions relating to pregnancy as a preexisting condition. Requires such issuers to provide coverage for maternity services. Authorizes the HHS Secretary to make grants for the purchase of ultrasound equipment. Requires the HHS Secretary to make grants to enable states to better identify and treat women who are victims of, or at risk of, domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, sexual coercion, or stalking. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to institutions of higher education to assist students who have decided to carry their pregnancies to term in continuing their studies and graduating. Requires the HHS Secretary to award grants for a national information campaign to educate the public about adoption. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase and make refundable the tax credit for adoption expenses. Revises and authorizes appropriations for the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC program). Requires the HHS Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine to study the range of choices women make in response to unintended pregnancy.</summary>
</bill>
