<bill session="112" type="s" number="2091" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Job Creation and International Tax Reform Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the international tax system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S497-498"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S498-502" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2735"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2012--Introduced.
United States Job Creation and International Tax Reform Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of foreign income, to allow: (1) a 95% tax deduction for the foreign source portion of dividends that a domestic corporation receives from a controlled foreign corporation of which it is a U.S. shareholder, (2) domestic corporations to treat gain on the sale or exchange of stock of a foreign corporation held for at least one year as dividends eligible for the 95% tax deduction, (3) a 50% tax deduction for the foreign intangible income of a domestic corporation, and (4) a U.S. shareholder of a controlled foreign corporation to elect a 70% tax deduction for certain amounts received from such a corporation. Includes certain low-taxed foreign income as subpart F income (e.g., certain passive income, insurance income, foreign-base company income, income from countries subject to international boycotts, illegal bribes, kickbacks, and similar payments, and income from countries where the United States has severed diplomatic relations). Makes permanent exemptions from treatment as subpart F income for: (1) certain payments of dividends, interest, rents, and royalties received from a related controlled foreign corporation; and (2) active financing income. Modifies rules relating to the foreign tax credit to create a separate income category for foreign intangible income. Accelerates the effective date of the worldwide interest allocation rules to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2012 (currently, after December 31, 2020).</summary>
</bill>
