<bill session="109" type="s" number="2161" updated="2013-07-19T20:32:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small System Safe Drinking Water Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to prevent the enforcement of certain national primary drinking water regulations unless sufficient funding is available or variance technology has been identified.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2005-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/22/2005 S14322"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arsenic"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water purification"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2005--Introduced.
Small System Safe Drinking Water Act of 2005 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA): (1) to convene a working group to study barriers to using specified treatments; (2) to develop model guidance to assist states in regulating and promoting such treatment options; and (3) when proposing a national standard for drinking water that includes a maximum containment level, to translate health effects into the quantity of water an individual can consume and the timeframe that may elapse before the effects of a contaminate can occur. Requires: (1) feasible technologies to reflect water sources from various regions of the United States; and (2) the Administrator to consider specified cost factors when establishing affordability criteria for variance technology. Prohibits the Administrator or a state from enforcing a national primary drinking water regulation when: (1) variance technology is not identified in guidance or regulations for public water systems serving a population of less than 10,000; and (2) sufficient funds are not available to assist each system in meeting regulations. Considers a system that conforms to a bilateral compliance agreement with the state to be in compliance with related federal drinking water standards. Revises provisions allowing an exemption of a system from maximum containment level and treatment technique requirements to: (1) increase the population threshold; and (2) allow state determinations of a renewal period. Establishes pilot programs to: (1) explore new technologies or approaches to comply with a standard; and (2) research technology transfer issues and disinfection strategies. Revises technical assistance provisions to require water systems to receive adequate technical assistance and training to meet requirements of final rules. Gives priority to systems not in compliance with specified rules concerning: (1) disinfectants and disinfection byproducts; and (2) arsenic and compliance and new source monitoring. Prohibits enforcement by the Administrator against a system unless adequate technical assistance and training are first provided. Authorizes appropriations through FY2010. Requires the Administrator to establish a panel to study the health effects of exposure to arsenic and disinfection byproducts.</summary>
</bill>
