<bill session="110" type="hr" number="92" updated="2013-07-19T20:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to clarify and make corrections to the House ban on air travel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H948"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2007--Introduced.
Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to revise the new prohibition against the use by a Member, Delegate or Resident Commissioner of personal funds, official funds, or campaign funds for a flight on a nongovernmental plane that is not licensed by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to operate for compensation or hire. Changes the prohibition to one against the use of such funds for a flight on a nongovernmental plane that is owned or operated by a registered lobbyist or agent of a foreign principal (or from a private entity retaining or employing such individuals), except for flights: (1) on regularly scheduled air carriers; (2) at the public rate on chartered aircraft where seats are generally available to the public; and (3) on aircraft used in support of official duties approved in advance by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</summary>
</bill>
