<bill session="113" type="h" number="2398" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Security and Federal Lands Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture from taking action on Federal lands that impede border security on such lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2013--Introduced.
National Security and Federal Lands Protection Act - Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) from prohibiting or restricting U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) activities on federal land under their respective jurisdictions, located within 100 miles of an international land border, to: (1) execute search and rescue operations, and (2) prevent all unlawful entries into the United States through the international land borders of the United States. Grants CBP access to such lands to conduct the following activities: (1) road and barrier construction and maintenance; (2) use of patrol vehicles; (3) installation, maintenance, and operation of surveillance equipment and sensors; and (4) deployment of temporary tactical infrastructure. Provides that a waiver by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) of specified laws regarding sections of the international border between the United States and Mexico and between the United States and Canada shall apply to all land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture within 100 miles of the international land borders of the United States with respect to CBP activities under this Act. States that this Act shall not be construed to restrict legal use (grazing, hunting, mining, or public-use recreational and backcountry airstrips) on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture. States that: (1) this Act shall have no effect on state or private lands, and shall not provide authority on or access to state or private lands; and (2) nothing in this Act supersedes, replaces, negates, or diminishes treaties or other agreements between the United States and Indian tribes.</summary>
</bill>
