<bill session="111" type="s" number="2819" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Processed Food Safety Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Poultry Products Inspection Act, the Federal Meat Inspection Act, and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require processors of food products to certify to the applicable Secretary that the processed food products are not adulterated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12009-12011"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12011" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/30/2009--Introduced.
Processed Food Safety Act of 2009 - Amends the Poultry Products Inspection Act and the Federal Meat Inspection Act to prohibit the sale or transport in commerce of any processed poultry, poultry product, meat, or meat food product capable of human consumption that has not undergone a pathogen reduction treatment for each ingredient or been certified to contain no verifiable traces of pathogens. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require each registered facility to: (1) apply pathogen reduction treatments to each food that it manufactures, processes, packages, or holds for consumption in the United States; and (2) certify that each such food contains no verifiable traces of pathogens, or that each such food leaving the facility has received required pathogen reduction treatments. Requires coloring, synthetic flavorings, and spices used in such products to be named.</summary>
</bill>
