<bill session="112" type="s" number="1891" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Roadless Area Conservation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide lasting protection for inventoried roadless areas within the National Forest System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Roadless Area Conservation Act of 2011 - Prohibits road construction and road reconstruction in inventoried roadless areas of the National Forest System. Specifies exceptions, including because: (1) there is threat of a catastrophic event, (2) a natural resource restoration action is necessary, or (3) a federal-aid highway project is in the public interest or is consistent with the purposes for which the land was reserved or acquired. Prohibits timber from being cut, sold, or removed in an inventoried roadless area. Permits various exceptions, including for specified environmental reasons, if the responsible official determines that the cutting, sale, or removal of timber is expected to be infrequent. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make modifications to roadless area maps to improve their accuracy or inclusiveness. Instructs the Secretary, in order to evaluate the effect of a modification to a roadless area map, to prepare an environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Declares that this Act does not: (1) revoke, suspend, or modify legal instruments and decisions concerning the use of NFS land made before January 12, 2001; (2) compel the amendment or revision of any land and resource management plan; or (3) apply to specified activities in the Tongass National Forest. States that the prohibitions and restrictions of this Act cannot be reconsidered, modified, or terminated under the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974.</summary>
</bill>
