<bill session="109" type="s" number="2584" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rocky Mountain FIRES Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rocky Mountain Forest Insects Response Enhancement and Support Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to help reduce the increased risk of severe wildfires to communities in forested areas affected by infestations of bark beetles and other insects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3235"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4875"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Rocky Mountain Forest Insects Response Enhancement and Support Act or the Rocky Mountain FIRES Act - Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to require the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to use not less than 70% of the funds allocated for authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in the Rocky Mountain region for: (1) projects in the wildland-urban interface; and (2) projects on land that is in proximity to a municipal water supply system or a stream feeding such a system in a municipal watershed and that has been identified for such projects in community wildfire protection plans. Authorizes the Secretary to designate insect-emergency areas. Authorizes grants to: (1) at-risk communities in the Rocky Mountain region to assist such communities in preparing or revising a community wildfire protection plan; and (2) owners or operators of facilities that use biomass to offset their costs of purchasing biomass. Requires the Secretary to establish at least one collection point for the placement of vegetative material removed from federal or other land as part of a hazardous fuel reduction project.</summary>
</bill>
