<bill session="112" type="s" number="3472" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Uninterrupted Scholars Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Uninterrupted Scholars Act (USA)</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Uninterrupted Scholars Act (USA)</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Uninterrupted Scholars Act (USA)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 to provide improvements to such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2012-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5880"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-17">
      <text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8091-8092" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-12-17" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-17T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Roe (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7450-7453" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3472.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:55:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Roe (TN) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-01T23:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7559" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2013-01-01T23:13:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/30/2012 H7450" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-01-01T23:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-01-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2013-01-14" type="public" number="112-278">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-278.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5871"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="3478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3345"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/14/2013--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 17, 2012. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Uninterrupted Scholars Act (USA) - Amends provisions of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 that prohibit the Department of Education from funding educational agencies or institutions that release student educational records (or personally identifiable information other than certain directory information) to any individual, agency, or organization without written parental consent. Expands the list of organizations exempt from such prohibitions (thereby permitting the educational agencies or institutions participating in a Department of Education program to release records or identifiable information to such organizations without parental consent) to include an agency caseworker or other representative of a state or local child welfare agency or tribal organization authorized to access a student's case plan when such agencies or organizations are legally responsible for the care and protection of the student. Sets forth conditions including that: (1) the education records, or the personally identifiable information contained in such records, will not be disclosed by such agency or organization, except to an individual or entity engaged in addressing the student's education needs and authorized by such agency or organization to receive such disclosure; and (2) such disclosures be consistent with applicable student record confidentiality laws of states and tribes. Permits the release of such records and information without additional notice to parents and students when a parent is a party to a court proceeding involving child abuse and neglect or dependency matters and a court order has already been issued in the context of that proceeding.</summary>
</bill>
