<bill session="110" type="h" number="1511" updated="2013-07-19T21:16:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide relief with respect to rent and mortgage payments for members of the reserve components who are called to active duty and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a refundable credit to lessors for payments foregone by reason of such relief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to allow a military reservist who is ordered to active duty for a period of more than 90 days: (1) an exemption during the period of active duty from payment of rent on a primary residence occupied by such member or dependents; and (2) a deferral of mortgage payments on a principal residence. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow lessors of military reservists granted an exemption from rent payments under this Act a refundable tax credit for the exempted lease amounts.</summary>
</bill>
