<bill session="111" type="h" number="5088" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">America's Commitment to Clean Water Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reaffirm the jurisdiction of the United States over waters of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2010-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E608-609"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2010--Introduced.
America's Commitment to Clean Water Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to replace the term "navigable waters," for waters subject to the Act, with the term "waters of the United States," defined to mean: (1) all waters that are currently used, were used in the past, or may be susceptible to use in interstate or foreign commerce including all waters that are subject to the ebb and flow of the tide; (2) all interstate and international waters, including interstate and international wetlands; (3) all other waters, including intrastate lakes, rivers, streams (including intermittent streams), mudflats, sandflats, wetlands, sloughs, prairie potholes, wet meadows, playa lakes, or natural ponds, the use, degradation, or destruction of which does or would affect interstate or foreign commerce, U.S. obligations under a treaty, or U.S. territory or property; (4) all impoundments of waters otherwise defined as waters of the United States; (5) tributaries of such waters; (6) the territorial seas; and (7) waters, including wetlands, adjacent to such waters. Excludes from such definition: (1) waters that are all or part of a waste treatment system, including treatment ponds or lagoons designed to meet the requirements of the Act; or (2) prior converted cropland. Declares that the final authority regarding jurisdiction under this Act remains with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) notwithstanding the Secretary of Agriculture's determination that an area is prior converted cropland. Sets forth provisions defining waste treatment systems and prior converted farmland. Prohibits a system or structure that is created in waters of the United States or results from the impoundment of such waters from being documented as a waste treatment system. Authorizes a waste treatment system in existence and documented before this Act's enactment to include a waste treatment system that was either originally created in or resultant from the impoundment of such waters if the system's discharge meets applicable standards and limitations at the point of discharge.</summary>
</bill>
