<bill session="113" type="s" number="205" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Consumer Financial Protection Regulations Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to replace the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection with a 5-person Commission, to bring the Bureau into the regular appropriations process, to provide for a safety and soundness check, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6079-6080" label="text of measure as introduced in Senate"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="450"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2402"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2446"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3192"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2013--Introduced.
Responsible Consumer Financial Protection Regulations Act of 2013 - Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (title X of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act) to replace the position of Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) with a five-member Commission whose members are appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Prohibits the Chair of the Commission from making requests for estimates related to appropriations without the prior approval of the Commission. Revises procedures for funding the CFPB. Eliminates the Consumer Financial Protection Fund and the requirement that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System transfer funds to the CFPB from the combined earnings of the Federal Reserve System. Authorizes appropriations for FY2013-FY2014. Directs the CFPB, in prescribing a rule under the federal consumer financial laws, to consider the rule's impact on the financial safety or soundness of an insured depository institution.</summary>
</bill>
