<bill session="109" type="s" number="131" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Clean Skies bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clear Skies Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to reduce air pollution through expansion of cap and trade programs, to provide an alternative regulatory classification for units subject to the cap and trade program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2005-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S319-348" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-867.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Bioaccumulation"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Eutrophication"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Sulphur dioxide"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Clear Skies Act of 2005 - Amends the acid deposition control provisions of the Clean Air Act with respect to emissions limitations and allowances programs for sulfur dioxide, nitrogen oxides, and mercury by: (1) revising the allowance system and associated transfer, tracking, permit, compliance plan, and penalty requirements, including those for auctions; and (2) establishing new emissions limitations and trading programs (including implementation of a separate sulfur dioxide scheme for States in the Western Regional Air Partnership). Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) promulgate performance standards (limiting emissions of sulfur dioxide, nitrogen oxides, particulate matter, and mercury) for new boilers, integrated gasification combined cycle plants, and combustion turbines; and (2) conduct a comprehensive research and environmental assessment program to enhance understanding of health and environmental effects of particulate matter and mercury and to demonstrate the efficacy of emission reductions under this Act. Excludes the following units from consideration as major emitting facilities or major stationary sources (or parts thereof) for purposes of compliance with provisions concerning prevention of significant deterioration of air quality and plan requirements for nonattainment areas: those that achieve a specified limit on particulate matter emissions or certain national emissions standards for hazardous pollutants or those with properly operated and maintained equipment to limit particulate matter emissions and that use good combustion practices to minimize carbon monoxide emissions. Establishes procedures by which owners or operators may petition the Secretary of Energy for a determination that electricity reliability will likely be threatened by the need to install pollution control technology. Allows a compliance delay in the case of a successful petition. Requires States to ensure in implementation plans that: (1) in an attainment or unclassifiable area, any emissions increase from the construction or modification of an affected unit will not result in exceeding a national ambient air quality standard; and (2) in a nonattainment area, the emissions increase will not interfere with a program to assure the achievement of such a standard. Provides for designation of transitional areas under implementation plans and states requirements for emissions inventories, the attainment of standards by the end of 2015, and penalties for not meeting the eight-hour ozone or fine particles standard.</summary>
</bill>
