<bill session="111" type="s" number="788" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">m-SPAM Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit unsolicited mobile text message spam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4319-4320"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
m-SPAM Act of 2009 - Amends the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 to exclude a message from the definition of "mobile service commercial message" (MSCM) if the message's purpose is to: (1) facilitate or confirm a commercial transaction; (2) provide warranty, recall, safety, or security information about a product or service used by the recipient; (3) provide certain information to message recipients who have an ongoing commercial relationship with the sender; (4) provide information relating to the recipient's benefit plan or employment; or (5) deliver goods or services to which the recipient is entitled. Amends that Act and the Communications Act of 1934 to exempt from a prohibition on sending unwanted MSCMs: (1) the sending of short messaging service (SMS) messages from one wireless device to another or from a mobile service provider to its subscribers at no charge; and (2) the sending of MSCMs by a mobile service provider to its subscribers at no charge (unless a subscriber has opted out). Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to revise the do-not-call registry provisions of the Telemarketing Sales Rule to: (1) consider commercial mobile service messaging practices that are costly or a nuisance to consumers; and (2) explicitly prohibit, as an abusive telemarketing act or practice, the sending of any MSCM to a telephone number that is both assigned to a commercial mobile service and listed on the do-not-call registry. Exempts such messages sent by a commercial mobile service provider to its subscribers at no charge.</summary>
</bill>
