<bill session="111" type="s" number="3696" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Direct Care Workforce Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act with regard to certain exemptions under that Act for direct care workers and to improve the systems for the collection and reporting of data relating to the direct care workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6653"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5902"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2010--Introduced.
Direct Care Workforce Empowerment Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exempt from minimum wage and maximum hour requirements any employee employed on a casual basis in domestic service employment to provide companionship services for individuals who because of disability (or because of age or infirmity, as under current law) are unable to care for themselves. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish: (1) a direct care workforce monitoring program; and (2) a National Advisory Council on the Direct Care Workforce. Directs the Secretary to award three-year grants to states and other eligible entities to improve the recruitment, retention, and education of the direct care workforce.</summary>
</bill>
