<bill session="112" type="s" number="351" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Surface Occupancy Western Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the exploration, leasing, development, and production of oil and gas in and from the western portion of the Coastal Plain of the State of Alaska without surface occupancy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2012-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S749-751"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2011--Introduced.
No Surface Occupancy Western Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act - Authorizes exploration, leasing, development, and production of oil and gas from the Western Coastal Plain. Defines the Western Coastal Plain as the area of Coastal Plain: (1) that borders the land of Alaska to the west and Alaska offshore waters of the Beaufort Sea on the north, and (2) from which the Secretary of the Interior finds oil and gas can be produced through horizontal drilling or other subsurface technology from sites outside or underneath the Coastal Plain surface. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will result in an environmentally sound program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Western Coastal Plain. Considers such program to be compatible with the purposes for which the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge was established. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish lease sale procedures, and (2) offer for lease those tracts the Secretary considers to have the greatest potential for the discovery of hydrocarbons. Authorizes the Secretary to grant a lease for land on the Western Coastal Plain to the highest responsible qualified bidder. Prescribes lease terms and conditions. Provides for expedited judicial review.Directs the Secretary to establish in the Treasury the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund to offset any planning, land use-related, or service-related impacts of offshore development caused by this Act. Prescribes a scheme for the allocation of revenues produced by bonus, rental, and royalty revenues from the federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
