<bill session="113" type="h" number="2746" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innocent Sellers Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent undue disruption of interstate commerce by limiting civil actions brought against persons whose only role with regard to a product in the stream of commerce is as a lawful seller of the product.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412482"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2013--Introduced.
Innocent Sellers Fairness Act - Exempts a lawful seller from liability for personal injury, monetary loss, or damage to property arising out of an accident or transaction involving a seller's products, unless the claimant proves one or more of the following activities by the seller: the seller was the manufacturer or participated in the design or installation of the product; the seller altered, modified, or expressly warranted the product in a manner not authorized by the manufacturer; the seller had actual knowledge of the defect in the product as a result of a recall from the manufacturer or governmental entity authorized to make such recall or actual inspection at the time the seller sold the product to the claimant; the seller had actual knowledge of the defect in the product at the time the seller supplied the product; the seller intentionally altered or modified a product warranty, warning, or instruction from the manufacturer in a way not authorized by the manufacturer; or the seller knowingly made a false representation about an aspect of the product not authorized by the manufacturer. Limits the seller's liability to the personal injury, monetary loss, or damage to property directly caused by such activity where a claimant proves one or more of such activities was negligent.</summary>
</bill>
