<bill session="110" type="h" number="2882" updated="2013-07-19T21:29:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Long-Term Care Life Safety Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to promote professional retrofit installation of fire alarm detection systems and other fire detection and prevention technologies in nursing homes, hospice facilities, and other appropriate facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412224"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2007--Introduced.
Long-Term Care Life Safety Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program to award grants to nursing homes, hospice facilities, assisted living facilities, residential care program facilities, board and care facilities and other appropriate facilities for the purpose of retrofitting such facilities with a professionally installed fire alarm detection system or other fire detection and prevention technology. Requires the Secretary to give priority to applicants that demonstrate a need or hardship. Allows the Secretary to consider such factors as the age and condition of the facilities, the need for facility beds in the community involved, and requirements imposed on the applicant to meet fire safety regulations under Medicare, Medicaid, other federal programs, or state or local licensing or building code standards.</summary>
</bill>
