<bill session="111" type="s" number="1272" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Devil's Staircase Wilderness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Devil's Staircase Wilderness Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the designation of the Devil's Staircase Wilderness Area in the State of Oregon, to designate segments of Wasson and Franklin Creeks in the State of Oregon as wild or recreation rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to provide for the designation of the Devil's Staircase Wilderness Area in the State of Oregon, to designate segments of Wasson and Franklin Creeks in the State of Oregon as wild or recreation rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6652-6653"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-285.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-257.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="527">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 527.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2888"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2888"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Devil's Staircase Wilderness Act of 2010 - Designates certain federal land in Oregon administered by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) as the Devil's Staircase Wilderness and as wilderness and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Specifies this Act's effect on: (1) the jurisdiction and responsibilities of the state of Oregon with respect to fish and wildlife; (2) protective perimeters and buffer zones around the Wilderness; (3) activities and uses outside of the boundary of the Wilderness; and (4) treaty rights of Indian tribes. Transfers the administrative jurisdiction over BLM land north of the Umpqua River to the Forest Service. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate Franklin and Wasson Creeks in Oregon as wild rivers and as components of the Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</summary>
</bill>
