<bill session="110" type="s" number="471" updated="2013-07-19T22:24:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey to The Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. certain Federal land associated with the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail in Nebraska, to be used as an historical interpretive site along the trail.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2007-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-156.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="354">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 354.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="761"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="761"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2007--Reported to Senate amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc., specified federal land associated with the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail in Nebraska, to be used as an historic site and interpretive center for the Trail. Directs the Secretary to enter into a written agreement with the Foundation to ensure that the land conveyed is operated in accordance with National Park Service standards for preservation, maintenance, and interpretation.</summary>
</bill>
