<bill session="112" type="s" number="936" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Infrastructure Investment Fund Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the American Infrastructure Investment Fund and other activities to facilitate investments in infrastructure projects that significantly enhance the economic competitiveness of the United States by improving economic output, productivity, or competitive commercial advantage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2011-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2011--Introduced.
American Infrastructure Investment Fund Act of 2011 - Establishes the American Infrastructure Investment Fund in the Department of Transportation (DOT) to: (1) invest in infrastructure projects that increase or otherwise improve U.S. economic output, productivity, or competitive commercial advantage; (2) provide funding for projects that face significant funding barriers because of the need to combine resources across multiple jurisdictions or modes of transportation; and (3) improve the efficiency or throughput, the safety, and the environmental sustainability of a national or regional transportation network. Requires the Fund to publish: (1) a detailed description of its strategy in an Investment Prospectus, and (2) its Operating Guidance for the Fund's management. Requires the President to appoint the Fund's Executive Director, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, as well as a Fund Advisory Committee. Authorizes the Fund to provide direct loans and loan guarantees to eligible recipients for activities related to the planning, preparation, or design of an eligible project proposal. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish: (1) a competitive national infrastructure investment grant program, and (2) an oversight program to monitor the effective and efficient use of funds authorized under this Act. Sets forth the federal share of net project costs at 80%.</summary>
</bill>
