<bill session="112" type="s" number="2076" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Courthouse Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve security at State and local courthouses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2012-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2012-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S390"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S391" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6185"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6185"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2012--Introduced.
Local Courthouse Safety Act of 2012 - Authorizes the Attorney General, as part of the Preventing Violence Against Law Enforcement and Ensuring Officer Resilience and Survivability Initiative (VALOR) of the Department of Justice (DOJ), to provide safety training and technical assistance to local law enforcement agencies. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to permit states and other grant recipients under the State Homeland Security Grant Program, the Urban Area Security Initiative, and Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to use grant funds to improve security at state or local government courthouses. Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to ensure that state or local governments have an opportunity to request excess security equipment (metal detectors, wands, baggage screening devices) for state or local courthouses having less security equipment than such courthouses require before such equipment is made available to any other individual or entity. Requires that priority be given to courthouses that have no security equipment.</summary>
</bill>
