<bill session="112" type="h" number="6430" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Buildings Reform Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 40, United States Code, to improve the functioning of the General Services Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2012-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Introduced.
Public Buildings Reform Act of 2012 - Sets forth new requirements for the purchase or lease of federal office space, for limiting rental costs for such space, and for suspending the construction of new courthouses after November 1, 2012. Requires that the acquisition of new federal office space through lease or purchase be offset by the elimination of at least a corresponding amount of space, and that such space be reduced by a minimum of 1 million square feet in each calendar year through 2016. Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) use commercial real estate management services to reduce the cost of federal office space, and (2) reduce the total number of full time employees of the Public Buildings Service (PBS) to 6,000 by FY2015. Suspends until October 1, 2014, the authority to use funds in the Federal Buildings Fund for bonuses, performance awards, or similar expenditures for members of the Senior Executive Service (SES). Requires the Administrator to notify specified congressional committees before entering into any contract related to a conference and to report on expenditures for such conference. Prohibits PBS, through FY2015, from hiring more than 50 individuals for an intern program, recent graduate program, Presidential Management Fellow program, or similar program. Requires the Inspector General of GSA to review PBS internship programs and report on the costs and benefits of such programs. Requires GSA to submit a detailed budget for PBS, including a breakdown of salaries, bonuses, travel and transportation, training, and conferences. Prohibits the Administrator from constructing, repairing, altering, or acquiring by lease, purchase, or otherwise a public building or space unless specifically authorized to do so by Congress. Requires the Administrator to report to Congress on: (1) utilization rates of owned and leased public buildings, (2) vacant public buildings, and (3) any increase or decrease of 5% or more in the cost of public projects.</summary>
</bill>
