<bill session="112" type="h" number="1263" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-11T19:58:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-11T19:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide surviving spouses with certain protections relating to mortgages and mortgage foreclosures.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide surviving spouses with certain protections relating to mortgages and mortgage foreclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E653"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 112-234.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-05T16:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="153">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 153.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Runyan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6727-6729" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1263.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-10-11T19:58:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6727" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2011--Passed House amended.
Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act, for five years after enactment of this Act, to afford surviving spouses of servicemembers who die while in the military and whose death is service-connected the same protections against sale, foreclosure, and seizure of property currently applicable to their husbands who while in military service are unable to meet an obligation on real or personal property. Requires each lending institution subject to specified requirements for a maximum 6% rate of interest on a servicemember's debts incurred before military service to designate one of its employees as a compliance officer responsible for: (1) ensuring the institution's compliance with such requirements, and (2) distributing information to servicemembers whose obligations and liabilities are covered by such requirements. Requires such a lending institution that had annual assets for the preceding fiscal year of $10 billion or more to maintain a toll-free telephone number and make it available on its primary Internet website. Extends from 9 months to 12 months after the end of military service the period of specified protections for servicemembers against mortgage foreclosures. Sunsets such extension on December 31, 2017.</summary>
</bill>
