<bill session="110" type="h" number="6553" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture regarding additional recreational uses of National Forest System lands subject to ski area permits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1502-1503"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2008--Introduced.
Amends the National Forest Ski Area Permit Act of 1986 to require the term and acreage of ski area permits for the operation of ski areas and associated facilities (under current law, for the operation of nordic and alpine ski areas and facilities) on National Forest System lands to be governed by provisions under the Act relating to such permits and other applicable law. Provides for the issuance of ski area permits for the use and occupancy of suitable lands within the National Forest System for skiing and other snow-sports and such other seasonal or year-round recreational activities associated with mountain resorts as the Secretary of Agriculture may authorize pursuant to this Act.Allows the Secretary to authorize the holder of a ski area permit issued pursuant to the Act to also provide on lands subject to such permit such other seasonal or year-round outdoor and natural-resource based developed recreation activities and associated facilities, in addition to skiing and other snow-sports, as determined appropriate.Prohibits any activity or facility from being authorized under this Act if its authorization would result in the primary recreational purpose of lands subject to a ski area permit not being skiing or other snow-sports.</summary>
</bill>
