<bill session="110" type="h" number="6074" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-20T13:28:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-20T13:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gas Price Relief for Consumers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">NOPEC</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Gas Price Relief for Consumers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">NOPEC</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Sherman Act to make oil-producing and exporting cartels illegal and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412233" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-19T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Scott (VA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-19T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4104-4109" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-19T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6074.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-19T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-05-20T13:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="332" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 324 - 84 (Roll no. 332).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/19/2008 H4104" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-05-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="744">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 744.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="879"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="879"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="OPEC countries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Gas Price Relief for Consumers Act of 2008 - Title I: Amendment to Sherman Act - No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2008 or NOPEC - (Sec. 102) Amends the Sherman Act to make it illegal for any foreign state or instrumentality thereof to act collectively or in combination with any other foreign state or any other person, when such action has a direct, substantial, and reasonably foreseeable effect on the market, supply, price, or distribution of petroleum in the United States, to: (1) limit the production or distribution of oil, natural gas, or any other petroleum product (petroleum); (2) set or maintain the price of petroleum; or (3) otherwise take any action in restraint of trade for petroleum. Denies a foreign state engaged in such conduct sovereign immunity from the jurisdiction or judgments of U.S. courts in any action brought to enforce this Act. States that no U.S. court shall decline, based on the act of state doctrine, to make a determination on the merits in an action brought under this Act. Authorizes the Attorney General to bring an action in U.S. district court to enforce this Act. (Sec. 103) Makes an exception to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state in an action brought under this Act. Title II: Creation of Department of Justice Petroleum Industry Antitrust Task Force - (Sec. 201) Directs the Attorney General to establish in the Department of Justice (DOJ) a Petroleum Industry Antitrust Task Force to: (1) develop, coordinate, and facilitate the implementation of DOJ investigative and enforcement policies related to petroleum industry antitrust issues under federal law; and (2) report annually to Congress on DOJ investigatory and enforcement efforts related to petroleum industry antitrust issues, and on issues related to the application of federal antitrust laws to the market for petroleum. Title III: Study by the Government Accountability Office - (Sec. 301) Directs the Comptroller General to: (1) conduct a study evaluating the effects of mergers addressed in covered petroleum merger consent decrees on competition in the markets involved, including the effectiveness of divestitures required in such decrees in preserving competition in those markets; and (2) report study results to Congress and DOJ. Directs the Attorney General to refer such report to the Task Force, which shall consider whether any further enforcement action is warranted to protect or restore competition in any market affected by a transaction to which any covered merger consent decree relates.</summary>
</bill>
