<bill session="113" type="h" number="1361" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inefficient Defense Elimination Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To terminate or retire certain aircraft and ship programs of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Inefficient Defense Elimination Act of 2013 - Prohibits any funds made available for the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2014 or thereafter from being obligated or expended to procure C-27J aircraft. Directs the Secretary of Defense, with respect to any such aircraft procured on or before the date of enactment of this Act, to: (1) make such aircraft available for sale to another federal department or agency or government of a U.S. ally, or (2) retire or dispose of such aircraft. Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of any DOD funds for FY2014 or thereafter to procure RQ-4 Block 30 Global Hawk unmanned aircraft systems. Requires the Secretary, with respect to each such system procured on or before the date of enactment of this Act, to take the same sale or disposal actions described above. Directs the Secretary to retire: (1) four Aegis guided missile cruisers during FY2014 and three during FY2015, and (2) two amphibious landing ships during FY2014. Directs the Secretary to submit to the congressional defense and appropriations committees an analysis of the necessity of stationing members of the Armed Forces in Europe, including an evaluation of property owned by the federal government there that could be sold if such stationing was reduced or eliminated.</summary>
</bill>
