<bill session="109" type="s" number="2816" updated="2013-07-19T20:38:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biofuels Security Tax Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an income tax credit for the manufacture of flexible fuel motor vehicles and to extend and increase the income tax credit for alternative fuel refueling property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2006-05-25" withdrawn="2006-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4624"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2006--Introduced.
Biofuels Security Tax Act of 2006 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow until 2017 a tax credit for flexible fuel vehicles. Defines "flexible fuel vehicle" as a motor vehicle which can operate on both gasoline and a blend of 85% ethanol and which is certified as having the same or better fuel economy rating when operating on 85% ethanol or on gasoline only. Extends until 2017 the tax credit for alternative fuel vehicle refueling property (service stations for dispensing alternative motor fuels to retail consumers). Increases the rate of such credit to 50% for all taxpayers and to 75% for taxpayers who place in service not more than five such refueling properties. Denies such credit to major oil companies (companies having at least 4,500 retail service stations).</summary>
</bill>
