<bill session="111" type="s" number="925" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Baby Products Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study the presence of contaminants and impurities in cosmetics and personal care products marketed to and used by children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4910-4911"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2009--Introduced.
Safe Baby Products Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA), to conduct and complete product testing of a full range of cosmetics, personal care products (including baby shampoo, baby bath, lipstick, nail polish, lotion, cream, sunscreen, liquid soap, and baby wipes) and other products that: (1) are marketed to or used by children aged 7 years and younger; and (2) are likely contaminated with impurities or contaminants. Requires a report on the results of the product testing to be submitted to Congress and made public. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to establish good manufacturing practices for the cosmetics industry for each impurity or contaminant for which contaminants or impurities may be reduced or eliminated by switching to alternate ingredients or for which manufacturing processes or practices may reduce or eliminate impurities from raw materials. Deems a cosmetic to be adulterated if the manufacture of such cosmetic is not in compliance with good manufacturing practices regulations.</summary>
</bill>
