<bill session="109" type="s" number="254" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Central Nevada Rural Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Central Nevada Rural Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain land to Lander County, Nevada, and the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain land to Eureka County, Nevada, for continued use as cemeteries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2005-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S767-768"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S768" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-02-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 02/17/05 without amendment. With written report No. 109-12.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-02-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="23">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 23.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="541"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2005--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Central Nevada Rural Cemeteries Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to convey to Lander County, Nevada, for no consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the National Forest System land (including any improvements on such land) known as Kingston Cemetery. Directs the Secretary to grant the County an easement allowing access for persons wanting to visit the Cemetery and other cemetery purposes over Forest Development Road #20307B, notwithstanding any future closing of the road for other use. Requires Lander County (including its successors) to continue using the land as a cemetery. Provides that, if the Secretary, after notice to the County and an opportunity for a hearing, makes a finding that the County has used or permitted the use of the land for any other purpose, and the County fails to discontinue that use: (1) title to the land shall revert to the Secretary, to be administered by the Secretary, and (2) the easement granted to the County shall be revoked. Permits the Secretary to waive the application of the reversion of the title to the land or the revocation of the easement if a waiver would be in the best interests of the United States. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, to convey to Eureka County, Nevada, for no consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the public land (including any improvements on such land) known as Maiden's Grave Cemetery. Directs the Secretary to grant the County an easement allowing access for persons wanting to visit the Cemetery and other cemetery purposes over an appropriate access route consistent with current access. Requires Eureka County (including its successors) to continue using the land as a cemetery. Provides for the reversion and waiver provisions specified above to apply to such County as well.</summary>
</bill>
