<bill session="111" type="h" number="2572" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Disclosures Protections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the Notification and Federal Employee Antidiscrimination and Retaliation Act of 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Congressional Disclosures Protections Act of 2009 - Amends federal personnel law to: (1) define "covered disclosure" with respect to federal whistleblower protections to mean a disclosure of information made by an employee to either house of Congress or to a congressional committee or staff member which such employee reasonably believes evidences a violation of any law, gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety; (2) allow federal employees to seek de novo review of their whistleblower claims within one year of filing such claims; (3) expand legal remedies for whistleblowers, including triple damages for lost wages, triple attorney fees, and triple compensatory damages; and (4) require the Office of Special Counsel to provide legal representation to whistleblowers, upon request. Amends the Notification and Federal Employee Antidiscrimination and Retaliation Act of 2002 (No Fear Act) to expand the reporting requirements of federal agencies relating to reimbursement of the expenses of employees who have filed whistleblower claims.</summary>
</bill>
