<bill session="109" type="s" number="1878" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Predatory Payday Loan Prohibition Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit predatory payday loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11437-11438"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11438-11439" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2005--Introduced.
Predatory Payday Loan Prohibition Act of 2005 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit a creditor from making a payday loan to any person if the creditor knows, or has reasonable cause to believe, that: (1) the personal check or share draft received in exchange for the loan is drawn on an insured depository institution or an insured credit union; or (2) the account that will be debited in exchange for the loan is a transaction or share draft account at an insured depository institution or an insured credit union. Defines payday loan as any transaction in which a short-term cash advance is made to a consumer in exchange for: (1) the consumer's personal check or share draft in the amount of the advance plus a fee, where presentment or negotiation of the check or draft is deferred by agreement of the parties until a designated future date; or (2) the consumer's authorization to debit his or her transaction or share draft account in the amount of the advance plus a fee, where such account will be debited on or after a designated future date. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to prohibit an insured depository institution from: (1) making any payday loan, either directly or indirectly; or (2) making a loan to another lender for purposes of financing, refinancing, or extending a payday loan.</summary>
</bill>
