<bill session="110" type="h" number="4351" updated="2013-07-19T21:41:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-12T18:55:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-12-12T18:55:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">AMT Relief Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">AMT Relief Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide individuals temporary relief from the alternative minimum tax, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11T20:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 861 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4351 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 861 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T16:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 861.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15368-15382" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T16:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4351 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T16:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4351.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McCrery moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15380" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H15380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Neal (MA) raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Neal stated that the provisions of the motion to recommit violate clause 10 of Rule XXI in that they increase the deficit over the requisite period. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McCrery appealed the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Neal (MA) moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15381" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:47:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 225 - 191 (Roll no. 1152).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-12-12T18:55:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="1153" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 193 (Roll no. 1153).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15368-15371" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12T18:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="861"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee stock options"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2007--Passed House without amendment.
AMT Relief Act of 2007 - Title I: Individual Tax Relief - (Sec. 101) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through 2007 for individual taxpayers: (1) the offset of nonrefundable personal tax credits against regular and alternative minimum tax (AMT) liability; and (2) the increased AMT exemption amounts.(Sec. 103) Increases the AMT refundable credit amount for individual taxpayers with long-term unused tax credits in prior taxable years. Abates any underpayment of tax and related interest and penalties attributable to the application of special AMT rules for the treatment of incentive stock options.(Sec. 104) Lowers in 2008 (from $10,000 to $8,500) the earned income threshold amount for determining the refundable portion of the child tax credit.Title II: Revenue Provisions - Subtitle A: Nonqualified Deferred Compensation From Certain Tax Indifferent Parties - (Sec. 201) Requires the inclusion in gross income for income tax purposes of employee compensation deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan of a nonqualified entity when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture of the rights to such compensation. Defines "nonqualified entity" as any foreign corporation unless substantially all of its income is: (1) effectively connected with a trade or business in the United States; or (2) subject to a comprehensive foreign income tax. Includes certain partnerships within such definition.Subtitle B: Codification of Economic Substance Doctrine - (Sec. 211) Sets forth rules and definitions for the application of the economic substance doctrine to transactions affecting tax liability. Deems a transaction as having economic substance only if: (1) the transaction changes in a meaningful way (apart from federal income tax effects) the taxpayer's economic position; and (2) the taxpayer has a substantial purpose for entering into such transaction. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations on economic substance.(Sec. 212) Imposes a penalty of 40% of any underpayment of tax attributable to nondisclosed noneconomic substance transactions. Sets forth a special rule for reductions of underpayment amounts subject to a tax penalty for corporations with gross receipts of more than $100 million.Subtitle C: Other Provisions - (Sec. 221) Delays until 2018 the application of special rules for the worldwide allocation of interest for purposes of computing the limitation on the foreign tax credit. (Sec. 222) Increases the penalty for failure to file a partnership tax return and extends from five to 12 the number of months in which such penalty may be imposed.(Sec. 223) Imposes an additional penalty on S corporations for failure to file required tax returns.(Sec. 224) Increases the minimum penalty for failure to file an individual income tax return.(Sec. 225) Amends the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005 to increase the estimated tax payment due in the third quarter of 2012 for corporations with assets of at least $1 billion.</summary>
</bill>
