<bill session="112" type="h" number="424" updated="2013-07-20T01:13:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Leave Ethanol Volumes at Existing Levels Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">LEVEL Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal certain amendments to the Clean Air Act relating to the expansion of the renewable fuel program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Leave Ethanol Volumes at Existing Levels Act or the LEVEL Act - Amends the Clean Air Act to revise the renewable fuel program, including by: (1) redefining "renewable fuel"; (2) reducing the percentage of renewable fuel that is required to be in gasoline sold or introduced into commerce in the United States (from 9% to 5.4% in 2008, 11.1% to 6.1% in 2009, 12.95% to 6.8% in 2010, 13.95% to 7.4% in 2011, and 15.2% to 7.5% in 2012); (3) revoking the renewable fuel standard for 2013-2022; (4) requiring the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration to provide to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) an estimate of the volumes of gasoline (currently of transportation fuel, biomass-based diesel, and cellulosic biofuel) projected to be sold or introduced into commerce in the following year; (5) making one gallon of cellulosic biomass ethanol or waste derived ethanol equivalent to 2.5 gallons of renewable fuel; (6) repealing provisions concerning cellulosic biofuel and biomass-based diesel; and (7) repealing a requirement that the Administrator of EPA promulgate fuel regulations to implement measures to mitigate adverse impacts on air quality as the result of renewable fuel requirements. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal provisions requiring EPA to report to Congress on current and future impacts of the renewable fuel requirements on environmental issues, resource conservation issues, and the growth and use of cultivated invasive or noxious plants and their impacts on the environment and agriculture. Prohibits the Administrator from permitting or authorizing (including by granting a waiver through the fuels and fuel additives waiver process) the introduction into commerce of an ethanol-gasoline blend containing greater than 10% ethanol by volume that is intended for general use in conventional gasoline-powered vehicles or engines. Requires the Administrator to study: (1) the effects of the introduction into commerce of an ethanol-gasoline blend on consumer products; (2) the impact of such blend on engine performance of conventional gasoline-powered vehicles and nonroad engines, emissions from the use of the blend, and materials compatibility and consumer safety issues associated with the use of such blend; and (3) the ability of wholesale and retail gasoline distribution infrastructure to introduce such blend into commerce without widespread misfueling by consumers.</summary>
</bill>
