<bill session="111" type="h" number="5588" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Enrollment Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for additional opportunities to enroll under part B of the Medicare Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2010--Introduced.
Medicare Enrollment Protection Act of 2010 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) establish a special Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) enrollment period period for individuals enrolled in COBRA (Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act) continuation coverage who elected not to enroll under part B during the individual's initial enrollment period; (2) require a continuous open Medicare part B enrollment, apart from an initial enrollment period or a special enrollment period, during which there shall be an increase in the monthly premium; (3) provide for special enrollment periods to correct errors, misrepresentations, or the inaction of officers, employees, or agents of group health plans or plan sponsors; and (4) direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to ensure appropriate coordination of Medicare part B with American Health Benefit Exchanges under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA). Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on enrollment in the Medicare part B program.</summary>
</bill>
