<bill session="110" type="s" number="2687" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Beneficiary Protection Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to enhance beneficiary protections under parts C and D of the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6359"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2008--Introduced.
Medicare Beneficiary Protection Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and maintain a Medicare plan complaint system. Requires non-network Medicare Advantage private fee-for-service plans to disclose providers that refuse to accept certain enrollees in the plan. Prohibits certain marketing practices with respect to Medicare Advantage plans and prescription drug plans, including provision for meals or other items of monetary value, telemarketing, cross-selling, and up-selling. Revises enrollment requirements under Medicare parts C (Medicare+Choice) and D (Voluntary Prescription Drugs). Allows an individual to discontinue an election of a Medicare+Choice plan if enrolled fewer than 60 days. Changes the beginning date of the annual, coordinated election period for such a plan from November 15 to October 1. Requires the Secretary, in establishing a process for the enrollment, disenrollment, termination, and change of enrollment of part D eligible individuals in prescription drug plans, to use rules similar to (and coordinated with) those under the Medicare+Choice program for a continuous open enrollment and disenrollment period for the first three months of the year in which an individual first becomes eligible.</summary>
</bill>
