<bill session="109" type="h" number="24" updated="2013-07-19T19:04:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preservation and Restoration of Orphan Works for Use in Scholarship and Education (PRO-USE) Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Film Preservation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Preservation of Orphan Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage the preservation and restoration of copyrighted works for research, scholarly, and educational purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2005-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1-2"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Preservation and Restoration of Orphan Works for Use in Scholarship and Education (PRO-USE) Act of 2005 - Preservation of Orphan Works Act - Provides that the limitation on rights of reproduction and distribution of copyrighted works does not apply to the authority of libraries or archives, during the last 20 years of any term of copyright of a published work, to reproduce, distribute, display, or perform in facsimile or digital form a copy or phonorecord of such work for purposes of preservation, scholarship, or research when certain conditions apply. National Film Preservation Act of 2005 - Amends the National Film Preservation Act of 1996 to direct the Librarian of Congress to carry out preservation activities, including: (1) generating public awareness of the National Film Registry; (2) updating the national film preservation program with technological advances; and (3) utilizing the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center to ensure that Registry films are properly stored and disseminated in accordance with copyright law and any relevant agreements. Directs the National Film Preservation Board to review special projects submitted for its approval by the National Film Preservation Foundation. Reauthorizes film preservation provisions. Allows the Foundation's board of directors to determine the location of its principal office. Authorizes appropriations to the Library of Congress for the Foundation. Directs the Foundation to design and support cooperative film preservation and access initiatives, with the approval of the Librarian and the Board.</summary>
</bill>
