<bill session="110" type="s" number="92" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Consumer Phone Records Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the unlawful acquisition and use of confidential customer proprietary network information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2007-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="780"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Protecting Consumer Phone Records Act - Makes it unlawful to: (1) acquire or use customer proprietary network information without written consent; (2) represent that another person has consented in order to acquire such information; (3) obtain unauthorized access to certain systems or records in order to acquire such information; (4) sell or offer for sale such information; or (5) request that another person unlawfully obtain such information. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for a civil forfeiture penalty for violation of this Act. Imposes on IP-enabled voice service providers a duty to protect the confidentiality of specified proprietary information. Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to require each telecommunications carrier to notify customers of unlawful disclosure of such information. Prohibits a commercial mobile services provider from providing any customer's wireless telephone number information to any wireless directory assistance service without express prior customer authorization. Requires de-listing on customer request without cost to the customer. Prohibits providers from publishing the information without such authorization. Prohibits fees for exercising these rights. Preempts any inconsistent state or local requirements. Requires that violations of certain provisions of this Act be enforced by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices. Gives the FCC concurrent enforcement jurisdiction. Provides for enforcement by states and preemption of state law. Requires public education about the protection afforded such information.</summary>
</bill>
