<bill session="111" type="h" number="2099" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E961-962"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="881"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization Act - Authorizes Sealaska Corporation, the Regional Corporation for southeast Alaska, notwithstanding specified provisions of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) and subject to conditions and restrictions, to select and receive conveyance of its remaining land entitlement under the ANCSA from federal land in southeast Alaska from each of the following categories: (1) specified economic development land; (2) sites with sacred, cultural, traditional, or historical significance; and (3) Alaska Native futures sites with traditional and recreational use value. Authorizes the Director of the National Park Service to enter into a cooperative management agreement with Sealaska, other village corporations and urban corporations, and federally recognized Indian tribes with cultural and historical ties to Glacier Bay National Park to recognize and perpetuate National Park Service values, including those associated with the Tlingit homeland and culture, wilderness, and ecological preservation. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to complete the conveyance of lands to Sealaska within one year of selection. Prohibits Sealaska from selecting or receiving any conveyance of lands under this Act from within any conservation system unit, federally designated wilderness area, or certain land use designation areas. Amends the National Historic Preservation Act to add to the definition of "tribal lands" land held under the ANCSA by incorporated Native groups, regional corporations, and village corporations.</summary>
</bill>
