<bill session="110" type="s" number="3078" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Innovation and Job Creation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a National Innovation Council, to improve the coordination of innovation activities among industries in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4971-4972"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial engineering"/>
    <term name="Industrial production"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2008--Introduced.
National Innovation and Job Creation Act of 2008 - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President a National Innovation Council, to be responsible for formulating and advocating for the federal government's innovation policy. Requires the Council to collaborate with major statistical agencies, collect data concerning the impact on productivity of the Council's programs, and annually report to Congress on national innovation and productivity. Places the Council under the direction of a National Innovation Council Board.Transfers to the Council specified research and innovation programs of the National Institute of Standards of Technology, the National Science Foundation, and the Department of Labor.Establishes within the Council the CLUSTER Information Center to promote the collection, development, and dissemination of data and analysis on industry clusters (geographic concentrations of interconnected businesses and associated institutions in a particular field).Requires the Council to award grants for: (1) operation of CLUSTER Initiatives (formal efforts to promote cluster growth and competitiveness through collaborative activities); (2) research partnerships between academic institutions and industry research alliances; (3) early-stage research, by academic institutions and joint ventures, into methods of increasing productivity and innovation; (4) state innovation-based economic development partnerships; and (5) diffusion of technological innovations by manufacturing extension partnership centers.</summary>
</bill>
