<bill session="110" type="h" number="3254" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BRAC COP Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BRAC Cost Overruns Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit cost growth associated with major defense base closures and realignments implemented as part of the 2005 round of defense base closure and realignment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1902"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2007--Introduced.
BRAC Cost Overruns Protection Act of 2007 or BRAC COP Act of 2007 - Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary of Defense to report to the congressional defense committees on the costs of implementing recommendations of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission that relate to military base closures and realignments that have not been fully implemented. Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify such committees if the Secretary determines that the current estimate of implementation costs for an individual major base closure or realignment is at least 25% greater than the baseline estimate for such closure or realignment; and (2) develop a business plan to reduce the costs of any individual substantially over-budget major base closure or realignment to a level less than 25% greater than its baseline estimate. Directs the: (1) Secretary to submit to the President a recommendation regarding whether to continue implementation of a substantially over-budget major base closure or realignment; and (2) President to report to Congress regarding the implementation of such a closure or realignment. Prohibits the Secretary from continuing or discontinuing the implementation of a substantially over-budget major closure or realignment recommended by the President if a joint resolution disapproving the President's recommendation is enacted.</summary>
</bill>
