<bill session="110" type="h" number="2241" updated="2013-07-19T21:23:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Diabetes Treatment and Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to prevention and treatment of diabetes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1000"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1343"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2007--Introduced.
Diabetes Treatment and Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish the Division of Diabetes Translation to eliminate diabetes.Requires the Director to develop pilot demonstration projects to evaluate various approaches to: (1) screening and identifying persons with pre-diabetes and undiagnosed diabetes; and (2) providing such persons with access to appropriate lifestyle interventions. Requires such projects to be carried out with the goal of translating the Diabetes Prevention Program clinical trial into interventions to reduce the incidence of type-2 diabetes and its related complications in the U.S. population.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director, to engage in partnerships with state and local health departments to carry out: (1) national, state, and local surveillance related to diabetes; and (2) education and information campaigns to increase awareness about the importance of primary prevention, ways to assess personal risk, and how to locate and access diabetes prevention programs.Requires the Director, acting through the Division, to develop a pilot program to improve treatment for individuals with diabetes and other co-occurring chronic conditions for which treatment may complicate the treatment for diabetes. Requires the Director to give preference to research that: (1) focuses on conditions which have a high prevalence among individuals with diabetes or for which the treatment involved has the potential to impact adherence to diabetes treatment regiments; and (2) builds upon existing work designed to improve the quality of care for patients with diabetes.</summary>
</bill>
