<bill session="113" type="h" number="748" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Universal National Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require all persons in the United States between the ages of 18 and 25 to perform national service, either as a member of the uniformed services or as civilian service in a Federal, State, or local government program or with a community-based agency or community-based entity, to authorize the induction of persons in the uniformed services during wartime to meet end-strength requirements of the uniformed services, to provide for the registration of women under the Military Selective Service Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2013--Introduced.
Universal National Service Act - Declares that it is the obligation of every U.S. citizen, and every other person residing in the United States, between the ages of 18 and 25 to perform a 2-year period of national service, unless exempted, either through military service or through civilian service in a federal, state, or local government program or with a community-based agency or entity engaged in meeting human, educational, environmental, or public safety needs. Requires induction into national service by the President. Allows persons to be inducted only: (1) under a declaration of war or national emergency, or (2) when members of the Armed Forces are engaged in a contingency operation. Requires each person, before induction, to be examined physically and mentally for classification for fitness to perform. Sets forth provisions governing: (1) induction deferments, postponements, and exemptions, including exemption of a conscientious objector from combatant training and military service; and (2) discharge following national service. Amends the Military Selective Service Act to authorize the military registration of females.</summary>
</bill>
