<bill session="113" type="h" number="2547" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Determination of Appropriate Risk-Based Capital Requirements for Community Financial Institutions Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To determine appropriate risk based capital requirements for community, mid-size, and regional institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2295"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2767"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="731"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Determination of Appropriate Risk-Based Capital Requirements for Community Financial Institutions Act of 2013 - Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (federal banking agencies) to conduct an empirical impact study before issuing a final rule in relation to proposed regulatory capital rules for the international Basel III agreement (Rules). Requires the study to include: (1) the potential impact of such Rules upon the U.S. financial services sector, specifically community, mid-size, and regional financial institutions; (2) the long-term impact of such Rules, including changes to the current risk weight framework; (3) the cost and complexity of the Rules for community financial institutions; (4) the potential indicators of community banks having to maintain higher leverage capital ratios and higher total risk-based capital ratios than non-community banks and whether such capital levels are commensurate with higher historical losses or greater risk; and (5) the impact of the Rules upon real estate markets, specifically residential mortgage lending and home equity lines of credit. Exempts this delay in rulemaking any rules applicable to global systemically important banks (as identified by the Financial Stability Board). Allows any financial institution to provide information for the study voluntarily upon agency request, but prohibits the agencies from requiring it. Requires the study to be made available to the public for notice and comment. Prohibits any regulation issued by the federal banking agencies to implement the Rules from taking effect until one year after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
