<bill session="111" type="h" number="6495" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-08T14:41:00-05:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-08T14:41:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Robert C. Byrd Mine Safety Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve compliance with mine safety and health laws, empower miners to raise safety concerns, prevent future mine tragedies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T13:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, George moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T13:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8131-8144" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T13:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6495.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T14:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8145" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2010-12-08T14:41:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="616" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 214 - 193 (Roll no. 616).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8131-8140" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5663"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5788"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2010--Introduced.
Robert C. Byrd Mine Safety Protection Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 (this Act) to require the Secretary of Labor (Secretary), in conducting health and safety related accident investigations in coal or other mines, to: (1) determine why an accident occurred and whether there were violations of law, mandatory health and safety standards, or other requirements; (2) in cases involving violations of federal criminal law, refer them to the Attorney General; and (3) make recommendations to avoid any recurrence. Requires an independent accident investigation by an independent panel appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) for any accident: (1) involving three or more deaths; or (2) whose severity or scale merits an independent investigation. Authorizes: (1) the Secretary's representatives and attorneys to question any individual privately during an inspection or investigation; and (2) any individual willing to speak with or provide a statement to such representatives or attorneys to do so without the presence, involvement, or knowledge of the mine operator or mine operator's agents or attorneys. Allows the closest relative of a miner who is entrapped or otherwise prevented by an accident to designate a representative for the miner to participate in a mine inspection. Requires mine inspections to be conducted during various shifts and days of the week when miners are normally present. Directs the Secretary, upon the request of the mine operator, to review with appropriate mine officials the Secretary's most recent evaluation for pattern (of violation) status during the course of a regular mine inspection, or at the Secretary's discretion, during the pre-inspection conference. Prohibits an attorney from representing both a mine operator and miner during an inspection, investigation, or litigation, unless such miner knowingly waives all possible conflicts of interest. Prescribes requirements for mine operators having a pattern of recurring citations, withdrawal orders, accidents, or injuries. Requires the Secretary to assess and collect fees from mines in pattern status for the costs of additional inspections. Requires the Secretary to: (1) revoke the approval of mine operator plans or programs based on certain criteria; and (2) order withdrawal of all persons from a mine or mine area, and prohibit them from entering it, until the operator submits and the Secretary approves a new plan. Revises civil and criminal penalties and related administrative procedures. Revises certain miner protections against discrimination. Prohibits discriminating against a miner or other employee of a mine operator for refusing to perform duties out of a good-faith and reasonable belief that performing such duties would pose a safety or health hazard. Entitles a miner to full compensation by a mine operator at the regular rate of pay for the entire period (not to exceed 60 days) for which the miner is idled because of a Secretary's withdrawal order. (Under current law, miners are entitled to full compensation only for the time that they are idled, or for one week, whichever is the lesser, after all interested parties are given an opportunity for a public hearing and after such order is final.) Prohibits an underground coal mine operator whose mine has been in pattern status for three years from discharging (or constructively discharging) a miner paid on an hourly basis without reasonable job-related grounds based on certain failures to perform job duties satisfactorily if the miner has completed the employer's probationary period of up to six months. Allows a miner aggrieved by violation of this prohibition to file a complaint in federal district court for reinstatement and compensatory damages. Requires each underground coal mine operator to implement a communication program to ensure that each miner is orally briefed on and made aware of current mine conditions before traveling to or arriving at the mine work area and commencing assigned tasks. Prescribes additional requirements for the monitoring of coal dust in underground mines. Requires the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH), acting through the Office of Mine Safety and Health Research, to issue recommendations to the Secretary regarding the use of atmospheric monitoring systems in the underground coal mining industry. Revises mine operator health and safety training program requirements. Increases from 8 to 9 the minimum number of hours of refresher training all miners must receive at least once every 12 months, including 1 hour of training on miners statutory rights and responsibilities. Requires such training programs to include distribution of miners' rights as well as a toll-free hotline telephone number. Requires the Secretary to order a mine operator to provide additional training to miners if a serious or fatal accident has occurred at a mine or it has experienced above-average accident and injury rates, citations, or withdrawal orders. Requires the Secretary to issue mandatory standards to establish certification requirements and procedures for persons authorized by a mine operator to perform duties or provide training under such Act. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to states to assist them in developing and implementing miner certification programs. Amends the Black Lung Benefits Act to require a mine operator to deliver within 14 days a complete copy of the examining physician's report to any miner required to submit to a medical examination.</summary>
</bill>
