<bill session="111" type="h" number="493" updated="2013-07-19T23:16:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coal Ash Reclamation, Environment, and Safety Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations concerning the storage and disposal of matter referred to as "other wastes" in the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2009-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E82-83"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2009--Introduced.
Coal Ash Reclamation, Environment, and Safety Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations that: (1) establish design, engineering, and performance standards that provide for safe storage and disposal of covered wastes in impoundments; and (2) contain requirements that are substantially similar to the requirements that apply to impoundments under provisions in the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 concerning environmental protection performance standards for surface coal mining and reclamation operations and standards and criteria for coal mine waste piles. Prohibits persons from constructing or operating impoundments for the storage or disposal of covered wastes on any land in any state except as in accordance with such regulations. Provides for the monitoring and enforcement of such requirements and prohibitions. Requires the Secretary to complete an inventory of existing impoundments for the deposit and maintenance of covered wastes. Authorizes the Secretary to issue orders necessary to ensure that impoundments comply with requirements. Defines the term "covered wastes" to mean wastes in areas other than the mine working or excavations, including coal ash, slag, and flue gas desulfurization materials stored or disposed of in liquid, semi-liquid, or solid form.</summary>
</bill>
