<bill session="111" type="h" number="5775" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Grant Accessibility and Transparency Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the establishment of a commission on earmark reform, to consolidate and streamline the grants management structure of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412232"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-19">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-19">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-19">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2010--Introduced.
Grant Accessibility and Transparency Enhancement Act of 2010 - Requires the President to establish the National Commission on Earmark Reform to: (1) study the laws and practices related to replacing earmarks with a full grant making process; and (2) develop a plan to transition from congressional member-directed earmarks to a grant making process. Requires the Commission to propose legislative or regulatory changes to implement: (1) a grant making application and review process under which a panel of subject area experts reviews and awards grant funding on a merit-based system; and (2) a specific governance structure for all grant functions, including grants management, within the federal government. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to establish the Office of Grant Making within OMB to: (1) direct and coordinate the development of the expert grant award panels and the specific recommendations of the Commission; and (2) be responsible for maintaining Grants.gov. Prescribes requirements to streamline the role of federal agencies in the grant making process. Requires all federal grants, both formula and discretionary, from all grant making agencies to be posted on Grants.gov. Requires the Director to ensure that duplication of effort and dual systems related to online federal grant activity are no longer in effect by merging USASpending.gov into Grants.gov. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to make it out of order in both chambers to consider any legislation or accompanying report that contains any congressional earmark or limited tax or tariff benefit.</summary>
</bill>
