<bill session="109" type="s" number="191" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tariff Relief Assistance for Developing Economies Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TRADE Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to extend certain trade preferences to certain least-developed countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2005-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S600"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="886"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Bangladesh"/>
    <term name="Bhutan"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="East Timor"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Kiribati"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Maldives"/>
    <term name="Nepal"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Samoa"/>
    <term name="Solomon Islands"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Sri Lanka"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Tuvalu"/>
    <term name="Vanuatu"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2005--Introduced.
Tariff Relief Assistance for Developing Economies Act of 2005 (TRADE Act of 2005) - Authorizes the President to designate Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Cambodia, Kiribati, Lao People's Democratic Republic, Maldives, Nepal, Samoa, Solomon Islands, Timor-Leste (East Timor), Tuvalu, Vanuatu, Yemen, and Sri Lanka or their successor political entities (TRADE Act of 2005 countries) as beneficiary TRADE Act of 2005 countries eligible to receive duty-free treatment for certain articles that are the growth, product, or manufacture of such countries, if after receiving the advice of the International Trade Commission (ITC) the President determines that such articles are not import-sensitive in the context of imports from such countries. Conditions such designation upon eligibility requirements of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) and the Trade Act of 1974. Prescribes the rule of origin for the articles for the duty-free treatment. Applies duty-free treatment, without any quantitative limitations, granted to textile and apparel articles under AGOA to articles imported directly into the U.S. customs territory from a beneficiary TRADE Act of 2005 country if their assembly meets specified U.S. origin requirements. Grants AGOA preferential treatment for apparel articles assembled in one or more beneficiary TRADE Act of 2005 countries or such former countries, or both, from regional fabric from yarn originating either in the United States or one or more of such countries. Establishes: (1) limitations on such preferential treatment; and (2) special rules for apparel articles wholly assembled in one or more beneficiary TRADE Act of 2005 countries or former beneficiary countries, or both, regardless of the country of origin of the yarn or fabric used to make such articles; and (3) applicable percentages of such benefits.</summary>
</bill>
