<bill session="111" type="h" number="3516" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enable Divestment from Sudan and Iran Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for rollover of gain from divesting certain qualified securities of business entities engaged in Iran or Sudan discouraged activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400371"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412264" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6296"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Enable Divestment from Sudan and Iran Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to promote the divestment of investments in Iran or the Sudan by permitting the deferral of tax on gain from the sale of securities in any business that is engaged in certain discouraged activities in Iran or the Sudan if the holder of such securities purchases replacement securities from a business not engaged in such discouraged activities. Includes as discouraged activities in Iran: (1) investment of $20 million or more in the energy sector of Iran (i.e., petroleum, natural gas, or nuclear power) or in a person who provides Iran with oil or liquefied natural gas tankers or pipelines; (2) an extension of credit of $20 million or more to a person who invests in the energy sector of Iran; (3) investment that enhances Iran's ability to develop petroleum resources; (4) the sale of goods, services, technology, information, or support to Iran that allows it to maintain or expand its petroleum industry; or (5) providing Iran with refined petroleum resources. Defines "Sudan discouraged activity" as an investment in any business operation described in the Sudan Accountability and Divestment Act of 2007 (e.g., businesses engaged in power production activities, mineral extraction activities, oil-related activities, or the production of military equipment). Includes as an Iran or Sudan discouraged activity business transactions with or charitable donations to any Iranian or Sudanese person designated as a terrorist or to any foreign terrorist organization. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to publish and update every six months a list of business entities engaging in any Sudan or Iran discouraged activities.</summary>
</bill>
