<bill session="112" type="s" number="1489" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Provider and Hospital Conscience Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the discrimination and retaliation against individuals and health care entities that refuse to recommend, refer for, provide coverage for, pay for, provide, perform, assist, or participate in abortions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
Health Care Provider and Hospital Conscience Protection Act - Prohibits the federal government and any state or local government that receives federal financial assistance from discriminating or retaliating against any individual or health care entity because of the refusal by the individual or entity to recommend, refer for, provide coverage for, pay for, provide, perform, assist, or participate in any abortion. Includes within such prohibited discrimination: (1) denial, deprivation, or disqualification in licensing; (2) withholding accreditations, authorizations, loans, grants, aids, assistance, benefits, or privileges; and (3) withholding authorization to expand, improve, finance, or create facilities or programs. Creates a cause of action for any violation of this Act. Gives federal courts jurisdiction to order any form of legal or equitable relief, including injunctive relief or an order preventing the disbursement of all or a portion of federal financial assistance to a state government until the prohibited conduct has ceased. Authorizes the Attorney General to file a civil action seeking injunctive or declaratory relief to enforce compliance with this Act. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate the Director of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to receive and investigate complaints alleging a violation of this Act. Requires this Act to be construed in favor of broad conscience protection for individuals and health care entities to the maximum extent permitted by the terms of this Act and the Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
