<bill session="111" type="s" number="1442" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Lands Service Corps Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 to expand the authorization of the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, and the Interior to provide service-learning opportunities on public lands, establish a grant program for Indian Youth Service Corps, help restore the Nation's natural, cultural, historic, archaeological, recreational, and scenic resources, train a new generation of public land managers and enthusiasts, and promote the value of public service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-223.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1612"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2009--Introduced.
Public Lands Service Corps Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 to rename the Public Lands Corps as the Public Lands Service Corps (the Corps). Creates a grant program for the establishment of Indian Youth Service Corps so that Indian youth can carry out projects determined to be priorities by their tribes and communities. Permits Corps participants to work in the National Marine Sanctuary System, coral reefs, and other coastal, estuarine, and marine habitats, and other lands and facilities administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Requires the: (1) establishment of offices within the Department of the Interior, Forest Service, and NOAA for the coordination of Corps activities; and (2) designation of a Corps coordinator for each agency within the Departments of the Interior, Agriculture, and Commerce that administers such activities. Establishes an Indian Youth Service Corps liaison to: (1) provide outreach to tribes about contracts and grants for establishing Corps programs on Indian lands; and (2) coordinate with the tribal liaison of the Corporation for National and Community Service in establishing Corps opportunities on those lands. Requires the Corps to consist of individuals between the ages of 16 and 25 who are enrolled as participants for a period of not more than two years. (Current law does not specify any time period for enrollment.) Requires a recruitment program and training program for Corps members. Describes the types of natural and cultural resources conservation projects that may be carried out by the Corps or any qualified youth or conservation corps on eligible service lands. Sets forth requirements regarding the use of Corps members to provide certain visitor and interpretation services. Authorizes the Secretaries to: (1) establish residential conservation centers; (2) provide temporary housing for the Corps and residential conservation centers; (3) as an appropriate natural and cultural resources conservation project, direct Corps participants to aid in the construction of residential conservation center facilities, including housing; (4) seek the assistance of the Secretary of Energy in identifying and using green building technologies and modular housing designs that may be adapted for such facilities; and (5) recruit mentors for Corps participants. Authorizes individual placements of consulting interns with federal land, coastal, and ocean management agencies to carry out management analysis. Authorizes cooperative agreements and competitive grants for tribes and tribally authorized organizations to establish Indian Youth Service Corps. Requires the issuance of management guidelines for programs of the Corps.</summary>
</bill>
