<bill session="109" type="s" number="977" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Radiation Exposure Compensation Act Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to include claims for injuries and death due to exposure during certain time periods from fallout emitted during the Government's above-ground nuclear tests in Nevada that exposed individuals who lived in the downwind affected area in the State of Montana.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300015"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4648"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4861-4862"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13776-13777"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Leukemia"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2005--Introduced.
Radiation Exposure Compensation Act Amendments of 2005 - Amends the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act to include specified counties in Montana among affected areas for purposes of payments to individuals with certain medical conditions who were exposed to fallout emitted during the U.S. government's atmospheric nuclear tests. Allows residents in other counties in Montana to apply for compensation and requires the National Cancer Institute to evaluate eligibility on a case-by-case basis for such applicants. Allows eligible individuals to receive additional compensation for the costs of screening, complications of screening, follow-up referrals, work-up diagnosis, and treatment related to the specific disease contracted by the individual. Requires the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) to conduct a program of education and communication about the health risks posed by radiation exposure from fallout from U.S. nuclear weapons testing.</summary>
</bill>
