<bill session="110" type="h" number="7240" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bringing Accounting, Increased Liquidity, Oversight and Upholding Taxpayer Security Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No BAILOUTS Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to issue rules regarding short selling of securities, to establish a net worth certificate program in the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, increase the maximum amount of depository insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2008--Introduced.
Bringing Accounting, Increased Liquidity, Oversight and Upholding Taxpayer Security Act of 2008 or the No BAILOUTS Act of 2008 - Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to report to Congress on the effect of its clarification on fair value accounting issued September 30, 2008. States that the order of the SEC issued September 17, 2008, continues in effect until: (1) canceled or withdrawn by the SEC; or (2) repealed by an Act of Congress. Directs the SEC to: (1) reinstate rule 10a-1 (uptick rule on short sales of securities); (2) rescind rule 201 of regulation SHO; and (3) reinstate the price test restrictions that applied to short sales of securities before its action in the proceeding entitled "Regulation SHO and Rule 10a-1," adopted June 28, 2007. Requires the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to establish a net worth certificate program to provide capital to assist insured depository institutions to resolve solvency problems. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act to increase from $100,000 to $250,000 the standard maximum deposit and share insurance amount.</summary>
</bill>
