<bill session="112" type="h" number="4198" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Grand Canyon Tourism Jobs Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide standards for determining whether the substantial restoration of the natural quiet and experience of the Grand Canyon National Park has been achieved and to clarify regulatory authority with respect to commercial air tours operating over the Park.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412398" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2012-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2012--Introduced.
Grand Canyon Tourism Jobs Protection Act of 2012 - Declares that the substantial restoration of the natural quiet and experience of the Grand Canyon National Park in Arizona shall be considered to be achieved in the Park if, for at least 75% of every day, half of the Park is free of sound produced by commercial air tour operations that have an allocation to conduct such tours in the Park. Prohibits the Secretary from considering sound produced by sources other than commercial air tour operations when: (1) making recommendations, developing a final plan, or issuing regulations related to commercial air tour operations in the Park; or (2) determining whether substantial restoration of the natural quiet and experience of the Park has been achieved. Requires the Secretary to continuously monitor noise from aircraft operating over the Park below 17,999 feet MSL to ensure compliance with such substantial restoration in the Park.</summary>
</bill>
