<bill session="113" type="h" number="1082" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">President's Salary SUBMIT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">President's Salary Suspended Unless Budget Measure Is On Time Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that compensation of the President shall be held in escrow upon failure to submit his budget in a timely manner.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412427"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2013--Introduced.
President's Salary Suspended Unless Budget Measure Is On Time Act or President's Salary SUBMIT Act - Requires the payroll administrator responsible for the disbursement of the President's compensation to deposit in an escrow account all such payments otherwise required to be made, if by the first Monday in February of a year the President has not submitted his budget for the succeeding fiscal year. Requires the deposits to begin the day after such Monday and to be released to the President on the earlier of: the day on which he submits the budget, or the last day of his term of office in which such first Monday occurs. Makes this requirement inapplicable to a budget required to be submitted by the President within 30 days after: the commencement date of the term for which the President is elected; or the date as of which a successor fills a vacancy in the office of the President which resulted from his removal from office, death, resignation, or inability to discharge the powers and duties of such office.</summary>
</bill>
