<bill session="110" type="h" number="1601" updated="2013-07-19T21:17:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telehealth and Medically Underserved and Advancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate the provision of telehealth services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental care facilities"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2007--Introduced.
Telehealth and Medically Underserved and Advancement Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) increase the type of originating sites allowed to offer telehealth services, including skilled nursing facilities, assisted living facilities, and county or community health clinics; and (2) remove the requirement that such originating sites must be in rural areas. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to convene a conference of state licensing boards, local telehealth projects, health care practitioners, and patient advocates to promote interstate licensure for telehealth projects. Authorizes the Director of the Office for the Advancement of Telehealth to award grants to: (1) demonstrate how telehealth technologies can be used to expand access to, coordinate, and improve the quality of health care services, and to improve and expand the training of health care providers, the quality of health information available, and efforts to eliminate health care disparities; and (2) provide oral health services to patients who reside in rural areas. Directs the Secretary to establish a Joint Working Group on Telehealth to: (1) identify, monitor, and coordinate federal telehealth projects, data sets, and programs; (2) analyze how telehealth systems are expanding access to health care services, education, and information; (3) analyze the quality of the telehealth services delivered; (4) analyze how telehealth systems can improve health care quality and eliminate disparities; and (5) make recommendations for coordinating federal and state efforts to increase access to health services, education, and information in rural and urban medically underserved areas.</summary>
</bill>
