<bill session="113" type="s" number="1566" updated="2013-11-02T07:05:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the period during which Iraqis who were employed by the United States Government in Iraq may be granted special immigrant status and to temporarily increase the fee or surcharge for processing machine-readable nonimmigrant visas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-09-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7049-7050" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7050" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30T23:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T00:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3233"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3233"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2013--Passed Senate without amendment.
Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 to provide that the total number of aliens eligible for special immigrant status (Iraqis who were employed by or on behalf of the U.S. government in Iraq) during the first three months of FY2014 shall be the sum of: (1) the number of such aliens whose applications were pending on September 30, 2013, and (2) 2000. Imposes a deadline of December 15, 2013, for applications for special immigrant status. Directs the Secretary of State to increase the fee or surcharge authorized under the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 by $1 for processing machine-readable nonimmigrant visas and machine-readable combined border crossing identification cards and nonimmigrant visas. Requires amounts collected as a result of the fee increase to be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
