<bill session="112" type="h" number="3975" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to extend the provisions of the Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400342"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2012-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act to authorize appropriations through FY2017 for grants for demonstration projects to promote pediatric device development. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow an exception to the prohibition against selling a device that is designed to treat or diagnose a disease or condition which affects fewer than 4,000 individuals in the United States and that is exempt from the effectiveness requirements of such Act for an amount that exceeds the costs of research and development, fabrication, and distribution of the device where the request for such exemption is submitted on or before October 1, 2017 (currently, October 1, 2012). Requires the proposed rule issued by the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) entitled "Medical Devices; Pediatric Uses of Devices; Requirement for Submission of Information on Pediatric Subpopulations That Suffer From a Disease or Condition That a Device Is Intended to Treat, Diagnose, or Cure" to take effect on January 1, 2013, unless such Commissioner issues the final rule before such date.</summary>
</bill>
