<bill session="109" type="s" number="100" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pitkin County Land Exchange Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the exchange of certain land in the State of Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-104.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1129"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Pitkin County Land Exchange Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) and the Secretary of the Interior, upon receipt of title to certain lands located in Pitkin County, Colorado, and certain lands located on Smuggler Mountain in the County, to convey to the County or to the Aspen Valley Land Trust, if the County so requests, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to certain National Forest and Bureau of Land Management lands located in the County. Prohibits the conveyance of a specified parcel to the County unless and until specified conditions are met, including that the County grants to the Aspen Valley Land Trust, the Roaring Fork Conservancy, or to another entity mutually agreeable to the County and the Secretary of the Interior, a permanent conservation easement which provides public access to the parcel and limits future use of the parcel to recreational, fish, and wildlife conservation, and open space purposes. States that lands acquired by the Secretary pursuant to this Act shall become part of White River National Forest.</summary>
</bill>
