<bill session="113" type="h" number="1331" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Health Records Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend certain requirements and penalties implemented under the Medicare and Medicaid programs by the HITECH Act of 2009, which would otherwise impede eligible professionals from adopting electronic health records to improve patient care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Electronic Health Records Improvement Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to exempt certain eligible physicians in solo practice and physicians near early retirement age from the application of the Medicare payment adjustment for not demonstrating electronic health record (EHR) meaningful use for certain payment years. Establishes a special rebate for eligible professionals who receive a negative adjustment to their payments for failure to establish an EHR process but subsequently do establish a process meeting the criteria for establishing meaningful use of certified EHR technology. Creates specified additional exceptions to the application of the Medicare negative payment adjustment for certain Medicaid providers participating in the Medicaid EHR incentive program and hospital-based eligible professionals not demonstrating EHR meaningful use. Adds as a criterion for meaningful EHR user that an eligible professional satisfactorily uses a qualified national specialty registry system that measures quality improvement or improves patient safety. Directs the Secretary to specify criteria for determining: (1) if a national specialty registry system is qualified under this Act, and (2) if an eligible professional has demonstrated satisfactory use of such a system for a period. Extends: (1) Medicare EHR incentives (increased payments and adjustments) to eligible professionals practicing in rural health clinics, and (2) Medicare Electronic Prescribing (ERx) and quality reporting incentives to rural health clinics. Disqualifies claims for items or services furnished by an eligible professional at an ambulatory surgical center during performance years for the 2015, 2016, or 2017 payment determinations from inclusion in data used to determine if the eligible professional is a meaningful EHR user. Exempts certain eligible professionals from certain EHR meaningful use requirements for purposes of the Medicare payment adjustment. Creates a process for eligible professionals to appeal a determination that they did not qualify as a meaningful EHR user. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to make certain requirements of this Act inapplicable to eligible professional Medicaid provider incentives to encourage the adoption and use of certified EHR technology.</summary>
</bill>
