<bill session="109" type="h" number="199" updated="2013-07-19T19:06:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reservist and National Guard Opportunities and Protection of Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to preserve the educational status and financial resources of military personnel called to active duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400363"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2005-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="333"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2063"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="College administration"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Reservist and National Guard Opportunities and Protection of Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to declare that: (1) whenever a student who is a member of the National Guard or other reserve component of the Armed Forces of the United States, or a member of such Armed Forces in a retired status, is called or ordered to active duty, the institution of higher education in which the student is enrolled shall grant the student a military leave of absence from the institution while the student is serving on active duty, and for one year after the conclusion of such service; (2) as a consequence of military leave, upon return, such student is entitled to restoration to his or her previous educational status with regard to academic credits earned, scholarships or grants awarded, or tuition and other fees paid; and (3) the institution is obligated to refund tuition or fees paid prior to the commencement of active duty.</summary>
</bill>
