<bill session="111" type="s" number="902" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SERV Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Services, Education, and Rehabilitation for Veterans Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide grants to establish veteran's treatment courts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2010-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2138"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2009--Introduced.
Services, Education, and Rehabilitation for Veterans Act or the SERV Act - Requires the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy to delegate to the Department of Justice (DOJ) the authority to administer the veteran's treatment courts program established by this Act. Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to states and other entities: (1) to develop, implement, or enhance veteran's treatment courts or to expand operational drug courts to serve veterans; and (2) for programs that involve continuing judicial supervision over nonviolent offenders with substance abuse or mental health problems who have served in the U.S. military. Requires such programs to include mandatory periodic testing for the use of drugs, substance abuse and mental health treatment, opportunities for diversion, probation, or supervised release, and programmatic, offender management, and aftercare services. Directs the National Drug Court Institute to conduct national training programs for state and local communities to improve the professional skills of drug court practitioners and provide comprehensive technical assistance to adult, juvenile, and family dependency drug courts.</summary>
</bill>
