<bill session="112" type="s" number="3663" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reassert the proper role of Congress in closing or realigning military installations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2012--Introduced.
Revises provisions concerning a required congressional notification and waiting period prior to the closure or realignment of a military installation by the Department of Defense (DOD) to instead prohibit, absent specific legislative authorization, any realignment involving a reduction of the lesser of: (1) 100 or more combined military and civilian personnel, or (2) 50% of the highest number of such personnel assigned to that installation during any of the previous four years. Allows only the Secretary of Defense (under current law, either such Secretary or the Secretary of the military department concerned) to provide such notification, and to include a description of the alternatives considered, an estimate of the number of military, civilian, and contractor personnel affected, and a plan to provide support for affected communities. Excepts from such requirements the relocation of personnel or functions required to support the deployment of members of the Armed Forces, as long as such personnel and functions are returned to the installation after the deployment. Includes as a military installation, for purposes of such requirements: (1) any public land under Bureau of Land Management control that is withdrawn and reserved for military training and testing, and (2) any leased space in which more than 300 combined military and civilian personnel are housed.</summary>
</bill>
