<bill session="110" type="h" number="4916" updated="2013-07-19T21:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aeronautics and Space Prize Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a National Endowment to advance private sector development of aeronautics and space technologies by way of the National Advanced Space and Aeronautical Technologies Prize Award Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space commercialization"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2007--Introduced.
Aeronautics and Space Prize Act - Establishes a National Endowment for Space and Aeronautics, to be headed by a Chairperson appointed by the President, to: (1) execute a program to award cash prizes for outstanding private sector achievements in basic, advanced, and applied research, technology development, and prototype demonstration that have the potential for application to the nation's aeronautics and space endeavors within the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and other governmental agencies as well as private entities in the United States; (2) with the advice of NASA and other agencies as appropriate, carry out advertising of commercial products and services in conjunction with such endeavors with NASA, other agencies involved in aeronautics and space, or independently; and (3) encourage private gifts for the benefit of, or in connection with, such endeavors in NASA as well as other governmental agencies and private entities involved in aeronautics and space in the United States. Requires the Endowment annually to report to Congress. Authorizes the Endowment to carry out a National Advanced Space and Aeronautical Technologies Prize Award Program as described above.</summary>
</bill>
