<bill session="113" type="h" number="1873" updated="2013-11-02T06:34:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Review Every Dollar Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require greater accountability in discretionary and direct spending programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Review Every Dollar Act of 2013 - Makes it out of order in both chambers to consider any bill, joint resolution, or other measure that: (1) reauthorizes any federal program for more than seven fiscal years, or (2) establishes a new federal program that exceeds such period. Requires each standing congressional committee with legislative jurisdiction over any direct spending program by July 31 during the second session of each Congress to apply specified criteria to determine whether any such program should be modified, terminated, or reauthorized. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require each of the chairs of the congressional budget committees to maintain a deficit reduction discretionary account and a deficit reduction direct spending account. Prescribes procedures for the crediting to such accounts of the amounts of either discretionary or direct spending deficit reduction in any amendment to a bill that reduces the appropriate budget authority. Requires any measure or Act that transfers funds from the general fund of the Treasury to the Highway Trust Fund to be counted as new budget authority and outlays equal to the amount of the transfer in the fiscal year in which it occurs. Prohibits from taking effect, except according to a specified procedure, any rule made to carry out a direct spending program that would require new budget authority of at least $100 million for the fiscal year it takes effect or for any of the nine ensuing fiscal years. Limits exceptions to this prohibition to rules necessary: (1) because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency, for the enforcement of criminal laws, or for national security; or (2) to implement an international trade agreement. Requires also for such an exception that the new budget authority to carry it out is provided by law. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) review proposed rules requiring new budget authority before their effective dates, and (2) take specified administrative steps to prevent further agency action pertaining to such rulemaking.</summary>
</bill>
