<bill session="111" type="s" number="3586" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Geothermal Exploration Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the mapping and development of United States geothermal resources by establishing a direct loan program for high risk geothermal exploration wells.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5855" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2010--Introduced.
Geothermal Exploration Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to: (1) establish a direct loan program for high risk geothermal exploration wells; (2) give preference to loan applicants to carry out projects for previously unexplored, underexplored, or unproven geothermal resources in a variety of geologic and geographic settings; (3) determine the cost shares for such loans, which may provide for higher federal shares for projects with higher risks; and (4) determine the number of wells for each selected geothermal project for which a loan may be made. Requires data from all exploratory wells that are carried out under the program to be provided to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior for mapping national geothermal resources and other uses, including subsurface geologic data, metadata, borehole temperature data, and inclusion in the National Geothermal Data System of the Department of Energy (DOE). Sets forth loan repayment and term provisions. Authorizes the Secretary to grant delays or dispense with a repayment obligation on a demonstration that a selected geothermal project is unproductive. Establishes in the Treasury the Geothermal Investment Fund to be administered by the Secretary to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
