<bill session="113" type="h" number="2418" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to prohibit an individual who is the subject of an outstanding arrest warrant for a felony from receiving various cash benefits under the Social Security Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2013-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2013--Introduced.
Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act of 2013 - Amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI), VIII (Special Benefits for Certain World War II Veterans), and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to prohibit from receiving benefits under those titles any individual who is the subject of: (1) an outstanding arrest warrant for a felony, or (2) an outstanding arrest warrant for violating a condition of prohibition or parole imposed under federal or state law. Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to furnish any federal, state, or local law enforcement officer, upon written request, with the current address, Social Security number, and photograph of any recipient of title VIII benefits if the officer furnishes the Commissioner with the individual's name and other identifying information as reasonably required to establish the individual's unique identity, and notifies the Commissioner that: (1) the individual is fleeing to avoid prosecution, or custody or confinement after conviction, or the individual is violating a condition of probation or parole; and (2) the location or apprehension of such individual is within the officer's official duties.</summary>
</bill>
