<bill session="110" type="s" number="2175" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Asthma Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with regard to research on asthma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12991-12992"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3904"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2007--Introduced.
Family Asthma Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to award grants to eligible entities to conduct pilot projects to prevent and control asthma symptoms and to reduce asthma attacks and improve self-management for individuals and families. Requires the Secretary to give: (1) priority to entities that serve a medically underserved population; and (2) consideration to an adequate rural-urban distribution, so as to gain better information about asthma at the national level. Authorizes additional appropriations to the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute to develop a National Asthma Action Plan and to fund a report to Congress by the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) collaborate with state and local health departments to conduct activities to inform and educate the public regarding asthma; (2) conduct asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma, the effectiveness of public heath asthma intervention, and the quality of asthma management; and (3) compile and annually publish asthma data. Requires the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to establish Dr. Irving J. Selikoff individual and institutional training grants for education and training of health care providers on the role of environmental factors in the development and prevention of asthma and recurrent asthma attacks.</summary>
</bill>
