<bill session="112" type="s" number="913" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Do-Not-Track Online Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Federal Trade Commission to prescribe regulations regarding the collection and use of personal information obtained by tracking the online activity of an individual, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2780-2781"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2781-2782" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2011--Introduced.
Do-Not-Track Online Act of 2011 - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate: (1) regulations that establish standards for the implementation of a mechanism by which an individual can indicate whether he or she prefers to have personal information collected by providers of online services, including by providers of mobile applications and services; and (2) rules that prohibit such providers from collecting personal information on individuals who have expressed a preference not to have such information collected. Requires such rules to allow for the collection and use of personal information if: (1) the information is necessary to provide a service requested by the individual so long as identifying particulars are removed or the information is deleted upon the provision of such service; or (2) the individual receives clear, conspicuous, and accurate notice on, and consents to, such collection and use. Provides for FTC and state enforcement of such rules and regulations.</summary>
</bill>
