<bill session="111" type="s" number="1322" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center in Lake County, Illinois, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6942-6944" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2009--Introduced.
Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to execute an executive agreement for use by the Departments of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA) of: (1) a new Navy ambulatory care center, parking structure, and supporting structures and facilities in North Chicago and Great Lakes, Illinois; and (2) related medical personal property and equipment. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer to the Secretary of the VA jurisdiction over the center, structures, facilities, and property and equipment covered by the agreement. Designates the transferred center, structures, and facilities as the Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center (Center). Provides a reversionary interest to the Secretary if the property is not used in accordance with the agreement or in the event of lack of facilities integration. Authorizes the Secretary and the Secretary of the Navy to transfer to the Secretary of the VA functions necessary for Center operation. Authorizes the DOD-VA Health-Care Resources Sharing Committee to provide for the joint funding of the Center in accordance with this Act. Establishes the Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center Fund to fund the Center's operations. Requires an annual review of such Fund for at least three years after this Act's enactment. Deems the Center a military facility for purposes of the eligibility of members of the Armed Forces to receive care and services there. Extends through FY2015 a joint DOD-VA program to identify, implement, and evaluate creative health care coordination and sharing initiatives at the facility, intraregional, and nationwide levels.</summary>
</bill>
