<bill session="110" type="h" number="7068" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western Hemisphere Counterterrorism and Nonproliferation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the security of the Western Hemisphere and bolster regional capacity and cooperation to counter current and emerging threats, to promote cooperation in the Western Hemisphere to prevent the proliferation of nuclear, chemical, and biological weapons, to secure universal adherence to agreements regarding nuclear nonproliferation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2008-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Organization of American States (OAS)"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
Western Hemisphere Counterterrorism and Nonproliferation Act of 2008 - States that, in order to enhance the security of the Western Hemisphere and bolster regional capacity to counter terrorism, it shall be U.S. policy to promote the signing, ratification, and implementation by all countries in the Western Hemisphere of specified counter terrorism conventions. Amends specified acts with respect to annual country reports on terrorism, as well reports on narcotics trafficking, money laundering, and law enforcement. Authorizes the President to impose specified sanctions on any country in the Western Hemisphere that the President has determined is engaged in state sponsored terrorism, is carrying out policies that threaten U.S. national security interests, or is not fully cooperating with U.S. counterterrorism or nonproliferation efforts. Expresses the sense of Congress that the International Law Enforcement Academy in San Salvador, El Salvador, should continue to serve as a critical component of United States regional counterterrorism efforts. Redirects 50% of the U.S. contribution to the Organization of American States (OAS) to the OAS Inter-American Committee Against Terrorism, the OAS Inter-American Drug Abuse Control Commission, and the Western Hemisphere Regional Coordination Centers. Directs the Secretary of State to negotiate the establishment of: (1) Western Hemisphere Regional Coordination Centers; and (2) the Western Hemisphere Nonproliferation Partnership Initiative. States U.S. policy with respect to the prevention of the proliferation of weapons-related nuclear, chemical, and biological materials, technology, and facilities, as well as policy with respect to nuclear fuel fabrication and provides specified directives and sanctions. Places restrictions on nuclear cooperation with countries assisting the nuclear program of Venezuela or Cuba. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Latin America Regional Strategic Initiative should serve as a critical component of U.S. regional counterterrorism and nonproliferation efforts.</summary>
</bill>
