<bill session="111" type="h" number="6397" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-15T15:14:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-11-15T15:14:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Marine Sergeant Michael H. Ferschke, Jr. Memorial Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Marine Sergeant Michael H. Ferschke, Jr. Memorial Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 101(a)(35) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for a marriage for which the parties are not physically in the presence of each other due to service abroad in the Armed Forces of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2010-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15T14:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15T14:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7408-7410" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15T14:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6397.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-11-15T15:14:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7408" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15T15:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Marine Sergeant Michael H. Ferschke, Jr. Memorial Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to count as a spouse, wife, or husband a party to a marriage ceremony in which the parties were not in each other's physical presence, and the marriage was not consummated, if the failure to consummate was caused by physical separation because of one party's active-duty status abroad in the U.S. Armed Forces. States that the budgetary effects of this Act for purposes of Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 compliance shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled "Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation" for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</summary>
</bill>
