<bill session="109" type="h" number="3607" updated="2013-07-19T19:36:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Future of Healthcare--Granting Access to Innovation in America Act (GAIA Act)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the quality of health care through the implementation of computerized provider order entry systems in hospitals and skilled nursing facilities that will result in a reduction in the rate of medication errors and in redundancies and will create more efficiency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2005-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2005-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2005-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Drug interactions"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
The Future of Healthcare-- Granting Access to Innovation in America Act (GAIA Act) - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to hospitals and skilled nursing facilities to carry out demonstration projects aimed at reducing the rate of medication errors and improving the quality of care by installing or upgrading computerized technology that: (1) provides information on drug-allergy contraindications and drug interactions; (2) ensures that all drug orders are legible; and (3) provides physicians and other clinicians with a menu of medications, complete with default doses and a range of potential doses for each medication. Requires grant applicants to agree to provide for technology including software that assists clinicians who order prescription drugs and tests in making medication-related decisions and that provides for an electronic medication administration record. Authorizes grant expenditures to purchase, install, and update such technology. Sets forth matching requirements. Requires each applicant to agree to submit to the Secretary, acting through the National Health Information Technology Coordinator, a report detailing: (1) quantitative reductions in medication errors; (2) the level of staff compliance; (3) the difference between administrative and clinical workflows before and after implementation of the technology; (4) alterations and improvements regarding the workflow in facilities that have the technology; (5) an analysis of the improvement of the quality of care and patient satisfaction within the hospital or skilled nursing facility involved; and (6) the overall economic savings associated with usage of the technology.</summary>
</bill>
