<bill session="109" type="h" number="5231" updated="2013-07-19T19:50:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deep Water Royalty Jurisdiction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit Federal court jurisdiction over certain suits pertaining to the application of a price threshold in determining the volume for which suspension of royalties applies to certain offshore oil and gas leases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2006-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2006--Introduced.
Deep Water Royalty Jurisdiction Act - Provides that, in any case brought by any person other than a federal department, agency, or instrumentality, no court created by Act of Congress shall have any jurisdiction, and the Supreme Court shall have no appellate jurisdiction, to hear or decide any question pertaining to: (1) the application of a price threshold in determining the volume for which suspension of royalties applies with respect to offshore oil and natural gas leases awarded in the five-year period beginning on November 28, 1995; or (2) the interpretation, or the constitutional validity, of this Act. Provides that, in any case brought by a federal department, agency, or instrumentality against any person to recover royalties under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, no legal or equitable defense shall be available to the defendant regarding the matters covered by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
