<bill session="109" type="h" number="4411" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-11T15:18:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-11T15:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Internet Gambling bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Internet Gambling Prohibition and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent the use of certain payment instruments, credit cards, and fund transfers for unlawful Internet gambling, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2006-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2006-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2006-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2006-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 109-412, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than May 26, 2006 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(l), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-412, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-26T17:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="267">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 267.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 907 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4411 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 907 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 907.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4978-5001" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4978-4980" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4411 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4411.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 907, the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Berkley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Berkley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Berkley demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5005-5008" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of the amendment offered by Ms. Berkely of Nevada, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5006-5008" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5006" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conyers motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back with an amendment which inserts a new section outlining a rule to protect against under-age gambling.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5007" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 167 - 243 (Roll no. 362).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-07-11T15:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="363" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 317 - 93 (Roll no. 363).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4980-4983" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="519">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 519.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="907"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4777"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1178"/>
    <amendment number="h1179"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/11/2006--Passed House amended.
Internet Gambling Prohibition and Enforcement Act - Title I: Modernization of the Wire Act of 1961 - (Sec. 101) Amends the federal criminal code to expand the definition of "wire communication facility" (renamed "communication facility") to include fixed or mobile (i.e., wireless) communication facilities. Defines "bets and wagers" to include bets for contests, sporting events, games predominantly subject to chance, and lotteries. Excludes from such definition: (1) activities governed by securities laws: (2) transactions under the Commodity Exchange Act; (3) over-the-counter derivative instruments; (4) contracts of indemnity or guarantee; (4) contracts for life, health, or accident insurance; and (5) reward programs or contests conducted by businesses. (Sec. 102) Modifies existing prohibitions against interstate gambling to prohibit the use of a communication facility to transmit: (1) bets or wagers; (2) information assisting in the placing of bets or wagers; or (3) a communication which entitles the recipient to receive money or credit as a result of bets or wages or for information assisting in the placing of bets or wagers. Prohibits any individual from accepting, in connection with the placing of bets or wagers to or from the United States: (1) credit, or the proceeds of credit; (2) electronic funds transfers; (3) checks, drafts, or similar instruments; or (4) the proceeds of any other form of financial transaction as prescribed by Treasury regulations. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to five years for violations. Requires any common carrier which receives notice of a violation of this Act by one of its communication facilities to discontinue or refuse service to such facility. Grants such common carrier immunity from liability for discontinuing or refusing such service. (Sec. 103) Grants U.S. district courts original and exclusive jurisdiction to prevent and restrain violations of the Internet gambling ban. Authorizes the Attorney General or any state attorney general to institute proceeding to enforce an Internet gambling ban. (Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Justice in FY2007-FY2010 for investigations and prosecutions of unlawful Internet gambling. (Sec. 105) Declares that nothing in this Act may be construed to prohibit any activity allowed under the Interstate Horseracing Act or to preempt any state law prohibiting gambling. (Sec. 106) Expresses the sense of Congress that this Act does not address the legality of certain horse racing activities under federal law. Title II: Policies and Procedures Required to Prevent Payments for Unlawful Gambling - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit persons engaged in a gambling business from knowingly accepting credit, electronic fund transfers, checks, drafts, or similar financial instruments or the proceeds of any other financial transaction in connection with unlawful Internet gambling (this prohibition is defined by this Act as a "restricted transaction"). Directs the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to prescribe regulations to identify and block restricted transactions. Grants immunity from civil liability for blocking a restricted transaction or one which is reasonably believed to be a restricted transaction. Title III: Internet Gambling in or through Foreign Jurisdictions - Calls upon the U.S. government, in deliberations with foreign governments, to: (1) encourage cooperation by foreign governments in identifying whether Internet gambling operations are being used for money laundering, corruption, or other crimes; (2) advance policies that promote international cooperation in enforcing this Act; and (3) encourage the Financial Action Task Force on Money Laundering to study the extent to which Internet gambling operations are being used for money laundering purposes. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to Congress annually on deliberations between the United States and other countries on Internet gambling.</summary>
</bill>
