<bill session="109" type="s" number="2017" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equal Access to Justice Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the provisions of titles 5 and 28, United States Code, relating to equal access to justice, award of reasonable costs and fees, and administrative settlement offers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12950-12951"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12951-12953" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="435"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2005--Introduced.
Equal Access to Justice Reform Act of 2005 - Includes within the functions and duties of the Small Business Administration's (SBA's) Office of Advocacy ensuring that the justice system remains accessible to small businesses for the resolution of disputes with the federal government. Directs the Office to advise, cooperate with, and consult with the President and Attorney General regarding provisions concerning the awarding of federal contracts to small businesses and minority-, female-, and veteran-owned businesses. Requires the Attorney General to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the effectiveness of the Equal Access to Justice Act (EAJA) in achieving its purpose of easing the burden upon small businesses of engaging in dispute resolution with the federal government; (2) variations in the frequency and amounts of fee awards paid by specified federal entities; and (3) recommendations for congressional oversight or legislative changes. Eliminates the EAJA's: (1) substantial justification standard whereby the government can deny attorney's fees to prevailing parties if the agency's position was substantially justified; and (2) rate cap on expert witness and attorney's fees. Sets forth provisions regarding settlement offers, declarations of intent to seek a fee award, payments from agency appropriations, and taxpayer eligibility for fee awards. Defines "prevailing party" in EAJA cases to include a party whose pursuit of a non-frivolous claim or defense was a catalyst for a voluntary or unilateral change in position by the opposing party that provides any significant part of the relief sought.</summary>
</bill>
