<bill session="111" type="h" number="6286" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Free Speech and Citizen Fairness Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to repeal the limitation on the annual aggregate amount of contributions individuals may make to candidates for election for Federal office, to repeal the limitations on the amount of coordinated expenditures by political parties, and to protect uncompensated Internet activity by individuals from treatment as a contribution or expenditure under the Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Free Speech and Citizen Fairness Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to repeal the annual aggregate limit on the amount of contributions by individuals in a federal election campaign to: (1) candidates and their authorized committees; and (2) political committees which are not political committees of national political parties. Repeals the limitations on the amount of coordinated or independent expenditures in a federal election campaign by national or state political parties. Exempts from treatment as a contribution or an expenditure in a federal election campaign any uncompensated personal services related to Internet activities, or use of equipment or services for uncompensated Internet activities, engaged in by any individual, group of individuals, or corporation wholly owned by one or more individuals that: (1) engages primarily in Internet activities; and (2) does not derive a substantial portion of its revenue from sources other than income from its Internet activities. States that "Internet activity" includes: (1) sending or forwarding electronic messages; (2) providing a hyperlink or other direct access to another person's website; (3) blogging; (4) creating, maintaining, or hosting a website; (5) paying a nominal fee for the use of another person's website; and (6) any other form of communication distributed over the Internet. Extends the general media exemption from treatment as an expenditure to any Internet or electronic publication (including a blog).</summary>
</bill>
