<bill session="111" type="h" number="5667" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Firearms Microstamping Evaluation and Study Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conduct of a study on the effectiveness of firearms microstamping technology and an evaluation of its effectiveness as a law enforcement tool.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400645"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2010-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Firearms Microstamping Evaluation and Study Act of 2010 - Directs the Attorney General to enter into an arrangement with the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study of the cost, feasibility, and benefits of firearms microstamping technology. Requires the Council to consult with federal, state, and local officials, law enforcement officials, entities affected by the actual and proposed uses of microstamping technology, and ballistics experts in carrying out such study. Defines "microstamping technology" to mean the process or technology of etching, engraving or otherwise imprinting on the interior surface or internal working parts of a firearm a microscopic array of alpha numeric characters, bar, gear, or other code or symbol that identifies the make, model, and serial number of the firearm.</summary>
</bill>
