<bill session="111" type="h" number="4354" updated="2013-07-19T23:51:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Principal Recruitment and Training Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recruit, support, and prepare principals to improve student academic achievement at high-need schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E3058"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="2896"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2009--Introduced.
School Principal Recruitment and Training Act of 2009 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award renewable five-year matching grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) and certain educational or nonprofit entities that partner with LEAs to recruit, support, and train principals for service in high-need schools. Requires grantees to: (1) recruit, select, and provide training to individuals who are or aspire to be principals in high-need schools, agree to serve for at least four years in such schools, and work to ensure that student academic achievement in their schools improves substantially within three to six years; (2) provide aspiring principals with a pre-service residency for at least one year that focuses on instructional leadership and organizational management and is followed by ongoing training for at least two years after their residency ends and school leadership begins; and (3) deliver high-quality, differentiated, school-level support services that meet the specific needs of high-need schools led by individuals that are receiving or have received training pursuant to this Act. Directs the Secretary to award a grant to one or more research groups to develop a high-quality evaluation and information clearinghouse system to facilitate the sharing of best practices and inform: (1) the recruitment, selection, and training of principals for high-need schools; (2) the development of principal effectiveness standards; and (3) the development of system-wide supports and policies that foster school and principal actions identified as most often differentiating the most dramatically improved schools from others.</summary>
</bill>
