<bill session="112" type="h" number="2643" updated="2013-07-20T01:33:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Neutrality Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for medical neutrality and to establish accountability for violations of the principle of medical neutrality, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1409"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2011--Introduced.
Medical Neutrality Protection Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of State to compile and update at least annually a list of those foreign governments that the Secretary determines have engaged in violations of medical neutrality and to provide a formal notification to a foreign government included in such list. Defines a &#8220;violation of medical neutrality&#8221; to mean: (1) militarized attacks on health care facilities, health care service providers, or individuals in the course of receiving medical treatment; (2) wanton destruction of medical supplies, facilities, records, or transportation services; (3) willful obstruction of medical ethics; (4) coercion of medical personnel to commit acts in violation of their ethical responsibilities; (5) deliberate misuse of health care facilities, transportation services, uniforms, or other insignia; (6) deliberate blocking of access to health care facilities and health care professionals; or (7) arbitrary arrest or detention of health care service providers or individuals seeking medical care. Prohibits specified presidential authorities, including the authority to transfer excess defense articles, furnish military training and education, or finance the procurement of defense articles, from being used to provide assistance to, and prohibits licenses for direct commercial sales of military equipment from being issued to, the government of a country that has engaged in a violation of medical neutrality. Makes such prohibition on assistance effective for a minimum of one fiscal year, after which the President may reinstate such assistance. Authorizes the President to temporarily waive the prohibitions in the interest of national security. Requires the Secretary to deny the issuance of a visa to any alien that is or was engaged in or has organized any act that is a violation of medical neutrality. Directs the heads of U.S. diplomatic and consular missions to investigate all reports of violations of medical neutrality.</summary>
</bill>
