<bill session="112" type="h" number="3225" updated="2013-07-20T01:38:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Agriculture Development and Jobs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote and enhance community agricultural production and technology in nontraditional communities through the establishment of a new office in the Department of Agriculture to ensure that Department authorities are coordinated more effectively to encourage local agricultural production and increase the availability of fresh food in nontraditional communities, particularly underserved communities experiencing hunger, poor nutrition, obesity, and food insecurity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2012-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/2011--Introduced.
Community Agriculture Development and Jobs Act - Amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Office of Community Agriculture to: (1) promote agriculture in nontraditional communities (communities or areas with limited or no traditional agricultural production), and (2) improve nutrition in such communities. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for initiatives in nontraditional communities to: (1) strengthen local food production, processing, and distribution; (2) create sustainable food systems; (3) encourage food assistance recipients to purchase locally grown or produced foods; (4) convert vacant land to agricultural production; and (5) support education and training. Amends the Farmer-to-Consumer Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to direct the Secretary to provide loans, loan guarantees, and grants to expand farmers markets. Gives assistance priority to nontraditional communities. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to extend the seniors farmers market nutrition program. Gives assistance priority to: (1) nontraditional communities, and (2) farmers markets with an operational seniors farmers market program. Amends the Census of Agriculture Act of 1997 to require as part of each agriculture census an evaluation of the state of farmers markets in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
