<bill session="112" type="h" number="3427" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STARTUP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Startup Technical Assistance for Reemployment Training and Unemployment Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the availability of self-employment assistance to individuals receiving extended compensation or emergency unemployment compensation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Small Business, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3630"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1826"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2011--Introduced.
Startup Technical Assistance for Reemployment Training and Unemployment Prevention Act or the STARTUP Act - Amends the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 to authorize states to establish a self-employment assistance program (a program to provide unemployed individuals with an allowance in lieu of extended unemployment compensation to establish a business and become self-employed). Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to allow individuals receiving emergency unemployment compensation to participate in a self-employment assistance program. Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) award grants to states for self-employment assistance programs; (2) develop model language that may be used by states in enacting such programs and provide technical assistance to states in establishing, improving, and administering such programs; (3) establish reporting requirement for states that have established such programs; and (4) report to Congress on the effectiveness of such programs. Amends the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 to repeal the program for investment in microentrepreneurs. Limits and rescinds funding for the Loan Modernization and Accounting System established by the Small Business Administration (SBA). Directs the Administrator of SBA to terminate the Special Purpose Counseling Grant program under the Small Business Act.</summary>
</bill>
