<bill session="111" type="h" number="2515" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domestic Violence Leave Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to allow leave to address domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking and their effects, and to include domestic partners under the Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Domestic Violence Leave Act - Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to entitle an eligible employee, his or her same-sex spouse, or domestic partner to up to 12 workweeks of leave during any 12-month period: (1) to care for such individual's family member, if the family member is addressing domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking and their effects; or (2) because such individual is addressing such matters, he or she is unable to perform any of the functions of his or her position. Authorizes such individual to substitute any of his or her accrued paid vacation leave, personal leave, family leave, or medical or sick leave for any of the 12-week period of such leave. Authorizes an employer to require an employee to certify with documentation the basis of the leave request. Declares that nothing in this Act shall require an employer to provide paid sick leave or paid medical leave in any situation in which such employer would not normally provide any such paid leave. Amends federal civil service law to entitle civilian federal employees, their same-sex spouses, or domestic partners to the same leave allowance. Provides for the substitution of accrued paid annual or sick leave for any part of the 12-week period. Authorizes the employing agency to require an employee to certify with documentation the basis of the leave request.</summary>
</bill>
