<bill session="111" type="sr" number="683" updated="2013-07-20T00:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the recent accomplishments of the people and Government of Moldova and expressing support for free and transparent parliamentary elections on November 28, 2010.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-11-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8107-8108" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8107-8108" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8065" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Supports the development of a democratic political system and free market economy in Moldova and a November 2010 parliamentary election process that comports with international standards. Recognizes that the government of Moldova's commitment to economic and political reforms since 2009 has resulted in progress towards integration into European institutions. Acknowledges that continued reform and commitment to a free election process will remain necessary for Moldova's full integration into the Western community of nations. Notes that continued reforms in Moldova could provide for an additional basis for the repeal of the Jackson-Vanik trade restrictions. Encourages ongoing negotiations between the European Union (EU) and the Republic of Moldova concerning visa liberalization and an Association Agreement.</summary>
</bill>
