<bill session="110" type="s" number="3062" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Shale Regulatory Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to modify certain provisions relating to oil shale leasing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4801-4803"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2008--Introduced.
Oil Shale Regulatory Act of 2008 - Amends the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008 to repeal its prohibition against the use of funds to: (1) publish regulations regarding a commercial leasing program for oil shale resources on public lands; or (2) conduct certain oil shale lease sales.Amends the Oil Shale, Tar Sands, and Other Strategic Unconventional Fuels Act of 2005 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) instruct the Secretary of the Interior to publish final regulations establishing a commercial leasing program for oil shale and tar sands not earlier than 90 days (currently, not later than six months) after completion of a specified programmatic environmental impact statement; and (2) authorize the Secretary, not earlier than December 31, 2011, to conduct a lease sale for oil shale and tar sands in a state that expresses support and interest in the development of tar sands and oil shale resources.</summary>
</bill>
