<bill session="109" type="s" number="498" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interstate Transmission Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for expansion of electricity transmission networks in order to support competitive electricity markets, to ensure reliability of electric service, to modernize regulation and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2005-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1946-1950" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2005--Introduced.
Interstate Transmission Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to: (1) establish incentive-based rate treatments for the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce by any public utility in order to ensure reliability and to decrease the cost of delivered power by reducing transmission congestion; and (2) provide for incentives to each transmitting utility or electric utility that joins a Regional Transmission Organization (RTO) or Independent System Operator. Prescribes guidelines for open nondiscriminatory access by unregulated transmitting utilities. Prohibits FERC from requiring an unregulated transmitting utility to transfer control or operational control of its transmitting facilities to an RTO or any other Commission-approved independent transmission organization designated to provide nondiscriminatory transmission access. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat electric transmission property treated as 15-year property. Repeals the requirement for FERC prior authorization of the disposition of public utility facilities. Grants FERC jurisdiction over Electric Reliability Organizations certified by FERC to establish and enforce reliability standards for the bulk-power system. Exempts Hawaii and Alaska from application of this Act. Prescribes guidelines governing the obligations of electric utilities to provide electric service to either end-users or to a distribution utility (native load service obligation). Specifies conditions under which FERC is required to approve a voluntary transmission pricing plan containing criteria for determining the person or persons that will be required to pay for any construction of new transmission facilities or expansion, modification or upgrade of transmission facilities, or new generator interconnection. Authorizes FERC to promote voluntary development of regional transmission organizations, independent transmission providers, and similar organizations in order to enhance electric energy transmission in interstate commerce.</summary>
</bill>
