<bill session="113" type="s" number="871" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Military Sexual Assault Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance assistance for victims of sexual assault committed by members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2013-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3161-3162"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3162-3163" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2002"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2013--Introduced.
Combating Military Sexual Assault Act of 2013 - Directs each military department Secretary to implement a program providing a Special Victims' Counsel (Counsel) to a victim of a sexual assault committed by a member of the Armed Forces (member). Outlines Counsel qualifications and duties, including providing advice and assistance in connection with criminal and civil legal matters related to the assault. Allows a member or member dependent who is a victim of an assault by another member to receive Counsel assistance. Requires such victim to be informed of the availability of such assistance at the time the victim originally seeks assistance from a sexual response coordinator or sexual assault victim advocate, a military criminal investigator, a victim/witness liaison, a trial counsel, health care providers, or any other personnel designated by the Secretary concerned. Makes such assistance available regardless of whether the victim elects unrestricted or restricted (confidential) reporting of the incident. Provides additional duties of the Director of the Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Office within the Department of Defense (DOD), including: (1) providing guidance and assistance for the military departments in addressing matters relating to sexual assault prevention and response, (2) acting as liaison between DOD and other federal and state agencies on sexual assault prevention and response programs, and (3) overseeing development of program guidance and joint planning objectives in support of such program. Requires the Director to also collect and maintain data of the military departments concerning sexual assault prevention and response. Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to provide for disposition and other requirements in connection with charges of rape or sexual assault, and to provide for victims' rights under such actions (including the right to a Counsel). Adds new provisions to the UCMJ concerning the commission of a sexual act upon, or abusive sexual contact with, a member by a military instructor. Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to require the National Guard of each state and territory to ensure that a sexual assault response coordinator is available at all times to its members.</summary>
</bill>
