<bill session="111" type="h" number="3026" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hazard Mitigation For All Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the United States Public Housing Act of 1937 to establish a predisaster mitigation program to benefit public and assisted housing residents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2009--Introduced.
Hazard Mitigation For All Act of 2009 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible public housing agencies (PHAs) for 75% of the cost of predisaster hazard mitigation activities benefiting assisted housing residents. Limits the use of such grants to eligible activities for residents of assisted housing whose family incomes do not exceed 80% of the area median income. Authorizes eligible activities that result in displacement of assisted residents only if accommodations provided for them during the period of displacement are similar to their existing assisted housing, located in a comparable community, and only a reasonable distance from it. Prescribes requirements for assistance to private owners of assisted housing.</summary>
</bill>
