<bill session="111" type="h" number="5861" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cancer Centers Assistance for Renovations and Expansion Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a cancer center construction loan program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2010-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2010--Introduced.
Cancer Centers Assistance for Renovations and Expansion Act of 2010 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a program that provides loans to qualifying cancer centers for payment of the capital costs of projects for the improvement of research, prevention, or patient care infrastructure. Sets the maximum amount of such loans at: (1) $50 million for any cancer center or comprehensive cancer center designated by the National Cancer Institute; and (2) $100 million for any entity that is a National Cancer Institute-designated comprehensive cancer center and a cancer hospital meeting certain requirements for a subsection (d) hospital. (Generally, a subsection [d] hospital is an acute care hospital, particularly one that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system [IPPS] when providing covered inpatient services to eligible beneficiaries.)</summary>
</bill>
