<bill session="109" type="h" number="6421" updated="2013-07-19T20:01:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stockholm and Rotterdam Toxics Treaty Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement the Stockholm Convention on Persistent Organic Pollutants, the Protocol on Persistent Organic Pollutants to the Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution, and the Rotterdam Convention on the Prior Informed Consent Procedure for Certain Hazardous Chemicals and Pesticides in International Trade.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2006-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2006-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2204-2205"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4591"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4800"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2006--Introduced.
Stockholm and Rotterdam Toxics Treaty Act of 2006 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) to provide for the implementation of three international environmental agreements: (1) the Stockholm Convention on Persistent Organic Pollutants (POPs Convention); (2) the Protocol on Persistent Organic Pollutants to the 1979 Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution (LRTAP POPs Protocol); and (3) the Rotterdam Convention on the Prior Informed Consent Procedure for Certain Hazardous Chemicals and Pesticides in International Trade (PIC Convention). Prohibits the manufacture, process, distribution for export, use, or disposal of specified Persistent Organic Pollutants (POPs). Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue or amend rules related to polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) in order to comply with the provisions of the POPs Convention or the LRTAP POPs Protocol. Requires a notice and comment procedure regarding the addition of a new chemical to the POPs Convention or the LRTAP POPs Protocol. Allows the Administrator to issue regulations concerning such chemicals, including prohibiting their use to protect human health and the environment in a manner that achieves a reasonable balance of social, environmental, and economic costs and benefits. Requires the Administrator to publish: (1) a decision regarding the treatment of any new source categories that are not already listed under the Clean Air Act as major source categories; (2) notice of the development of action plans under the POPs Convention; and (3) a decision on whether to promulgate regulations for newly listed POPs or the status of a rulemaking if the Administrator has not made a decision about such POPs. Requires the President to consult with and report to Congress before consenting to bind the United States to an amendment of the POPs Convention. Requires the Administrator, in cooperation with the Secretary of State and the heads other federal agencies, to participate in international efforts concerning POPs. Prohibits the Administrator from promulgating a rule authorizing PCB manufacture, processing, or distribution activities or granting an exemption from PCB regulations under TSCA, unless they are consistent with the exemptions under the POPs Convention and the LRTAP POPs Protocol. Prohibits the distribution for export equipment that contains more than a specified percentage of PCBs in liquid stock, except for the purpose of legal, environmentally sound waste management. Establishes conditions for exporting chemicals listed on Annex III of the PIC Convention.</summary>
</bill>
