<bill session="112" type="hr" number="423" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that in order to increase and sustain pressure on the Taliban, their terrorist allies and supporters, enable an expeditious and safe withdrawal of United States and NATO soldiers, reducing the great cost in lives and money, the United States should empower and recognize Afghanistan's ethnic diversity through free local and provincial elections and replace the present failed centralized system of government with a federal political structure that ensured the full participation of all ethnic communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2011-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and South Asia .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and South Asia" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Militias and paramilitary groups"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/2011--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) engage in broadening the regional dialogue on Afghanistan to include countries that have been supportive of the U.S. effort to defeat the Taliban; (2) support constitutional reform and a decentralized, democratic federal political system in Afghanistan and abandon its support for the present failed centralized system of government; (3) support the establishment of properly regulated regional militias as well as a national army to fight the Taliban insurgency; and (4) oppose the inclusion of the Taliban in the government of Afghanistan.</summary>
</bill>
