<bill session="112" type="h" number="3154" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education for Tomorrow's Jobs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 1112 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2011-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2011-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1686"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
Education for Tomorrow's Jobs Act - Amends part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies receiving subgrants under part A to describe how they will establish and carry out a school improvement program, including how they will: create a network of schools or programs of study that integrate a rigorous curriculum emphasizing college and career readiness, and wraparound support services; use school-level strategies to personalize students' educational experience; demonstrate their capacity to implement and sustain their program; involve institutions of higher education, employers, community-based organizations, parent organizations, and other stakeholders in the school improvement process; provide school staff and other stakeholders with high-quality training and technical assistance; facilitate student transitions from secondary schools that do not award diplomas to secondary schools that do, and from the latter to postsecondary education; enable their program through policies that may include budgeting, governance, curriculum, and scheduling autonomies; place students, when possible, in a school or program of study that the student or their parents choose; assure that students are able to fully participate in their school or program of study and are not placed in a school or program of study on the basis of their prior academic achievement or status as a poor, minority, disabled, or limited English proficient student; and arrange for an ongoing and rigorous evaluation of their program, and disseminate best practices.</summary>
</bill>
