<bill session="109" type="s" number="2564" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biodefense and Pandemic Vaccine and Drug Development Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prepare and strengthen the biodefenses of the United States against deliberate, accidental, and natural outbreaks of illness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300045" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2006-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3222-3227" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5533"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Orphan drugs"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Biodefense and Pandemic Vaccine and Drug Development Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and make public a strategic plan to integrate biodefense and emerging infectious disease requirements with the advanced research and development, strategic initiatives for innovation, and the procurement of qualified countermeasures and qualified pandemic or epidemic products. Establishes the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA) within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Requires the Secretary to: (1) coordinate and oversee the acceleration of countermeasure and product advanced research and development; and (2) delegate to the Director of BARDA any necessary functions and authorities. Establishes the Biodefense Medical Countermeasure Development Fund. Requires the Secretary to establish the National Biodefense Science Board to provide expert advice and guidance to the Secretary on matters relating to current and future chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological agents. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to extend the period of market exclusivity from seven years to ten years for certain new drugs, antibiotics, or anti-infective drugs to treat a rare disease or condition caused by a biological agent, toxin, chemical, radiological, or nuclear agent that is deemed by the Secretary to be a material threat to the United States. Provides an antitrust exemption for: (1) meetings and consultations held by the Secretary among persons engaged in the development of countermeasures or pandemic or epidemic products; and (2) agreements resulting from such meetings. Prohibits payment on a security countermeasure procurement contract until the delivery of an acceptable portion of such product to the Secretary unless advance payment is necessary to ensure the success of the project.</summary>
</bill>
