<bill session="112" type="s" number="599" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Civil War Sesquicentennial Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a commission to commemorate the sesquicentennial of the American Civil War.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-124.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1420"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2011--Introduced.
Civil War Sesquicentennial Commission Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a Civil War Sesquicentennial Commemoration Commission to plan, develop, and carry out programs and activities appropriate to commemorate the sesquicentennial of the Civil War, and to carry out other specified duties. Directs the National Endowment for the Humanities to award grants for appropriate activities relating to the Civil War sesquicentennial, and to consider and give priority to programs carried out by institutions of higher education, museums, nonprofit organizations, professional associations, or state sesquicentennial commissions that support the duties of the Commission, including those that concentrate on the role of African Americans in the Civil War.</summary>
</bill>
