<bill session="113" type="s" number="1075" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Homeowners from Onerous Rate Escalations Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHORE Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the phase-in of actuarial rates for flood insurance for certain properties under the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Saving Homeowners from Onerous Rate Escalations Act of 2013 or SHORE Act of 2013 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to phase in, over an eight-year period, any increase in the flood insurance risk premium rate caused by the prohibition against extending subsidies to new or lapsed policies. Extends from a 5-year to a 10-year period the phase-in period for premium adjustment increases in the flood insurance risk rate. Prescribes a phase-in rate of: (1) 5% for each of the first 5 years after the effective date of an update, and 15% for each of the 5 ensuing years; and (2) 5% for each of the first 5 years following the effective date of designation as a special flood area of any area not previously so designated, and 15% for each of the 5 ensuing years.</summary>
</bill>
