<bill session="112" type="hr" number="762" updated="2013-07-20T01:09:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding community-based civil defense and power generation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400017"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Encourages: (1) every community to work with citizens, leaders, and institutions ranging from local fire halls and schools to faith-based organizations to develop its own civil defense program to create sustainable local infrastructure and planning capacity for tranquil times and disaster scenarios; (2) every citizen to develop an individual emergency plan to prepare for the absence of government assistance for extended periods; (3) each local community to foster the capability of providing at least 20% of its own critical needs, such as local power generation, food, and water, while protecting local infrastructure whenever possible from threats to centralized infrastructure; and (4) state governments and federal agencies to support the ability of local communities to become stronger, self-reliant, and better able to assist neighboring communities in times of great need.</summary>
</bill>
