<bill session="112" type="hr" number="203" updated="2013-07-20T01:04:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-06T14:30:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-04-06T14:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 910) to amend the Clean Air Act to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from promulgating any regulation concerning, taking action relating to, or taking into consideration the emission of a greenhouse gas to address climate change, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-05T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-54, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-05T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. All points of order againist the committee amendment</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-05T17:40:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="26">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 26.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2338-2350" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 203.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 266 - 158 (Roll no. 230).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2348-2349" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2348" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-04-06T14:30:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="231" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 250 - 172 (Roll no. 231).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2338-2339" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 910) to amend the Clean Air Act to prohibit to Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from promulgating any regulation concerning, taking action relating to, or taking into consideration the emission of a greenhouse gas to address climate change.</summary>
</bill>
