<bill session="112" type="s" number="1187" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jason's Law</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to improve a pilot program on addressing shortages of long-term parking for commercial motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1803"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2011--Introduced.
Jason's Law - Amends the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) to direct the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), with respect to the pilot program to allocate funds to states, metropolitan planning organizations, and local governments, to establish long-term parking facilities for commercial motor vehicles (trucks) on the National Highway System. Requires applications to incorporate one or more specified factors, such as: (1) addressing a safety need through development of additional truck parking capacity for use in hours-of-service compliance, and (2) reducing congestion and improving air quality mitigation. Directs the Secretary to conduct a survey annually: (1) regarding the capacity of each state to provide adequate parking and rest facilities for trucks, and (2) assessing the volume of truck traffic through the state and developing a metrics system to measure the adequacy of the state's parking facilities.</summary>
</bill>
