<bill session="110" type="h" number="2062" updated="2013-07-19T21:21:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iraq Troop Protection and Reduction Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To set forth limitations on the United States military presence in Iraq and on United States aid to Iraq for security and reconstruction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="670"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Government officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Islam"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Logistics"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2007--Introduced.
Iraq Troop Protection and Reduction Act of 2007 - Prohibits, with a limited presidential national security waiver, U.S. military force levels in Iraq after the date of the enactment of this Act from exceeding such levels as of January 1, 2007. Prohibits appropriations for security and reconstruction assistance to the government of Iraq 90 days after enactment of this Act unless the President provides Congress with a specified certification respecting Iraq's: (1) security forces; (2) oil revenue distribution; (3) civil rights and political accommodation concerning its ethnic and sectarian groups; and (4) policy towards the participation of former Baath party members in the Iraqi government. Terminates authority for the use of U.S. military forces in Iraq 90 days after enactment of this Act unless the use of such forces is specifically authorized by Congress in a statute enacted after enactment of this Act or the President provides Congress with a specified certification respecting: (1) U.S. redeployment and mission transition; (2) Iraq's security forces; (3) oil revenue distribution; (4) civil rights and political accommodation concerning Iraq's ethnic and sectarian groups; (5) the participation of former Baath party members in the Iraqi government; and (6) the convening of an international conference on Iraq. States that the termination shall: (1) continue in effect if Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving the President's certification; and (2) not be construed to prohibit the use of U.S. military forces in Iraq for force protection, force security, or similar purposes during the U.S. military withdrawal from Iraq. Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds to deploy U.S. military forces to Iraq unless the Secretary of Defense certifies to Congress that such forces are adequately equipped and trained for their missions.</summary>
</bill>
