<bill session="113" type="h" number="2226" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal and State Partnership for Environmental Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal and State Partnership for Environmental Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 relating to State consultation on removal and remedial actions, State concurrence with listing on the National Priorities List, and State credit for contributions to the removal or remedial action, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 11 - 7 .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 19.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-178, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 1, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-01T13:58:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="182">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 182.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2013--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Federal and State Partnership for Environmental Protection Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to require the President to consult with affected states: (1) in undertaking a removal action concerning hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants (substances); and (2) during (currently, before) the process of selecting any appropriate remedial action. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and each federal entity responsible for federal facility compliance to consult with state and local officials and provide them the opportunity to participate in the planning and selection of a remedial action with respect to such a facility. Requires a determination made by state or local officials to not participate in such action to be documented in the administrative record regarding the action. (Sec. 3) Requires the President to grant states credit for the share of costs with respect to a facility listed on the National Priorities List under the National Contingency Plan for amounts expended for removal at such facility of such substances in addition to the credits currently given for remedial actions. Authorizes credit to be given for oversight costs and in-kind expenditures. (Sec. 4) Requires the President, upon the request of a state, to provide to such state the basis for not including a priority among releases of such substances on the revised national list. Prohibits the President from adding a facility to the national list over the written objection of the state, unless: the state, as an owner or operator or a significant contributor of hazardous substances to the facility, is a potentially responsible party; the President determines that the contamination has migrated across a state boundary, resulting in the need for response actions in multiple states; or the criteria under the national contingency plan for issuance of a health advisory have been met. Removes provisions concerning the 100 highest priority facilities. Authorizes states to designate a facility to the national list no more than once every five years. Includes, as a minimum requirement in regulations that provide for involvement by each state in remedial actions, state concurrence in adding sites to the National Priorities List. (Sec. 5) Requires remedial actions to meet any state environmental covenant law or state law or regulation requiring the use of engineering control or land use control if they are more stringent than federal requirements.</summary>
</bill>
