<bill session="109" type="h" number="3475" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the prompt review by the Secretary of the Interior of Petition No. 120 for Federal recognition of the Amah Mutsun of Mission San Juan Bautista as an Indian tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2005--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, within six months after enactment of this Act, to publish a proposed finding with respect to Petition No. 120 for federal recognition of the Amah Mutsun of Mission San Juan Bautista (Tribe) as an Indian Tribe. Requires the Secretary to publish a final determination within one year after enactment of this Act. States that the number of persons listed on the membership roll for Petition No. 120 shall not be taken into account in considering it. Allows the Secretary, however, to review the eligibility of individual members or groups listed in the petition. Authorizes the Tribe to seek in the appropriate U.S.district court a determination of whether the Tribe should be recognized as an Indian tribe, if the Secretary fails to meet either of the deadlines established by this Act. Authorizes the Tribe to seek in the appropriate U.S. district court review of any final determination refusing to recognize the Tribe, notwithstanding the availability of other administrative remedies.</summary>
</bill>
