<bill session="110" type="s" number="1224" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">SCHIP Extension bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to reauthorize the State Children's Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5186-5199" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5186"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10213-10214"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Obesity"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2007--Introduced.
Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) Reauthorization Act of 2007 - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to make appropriations for CHIP for FY2008-FY2012. Revises requirements for annual state CHIP allotments to create a formula including: (1) a coverage factor, based on a state's prior spending adjusted for health care cost growth and child population growth; and (2) an uninsured children factor, based on the number of low-income uninsured children. Requires: (1) a two-year initial availability of CHIP allotments for all states and territories; and (2) reallocation to a shortfall state or territory of amounts equal to the projected shortfall. Extends the authority for qualifying states to use CHIP allotments for certain expenditures under SSA title XIX (Medicaid). Gives states the option to expand coverage of children under CHIP to up to 300% of the poverty line. Prescribes conditions for state plan amendment expansion of CHIP eligibility beyond the highest income eligibility permitted. Prescribes requirements for an Express Lane option for a state agency to determine a child's eligibility for Medicaid or CHIP. Provides for enhanced administrative funding for: (1) information technology used to simplify eligibility determinations; and (2) translation or interpretation services. Authorizes conveyance to a state Medicaid agency by a federal or another state agency or private entity of data potentially pertinent to Medicaid eligibility determinations. Provides for enhanced coverage cost assistance for states with increasing or high coverage rates among children. Gives states the option to require satisfactory documentary evidence for proof of citizenship or nationality for Medicaid eligibility purposes. Gives states the option to expand or add coverage of: (1) certain pregnant women and legal immigrants under Medicaid and CHIP; and (2) targeted low-income pregnant women under CHIP. Requires CHIP coverage of dental and mental health services. Requires a childhood obesity demonstration project. Establishes the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission (MACPAC). Requires updating and enhancement of quality of care measures for children Permits coverage of children of employees of a public agency in the state under CHIP.</summary>
</bill>
