<bill session="112" type="h" number="4401" updated="2013-07-20T01:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">RACE for Space Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Revitalizing America's Commercial Entrepreneurs for Space Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Defense to work with non-Federal entities and accept non-Federal funding under strict implementation guidelines to promote efficiencies of the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense in commercial space activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1540"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4310"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1253"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1254"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1867"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2012--Introduced.
Revitalizing America's Commercial Entrepreneurs for Space Act or RACE for Space Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense, in order to assist the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) with respect to private-sector involvement in commercial space activities and public-private partnerships pertaining to space transportation infrastructure (STI), to: (1) maximize the use of Department of Defense (DOD) STI by the private sector, (2) maximize the effectiveness and efficiency of the DOD STI, (3) reduce the cost of STI services provided by DOD, (4) encourage commercial space activities by enabling investment in the DOD STI by non-federal entities engaged in commercial space activities, and (5) foster cooperation between DOD and such entities. Establishes the Defense Cooperation Space Launch Account for such purposes. Requires an annual report from the Secretary to the congressional defense and appropriations committees on funds and equipment accepted and used for such purposes.</summary>
</bill>
