<bill session="110" type="h" number="5525" updated="2013-07-19T21:52:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Inclusion of Veteran Service Organizations in the National Veterans Business Development Corporation Board Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the National Veterans Business Development Corporation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military service clubs"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Removal of officials"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2008--Introduced.
Inclusion of Veteran Service Organizations in the National Veterans Business Development Corporation Board Act - Amends Small Business Act provisions establishing a National Veterans Business Development Corporation (Corporation) to: (1) increase from 9 to 11 the number of Corporation voting members; (2) require the chairmen of the congressional small business and veterans' committees to appoint 4 of the 11 voting members, who shall be representatives of a congressionally chartered veterans' service organization or military service organization; (3) prohibit any member of the Corporation's Board of Directors from serving after the expiration of their term; (4) provide for the removal of Board members; (5) require all Board meetings to be public; and (6) require notification to Corporation stakeholders of Board meetings and agendas.</summary>
</bill>
