<bill session="111" type="s" number="3787" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upstate Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and modify the benefits available in empowerment zones and other tax-incentive areas, to require the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program for the award of grants to States to establish revolving loan funds for small and medium-sized manufacturers to improve energy efficiency and produce clean energy technology, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit for farmers' investments in value-added agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2010--Introduced.
Upstate Works Act - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to: (1) direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program to provide grants to states to establish revolving loan funds to provide loans to small and medium-sized manufacturers to finance the cost of reequipping, expanding, or establishing manufacturing facilities in the United States to produce clean energy technology and energy efficient products or of reducing the energy intensity or greenhouse gas production of a manufacturing facility; and (2) include as an activity of Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology (known as the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Centers) the establishment of a clean energy manufacturing supply chain initiative. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a 50% tax credit for investment in value-added agricultural property; (2) allow a credit for 50% of the cost of property used to furnish broadband services in rural areas; (3) extend through 2019 the period for designation of empowerment zones and renewal communities; (4) expand the eligibility criteria for enterprise zone businesses and the use of tax-exempt enterprise facility bonds; and (5) authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to award grants to state or local governments or nonprofit entities for the purpose of making businesses aware of benefits of empowerment zones and renewal communities. Directs the Secretary of Labor to award grants to improve job skills necessary for employment in specific industries.</summary>
</bill>
