<bill session="112" type="h" number="4061" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Student Right to Know Before You Go Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support statewide individual-level integrated postsecondary education data systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2012-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="2098"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2012--Introduced.
Student Right to Know Before You Go Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) participating in title IV (Student Assistance) programs to participate in, and provide all the data required for, an individual-level integrated postsecondary education data system administered by a state, a multi-state compact, or the Secretary of Education. Allows system administrators to include, in addition to data from IHEs, data from certain other postsecondary education and training programs. Requires the systems to be certified by the Secretary as meeting certain data inclusion, quality, governance, and privacy requirements. Requires the systems to include: (1) all student components of reporting required for the Integrated Postsecondary Data System (IPEDS), and submit such data to IPEDS; (2) rates of remedial enrollment, credit accumulation, and postsecondary completion by high school completion status; and (3) earnings data, disaggregated by educational program, institution, degree, employment sector, and state to create an interoperable employment and learning exchange. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to educational institutions and system administrators to assist them in complying with, developing, and implementing individual-level integrated postsecondary education data systems.</summary>
</bill>
