<bill session="109" type="s" number="1713" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iran Nonproliferation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Iran Nonproliferation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Iran Nonproliferation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Iran Nonproliferation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make amendments to the Iran Nonproliferation Act of 2000 related to International Space Station payments.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">An Act to make amendments to the Iran Nonproliferation Act of 2000 related to International Space Station payments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An act to make amendments to the Iran Nonproliferation Act to 2000 related to International Space Station payments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10257-10258" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-09-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10257-10258" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rohrabacher moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9240-9246" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1713.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE" datetime="2005-10-26T19:18:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9240-9241" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26T19:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26T19:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-11-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment and title amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12550-12551" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S12550-12551" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-11-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-11-22" type="public" number="109-112">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-112.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4003"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cruise missiles"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in astronautics"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space agreements"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/22/2005--Public Law.
Iran Nonproliferation Amendments Act of 2005 - Amends the Iran Nonproliferation Act of 2000 to state that the definition of "extraordinary payments in connection with the International Space Station" does not mean payments in cash or in kind made or to be made by the U.S. government prior to January 1, 2012, for work to be performed or services to be rendered prior to that date necessary to meet U.S. obligations under the Agreement Concerning Cooperation on the Civil International Space Station, with annex, signed at Washington January 29, 1998, and entered into force March 27, 2001, or any protocol, agreement, memorandum of understanding, or contract related thereto. (Under such Act the United States is prohibited from making such payments to the Russian Aviation and Space Agency unless specified determinations are made with respect to Russian cooperation in preventing proliferation to Iran, or to a foreign person identified as contributing to proliferation to Iran.) Prohibits any U.S. agency from making extraordinary payments and any other payments (currently, such prohibition is limited to extraordinary payments) in connection with the International Space Station to a foreign person subject to specified measures under such Act or Executive Order No. 12938. Directs the President to submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives a report that identifies each Russian entity or person to whom the United States has, since the date of enactment of this Act, made a cash or in-kind payment under the Agreement. Requires such report to include: (1) the purpose of each payment; and (2) with respect to each such payment, an assessment that the payment was not prejudicial to preventing the proliferation of ballistic or cruise missile systems in Iran and other countries that have supported acts of international terrorism. Applies the provisions of such Act to: (1) Syria with respect to transfers on or after January 1, 2005; and (2) transfers to or from such countries (currently, limited to transfers to Iran). Redefines "foreign person" or "person" to include any foreign government or government entity (currently, any governmental entity operating as a business enterprise). Retitles the Iran Nonproliferation Act of 2002 as the Iran and Syria Nonproliferation Act.</summary>
</bill>
