<bill session="109" type="s" number="2104" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Center for Cures Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish the American Center for Cures to accelerate the development of public and private research efforts towards tools and therapies for human diseases with the goal of early disease detection, prevention, and cure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2005-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13577-13583"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13583-13589" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical libraries"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nanotechnology"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2005--Introduced.
American Center for Cures Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the National Institutes of Health (NIH) an American Center for Cures to promote translational research to speed the development of effective therapies, diagnostics, and cures. Establishes a Cures Council to help advise and direct the Center's translational research efforts. Authorizes the Center's Director (the Director of Cures) to establish Federally Funded Research and Development Centers to serve as research sites. Establishes within the Center a Health Advanced Research Projects Agency to advance the development and deployment of critical health products. Authorizes the Agency to flexibly fund projects. Requires the Director of Cures to establish a series of Centralized Institutional Review Boards to serve as human subject safety and well being custodians for multi-institutional clinical trials that are funded by public dollars. Requires the Director of NIH to commission the Institute of Medicine to study the rules that protect patient safety and anonymity with respect to clinical research. Establishes an Office of Bioscientific Enterprise Development (OBED) and transfers to it the Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer programs. Requires OBED to partner grantees with potential purchasers of products. Establishes an Office of Technology Transfer (OTT) and transfers to it appropriate NIH functions. Requires OTT to establish: (1) an Office of Rapid Access to Intervention Development to accelerate the process from laboratory to clinic; and (2) a program that cultivates industry interest in NIH-funded research. Establishes an Office of Intramural Risk Opportunity and Mapping to oversee the intramural research programs of NIH. Requires the Center for Biotechnology Information to develop new computational methods to aid in the processing of genomic data. Provides for the construction of a clinical study registry and results database.</summary>
</bill>
