<bill session="109" type="h" number="2487" updated="2013-07-19T19:26:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Medicare for All Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, to provide additional beneficiary protections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1046"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2005--Introduced.
Preserving Medicare for All Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, to repeal provisions prohibiting the Secretary of Health and Human Services from: (1) interfering with the negotiations between drug manufacturers and pharmacies and prescription drug plan sponsors; and (2) requiring a particular formulary to institute a price structure for the reimbursement of covered Medicare part D drugs. Allows the Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) eligible individual, as an alternative to the current choice of coverage in at least two qualifying plans in the area in which the individual resides, to choose enrollment in a nationwide prescription drug plan offered by the Secretary (to replace enrollment in a fallback prescription drug plan in any case in which such plans are not available). Directs the Secretary, through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, to: (1) take necessary steps to qualify and serve as a prescription drug plan sponsor; and (2) offer a prescription drug plan that offers basic prescription drug coverage throughout the United States, with a $35 premium for 2006, adjusted annually thereafter. Requires such a plan to be in addition to, and not in lieu of, other prescription drug plans offered. Provides for full reimbursement to employers for the cost of qualified retiree drug coverage, and permits their costs to count towards senior's catastrophic limits. Abolishes the comparative cost adjustment program. Eliminates the MA Regional Plan Stabilization Fund. Repeals certain cost containment requirements.</summary>
</bill>
