<bill session="112" type="h" number="6290" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the deployment of a unit or individual of the United States Armed Forces or element of the intelligence community in support of a North Atlantic Treaty Organization military operation absent express prior statutory authorization from Congress for such deployment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2012-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
States that it is the policy of the United States: (1) to protect the role of Congress as a coequal branch of government and ensure protection of its constitutional authority to declare war and support the Armed Forces; (2) to prevent the need for U.S. and international military intervention abroad through the utilization of diplomacy to resolve issues of concern to the United States and the international community; and (3) that no federal funds may be used to carry out any North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) military operation or to deploy a unit of individual of the U.S. Armed Forces or an element of the intelligence community (IC) in support of a NATO military operation unless the President determines that such operation is warranted and seeks express prior authorization by Congress, as required under the Constitution. Provides an exception in the case of a military operation to directly thwart or repel an offensive military action launched against the United States or an ally with whom the United States has a mutual defense assistance agreement. Prohibits any unit or individual of the U.S. Armed Forces or IC element from being deployed in support of a NATO military operation absent express prior statutory authorization from Congress, unless under the exception described above.</summary>
</bill>
