<bill session="109" type="h" number="1128" updated="2013-07-19T19:14:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit for carbon dioxide captured from anthropogenic industrial sources and used as a tertiary injectant in enhanced oil and natural gas recovery.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compressed natural gas"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of gas"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of oil"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business tax credit for amounts of qualified carbon dioxide captured in the United States from anthropogenic industrial sources (e.g., an ethanol plant, fertilizer plant, or chemical plant) and used as a tertiary injectant in enhanced oil and natural gas recovery. Sets the credit amount at 75 cents (adjusted for inflation) per 1,000 standard cubic feet of the carbon dioxide captured. Defines "qualified carbon dioxide" as carbon dioxide captured from an anthropogenic source that: (1) would otherwise be released into the atmosphere as industrial emission of greenhouse gas; (2) is measurable at the source of capture; (3) is compressed, treated, and transported by pipeline; (4) is sold as a tertiary injectant in qualified enhanced oil and natural gas recovery; and (5) is permanently sequestered in geological formations as a result of the oil and natural gas recovery process.</summary>
</bill>
