<bill session="113" type="h" number="2895" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Accessibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend the reduced interest rate for Federal Direct Stafford Loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412432"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Student Loan Accessibility Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend the 3.4% interest rate on Direct Stafford loans first disbursed to undergraduate students between July 1, 2011, and July 1, 2013, to Direct Stafford loans first disbursed to undergraduate students between July 1, 2011, and July 1, 2014. Amends the federal criminal code to provide that a prisoner who is serving a term of imprisonment of more than one year, other than a term of life imprisonment, shall receive credit in addition to the time actually served at a rate of 84 days per year of sentence imposed if the Bureau of Prisons determines that the prisoner has displayed exemplary compliance with institutional disciplinary regulations. Prohibits the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) from implementing the Screening of Passengers by Observation Techniques (SPOT) program. Requires any unobligated funds for that program to be expeditiously returned to the U.S. Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
