<bill session="109" type="s" number="1890" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Settlement Transparency Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to deny a deduction for certain fines, penalties, and other amounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11565-11566"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11566-11567" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2005--Introduced.
Government Settlement Transparency Act of 2005 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise the rule denying a tax deduction for fines and penalties paid to a government for the violation of any law to provide that no deduction shall be allowed for any fine or penalty paid (whether by suit, agreement, or otherwise) to, or at the direction of, a government or nongovernmental regulatory entity for a violation of law or for the investigation or inquiry by such government or entity into a potential violation of any law. Allows exceptions to the general rule of nondeductibility for: (1) certain restitution payments or payments required to come into compliance with law; (2) court-ordered payments not involving a government or nongovernmental regulatory entity; and (3) amounts paid or incurred as taxes due. Requires governmental agencies involved in a settlement with a taxpayer to report to the Secretary of the Treasury and the taxpayer information about such settlement, including the amount of the settlement, the amount paid as restitution or remediation of property, and the amount paid to come into compliance with law.</summary>
</bill>
