<bill session="109" type="s" number="475" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Housing Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 and other Acts to improve housing for Indians.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2005-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="797"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2005--Introduced.
Native American Housing Enhancement Act of 2005 - Amends the Native American Housing Assistance Act of 1996 to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from restricting access to a Native American affordable housing grant based solely on one of four specified factors. Amends title V (Farm Housing) of the Housing Act of 1949 to state that federally recognized Indian tribes who exercise powers of self-government (or their instrumentalities) shall comply with the Indian Civil Rights Act (title II of the Civil Rights Act of 1968) when receiving assistance under title V. States that title VI (Federally Assisted Programs) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and title VIII (Fair Housing) of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 shall not apply to tribes: (1) covered by Federal law commonly known as the Indian Civil Rights Act; or (2) tribes acting under affordable housing provisions of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996. Amends the Cranston-Gonzales National Affordable Housing Act to make Indian tribes, tribally designated housing entities, or other agencies primarily serving Indians eligible for Youthbuild grants.</summary>
</bill>
