<bill session="110" type="s" number="1967" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Savers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide administrative ease and incentives for increased saving by Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Savings bonds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax preparers"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2007--Introduced.
New Savers Act - Requires the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to notify individual taxpayers of their options to: (1) have their income tax refunds electronically deposited to a designated bank account (e.g., savings account); and (2) purchase U.S. savings bonds when they file their federal income tax returns.Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) make grants to provide matching funds for clinics to assist low-income taxpayers in preparing and filing their federal income tax returns; (2) increase payments to financial institutions to offset the costs of opening electronic transfer accounts; and (3) provide grants to states to increase participation in qualified tuition programs by moderate and low-income families.Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish performance measures to evaluate the extent to which Americans save and use the federal tax filing process to facilitate savings activities; (2) establish a program to support and promote the expansion of access to financial services and development of new financial products and services; (3) convene a federal advisory board to expand access to U.S. savings bonds; and (4) publish an annual report on the use of qualified tuition programs for paying tuition and other higher education costs.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a performance measure for the percentage of state benefit recipients who receive benefits by direct deposit into insured bank accounts.Establishes as a tax-exempt individual retirement account (IRA) a young savers account, to be treated in the same manner as a Roth IRA.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow tax credits for contributions to qualified tuition programs and Coverdell education savings accounts and for employer contributions to employee payroll savings plans; and (2) impose certain reporting requirements for managers of qualified tuition programs.</summary>
</bill>
