<bill session="110" type="s" number="1531" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Renewable Energy and Economic Development Incentives Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives and extend existing incentives for the production and use of renewable energy resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6955-6960" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2007--Introduced.
Clean Renewable Energy and Economic Development Incentives Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through 2018 the tax credits for producing electricity from renewable resources and for investment in clean renewable energy bonds.Allows new tax credits for: (1) holders of water conservation, reuse, and efficiency bonds; (2) expenditures for geothermal exploration; (3) holders of qualified renewable school energy bonds; and (4) investment in solar energy manufacturing facilities.Expands the tax credit for residential energy efficient property to include expenditures for wind energy property that uses a qualifying wind turbine (with a rated capacity of 100 kilowatts or less) to generate electricity.Extends through 2013 the new energy efficient home tax credit.Expands the energy tax credit to include investment in equipment used to produce advanced battery and related power electronics for use in certain electric or hybrid motor vehicles or in residential or small commercial applications.Allows the tax-exempt bond financing of renewable energy resource facilities (i.e., facilities for the production of electric or thermal energy from certain renewable resources).Makes permanent the energy tax credit for investment in solar energy property. Includes as energy property for purposes of such credit excess energy storage devices.Allows solar and geothermal public utility property to qualify for the energy tax credit. Makes permanent the tax credit for residential energy efficient property expenditures. Allows three-year accelerated depreciation of solar energy property.</summary>
</bill>
