<bill session="112" type="sr" number="481" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-05">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution celebrating the 60th Anniversary of the United States-Philippines Mutual Defense Treaty and the vitality of the overall bilateral relationship.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2012-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-06-05" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3737-3738" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3737-3738" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3733-3734" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Celebrates the 60th Anniversary of the United States-Philippines Mutual Defense Treaty and the vitality of the bilateral relationship. Confirms the alliance's centrality as one of the key pillars of peace, security, and prosperity in the Asia-Pacific region. Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States should use the U.S.-Philippines Bilateral Security Dialogue and the Mutual Defense Board and Security Engagement Board to promote greater alliance cooperation and enhance bilateral security ties; (2) the United States should redouble efforts to expand the economic relationship with the Philippines; (3) the government of the Philippines should continue its efforts to strengthen democratic institutions to fight corruption, curtail politically motivated violence, expand economic opportunity, and tackle internal security challenges; (4) the United States should designate an appropriate U.S. entity to ensure ongoing maintenance of Clark Veterans Cemetery in the Philippines; and (5) the United States should continue efforts to assist the Philippines in the areas of maritime security, humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, and related communications infrastructure to enable enhanced information-sharing and overall military professionalization.</summary>
</bill>
