<bill session="111" type="h" number="3723" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Credit Expansion and Loan Markets Stabilization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the activities carried out under section 7(a) of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412279"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="2009-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Tax.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated into H.R. 3854.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM19" subcommittee="Finance and Tax" name="House Small Business"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Credit Expansion and Loan Markets Stabilization Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish and carry out: (1) a program to provide support to SBA regional, district, and branch offices to assist small lenders not participating in the SBA Preferred Lenders Program to participate in other programs for assistance to small businesses under the SBA 7(a) general business loan program; (2) a rural lending outreach program; and (3) a lender training program for new and existing lenders. Makes permanent (currently pilot programs): (1) the SBA's Community Express Program; and (2) a program for reduced fees for veteran participation loans. Reduces restrictions with respect to borrower leasing of space constructed with the proceeds of an SBA-guaranteed loan. Directs the Administrator to establish and permit a lender making a 7(a) loan to use an alternative loan size standard based on factors including a business's maximum tangible net worth and average net income. Prohibits more than 10% of SBA-guaranteed loans in a fiscal year from being awarded as part of a pilot program. Provides additional pilot program dollar limitations. Prohibits pilot programs (other than existing ones) from exceeding three years in duration. Authorizes the Administrator to provide loans to cooperatives, under specified conditions. Directs the Administrator to establish: (1) a capital backstop program, under which the Administrator collects information from a small business to determine the creditworthiness and repayment ability of a small business attempting to secure an SBA-guaranteed loan; and (2) a process for providing such information to participating lenders. Prohibits the Administrator from applying any application, processing, or approval standard to a loan for the purpose of financing goodwill, unless such standard applies to all 7(a) loans. Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish an independent SBA appellate process for reviewing material determinations affecting a lender or investment company participating or applying to participate in an SBA program; and (2) appoint an SBA ombudsman. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to extend and expand certain loans made available to small businesses. Increases certain SBA loan limits. Revises real estate appraisal requirements with respect to SBA loans secured by commercial property.</summary>
</bill>
