<bill session="109" type="h" number="5002" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Information Sharing Partnerships Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for information sharing partnerships, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM05" subcommittee="Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
Homeland Security Information Sharing Partnerships Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a State, Local, and Tribal Information Fusion Center Initiative to establish partnerships with state, local, tribal, and regional information fusion centers (designated entities that serve as data analysis and dissemination centers for potentially relevant homeland security information). Specifies the Secretary's duties through such Initiative, including: (1) coordinating with the principal official of each state, local, tribal, or regional information fusion center and the official designated as the Homeland Security Advisor of the State; (2) providing Department of Homeland Security (DHS) operational and intelligence advice and assistance to such centers; (3) reviewing homeland security information gathered by such centers and incorporate relevant information with Department information; and (4) providing training to such centers and encourage them to participate in terrorist threat-related exercises conducted by the Department. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees with a concept of operations for the Initiative, including a privacy and civil liberties impact assessment. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, to establish a Homeland Security Information Sharing Fellows Program.</summary>
</bill>
