<bill session="112" type="h" number="3532" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Indian Empowerment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To empower federally recognized Indian tribes to accept restricted fee tribal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2012-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/30/2011--Introduced.
American Indian Empowerment Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to transfer land the federal government holds in trust for a federally recognized Indian tribe to such tribe as restricted fee tribal land, subject to a restriction against alienation and taxation, after receiving the Indian tribe's request for such transfer. (Restricted fee tribal land is land to which a tribe holds legal title, but which carries legal restrictions against alienation or encumbrance.) Allows Indian tribes to lease, or grant an easement or right-of-way on, restricted fee tribal land for any period of time without the Secretary's review and approval. Gives the laws of a federally recognized Indian tribe that establish a system of land tenure governing the use of the land it holds precedence over any federal law or regulation governing the use of such land, excepting a federal restriction against its alienation and taxation.</summary>
</bill>
