<bill session="109" type="s" number="1609" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">20/20 Biofuels Challenge Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase the production and use of biofuels and diversify biofuel feedstock as key elements to achieving energy independence for the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy crops"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm manure"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
20/20 Biofuels Challenge Act of 2005 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations ensuring that motor vehicle fuel sold or dispensed to consumers in the contiguous United States, on an annual average basis, contains specified volumes of renewable fuel for calendar years 2006-2020. Amends federal transportation law to require that personal and commercial land and water transportation and shipping vehicles and vessels, as well as large farm equipment manufactured after model year 2010, and capable of operating on either gasoline or diesel fuel, also be capable of operating on a flexible fuel mixture. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to prescribe regulations requiring a vehicle or vessel manufacturer to include certain consumer information concerning a vehicle's capability of operating on a flexible fuel mixture (alternative biofuels). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) support development of cellulosic feedstock by directing that erosion-preventing, renewable fuel-producing crops be grown on certain arable land in a specified conservation reserve program established under the Food Security Act of 1985; and (2) implement an integrated 10-year research program to improve crop productivity and cost for cellulosic-based ethanol and biodiesel feedstock. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to implement an eight-year research and development plan to improve significantly processes for converting: (1) cellulosic feedstock into ethanol production; and (2) biodiesel feedstock into biodiesel fuel.</summary>
</bill>
