<bill session="112" type="h" number="4966" updated="2013-07-20T01:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sequester Replacement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Sequester Replacement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to replace the sequester established by the Budget Control Act of 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Budget"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Budget"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Budget. H. Rept. 112-469, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Rules discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-05-09T19:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="329">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 329.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5652"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Sequester Replacement Act of 2012 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to remove veterans medical care from the accounts subject to a sequester. Abolishes the distinction between security and nonsecurity categories of discretionary spending for new budget authority in FY2013. Combines the dollar amounts of the current categories ($686 billion for the security category and $361 billion for the nonsecurity category) into a single amount of $1.047 trillion in new budget authority. Revises sequestration requirements for FY2013 to require a $19.104 billion across-the-board decrease in the discretionary spending category as of January 2, 2013. Directs the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue a supplemental sequestration report for FY2013 to eliminate any discretionary spending breach of the $1.047 trillion spending limit, as adjusted by the $19.104 billion across-the-board reduction requirement of this Act. Directs the President to order a sequestration, if any, as required by such report. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to authorize the chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives or the Senate to make adjustments to any legislative measure to conform to the discretionary spending limits of this Act. Nullifies any sequestration order the President may issue under the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act to carry out reductions to direct spending for the FY2013 defense function (050).</summary>
</bill>
