<bill session="112" type="h" number="6527" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women Veterans and Other Health Care Improvements Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the assistance provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to women veterans, to improve health care furnished by the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2012-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2012-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2012-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412418" joined="2012-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2012-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2012-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2012-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2012-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="3313"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Women Veterans and Other Health Care Improvements Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to facilitate collaborative research to meet the long-term reproductive health care needs of veterans who have a service-connected genitourinary disability or a condition that was aggravated in the line of active duty, such as a spinal cord injury, that affects the veterans' ability to reproduce. Includes fertility counseling and treatment within authorized VA medical services. Directs the Secretary to furnish such counseling and treatment, including the use of assisted reproductive technology, to a spouse or surrogate of a severely wounded veteran who has an infertility condition incurred or aggravated in the line of duty and who is enrolled in the VA health care system, as long as the spouse and veteran apply jointly for such counseling and treatment. Requires the Secretary to enhance the capabilities of the VA women veterans call center: (1) to respond to requests for assistance with accessing VA health care and benefits, and (2) for referral to community resources to obtain assistance with services not furnished by the VA. Amends the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010 relating to a pilot program of group retreat reintegration and readjustment counseling for women veterans recently separated from service to: (1) increase from at least 3 to at least 14 the number of locations for such counseling, and (2) extend the pilot program for an additional 2 years. Requires a pilot program under such Act relating to the provision of child care assistance for certain veterans receiving VA health care to be extended until two years after the program is established in the third Veterans Integrated Service Network. (Under current law, such program terminates two years after its original commencement.) Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing child care assistance to veterans receiving or in need of VA readjustment counseling and related mental health services. Requires the program to continue until two years after it is begun at the last Readjustment Counseling Service Region chosen by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
