<bill session="109" type="s" number="317" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Library, Bookseller, and Personal Records Privacy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect privacy by limiting the access of the Government to library, bookseller, and other personal records for foreign intelligence and counterintelligence purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2005-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1131-1133"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1133" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Library, Bookseller, and Personal Records Privacy Act - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 and the Federal criminal code with respect to applications by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) (or a designee) for an order requiring production of any tangible things (including books, records, papers, documents, and other items) for an investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a U.S. person or to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities. Requires such applications, any resulting ex parte orders, and requests to booksellers and libraries to specify that there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the person to whom the records pertain is a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power. Amends the USA PATRIOT Act of 2001 to terminate as of December 31, 2005, specified authority for FBI investigative requests for telephone toll and transactional records as well as financial records and consumer reports.</summary>
</bill>
