<bill session="112" type="s" number="1255" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2012 for military construction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Levin. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="82">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 82.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1253"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1867"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012- Division B: Military Construction Authorizations - Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 - (Sec. 2002) Terminates all authorizations contained in Titles XXI through XXVII of this Act on October 1, 2014, or the date of enactment of an Act authorizing funds for military construction for FY2015, whichever is later, with an exception. Title XXI [sic]: Army - (Sec. 2101) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes such Secretary to construct or acquire family housing units, carry out architectural planning and design activities, and improve existing military family housing in specified amounts. Authorizes appropriations to the Army for fiscal years after 2011 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Army. (Sec. 2105) Revises construction authority under certain prior-year military construction projects. (Sec. 2108) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to carry out a military construction project at Fort Irwin, California. (Sec. 2109) Extends certain prior-year military construction projects. (Sec. 2112) Rescinds $100 million from prior-year Army military construction funds. (Sec. 2113) Prohibits funds from being obligated or expended for tour normalization until: (1) the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation conducts an analysis of alternatives, (2) the Secretary of the Army submits to the defense and appropriations committees a master plan for completing all phases of tour normalization, and (3) legislation enacted after the enactment of this Act authorizes the obligation of funds for such purpose. Title XXII: Navy - (Sec. 2201) Provides, with respect to the Navy, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army under the previous title. (Sec. 2205) Extends certain prior-year military construction projects. (Sec. 2207) Rescinds $25 million from prior-year Navy military construction funds. (Sec. 2208) Prohibits the use of funds authorized under this title, or provided by Japan, to implement the realignment of U.S. Marine Corps forces from Okinawa to Guam until: (1) the Commandant of the Marine Corps provides to the congressional defense and appropriations committees the preferred force lay-down for the U.S. Pacific Command area of responsibility; (2) the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) submits to such committees a master plan for the construction of facilities and infrastructure to execute the preferred force lay-down on Guam; (3) the Secretary certifies to such committees that tangible progress has been made regarding the relocation of Marine Corps Air Station Futenma; and (4) a plan is provided to such committees detailing descriptions of work, costs, and a schedule for completion of construction, improvements, and repairs to the non-military utilities, facilities, and infrastructure on Guam affected by the realignment. Title XXIII: Air Force - (Sec. 2301) Provides, with respect to the Air Force, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army under Title XXI. (Sec. 2305) Revises a certain prior-year military construction project. (Sec. 2306) Extends a certain prior-year military construction project. (Sec. 2307) Rescinds $32 million from prior-year Air Force military construction funds. Title XXIV: Defense Agencies - Subtitle A: Defense Agency Authorizations - (Sec. 2401) Authorizes the Secretary to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out energy conservation projects in specified amounts. Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 2011 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Department of Defense (DOD). Subtitle B: Chemical Demilitarization Authorizations - (Sec. 2411) Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 2011 for military construction and land acquisition for chemical demilitarization for the construction of: (1) phase 13 of a chemical munitions demilitarization facility at Pueblo Chemical Activity, Colorado; and (2) phase 12 of a munitions demilitarization facility at Blue Grass Army Depot, Kentucky. (Sec. 2412) Rescinds $131 million from prior-year DOD military construction funds. Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program - (Sec. 2501) Authorizes the Secretary to make contributions for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program and authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 2011 for such Program. Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities - (Sec. 2601) Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned (Secretary concerned) to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects for the National Guard and reserves. (Sec. 2606) Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 2011 for National Guard and reserve forces for acquisition, architectural and engineering services, and construction of facilities. (Sec. 2607) Extends certain prior-year National Guard and reserve military construction projects. (Sec. 2609) Revises a certain prior-year military construction project. Title XXVII: Base Closure and Realignment Activities - (Sec. 2701) Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 2011 for military base closure and realignment activities authorized under the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 and funded through the Department of Defense Base Closure Account 1990. (Sec. 2702) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out base closure and realignment activities authorized under the above Act and funded through the Department of Defense Base Closure Account 2005. Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 2011 for such purpose. (Sec. 2704) Rescinds $100 million from prior-year base closure and realignment activities funds. Title XVIII: Military Construction General Provisions - Subtitle A: Military Construction Program and Military Family Housing Changes - (Sec. 2801) Authorizes the Secretaries concerned, in the national interest, to transfer up to $400 million of FY2012 military construction funds between any such authorizations for that military department or defense agency. Requires prompt notification to the defense and appropriations committees of each transfer. (Sec. 2802) Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act (MCAA) for Fiscal Year 2004 to extend through FY2012 the temporary, limited authority to use DOD operation and maintenance funds for construction projects outside the United States. Extends related report requirements. (Sec. 2803) Authorizes the Secretary to use Pentagon Reservation Maintenance Revolving Fund amounts to support construction or alteration activities at the Pentagon within the unspecified minor construction project limits. Subtitle B: Real Property and Facilities Administration - (Sec. 2811) Authorizes the exchange (under current law, the conveyance) of property at or near military installations for land acquisition purposes. Makes such authority permanent (under current law, ends at the end of FY2013). (Sec. 2812) Authorizes the use of the DOD readiness and environmental protection initiative authority to protect areas near military installations from encroachment that is incompatible with the mission of the installation. Allows for lump-sum payments by the United States for property acquired under such authority. (Sec. 2813) Includes sustainability of military operations as an authorized purpose of wildlife studies conducted under DOD conservation and cultural activities. Allows, under such activities, the implementation of ecosystem-wide land management plans. Subtitle C: Land Conveyances - (Sec. 2821) Amends the MCAA for 2010 to: (1) make a technical correction with respect to a land conveyance at Camp Joseph T. Robinson, Arkansas; and (2) revise the Secretary of the Navy's authority with respect to a land conveyance at Camp Caitlin and the Ohana Nui areas, Hawaii. Subtitle D: Other Matters - (Sec. 2831) Directs the Secretary of the Navy to submit to the defense and appropriations committees a plan to address the facilities and infrastructure requirements at each Navy public shipyard. (Sec. 2832) Prohibits a DOD department, agency, or component, during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on May 1, 2012, from obligating funds for a data server, upgrade, farm, or center unless approved by the DOD Chief Information Officer (CIO) or the appropriate department, agency, or component chief information officer designated by the CIO. Requires, after May 1, 2012, any obligation of funds for such purpose to be in conformance with a performance plan for the reduction of resources required for data servers and centers, as submitted by the Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of the defense agencies. Requires the CIO, after such submission, to submit to the defense and appropriations committees a DOD-wide performance plan. Provides an exception to the requirements of this section with respect to such DOD intelligence components that are funded through the National Intelligence Program as the CIO considers appropriate. Directs the CIO, annually through 2016, to report to the defense, appropriations, and intelligence committees on cost savings, reductions, avoidances, and performance gains achieved as a result of activities taken under this section.</summary>
</bill>
