<bill session="112" type="s" number="1049" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Health Relief Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to lower health premiums and increase choice for small business.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3228-3229" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2676"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1880"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2011--Introduced.
Small Business Health Relief Act of 2011 - Repeals provisions of the Internal Revenue Code (IRC), as added by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), that: (1) impose fines on large employers (employers with more than 50 full-time employees) who fail to offer their full-time employees the opportunity to enroll in minimum essential health insurance coverage; and (2) require such large employers to file a report with the Secretary of the Treasury on health insurance coverage provided to their full-time employees. Repeals provision of PPACA that: (1) set limits on the annual deductible on health plans offered in the small group market, (2) allow catastrophic plans to be offered in the individual market to individuals under the age of 30, and (3) impose an annual fee on health insurance entities. Deems high deductible health plans to meet essential health benefits coverage requirements if the enrollee has established a health savings account. Amends the Public Health Service Act, as amended by PPACA, to repeal provision that allow a premium rate variance by age in the individual or small group market. Repeals restrictions on payments for medications from health savings accounts, medical savings accounts, and health flexible spending arrangements to prescription drugs or insulin. Repeals provisions limiting annual salary reduction contributions by an employee to a health flexible spending arrangement under a cafeteria plan to $2,500. Allows a health plan to maintain its status as a grandfathered health plan regardless of any modification to the cost-sharing levels, employer contribution rates, or covered benefits. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to promulgate regulations to clarify the application of such provision. Makes this provision effective as if included in PPACA. Voids any regulations promulgated related to such provisions before enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
