<bill session="113" type="s" number="740" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Drug Savings Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require drug manufacturers to provide drug rebates for drugs dispensed to low-income individuals under the Medicare prescription drug benefit program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2687"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1588"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2013--Introduced.
Medicare Drug Savings Act of 2013 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require drug manufacturers to pay the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) drug rebates for rebate eligible (low-income) individuals. Excludes from Medicare coverage as a part D drug any drug or biological manufactured by a manufacturer that has not entered into and have in effect a rebate agreement with the Secretary. Requires a rebate agreement to require a drug or biological manufacturer to provide to the Secretary a rebate, determined according to a specified formula, for each rebate period ending after December 31, 2011, for any covered Medicare part D drug dispensed after that date to any rebate eligible individual for which payment was made by a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor or MedicareAdvantage (MA) organization for such period. Specifies a formula for determination of Medicaid rebate amounts for such drugs or biologicals. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to exclude any amounts paid under a rebate agreement from the determination of best price and average manufacturer price under the Medicaid program.</summary>
</bill>
