<bill session="111" type="h" number="6083" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Act of 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2010-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6081"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3751"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/2010--Introduced.
Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Reauthorization Act of 2010 - Amends the Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Act of 2005 to revise the National Cord Blood Inventory Program, including to: (1) remove the cap of 150,000 new units of cord blood to be made available for transplantation under the Program; and (2) require an application under the Program to include a&#160; plan for, and demonstration of, ongoing measurable progress toward achieving self-sufficiency of cord blood unit collection and banking operations. Extends financial support provided under the Program for an additional five years. (Current law allows financial support for a maximum of ten years.) Sets forth requirements for such an extension, including that a qualified cord blood bank demonstrate a superior ability to satisfy the requirements of such Program and achieve the overall goals for which the contract was awarded. Redefines the term "first-degree relative" to exclude a parent. Reauthorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for the collection or maintenance of cord blood. Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise the requirements of the C.W. Bill Young Cell Transplantation Program to: (1) require studies and projects under such Program to include exploring novel approaches or incentives to expand the number of cord blood unit collection sites partnering with federally-supported cord blood banks; and (2) revise privacy provisions to protect the privacy of patients and donors in accordance with federal and state law. Reauthorizes appropriations for such Program for FY2011-FY2015. Directs the Comptroller General to submit a report to the relevant congressional committees and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) that reviews studies, demonstration programs, and outreach efforts to increase&#160; cord blood unit donation and collection.</summary>
</bill>
