<bill session="111" type="sr" number="480" updated="2013-07-20T00:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-07">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution condemning the continued detention of Burmese democracy leader Daw Aung San Suu Kyi and calling on the military regime in Burma to permit a credible and fair election process and the transition to civilian, democratic rule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2010-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2299" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3432-3433" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-05-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with amendments and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3432-3433" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3913"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/7/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Condemns the detention of, and calls for the immediate release of, Burmese democracy leader Daw Aung San Suu Kyi and all prisoners of conscience in Burma. Calls on the military regime in Burma to engage in dialogue with all political groups and individuals dedicated to democratic ideals, as well as with ethnic minorities, to broaden political participation in an environment free from intimidation. Calls upon the Secretary of State to: (1) assess the effectiveness of the policy of engagement with the military regime in Burma in furthering U.S. interests and to maintain and consider strengthening sanctions if the military regime continues its systematic violation of human rights; (2) engage regional governments and multilateral organizations to push for democratic transition to civilian rule in Burma; and (3) support the people of Burma in calling for constitutional and election reforms by the military regime.</summary>
</bill>
