<bill session="112" type="hj" number="68" updated="2013-07-20T02:08:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-24T12:15:00-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-06-24T12:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing the limited use of the United States Armed Forces in support of the NATO mission in Libya.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 328 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 68 and H.R. 2278 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without installowed. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides one hour of dbeate on H.J.Res. 68 with 40 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs and 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Armed Services. All points of order against consideration and provisions are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 328.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4540-4550" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4534" label="text as introduced in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 68 and H.R. 2278 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides one hour of debate on H.J.Res. 68 with 40 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs and 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Armed Services. All points of order against consideration and provisions are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4549" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="2011-06-24T12:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="493" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Failed by recorded vote: 123 - 295 (Roll no. 493).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24T12:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="328"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="328"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="67"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="74"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sj" number="20"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sj" number="20"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
Authorizes the President to continue the limited use of U.S. Armed Forces in Libya in support of U.S. security policy interests as part of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) mission to enforce U.N. Security Council Resolution 1973, as requested by the Transitional National Council, the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC), and the Arab League. Terminates such authorization one year after the date of enactment of this joint resolution. States that Congress does not support deploying, establishing, or maintaining the presence of units and members of U.S. Armed Forces on the ground in Libya unless the purpose of the presence is limited to the immediate personal defense of U.S. government officials (including diplomatic representatives) or to rescuing members of NATO forces from imminent danger. Directs the President to consult frequently with Congress regarding U.S. efforts in Libya, including by providing regular briefings and reports. Includes as elements in such briefings and reports: (1) an updated description of U.S. national security interests and policy objectives in Libya; (2) an updated list of U.S. Armed Forces activities in Libya; (3) an updated assessment of the opposition groups in Libya, including potential successor governments; and (4) an updated explanation of the President's legal and constitutional rationale for conducting military operations in Libya consistent with the War Powers Resolution.</summary>
</bill>
