<bill session="110" type="s" number="2330" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Homelessness Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize a pilot program within the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development with the goal of preventing at-risk veterans and veteran families from falling into homelessness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="4161"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2007--Introduced.
Veterans Homelessness Prevention Act - Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish a pilot program to provide assistance to private nonprofit organizations and consumer cooperatives to expand the supply of supportive housing for certain very low-income veteran families. Allows such assistance to be in the form of: (1) a grant for costs of planning a supportive housing project; (2) a capital advance for such project; and (3) project rental assistance. Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) ensure that any housing assistance provided to veterans or veteran families includes a range of specified services tailored to the needs of very low-income veteran families; and (2) provide financial assistance for such services. Requires HUD periodically to establish development cost limitations by market area for various types and sizes of such supportive housing. Establishes a special housing account. Requires the owner of such supportive housing to adopt HUD-approved tenant selection procedures.</summary>
</bill>
