<bill session="112" type="h" number="3791" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require annual disclosures relating to the compensation brackets in which an issuer's minority and women employees reside.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400271"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/18/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to promulgate final rules requiring each securities issuer required to file annual reports to: (1) determine the 5 compensation brackets in which its employees reside (where such brackets contain an equal number of employees and range from the 20% of employees with the lowest compensation to the 20% with the highest compensation), and (2) include in the issuer's annual reports the number of minorities and women employed that fall into each of the compensation brackets. Requires such issuers, for purposes of identifying an employee as a minority or woman under this Act, to rely on self-reporting by the employee.</summary>
</bill>
