<bill session="112" type="s" number="763" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing Teacher Effectiveness, Leaders, Learning, And Results Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STELLAR Student Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the establishment of teacher evaluation programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2273-2274"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2274-2276" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1368"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2011--Introduced.
Securing Teacher Effectiveness, Leaders, Learning, And Results Act or STELLAR Student Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require each state receiving school improvement funds to: (1) define teacher and principal effectiveness and establish performance ratings; (2) demonstrate that it has developed a model teacher and principal evaluation program; (3) demonstrate that each of its local educational agencies (LEAs) has adopted a teacher and principal evaluation program; (4) demonstrate that each LEA is seeking input from teachers and principals in making annual improvements to such program; and (5) review, report on, and assist LEAs in improving such evaluation programs. Requires teacher evaluations to: (1) emphasize student academic growth, (2) include observations of the teacher's classroom performance, (3) rate teachers using at least four performance categories, and (4) provide results that are comparable for all teachers in grade levels and subject areas across the state and within the teacher's LEA. Requires principal evaluations to: (1) emphasize student academic growth; (2) factor in their school's graduation rates; (3) assess the principal's success in recruiting, developing, evaluating, and retaining effective teachers; (4) assess the principal's leadership abilities through observations and other relevant data; (5) factor in student attendance rates; (6) rate principals using at least four performance categories; and (7) provide results that are comparable across all principals within the LEA. Requires states to take steps to ensure that poor and minority children are not taught at higher rates than other children by teachers rated as less than effective. Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a clearinghouse to share best practices relating to teacher and principal evaluation. Requires states and LEAs to report the number and percentage of teachers and principals in each performance rating at: (1) the state, LEA, and school level; and (2) their LEAs and schools that have the highest and lowest poverty rates or the highest and lowest percentages of minority students. Directs the Secretary to recognize each LEA that has innovative, high-quality, and effective teacher or principal evaluation programs that lead to professional development and improved student performance.</summary>
</bill>
