<bill session="109" type="h" number="214" updated="2013-07-19T19:06:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advanced Internet Communications Services Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote deployment of and investment in advanced Internet communications services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2005-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Advanced Internet Communications Services Act of 2005 - Requires an advanced Internet communications service to be considered: (1) an interstate service; and (2) neither a telecommunications service nor an information service for purposes of the Communications Act of 1934. Prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) and States from regulating the rates, charges, terms, or conditions for, entry into, or exit from the provision of advanced Internet communications service, subject to provisions of this Act giving the FCC exclusive authority to regarding such services. Requires the FCC, to the extent technically feasible and economically reasonable, to impose requirements or obligations on advanced Internet communications voice service providers in order to: (1) ensure that appropriate E-911 services are available to users of such services; (2) provide access for persons with disabilities; (3) contribute directly to the universal service fund; and (4) provide for just and reasonable compensation for use of the public switched telephone network. Directs the FCC to ensure that such requirements or obligations apply equally to all advanced Internet communications voice service providers. Prohibits the FCC or any State from regulating the underlying Internet Protocol transmission networks, facilities, or equipment in a manner that results in unequal application of regulations.</summary>
</bill>
