<bill session="110" type="s" number="633" updated="2013-07-19T22:25:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Working Together for Rural Access to Mental Health and Wellness for Children and Seniors Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide assistance to rural schools, hospitals, and communities for the conduct of collaborative efforts to secure a progressive and innovative system to improve access to mental health care for youth, seniors and families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2000-2002, S2080"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2080-2082" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2007--Introduced.
Working Together for Rural Access to Mental Health and Wellness for Children and Seniors Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to enable states to award grants for: (1) operating a mobile van outreach program under which a hospital and elementary or secondary schools provide mental health care services to students in a rural area; and (2) providing telemental health services to persons of all ages in a rural area. Requires the governor of a state to designate a lead agency to: (1) administer the state program under the grant; and (2) develop a state plan for the provision of mental health services in rural areas.</summary>
</bill>
