<bill session="111" type="h" number="919" updated="2013-07-19T23:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Medical Personnel Recruitment and Retention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to enhance the capacity of the Department of Veterans Affairs to recruit and retain nurses and other critical health-care professionals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2009--Introduced.
Veterans' Medical Personnel Recruitment and Retention Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to appoint personnel for health care positions within the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) not specifically listed as authorized categories for appointment, as long as the Secretary provides prior notification to the congressional veterans' committees and the Office of Management and Budget. Requires newly-appointed nurses to serve a probationary period. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) appoint nurse assistants; and (2) waive required pay offsets for federal annuitants reemployed in VA health care positions. Sets the minimum rate of basic pay for appointees to certain positions in the Office of the Under Secretary for Health at the lowest rate of basic pay for a Senior Executive Service position. Allows for the payment of: (1) comparability pay of up to $100,000 annually for Office positions which are not physicians or dentists; and (2) special incentive pay of up to $40,000 annually to a VHA pharmacist executive. Removes or waives certain pay restrictions for: (1) physicians or dentists occupying administrative or executive leadership positions; (2) nurses; and (3) certified registered nurse anesthetists. Revises locality pay scale computations. Increases from $25,000 to $100,000 the special pay for nurse executives. Makes part-time nurses eligible for additional nurse pay. Provides limitations on overtime duty, weekend duty, and alternative work schedules for nurses, with exceptions for emergency situations. Reinstates the VA's health professionals educational assistance scholarship program, and increases maximum assistance amounts. Authorizes the Secretary to provide an educational loan repayment program for clinical researchers from disadvantaged backgrounds.</summary>
</bill>
