<bill session="110" type="s" number="562" updated="2013-07-19T22:25:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Child Left Behind Flexibility and Improvements Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for flexibility and improvements in elementary and secondary education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1904-1905"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27">
      <text>Star Print ordered on S. 562.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2007--Introduced.
No Child Left Behind Flexibility and Improvements Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to revise requirements relating to annual yearly progress (AYP) of students and schools, statewide and local accountability systems, special education, limited English proficiency students, funding levels and academic assessment deferrals, highly qualified teachers, and reading activities. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to modify an AYP timeline. Allows states to use: (1) additional types of statewide models and systems for measuring all students' progress; and (2) alternative assessments, designated by their individualized education program plan teams, for students with disabilities. Gives states an option to include as limited English proficiency students, until they complete secondary school, those formerly in such subgroup who have subsequently acquired English proficiency. Permits use of local assessments in measuring AYP.Increases the levels of ESEA funding which must be reached before states are not allowed certain deferrals of academic assessments. Revises requirements relating to AYP by group and subgroup. Adds options for deeming teachers of multiple academic subjects as highly qualified, and for general social studies certification.Authorizes use of reading activities subgrants for individual or small-group instruction, as well as for class-wide instruction.</summary>
</bill>
