<bill session="111" type="s" number="1759" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Transfer Facilitation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Water Transfer Facilitation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize certain transfers of water in the Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10218-10220, S10220-10221"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10220" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-339.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-144.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="294">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 294.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3750"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Water Transfer Facilitation Act of 2009 - Provides that the following voluntary water transfers shall be considered to meet conditions specified for authorized transfers of Central Valley Project (CVP) water under the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992: (1) a transfer of irrigation water among CVP contractors from the Friant, San Felipe, West San Joaquin, and Delta divisions; and (2) a transfer from a long-term Friant Division water service or repayment contractor to a temporary or prior temporary water service contractor within the place of use in existence on the date of the transfer, as identified in the Bureau of Reclamation water rights permits for the Friant Division. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the Commissioner of Reclamation, to initiate and complete on an expedited basis programmatic documentation to facilitate voluntary water transfers within the CVP. Directs the Commissioner to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that: (1) describes the status of efforts to help facilitate and improve the water transfers under this Act; (2) evaluates potential effects of this Act on federal programs, Indian tribes, CVP operations, the environment, groundwater aquifers, refuges, and communities; and (3) provides recommendations on ways to facilitate and improve the process for water transfers within the CVP and water transfers between the CVP and other water projects in California. Requires the Commissioner to update the report by the end of the water year in which the report is submitted and each of the four water years thereafter.</summary>
</bill>
