<bill session="113" type="h" number="404" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Straw Purchaser Penalty Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance criminal penalties for straw purchasers of firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Straw Purchaser Penalty Enhancement Act - Amends the federal criminal code to provide for an additional sentence of two years' imprisonment for violating the prohibitions against making false statements or misrepresenting identification regarding the acquisition of a firearm or ammunition: (1) knowing that the violation will further the transfer of two or more firearms to a person prohibited by law from shipping, transporting, possessing, or receiving a firearm; and (2) with the intent to conceal such person's identity from the transferor. Prohibits the court from: (1) placing any person convicted of such violation on probation; and (2) reducing a term of imprisonment for such a violation so as to compensate for, or otherwise take into account, a term of imprisonment imposed or to be imposed for a separate such violation. Prohibits a term of imprisonment imposed under this Act from running concurrently with a term imposed on the person under any other legal provision, except that a term imposed may, in the court's discretion, run concurrently with another term imposed by the court at the same time for a separate such violation, subject to applicable guidelines and policy statements issued by the United States Sentencing Commission. Requires the court to specify in its statement of the reasons for imposing a sentence for such a violation the factors that require any sentence below the statutory minimum. Directs the Attorney General to issue regulations requiring any form required to be completed by the purchaser of a firearm from a licensed firearms dealer to include a notice of the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
