<bill session="113" type="h" number="1380" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Congressionally Mandated Reports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Public Printer to establish and maintain a website accessible to the public that allows the public to obtain electronic copies of all congressionally mandated reports in one place, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412438" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412537" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2013-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Access to Congressionally Mandated Reports Act - Requires the Public Printer to establish and maintain a website accessible by the public for obtaining electronic copies of all congressionally mandated reports in one place. Requires each federal agency to provide the Public Printer with electronic copies of its congressionally mandated reports for publication on the website. Prohibits an agency head from changing or removing a report published on the website, except for technical changes, without the express, written consent of the chairman of each congressional committee to which the report is submitted. Exempts information or records that are exempt from public disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) from publication on the website. Requires each agency head to redact from congressionally mandated reports any information that may not be publicly released under FOIA before submission for publication on the website.</summary>
</bill>
