<bill session="112" type="hr" number="32" updated="2013-07-20T01:03:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-12T17:58:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-12T17:58:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to the tragic shooting in Tucson, Arizona, on January 8, 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T10:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T10:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a special order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H144-160" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T10:09:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order the House proceeded with 6 hours of debate on H.Res. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T12:42:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that further proceedings on H.Res. 32 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T13:56:00-05:00">
      <text>The Chair announced that pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, proceedings would resume on H. Res. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T13:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H160-200" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T13:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Chair announced that when proceedings were postponed earlier, 4 hours and 6 minutes of debate remained on the resolution. The House proceeded with further debate on H. Res. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H200" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-01-12T17:58:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H144" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-01-12T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2011--Passed House without amendment.
Condemns in the strongest possible terms the horrific attack that occurred at the "Congress on your Corner" event hosted by Representative Gabrielle Giffords in Tucson, Arizona, on January 8, 2011. Offers heartfelt condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of those killed in that attack. Expresses hope for the rapid and complete recovery of those wounded in the shooting. Honors the memory of Christina Taylor Green, Dorothy Morris, John Roll, Phyllis Schneck, Dorwan Stoddard, and Gabriel Zimmerman. Applauds the bravery and quick thinking exhibited by those who prevented the gunman from taking more lives and helped to save those who had been wounded. Recognizes the service of the first responders who raced to the scene and the health care professionals who tended to the victims once they reached the hospital and whose service and skill saved lives. Reaffirms the bedrock principle of American democracy and representative government, memorialized in the First Amendment and which Representative Giffords herself read in the Hall of the House of Representatives on January 6, 2011, of "the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances." Stands firm in the belief in a democracy in which all can participate and in which intimidation and threats of violence cannot silence the voices of any American. Honors the service and leadership of Representative Giffords, a distinguished Member of the House of Representatives, as she courageously fights to recover. States that when the House adjourns on January 12, 2011, it does so out of respect to the victims of this attack.</summary>
</bill>
