<bill session="113" type="h" number="798" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Investment Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to strengthen the United States workforce investment system through innovation in, and alignment and improvement of, employment, training, and education programs, and to promote national economic growth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412543" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2013-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2560"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2013--Introduced.
Workforce Investment Act of 2013 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (WIA) to revise requirements and reauthorize appropriations for: (1) WIA title I, workforce investment systems for job training and employment services; and (2) WIA title II, adult education and family literacy education programs. Revises member composition of state and local workforce investment boards to require at least 20% of the board be composed of representatives of the workforce within the state. Revises requirements for a five-year state worker investment plan. Revises requirements for the state unified plan for adult education and literacy programs. Revises requirements for: (1) local workforce investment areas, boards, and plans; (2) one-stop delivery systems; and (3) the allotment of federal funds among states for statewide youth (including disadvantaged youth) activities and statewide workforce investment activities, Native American workforce investment programs, and adult and dislocated worker employment and training activities. Defines "core programs" to mean: (1) youth workforce investment activities and adult and dislocated worker employment and training activities, (2) adult education and literacy activities, (3) employment services, and (4) vocational rehabilitation services. Establishes unified state and local performance accountability measures for the core programs. Directs the Secretary of Labor to allocate federal funds for the costs of infrastructure associated with one-stop centers for job training and employment services. Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for the Job Corps program. Prescribes a special rule to make Armed Force veterans eligible for the Job Corps if certain requirements are met. Directs the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education to establish jointly a demonstration College Corps project to provide certain at-risk youth intensive education and skills training to prepare them for college and for high-skilled employment. Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish annually performance indicators for Job Corps centers and for recruitment and career transition service providers serving the Job Corps program. Revises requirements for the Native American, migrant and seasonal farm worker, and veterans' workforce investment programs. Requires the establishment of performance accountability measures for such programs. Repeals the youth opportunity grant program. Replaces demonstration, pilot, multiservice, research, and multistate work investment projects with innovation work investment projects. Subjects such projects to certain performance accountability measures. Directs the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education to provide for the competitive award of: (1) transition grants to states to assist them in making the transition to meeting the requirements of this Act; (2) workforce innovation and best practices grants to state partnerships or regional entities for workforce investment projects to target services to low-income individuals, low-skill individuals, long-term unemployed, and other populations with barriers to employment; and (3) youth innovation and best practices grants to states or local boards and other specified entities for innovative strategies and activities to improve education and employment outcomes for eligible youth. Converts the national emergency grants program into a national dislocated worker grants program. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award national dislocated worker grants to provide disaster relief employment in a disaster area of a state. Revises and reauthorizes appropriations for the YouthBuild program. Reauthorizes appropriations for the Native American, migrant and seasonal farm worker, and veterans' workforce investment programs. Establishes an Office of Disability Employment Policy within the Department of Labor. Directs the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to: (1) institutions of higher education for educational or career training programs for workers; (2) state or local organizations in partnership with community colleges and other training providers for pay-for-performance projects and pay-for-success job training projects; (3) state or local governments to provide job training or recruiting activities necessary to provide skilled workers for businesses that are considering relocating back to the United States; and (4) institutions of higher education in partnership with local or regional economic development entities to provide training in starting a small business and entrepreneurship. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to evaluate the efficiency and effectiveness of federally-funded job training programs to provide job training services to eligible individuals, particularly individuals with barriers to employment. Directs the Secretary of Labor to award grants to states for integrated English literacy and civics education. Amends the Wagner-Peyser Act to authorize use of a state's allotment of public employment services funds to provide unemployment insurance claimants and other unemployed individuals with referrals to, and application assistance for, training and education resources and programs, including student assistance under Federal Pell Grants of the Higher Education Act of 1965, educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill and the Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance, state student higher education assistance, and training and education programs under WIA titles I and II, and title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973. Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish a pilot program of competitive grants to state employment agencies to carry out pilot projects that enhance the professional development and the provision of public employment services by agency staff. Replaces the nationwide employment statistics system, which the Secretary of Labor is required to oversee, with a nationwide labor market information system. Establishes the Workforce Information Advisory Council. Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to transfer the Rehabilitation Services Administration from the Office of the Secretary of Education and reestablish it in the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitation Services. Revises requirements for: (1) state plans for vocational rehabilitation services to individuals with disabilities, (2) eligibility for vocational rehabilitation assistance and individualized plans for employment for disabled individuals, (3) monitoring and review of vocational rehabilitation programs, and (4) state allotments for such programs. Requires: (1) states to make certain funds available to designated state units for pre-employment transition services for students with disabilities who are transitioning to employment from education or training, and (2) each local office of a state unit to designate at least one Local Pre-Employment Transition Coordinator for students with disabilities. Directs the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education to each designate a National Pre-Employment Transition Coordinator for Students with Disabilities. Revises American Indian vocational rehabilitation services grant program eligibility requirements to permit grants to be renewed for an additional 5-years, provided certain conditions are met. Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for the National Institute on Disability and Rehabilitation Research. Reauthorizes appropriations for: (1) vocational rehabilitation services grants to individuals with disabilities who are migrant or seasonal farmworkers, (2) recreational programs for individuals with disabilities, (3) the National Council on Disability, (4) the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board, and (5) employment opportunities for individuals with disabilities. Authorizes appropriations to assist states in developing collaborative programs to provide supported employment services for individuals (including youth) with the most significant disabilities to enable them to achieve supported employment in competitive integrated employment. Establishes within the Department of Education an Independent Living Administration (ILA), independent of the Rehabilitation Services Administration. Revises requirements for a state plan for state independent living services for individuals with significant disabilities, including through establishment of additional centers for independent living or focused outreach to serve underserved populations. Directs the ILA Director (currently, the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration) to make allotments to states for independent living services to individuals with significant disabilities. Revises the composition and functions of State Independent Living Councils. Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for: (1) the centers for independent living grant program, and (2) independent living services for older individuals who are blind grant program. Directs the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Labor and in coordination with the Commissioners of the Rehabilitation Services Administration, of Social Security, and of the Internal Revenue Service, as well as the heads of other relevant federal agencies, to carry out campaigns to educate employers and the general public on the benefits of hiring individuals with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
