<bill session="109" type="h" number="6263" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400372" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Amends the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988 to revise the appropriate steps the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission is required to take in implementing its Cultural Heritage and Corridor Management Plan for the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor. Requires the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor, Incorporated to develop a Strategic Plan for the Corridor that takes into account the findings and recommendations of a specified study conducted by the National Park Service Conservation Study Institute. Requires the plan to compliment the Corridor's management plan. Makes the Corporation the management entity for the Corridor, assuming the Commission's duties in implementing the management action plan. Authorizes the Corporation to use federal funds to make grants to and enter into cooperative agreements with Pennsylvania, local governments, nonprofit corporations, and individuals. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of sites and associated landscape features within the Corridor, including resources of the greater anthracite region of Pennsylvania covered by other designated national heritage areas, that contribute to the understanding of the Corridor's national siginificance. Requires the Secretary, in coordination with the Corporation, to evaluate and report to specified congressional committees on the possibility of: (1) designating one or more sites or landscape features as a unit of the National Park System; and (2) coordinating and complementing actions by the Corporation, Pennsylvania, local governments, and nonprofit agencies in the preservation and interpretation of significant resources within the Corridor and greater anthracite region. Extends the Corporation, in place of the Commission, through November 18, 2019.</summary>
</bill>
