<bill session="112" type="h" number="1829" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the eradication and control of nutria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2011-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2011-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="899"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3525"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2011--Introduced.
Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2011 - Amends the Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2003 to revise the nutria eradication program by authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to provide financial assistance to Delaware, Louisiana, Maryland, North Carolina, Oregon, Virginia, and Washington (currently only to Maryland and Louisiana). Establishes the goals of such Program as: (1) eradicating nutria in Maryland; (2) eradicating or controlling nutria in Louisiana, Delaware, North Carolina, Oregon, Virginia, and Washington; and (3) restoring wetlands damaged by nutria. Requires that the Maryland program consist of management, research, and public education activities carried out in accordance with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service's document entitled "Eradication Strategies for Nutria in the Chesapeake and Delaware Bay Watersheds" dated March 2002 and updated in March 2009. Authorizes appropriations for FY2012-FY2016. Requires the Secretary and the National Invasive Species Council to develop long-term nutria control or eradication programs to: (1) significantly reduce and restore nutria damaged wetlands in Delaware, Oregon, North Carolina, Virginia, and Washington; and (2) promote voluntary, public-private partnerships to eradicate or control nutria and restore nutria-damaged wetlands in such states.</summary>
</bill>
