<bill session="111" type="s" number="3473" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to authorize advances from Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund for the Deepwater Horizon oil spill.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-06-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4785" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4785" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4749" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09T20:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Oberstar moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4336-4342" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3473.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10T11:24:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4365-4366" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-06-10T14:47:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="354" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 0, 1 Present (Roll no. 354).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4336" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10T14:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-06-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-06-15" type="public" number="111-191">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-191.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5499"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2010--Public Law.
Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to exempt advances to the Coast Guard in connection with the explosion on, and sinking of, the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon from the requirement that amounts in the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund shall be available only as provided in annual appropriations. Limits such advances to a maximum of $100 million each, with the total amount for all advances subject to limits under existing law (i.e., not to exceed $1 billion for any single incident and $500 million for natural resource damage assessments and claims for any single incident, provided that, except in the case of payments of removal costs, an advance may be made only if the amount in the Fund after such advance will not be less than $30 million). Requires the Coast Guard to notify Congress of the amount advanced and the facts and circumstances necessitating the advance within seven days of the advance. Requires the budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go-Act of 2010, to be determined by reference to the latest statement titled "Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation" for this Act submitted by the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</summary>
</bill>
