<bill session="110" type="s" number="1831" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Private Student Loan Disclosure Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act, to improve disclosures for private student loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2007--Introduced.
Private Student Loan Disclosure Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to subject private education loans to its consumer credit disclosure requirements. Sets forth the private student loan terms and conditions which lenders must clearly and conspicuously disclose to borrowers in any application or solicitation for such a loan and contemporaneously with the approval of a private student loan application. Gives private student loan borrowers 30 days after the loan is approved and the required loan disclosure information is received to accept and consummate the loan transaction. Subjects lenders to civil liability for violating such requirements. Requires civil actions to be brought within one year after the first monthly payment on the loan becomes due after the borrower leaves school, unless full repayment begins earlier. Requires private student loan providers, when making the required loan disclosures, to inform borrowers of their possible eligibility for federal educational loans. Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to develop and test a student borrower disclosure statement that encourages students to use federal educational loans and discloses their average interest rate and the fact that they are less costly than private education loans.</summary>
</bill>
