<bill session="111" type="h" number="4799" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Retraining a New Health Care Workforce Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a strategic plan to retrain displaced workers to become health care professionals serving areas with a shortage of such professionals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412229"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2010--Introduced.
Retraining a New Health Care Workforce Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and submit to Congress within nine months a strategic plan to retrain displaced workers to become health care professionals serving areas with a shortage of the type professionals involved. Requires the plan to include: (1) an overview of national shortages in health care professions; (2) an assessment of how existing federal health care workforce programs may be used to retrain displaced workers; and (3) recommendations for legislative and administrative changes for making such programs more effective. Requires the Secretary to establish a grant program for states to assist displaced workers to become state-licensed or certified health care professionals serving areas with a shortage of health care professionals.</summary>
</bill>
