<bill session="109" type="h" number="3134" updated="2013-07-19T19:32:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Real Property Disposal Pilot Program and Management Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 40, United States Code, to require the Federal Real Property Council to carry out a pilot program for the expeditious disposal of underutilized Federal real property, and to improve the economy and efficiency of Federal real property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2005-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
Federal Real Property Disposal Pilot Program and Management Improvement Act of 2005 - Requires the Federal Real Property Council (established by this Act) to conduct a Federal Real Property Disposal Pilot Program under which excess property, surplus property, or underutilized real property shall be disposed of in accordance with this Act. Requires specified agencies to develop and implement an agency asset management planning process. Requires the Federal Real Property Council to develop guidance for, and facilitate the success of, each agency's asset management plan. Provides for the Federal Real Property Council to serve as a clearinghouse for executive agencies for best practices in evaluating progress in the implementation of real property enhancements. Directs the Administrator of General Services to establish a database of all real property under the custody and control of all executive agencies, other than real property excluded for national security reasons. Directs the heads of executive agencies to identify all underutilized properties under that agency's custody and control and submit a list describing the underutilized properties to the Federal Real Property Council.</summary>
</bill>
