<bill session="109" type="h" number="1629" updated="2013-07-19T19:18:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Budget Autonomy Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to provide the District of Columbia with autonomy over its budgets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2005-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Appropriations, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="City councils"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Item veto"/>
    <term name="Local budgets"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Municipal home rule"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
District of Columbia Budget Autonomy Act of 2005 - Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to provide that the District of Columbia budget passed by the Council of the District of Columbia shall be enacted without referral to the President or approval by the Congress, unless it is the budget for a fiscal year which is a control year. Prohibits the Mayor of the District during a control year from transmitting the budget, or amendments or supplements thereto, to the President until the completion of the budget procedures contained in this Act and the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995. Prohibits obligations or expenditures by District government officers and employees without the Council's approval and in the case of a control year, congressional approval. Allows the Council to reenact provisions of any line-item veto by the Mayor in a budget Act without submitting such veto to the President, unless such item or provision is contained in a budget act for a control year. Permits hiring of full or part-time District government employees and their transfer among programs only if such position is authorized by an Act of the Council or, in the case of a control year, an Act of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
