<bill session="111" type="h" number="2289" updated="2013-07-19T23:32:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Juvenile Justice Accountability and Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a meaningful opportunity for parole or similar release for child offenders sentenced to life in prison, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400364"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2009-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2009--Introduced.
Juvenile Justice Accountability and Improvement Act of 2009 - Requires states to: (1) enact laws and adopt policies to grant child offenders who are serving a life sentence a meaningful opportunity for parole or supervised release at least once during their first 15 years of incarceration and at least once every three years thereafter; and (2) provide notice of such laws and policies to the public and to victims of child offenders. Defines "child offender who is serving a life sentence" as an individual who is convicted of a criminal offense before attaining the age of 18 and sentenced to a term of imprisonment for life or a term exceeding 15 years. Requires the Attorney General to: (1) establish and implement a system of early release for each child offender who is under a life sentence in a federal prison; and (2) award grants to states to improve legal representation and other services for child defendants charged with an offense carrying a possible sentence of life in prison.</summary>
</bill>
