<bill session="109" type="h" number="6332" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sandra Day O'Connor and William H. Rehnquist Law Centers Establishment Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Sandra Day O'Connor Center on Constitutional Law at Stanford Law School and to establish the William H. Rehnquist Center on Constitutional Structures of Government at the University of Arizona James E. Rogers School of Law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2006-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2006--Introduced.
Sandra Day O'Connor and William H. Rehnquist Law Centers Establishment Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Attorney General to provide a grant to: (1) Stanford Law School to establish the Sandra Day O'Connor Center on Constitutional Law; and (2) the University of Arizona James E. Rogers School of Law to establish the William H. Rehnquist Center on Constitutional Structures of Government. Requires such Law Schools to provide specified nonfederal contributions toward the establishment of such Law Centers.</summary>
</bill>
