<bill session="111" type="h" number="3991" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Influenza Containment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that American workers are able to follow, without financial harm, the recommendations of their employer and public health authorities to stay home when they have symptoms of a contagious disease that may put co-workers, customers, or the public at risk.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2009--Introduced.
Emergency Influenza Containment Act - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to ensure that American workers are allowed to follow, without financial harm, employer and public health authority recommendations to stay home when they have symptoms of a contagious disease that may put co-workers, customers, or the public at risk. Requires an employer to provide paid sick leave to an employee for each workday, or portion of workday, that the employer directs the employee to leave work, or not come in to work, because the employee has symptoms of a contagious illness, or has been in close contact with an individual who has such symptoms. Limits paid sick leave up to a maximum of 5 days per 12-month period. Makes it unlawful for an employer to discharge, discipline, or otherwise discriminate against an employee who: (1) complies with this Act; or (2) has filed a complaint or instituted a proceeding under this Act, or has testified or is about to testify in such a proceeding. Subjects an employer to certain penalties for unpaid sick leave to, or unlawful termination of, an employee.</summary>
</bill>
