<bill session="110" type="h" number="717" updated="2013-07-19T21:10:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community College Partnership Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage partnerships between community colleges and four-year colleges and universities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="596"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College entrance requirements"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student enrollment"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2007--Introduced.
Community College Partnership Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a Community College Opportunity program to help students at community or technical colleges transfer to four-year institutions and complete bachelor's degrees. Directs the Secretary of Education to award program grants to eligible partnerships that include one or more community or technical colleges that award associate's degrees and one or more institutions of higher education (IHEs) that offer a baccalaureate or postbaccalaureate degree not awarded by the partner colleges. Authorizes the inclusion of a state agency overseeing or coordinating IHEs. Requires such grants to be used for: (1) the development of policies and programs that expand opportunities for community or technical college students to earn bachelor's degrees, including those that promote the transfer of academic credits between institutions and expand articulation and guaranteed transfer agreements between IHEs; (2) support services to students participating in the program, including tutoring, mentoring, academic and personal counseling, and transition facilitation; (3) academic program enhancements at the community or technical college that increase program quality and the number of student participants in the program offered in cooperation with a baccalaureate degree-granting institution; and (4) programs to identify barriers that inhibit student transfers.</summary>
</bill>
