<bill session="111" type="h" number="1796" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-28T12:56:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-28T12:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Residential Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to require residential carbon monoxide detectors to meet the applicable ANSI/UL standard by treating that standard as a consumer product safety rule, to encourage States to require the installation of such detectors in homes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E814-815"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 111-573.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-27T20:45:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="330">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 330.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sarbanes moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6190-6192" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1796.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-28T12:56:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6190-6191" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1216"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2010--Passed House amended.
Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act (the Act) to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to publish the American National Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms (American National Standard ANSI/UL 2034) and the American National Standard for Gas and Vapor Detectors and Sensors (ANSI/UL 2075) as mandatory consumer product safety standards. Requires the Underwriters Laboratories to notify the CPSC when either such standard is revised and to incorporate the revision in the consumer product safety rule, unless the CPSC determines that such revision does not carry out the purposes of this Act. Allows the CPSC, at any time subsequent to publication of such consumer product safety standards, to initiate a rulemaking to amend either standard to include any provision determined necessary to ensure the safe and effective operation of carbon monoxide alarms. Treats the national standards published by the CPSC pursuant to this Act, including any revision, as consumer product safety rules for purposes of enforcement under the Act. Requires the CPSC to evaluate whether requiring a language or languages in addition to English would improve the effectiveness of the label required to warn consumers of carbon monoxide hazards. Requires the CPSC to establish a grant program to provide assistance to eligible states and local governments to carry out carbon monoxide prevention activities, including activities for: (1) the purchase and installation of approved carbon monoxide alarms in the dwelling units of low-income families or elderly persons, facilities that commonly serve children or the elderly, or student dwelling units owned by public universities; (2) training state or local fire officials in the proper enforcement of state or local laws concerning such alarms and their installation; and (3) educating the public about the risk associated with carbon monoxide as a poison and the importance of proper carbon monoxide alarm use. Sets limitations on the use of grant funds for: (1) administrative costs not directly related to such training of state and local fire officials; and (2) the costs of the activities of such public outreach. Gives priority to applications from states or local governments that: (1) require the installation of approved carbon monoxide alarms in existing dwelling units within which a fuel-burning appliance, apparatus, or device is installed or which has an attached garage; (2) propose to serve vulnerable populations; and (3) have greater than average losses of life from carbon monixide poisoning in the home. Authorizes appropriations through FY2015 to the CPSC to carry out this Act. Requires the CPSC to report on the implementation of the grant program authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
