<bill session="113" type="s" number="307" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close Big Oil Tax Loopholes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the Federal budget deficit by closing big oil tax loopholes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2956"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="277"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="278"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Close Big Oil Tax Loopholes Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to limit or repeal certain tax benefits for major integrated oil companies (defined as companies with annual gross receipts over $1 billion and an average daily worldwide production of crude oil of at least 500,000 barrels or certain successors in interest of such companies), including: (1) the foreign tax credit for companies that are dual capacity taxpayers; (2) the tax deduction for income attributable to the production, refining, processing, transportation, or distribution of oil, natural gas, or primary products thereof; (3) the tax deduction for intangible drilling and development costs; (4) the percentage depletion allowance for oil and gas wells; and (5) the tax deduction for qualified tertiary injectant expenses. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal royalty relief (suspension of royalties) for: (1) natural gas production from deep wells in shallow waters of the Gulf of Mexico; and (2) deep water oil and gas production in the Western and Central Planning Area of the Gulf (including the portion of the Eastern Planning Area encompassing whole lease blocks lying west of 87 degrees, 30 minutes west longitude). Dedicates any increased revenue generated by this Act to the reduction of a federal budget deficit or the federal debt. Provides for compliance of the budgetary effects of this Act with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
