<bill session="109" type="s" number="3584" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 41 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the establishment and authorization of funding for certain training programs for supervisors of Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6579"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6579-6580" label="text of measure as introduced in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2006--Introduced.
Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2006 - Revises provisions relating to specific training programs for managers of federal agencies. Specifies that the head of each federal agency shall establish: (1) a program to provide training to supervisors on prohibited personnel practices; and (2) a program under which experienced supervisors mentor new supervisors. Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to issue guidance to federal agencies on standards supervisors are expected to meet in order to effectively manage, and be accountable for managing, the performance of employees. Requires each agency to: (1) develop standards to assess the performance of each supervisor and, in developing such standards, to consider such guidance developed by OPM and any other qualifications or factors determined by the agency; (2) assess the overall capacity of the supervisors in the agency to meet such guidance; and (3) develop and implement a supervisor training program to strengthen issues identified during such assessment. Instructs each agency, every year, or on any basis requested by the Director of OPM, to submit a report to OPM on the progress of such agency in implementing the requirements specified above with respect to developing those standards.</summary>
</bill>
