<bill session="110" type="h" number="6803" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Real Estate Assessment Center Inspection Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve inspections of public housing and federally assisted multifamily housing conducted by the Real Estate Assessment Center of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Real Estate Assessment Center Inspection Improvement Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to take necessary actions to improve the activities of the Real Estate Assessment Center of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) for physical assessment and inspection of public housing and federally assisted multifamily housing, including developing a detailed process to improve planning and preparation for such inspections.Requires the Secretary to: (1) make the three-day Real Estate Assessment Center physical inspection training for non-inspectors, held in Washington, DC, available to personnel of all public housing agencies throughout the nation, by use of the Web or other electronic means; and (2) convene an advisory committee to review and make recommendations for revising, as necessary, the Center's scoring system.</summary>
</bill>
