<bill session="112" type="h" number="748" updated="2013-07-20T01:16:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from authorizing the use of gasoline containing greater than 10 percent ethanol in certain vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2011-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2011-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2011-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2011-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2011--Introduced.
Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from authorizing or allowing the introduction into commerce of gasoline that contains greater than 10-volume-percent ethanol for use in light-duty motor vehicles, including by granting a waiver for new fuels and fuel additives from the Clean Air Act's fuel standards. Includes within the definition of "light-duty motor vehicles" light-duty vehicles, light-duty trucks, and medium-duty passenger vehicles. Repeals any waiver granted under such Act prior to this Act's enactment that allows for the introduction into commerce of gasoline that contains greater than 10-volume-percent ethanol for use in such vehicles, including: (1) the "Partial Grant and Partial Denial of Clean Air Act Waiver Application Submitted by Growth Energy To Increase the Allowable Ethanol Content of Gasoline to 15 Percent; Decision of the Administrator" published on November 4, 2010, and (2) the "Partial Grant of Clean Air Act Waiver Application Submitted by Growth Energy To Increase the Allowable Ethanol Content of Gasoline to 15 Percent; Decision of the Administrator" published on January 26, 2011.</summary>
</bill>
