<bill session="112" type="h" number="5545" updated="2013-07-20T01:57:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Berryessa Snow Mountain National Conservation Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Conservation Area in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="3375"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2012--Introduced.
Berryessa Snow Mountain National Conservation Area Act - Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Conservation Area, to comprise approximately 319,300 acres of federal land within Napa, Lake, Mendocino, and Yolo Counties in California. States that the purpose of the Conservation Area is the conservation, protection, and enhancement of the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the lands included in the Area for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations. Continues to provide private landowners with adequate access to inholdings in the Conservation Area. Allows only those uses of the Conservation Area that would further the purposes for which it is established. Requires a comprehensive plan for the protection and management of the federal lands included within the Conservation Area. Requires such plan to: (1) assess the impacts of climate change, (2) include a comprehensive weed management strategy, and (3) include a plan to address the public safety and environmental clean-up issues associated with illegal marijuana production. Permits grazing in the Conservation Area: (1) where established before this Act's enactment, or (2) through issuing annual permits for non-commercial grazing to control noxious weeds. Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Conservation Area Advisory Council to advise with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan. Requires the appointment of one Council member to represent Native American Tribes.</summary>
</bill>
