<bill session="112" type="h" number="6070" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study to determine the impact on the United States of the policy announced by the Secretary of Homeland Security on June 15, 2012, concerning the exercise of prosecutorial discretion with respect to individuals who came to the United States illegally as children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2012-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study to determine the impact on the United States of the policy set forth in the memorandum dated June 15, 2012, from the Secretary of Homeland Security regarding exercising prosecutorial discretion with respect to individuals who came to the United States illegally as children. Requires the study to examine the impact on: (1) national security, including how much implementing this policy will cost the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) in terms of manpower and other costs; (2) fraud, including how impacted federal agencies will address an increase in fraudulent documents; (3) U.S. workers, including the effectiveness of programs under the Social Security Act (such as Medicare), the national unemployment rate and unemployment compensation, and the implementation of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act; and (4) the U.S. economy, including federal Pell grants, the supplemental nutrition assistance program, college admissions and scholarships, and federal work-study programs. Directs the Secretary to refrain from implementing such policy until after the Comptroller General has reported to Congress on the results of such study.</summary>
</bill>
