<bill session="109" type="h" number="3672" updated="2013-07-19T19:36:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">TANF Programs Extension bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TANF Emergency Response and Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">TANF Emergency Response and Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">TANF Emergency Response and Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">TANF Emergency Response and Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to families affected by Hurricane Katrina, through the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2005-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7766-7773" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3672.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H.R. 3672.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-09-08T13:44:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7766-7767" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-09-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10149-10150" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2005-09-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-09-21" type="public" number="109-68">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-68.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2005--Public Law.
TANF Emergency Response and Recovery Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to pay each state family assistance grant payable for the first quarter of FY2006, as soon as practicable after the enactment of this Act.Provides that activities authorized by part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act shall continue through December 31, 2005, in the manner authorized for FY2005. Makes necessary appropriations for such purpose. Provides that grants and payments may be made pursuant to this authority through the first quarter of FY2006 at the same level as provided through the first quarter of 2005. Extends the National Random Sample Study of Child Welfare and Child Welfare Waiver Authority through December 31, 2005. (Sec. 3) Provides that, between the enactment of this Act and August 31, 2006, a state shall be considered a needy state for purposes of the TANF Contingency Fund for State Welfare Programs if: (1) cash benefits under the state TANF program have been provided on a short-term, nonrecurring basis to a family which has resided in another state that includes an area for which a major disaster has been declared as a result of Hurricane Katrina, and has traveled (not necessarily directly) to the state from such other state as a result of the hurricane; and (2) the state has determined that the family is not receiving cash benefits from any program funded under part A of any other state. Declares that no state match is required for such state payments. (Sec. 4) Provides that between the enactment of this Act and the end of FY2006: (1) the states of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama shall be considered eligible for federal loans for State Welfare Programs; and (2) the cumulative dollar amount of all loans made to such a state by reason of this Act shall not exceed 20% of the state family assistance grant payable to the state for FY2006. Prohibits the imposition of a penalty against Louisiana, Mississippi, or Alabama for failure to repay such a loan or make any interest payment on it. (Sec. 5) Authorizes a state or tribe to use a grant made under the TANF program for any fiscal year to provide, without fiscal year limitation, any benefit or service that may be provided under the state or tribal TANF program to support needy families affected by Hurricane Katrina. (Sec. 6) Declares that benefits provided on a short-term, nonrecurring basis under a state TANF program, between the enactment of this Act and the end of FY2006, to meet a subsistence need of a family resulting from Hurricane Katrina shall not be considered assistance for purposes of mandatory work requirements and the five-year limit on assistance. (Sec. 7) Prohibits the Secretary from imposing a penalty on Louisiana, Mississippi, or Alabama for failure to comply with any provision of the TANF program between the enactment of this Act and the end of FY2006, if the failure resulted from Hurricane Katrina or reasonable conduct of the state in addressing needs of Hurricane Katrina victims. (Sec. 8) Designates each amount provided in this Act (other than in Sec. 2) as an emergency requirement exempt from the budget enforcement requirements of H.Con. Res. 95 (109th Congress).</summary>
</bill>
