<bill session="113" type="h" number="2499" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Parity for Health Plan Beneficiaries Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the exclusion from gross income for employer-provided health coverage for employees' spouses and dependent children to coverage provided to other eligible designated beneficiaries of employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="728"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Introduced.
Tax Parity for Health Plan Beneficiaries Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) exclude from an employee's gross income employer-provided accident and health plan benefits extended to a domestic partner or non-dependent, non-spouse beneficiary eligible to receive such benefits under an employer plan (i.e., "eligible beneficiary"); (2) exempt such benefits paid to eligible beneficiaries from otherwise applicable employment and unemployment taxes; (3) allow self-employed individuals a tax deduction for the health insurance costs of their eligible beneficiaries; (4) allow tax-exempt voluntary employees' beneficiary associations to provide sick and accident benefits to the domestic partners and non-dependent, non-spouse beneficiaries of their members; (5) allow reimbursement of the medical expenses of an eligible beneficiary from a health savings account (HSA); and (6) extend tax-exempt medical benefits to the eligible beneficiaries of retired employees Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to provide guidance relating to reimbursements from a flexible spending arrangement and a health reimbursement arrangement attributable to an eligible beneficiary as defined by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
