<bill session="111" type="s" number="562" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prepaid Calling Card Consumer Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require accurate and reasonable disclosure of the terms and conditions of prepaid telephone calling cards and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2967-2968"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2968-2970" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3993"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2009--Introduced.
Prepaid Calling Card Consumer Protection Act of 2009 - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to require every prepaid telephone calling service provider and prepaid telephone calling card distributor to disclose certain information, including: (1) the number of calling units or minutes of domestic interstate calls provided or the dollar value and the domestic interstate rate per minute; (2) the calling unit or per minute rates for each served international preferred destination; (3) the applicable per minute rates for each served international destination; (4) other material terms and conditions, including regarding fees, policies on refunds, recharges, decrements, and expiration, and time imitations; and (5) a toll-free customer service number and hours. Makes it unlawful to: (1) deduct anything but the per minute rate and disclosed fees; (2) provide fewer minutes or charge a higher per minute rate than promoted or advertised; (3) provide fewer minutes than the number of minutes announced, promoted, or advertised through any voice prompt; (4) have an expiration date less than one year after first use (or after additional minutes are purchased); (5) charge a fee for an unconnected call; and (6) deduct a per-minute rate in an increment greater than one minute for calls that are less than one full minute (but allows deducting different destination-specific rates for each full minute of calling time in certain circumstances). Prohibits avoiding liability by stating that the terms are subject to fees or charges. Treats violations as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under specified provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act. Prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from exercising any authority given to the FTC under this Act. Allows state civil enforcement and state laws offering greater protection to consumers.</summary>
</bill>
