<bill session="109" type="h" number="1515" updated="2013-07-19T19:17:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-25T14:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-25T14:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To adjust the boundary of the Barataria Preserve Unit of the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve in the State of Louisiana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400634"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2005-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Renzi moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6942-6943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1515.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-25T14:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6942" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="207"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2006--Passed House amended.
Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2006 - Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 to: (1) adjust the boundary of the Barataria Preserve Unit of Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve in Louisiana by increasing the acreage limitation; and (2) authorize the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to acquire any such additional land, water, and interests in land and water by donation, purchase (but only with the owner's consent), transfer from any other federal agency, or exchange. Requires, with respect to the Bayou aux Carpes Addition and the CIT Tract Addition, any federal land acquired in such Additions to: (1) be transferred without consideration to the administrative jurisdiction of the National Park Service; and (2) any federal land in the Additions that is transferred, be subject to any easements that have been agreed to by the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army. Permits the acquisition of any private land, water, or interests in land and water in the Unit only with the owner's consent. Modifies and/or eliminates certain provisions related to the acquisition of property within the Unit. Permits hunting, fishing, and trapping within the Unit, but only as to land, water, or interests in land and water managed by the Secretary. Continues to provide for the designation of zones where, and established periods when, no hunting, fishing, or trapping shall be permitted except for public safety reasons.</summary>
</bill>
