<bill session="111" type="h" number="3420" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SUPPORT for Substance Use Disorders Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supporting Uniformed Personnel by Providing Oversight and Relevant Treatment for Substance Use Disorders Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve and enhance substance use disorder programs for members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2009-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="459"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2009--Introduced.
Supporting Uniformed Personnel by Providing Oversight and Relevant Treatment for Substance Use Disorders Act or SUPPORT for Substance Use Disorders Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to conduct a comprehensive review of Department of Defense (DOD) programs and activities for the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and management of, and research on, substance use disorders among members of the Armed Forces. Requires the Secretary to submit to the congressional defense and appropriations committees a plan for the improvement and enhancement of such programs and activities for members and their dependent family members, which shall include mechanisms to ensure the availability of appropriate treatment for such disorders and facilitate their prevention and reduction. Requires the plan to include instructions on: (1) the prevention of such disorders; (2) the appropriate training of health care professionals in the treatment of such disorders; (3) services for the dependents of members with such disorders; and (4) the dissemination of disorder prevention materials. Directs the Secretary to study such disorders in members and establish within DOD a Center of Excellence in the Prevention, Diagnosis, Mitigation, Treatment, and Management of Substance Use Disorders.</summary>
</bill>
