<bill session="112" type="s" number="3616" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Making Adoption Affordable Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent the expansion of tax benefits for adoption enacted in 2001 and to permanently reinstate the expansion of tax benefits for adoption enacted in 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4373"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Making Adoption Affordable Act of 2012 - Makes permanent provisions of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 allowing an increased tax credit for adoption expenses and an increased exclusion from an employee's gross income for amounts paid by an employer for adoption expenses. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reinstate and make permanent: (1) the increase in the tax credit for adoption expenses and the increased exclusion from an employee's gross income for amounts paid by an employer for adoption expenses that were enacted by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, (2) the annual inflation adjustments for such increased amounts, and (3) the refundability of the tax credit for adoption expenses. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to take certain actions concerning: (1) Internal Revenue Service (IRS) communications efforts about the adoption tax credit, and (2) documentation of adoption expenses required before initiation of a tax audit.</summary>
</bill>
