<bill session="111" type="h" number="6491" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Human Trafficking Fraud Enforcement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for the purpose of establishing an office within the Internal Revenue Service to focus on violations of the internal revenue laws by persons who are under investigation for conduct relating to the promotion of commercial sex acts and trafficking in persons crimes, and to increase the criminal monetary penalty limitations for the underpayment or overpayment of tax due to fraud.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2010--Introduced.
Human Trafficking Fraud Enforcement Act of 2010 - Authorizes appropriations in FY2011 to establish an office within the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to investigate and prosecute violations of internal revenue laws by persons that appear to be engaged in sex trafficking of children, transportation and coercion of individuals and minors for the purpose of prostitution, racketeering, forced labor and trafficking in slavery, and importation of aliens for prostitution. Makes victims of sex trafficking eligible for whistleblower awards. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase criminal penalties and fines for: (1) attempts to evade or defeat tax attributable to human trafficking and commercial sex acts; (2) willful failure to file returns for tax attributable to income derived from human trafficking and commercial sex acts; and (3) fraud and false statements with respect to tax attributable to human trafficking and commercial sex acts.</summary>
</bill>
