<bill session="111" type="s" number="629" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Part-Time Reemployment of Annuitants Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Part-Time Reemployment of Annuitants Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to facilitate the part-time reemployment of annuitants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3373-3374"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-04-12">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-04-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="342">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 342.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Part-Time Reemployment of Annuitants Act of 2009 - Allows a federal agency head (other than for the Government Accountability Office [GAO]) to waive the application of civil service retirement system and federal employee retirement system provisions restricting annuities and pay upon reemployment with respect to an annuitant employed as a limited time appointee (an annuitant appointed under a temporary appointment limited to one year or less) if the annuitant's employment is necessary to: (1) fulfill functions critical to the mission of the agency or any component thereof; (2) assist in the implementation or oversight of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 or the Troubled Asset Relief Program; (3) assist in the development, management, or oversight of agency procurement actions; (4) assist the Inspector General for that agency in the performance of that Inspector General's mission; (5) promote appropriate training or mentoring programs of employees; (6) assist in the recruitment or retention of employees; or (7) respond to an emergency involving a direct threat to life or property or other unusual circumstances. Prohibits waiving such provisions with respect to an annuitant for more than: (1) 520 hours of service performed during the six months following the individual's annuity commencing date; (2) 1040 hours of service performed during any 12-month period; or (3) a total of 3120 hours of service performed by that annuitant. Limits the total number of annuitants to whom such a waiver may apply to not more than 2.5% of the total number of full-time agency employees. Requires an agency head to submit a justification if the number of annuitants to whom a waiver applies exceeds 1% of the number of employees. Terminates such waiver authority five years after this Act's enactment. Sets forth reporting requirements by agency heads and by the Comptroller General.</summary>
</bill>
