<bill session="110" type="h" number="6929" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Office of Legal Counsel Reporting Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 28 of the United States Code to require reporting on certain authoritative legal interpretations issued by the Department of Justice, including the Office of Legal Counsel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400280"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2008--Introduced.
Office of Legal Counsel Reporting Act of 2008 - Amends the federal judicial code to require the Attorney General to report to Congress on certain authoritative Department of Justice legal interpretations (including those by the Office of Legal Counsel) submitted to the President, executive branch agency heads, or the Secretaries of the military departments about the constitutionality, non-application, or supersession of federal law. Requires any qualified legal opinion issued to the President, any person or entity in the executive branch, or any member of the Armed Forces to be issued in writing, except when immediate action is required. Requires the Comptroller General to evaluate and report to Congress on the performance of the Office of Legal Counsel during the 25-year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
