<bill session="112" type="hr" number="657" updated="2013-07-20T01:08:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives supporting Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2012--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) Congress and the President should end the pay freeze for federal employees in January 2013 and should prevent any further cuts to federal employee pensions or benefits; (2) federal employee contributions to their retirement system should not be increased; (3) the annuity multiplier used to determine retirement benefits for federal employees should not be decreased; (4) the Federal Employees Retirement System annuity supplement should not be eliminated and federal employees who are eligible to retire should be able to do so regardless of their age; (5) Social Security reform should not include utilizing a Chained Consumer Price Index, which would reduce federal annuities; (6) the Federal Employee Health Benefits Program should not be turned into a voucher program that shifts the costs of health insurance to employees and retirees; (7) the tax increase on new federal employees that funds part of the extension of the Unemployment Insurance program should be repealed; (8) the work that federal employees perform on behalf of the American people should be respected; and (9) Congress should recognize that efforts to reduce the compensation and support provided to federal employees undermine our government's ability to meet its obligations to citizens and hurt federal agencies' ability to recruit and retain a high-quality federal workforce.</summary>
</bill>
