<bill session="110" type="h" number="3164" updated="2013-07-19T21:31:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal Government Tax-Exempt Bond Parity Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the treatment of Indian tribal governments as State governments for purposes of issuing tax-exempt governmental bonds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2007-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Tribes and tribal system"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2007--Introduced.
Tribal Government Tax-Exempt Bond Parity Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit the issuance of tax-exempt bonds by an Indian tribal government or subdivision if: (1) at least 95 percent of the net proceeds are used to finance facilities on an Indian reservation; or (2) the obligation is part of an issue substantially all of whose proceeds are to be used in the exercise of an essential government function. Excludes an obligation used to finance any part of a building in which class II or III gaming is conducted or housed or any other property actually used in the conduct of such gaming. Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to exempt obligations issued by an Indian tribal government or subdivision from registration requirements.</summary>
</bill>
