<bill session="109" type="s" number="1354" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wartime Treatment Study Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Wartime Treatment Study Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish commissions to review the facts and circumstances surrounding injustices suffered by European Americans, European Latin Americans, and Jewish refugees during World War II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7837-7838"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7838-7840" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Specter without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="296">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 296.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3198"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European American ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Latin Americans"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2005--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Wartime Treatment Study Act - Title I: Commission On Wartime Treatment Of European Americans - (Sec. 101) Establishes a seven member Commission on Wartime Treatment of European Americans. Requires the Commission to include two members representing the interests of Italian Americans and two members representing the interests of German Americans. (Sec. 102) Directs the Commission to review U.S. government wartime treatment (from September 1, 1939, through December 31, 1948) of European Americans and European Latin Americans and include in such review: (1) civil liberties violations resulting from enforcement of the Alien Enemies Acts, Presidential Proclamations 2526, 2527, 2655, 2662, Executive Orders 9066 and 9095, and related directives pertaining to the registration, arrest, exclusion, internment, exchange, or deportation of European Americans and European Latin Americans; (2) U.S. government actions against European Americans under the Alien Enemies Acts and Executive Order 9066, including registration requirements, travel and property restrictions, internment, and forced abandonment of property; (3) participation by European Americans in the U.S. Armed Forces; and (4) appropriate remedies, including future protection of civil liberties during wartime. Requires the Commission to: (1) hold public hearings; and (2) submit a written report to Congress on its findings and recommendations. Terminates the Commission 60 days after it submits its report. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Commission On Wartime Treatment Of Jewish Refugees - (Sec. 201) Establishes a seven member Commission on Wartime Treatment of Jewish Refugees. Requires the Commission to include two members representing the interests of Jewish refugees. (Sec. 202) Directs the Commission to review the U.S. government's refusal to allow entry into the United States of Jewish and other refugees fleeing persecution in Europe between January 1, 1933, and December 31, 1945, including: (1) the underlying rationale for such refusal; (2) the perceived benefits of such refusal; (3) the impact of such refusal on the refugees; and (4) federal refugee policy, including recommendations for improving access of future victims of persecution or genocide to refuge in the United States. Requires the Commission to: (1) hold hearings; and (2) submit a written report to Congress on its findings and recommendations. Terminates the Commission 60 days after it submits its report to Congress. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
