<bill session="111" type="hr" number="702" updated="2013-07-19T23:02:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Comptroller General of the United States to submit reports ensuring the effectiveness of Federal programs and amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require that certain standing committees of the House hold at least one hearing on each such report that falls within their jurisdiction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the effectiveness of each federal program, within two years after it begins to be implemented, to determine its effectiveness and whether it is carrying out the intent of Congress. Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a standing committee,within 30 legislative days after it receives such a report, to hold a hearing on the subject matter of that report. Requires the committee, at a hearing for a program authorized for 10 or more years or with an open-ended authorization, to determine appropriate intervals for additional hearings respecting the program's effectiveness. Exempts from such requirement the House Committees on: (1) Appropriations; (2) House Administration; (3) Rules; and (4) Standards of Official Conduct.</summary>
</bill>
