<bill session="110" type="s" number="3723" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a framework for coordination and cooperation on energy and environmental issues among the United States, the People's Republic of China, and India, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2008--Introduced.
Declares it to be the policy of the United States to develop an informed dialogue with China and India on the sustainable use of energy and the protection of the environment, the promotion of best practices for clean energy and technology investments, and the development and transfer of energy and environmental technologies.Establishes a Congressional-Executive Commission on Clean Energy Trade Between Key Consuming Nations to coordinate energy and environmental issues relating to the United States, China, and India and to establish a dialogue among such nations on the development and promotion of clean energy production, clean air and water, clean and efficient transportation, and the conservation and management of forests and wetlands and their ecosystems.</summary>
</bill>
