<bill session="110" type="h" number="7083" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-27T14:50:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-27T14:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Charity Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Charity Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance charitable giving and improve disclosure and tax administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2008-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10196-10198" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7083.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-27T14:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10196-10197" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Charity Enhancement Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify rules and definitions relating to the excise tax on distributions from donor advised funds (charitable funds in which a donor has, or reasonably expects to have, advisory privileges with respect to the distribution or investment of amounts held in such funds by reason of his or her status as a donor). Excludes from the definition of "donor advised fund" charitable funds that receive contributions or are advised solely by one or more public charities or governmental entities. Exempts certain scholarship distributions from the tax on distributions from donor advised funds.Repeals the requirement of a written acknowledgment by a supporting organization (a charitable organization that maintains one or more donor advised funds) that it has exclusive legal control over assets contributed to it. Exempts certain compensation and benefits paid to substantial contributors by supporting organizations from treatment as excess benefits.Exempts certain supporting organizations established before January 1, 1970, from applicable holdings and payout requirements.Treats contributions to tax-exempt organizations by Indian tribal governments in the same manner as contributions by states for purposes of determining the classification of an organization as a public charity or private foundation. Requires certain tax-exempt organizations that file at least five tax returns annually with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to use electronic filing.Extends the bad check penalty to payments of tax by commercially acceptable means (e.g., electronic payments).</summary>
</bill>
