<bill session="111" type="h" number="1880" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Insurance Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a system of regulation and supervision for insurers, insurance agencies, and insurance producers chartered or licensed under Federal law that ensures the stability and financial integrity of those insurers, agencies, and producers and that protects policyholders and other consumers served by such insurers, agencies, or producers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400631"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412279" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2009-09-16" withdrawn="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
National Insurance Consumer Protection Act - Establishes in the Department of the Treasury the Office of National Insurance (Office), headed by a Commissioner, with regulatory oversight over national insurers and national insurance agencies. Directs the Commissioner to license, regulate, and supervise national insurance producers. Requires the Commissioner to establish: (1) a Division of Consumer Affairs; (2) a Division of Insurance Fraud; and (3) an Office of the Ombudsman. Authorizes the Commissioner to provide for the registration of insurance self-regulatory organizations and to supervise and regulate them. Requires the Commissioner to: (1) issue regulations on prudential supervision; (2) require national insurers and national insurance agencies to comply with federal anti-money laundering requirements; (3) promulgate regulations for prompt corrective action for any hazardous financial condition of a national insurer; (4) issue charters for national insurers and national agencies; (5) promulgate financial, policy, and market conduct standards; and (6) establish standards for a national insurance holding company. Authorizes the Commissioner to: (1) examine national insurers or national insurance agencies; (2) impose fees upon national insurers, national insurance agencies, and national insurance producers; (3) revoke the charter of a national insurer or national insurance agency for specified cause, (4) implement enforcement powers, including cooperation with foreign governments; (5) secure bilateral and multilateral agreements with foreign insurance regulators and regional and global regulatory organizations; and (6) license individual persons as a national insurance producer. Establishes criminal penalties for insurance fraud by national insurers, national insurance agencies, national insurance producers, and other persons. Directs the President to designate a systemic risk regulator for a national insurer and any insurance company subject to state supervision. Establishes: (1) the Coordinating National Council for Financial Regulators; and (2) the National Insurance Guaranty Corporation. Prescribes procedures for conservatorship, receivership, benefits and claims payments, and assessments on national insurers.Exempts insurers, national insurance agencies, and national insurance producers from state supervision relating to the sale, solicitation, negotiation, or underwriting of insurance, or to any other insurance operations.</summary>
</bill>
