<bill session="112" type="sr" number="435" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling for democratic change in Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2012-06-04" withdrawn="2012-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2734-2735" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-05-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="388">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 388.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Condemns: (1) Syrian President Bashar al-Assad's ongoing slaughter of his own people; (2) Russia and Iran for providing the government of Syria with military and security equipment; and (3) President Bashar al-Assad's failure to uphold his March 25, 2012, commitment to the six point plan outlined by Joint Special Envoy Kofi Annan and failed compliance with U.N. Security Council Resolution 2042. Reaffirms U.S. policy that Bashar al-Assad must relinquish power and step aside. Recognizes the efforts of the United Nations and the League of Arab States to establish a cessation of armed violence in Syria. Urges: (1) support for the U.N.-administered Emergency Response Fund to ensure the provision of humanitarian and emergency medical support for the population of Syria, and (2) the continued provision of humanitarian assistance to displaced Syrians in Turkey, Jordan, Lebanon, and Iraq. Calls on the President to engage with the League of Arab States, the European Union (EU), and Turkey to explore protective options for civilians in Syria. Demands that Syria allow: (1) additional U.N. personnel into the country to observe the cease fire with complete freedom of movement and the government of Syria's adherence to the U.N. peace plan; and (2) humanitarian relief organizations, medical workers, and independent and foreign news media to operate freely inside Syria. Urges the Syrian opposition to renew its commitment to a democratic and inclusive society in the post-Assad era. Supports the President's efforts to provide non-lethal support, including communications equipment, to organizations in Syria that: (1) are representative of the Syrian people, (2) protect human rights and religious freedom, (3) cooperate with international counterterrorism and nonproliferation efforts, and (4) abstain from destabilizing neighboring countries. Supports the imposition of an EU ban on the sale of luxury goods and products to Syria. Urges the President to identify weapons stockpiles and prevent the proliferation of conventional, biological, and chemical weapons in Syria. Urges all governments, including those that have provided military and security assistance to the government of Syria in the past, including the Republic of Belarus and the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, to not provide any additional such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
