<bill session="111" type="h" number="5891" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Poverty Measurement Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Bureau of the Census to publish improved annual measures of family income for use in more accurately determining the extent of poverty in the United States and the anti-poverty effectiveness of means-tested benefit and tax programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2010--Introduced.
Poverty Measurement Improvement Act - Amends the Social Security Act to require the Bureau of the Census, annually, to publish statistics on levels of family income in the United States that take into account the full benefits poverty income measure and the partial benefits poverty income measure. Defines: (1) "partial benefits poverty income measure" to mean money income as defined by the Bureau for purposes of any survey relating to income or poverty in the United States; and (2) "full benefits poverty income measure" to mean the sum of the partial benefits poverty income measure and other non-cash benefits (including supplemental nutrition assistance benefits, housing subsidies, the actuarial value of health insurance coverage, and any other state or federal means-tested benefits) attributable to the members of the household involved, including non-related members, as calculated by the Bureau by applying its current disposable income methodology. Requires the Bureau to produce corresponding tables and graphs showing for each year the poverty rates (and related data) determined by using each such measure.</summary>
</bill>
