<bill session="111" type="h" number="5223" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chimney Rock National Monument Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Chimney Rock National Monument in the State of Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400620"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3303"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2010--Introduced.
Chimney Rock National Monument Act of 2010 - Designates the Chimney Rock National Monument in Colorado to preserve, protect, and restore the archeological, anthropological, geological, hydrologic, biological, visual, and scenic resources of Chimney Rock. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make minor adjustments to the boundaries of the Monument for the inclusion of significant archaeological resources discovered on adjacent public land. Requires management of, and authorizes use of, the Monument as a unit of San Juan National Forest. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out vegetative management treatments within the Monument, with the exception of timber harvesting and the use of prescribed fire, which may only be used when necessary to address the risk of wildfire, insects, or diseases. Prohibits uses of the Monument other than those authorized by the Secretary. Includes as authorized uses: (1) construction of a visitor's center and related exhibit and curatorial facilities to interpret the Monument's scientific and cultural resources; (2) scientific research (including archaeological research) and educational and interpretive uses; (3) acquisition and display of artifacts; (4) recreational use of mountain bikes and motorized vehicles; (5) installation and maintenance of a certain public utility right of way; and (6) grazing uses. Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Monument, which shall include: (1) providing for the continued use of the Monument by Indian tribes for traditional ceremonies and as a source for traditional plants and other materials; and (2) specifying permitted uses of artifacts.</summary>
</bill>
