<bill session="109" type="h" number="3084" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Professional Athletes Drug Testing bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Free Sports Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Drug Free Sports Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to issue regulations requiring testing for steroids and other performance-enhancing substances for certain sports associations engaged in interstate commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2005-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 38 - 2.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28T22:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 109-210, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28T22:15:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Education and the Workforce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 30, 2005.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Workforce Protections Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Education Reform Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-30T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-09-30T16:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="133">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 133.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1862"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hockey"/>
    <term name="Hormones"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Soccer"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Drug Free Sports Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Commerce to issue regulations requiring professional sports associations to adopt and enforce policies and procedures for the random testing of athletes for the use of performance-enhancing substances. Requires that each athlete be tested five times each year at random intervals during both the season of play and the off-season and without advance notification of the athlete or coaching and training staffs. Requires the Secretary to prescribe the substances for which each athlete is to be tested, to include: (1) prohibited substances as determined by the World Anti-Doping Agency; and (2) substances the Secretary determines are performance-enhancing substances for a particular sport or are designed to conceal the presence of performance-enhancing substances in the body and for which testing is reasonable and practicable. Requires the Secretary to establish criteria for: (1) exempting athletes for documented legitimate medical or therapeutic usage; (2) testing to be administered by an independent party; and (3) reducing the suspension for an athlete who has tested positive but who establishes that he or she bears no fault or negligence or no significant fault or negligence. Directs that the penalty for a positive test result is suspension without pay for one-half of the season of play for the first violation, for one full season of play for the second violation, and permanently for a third violation. Requires disclosure to the public of the name of any athlete who tests positive. Provides for an opportunity for a prompt hearing and an appeal before an arbiter. (Sec. 4) Allows the Secretary to: (1) fine any such association for failure to adopt and enforce testing policies and procedures consistent with the regulations; and (2) reduce such fines if they are unduly burdensome. (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the effectiveness of, and compliance with, regulations prescribed under this Act. Requires the Comptroller General to study the testing policies and practices for the use of performance-enhancing substances by college and secondary school athletes, including: (1) an examination of prohibited substance policies and testing procedures of intercollegiate athletic associations, college and university athletic departments, secondary schools, and state and regional interscholastic athletic associations; and (2) an analysis of the best available estimates for both licit and illicit use of anabolic steroids and human growth hormones by such athletes. Requires the Comptroller General to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the adequacy of such testing policies and procedures in detecting and preventing the use of performance-enhancing substances and include recommendations regarding expanding the application of this Act to intercollegiate and interscholastic athletic associations. (Sec. 6) Provides that this Act does not prohibit professional sports associations and their athletes from negotiating and agreeing upon more stringent requirements.</summary>
</bill>
