<bill session="112" type="hj" number="74" updated="2013-07-20T02:08:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing the limited use of the United States Armed Forces in support of the NATO mission in Libya.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2011-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="67"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="68"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sj" number="20"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2011--Introduced.
Authorizes the President to continue the limited use of U.S. Armed Forces in Libya in support of U.S. security policy interests as part of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) mission to enforce U.N. Security Council Resolution 1973, as requested by the Transitional National Council, the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC), and the Arab League. Terminates such authorization on the date on which the NATO mission ends or 180 days after the date of the enactment of this joint resolution, whichever occurs first. Declares that such authorization is intended to constitute specific statutory authority within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution. States that the President is not authorized to deploy, establish, or maintain the presence of units of the U.S. Armed Forces on the ground in Libya unless the purpose of the presence is limited to: (1) the immediate personal defense or rescue of U.S. government personnel (including diplomatic representatives), (2) rescuing members of NATO forces from imminent danger; or (3) the provision of humanitarian aid or assistance to the people of Libya. Directs the President to consult frequently with Congress regarding U.S. efforts in Libya, including by providing regular briefings and reports. Includes as elements in such briefings and reports: (1) an updated description of U.S. national security interests and policy objectives in Libya; (2) an updated list of U.S. Armed Forces activities in Libya; (3) an updated assessment of the opposition groups in Libya, including potential successor governments; and (4) an updated explanation of the President's legal and constitutional rationale for conducting military operations in Libya consistent with the War Powers Resolution.</summary>
</bill>
