<bill session="112" type="s" number="3461" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Pediatric Research Network Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to provide for a National Pediatric Research Network, including with respect to pediatric rare diseases or conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2012-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2012-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5735-5736"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="6163"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2012--Introduced.
National Pediatric Research Network Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), in carrying out the Pediatric Research Initiative, to act through the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development and in collaboration with other appropriate national research institutes and national centers that carry out activities involving pediatric research to provide for the establishment of a National Pediatric Research Network. Authorizes the Director of the Institute to award cooperative agreements and grants to public or private nonprofit entities for: (1) planning, establishing, or strengthening pediatric research consortia; and (2) providing basic operating support for such consortia, including for pediatric research needs and training. Authorizes the Director to make awards for not more than 20 pediatric research consortia. Requires the Director to provide for the coordination of activities among the consortia and to require the periodic preparation and submission of reports on their activities. Requires the Director of NIH to ensure that an appropriate number of such awards are awarded to consortia that agree to: (1) focus primarily on pediatric rare diseases or conditions; (2) conduct or coordinate multi-site clinical trials of therapies for, or approaches to, the prevention, diagnosis, or treatment of pediatric rare diseases or conditions; and (3) disseminate trial findings. Requires the Director of NIH to establish a data coordinating center to: (1) distribute such findings; (2) provide assistance in the design and conduct of collaborative research projects and the management, analysis, and storage of data associated with such projects; (3) organize and conduct multi-site monitoring activities; (4) provide assistance to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) in the establishment of patient registries; and (5) report regularly on consortia research.</summary>
</bill>
