<bill session="112" type="s" number="615" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fiscal Accountability and Transparency in Infrastructure Spending Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the accountability and transparency in infrastructure spending by requiring a life-cycle cost analysis of major infrastructure projects, providing the flexibility to use alternate infrastructure type bidding procedures to reduce project costs, and requiring the use of design standards to improve efficiency and save taxpayer dollars.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2602"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2011--Introduced.
Fiscal Accountability and Transparency in Infrastructure Spending Act of 2011 - Requires each executive agency to obtain a life-cycle cost analysis for each major infrastructure project prior to obligating funds. Defines "life-cycle cost analysis" as a process for evaluating the total economic worth of an infrastructure project by analyzing specified costs over a minimum 50-year period. Authorizes the use of alternate infrastructure type bidding procedures for awarding contracts for projects on the National Highway System and for major infrastructure projects. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to require states to utilize the Mechanistic-Empirical Pavement Design Guide (developed under the National Cooperative Highway Research Program Project I-37A)&#160;for the initial design phase of all authorized highway projects.</summary>
</bill>
