<bill session="113" type="s" number="944" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Educational Transition Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require courses of education provided by public institutions of higher education that are approved for purposes of the All-Volunteer Force Educational Assistance Program and Post-9/11 Educational Assistance to charge veterans tuition and fees at the in-State tuition rate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3432"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3432-3433" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2013--Introduced.
Veterans' Educational Transition Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to disapprove, for purposes of the all-volunteer force or post-9/11 educational assistance program, a course of education provided by a public institution of higher education if such institution charges veterans who are living in the state of such institution while taking such course tuition and fees at a rate higher than that charged to residents of such state, regardless of the veteran's regular state of residence. Provides that it shall not be grounds for such disapproval if the institution requires the veteran to demonstrate an intent to establish residency in such state in order to be charged the in-state rates.</summary>
</bill>
