<bill session="111" type="h" number="6169" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Making Investments Now for Dementia Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the issuance of United States bonds to fund Alzheimer's research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
Making Investments Now for Dementia Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury (the Secretary) to issue bonds to aid in the funding of Alzheimer's research in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Declares that the bonds authorized under this Act shall be in such form and denominations, and shall be subject to such terms and conditions of issue, conversion, redemption, maturation, payment, and rate of interest, as the Secretary may prescribe. Requires the Secretary to submit an annual report to Congress describing the actions taken by the Secretaries during the year, with the first such report describing the implementation of the program and subsquent reports describing the use of funds and the status of the program. Authorizes appropriations to the Director of NIH for research on Alzheimer's research equal to the amounts received by the Secretary from the sale of bonds under this Act, less amounts determined by the Secretary to be necessary for administration of such sales. Expresses the sense of Congress that any funds collected pursuant to this Act are in addition to yearly appropriated funds and are not to be used to supplement current funding.</summary>
</bill>
