<bill session="110" type="h" number="7199" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Information and Treatment Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish programs that use the Internet to provide to patients and health care practitioners coordinated information on diseases and other conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2008--Introduced.
Medical Information and Treatment Access Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to utilize an Internet site to: (1) consolidate and translate health care information that is available to the public from federal agencies, linking the various health-related Internet sites of such agencies; and (2) assist in the translation and reporting of disease or condition protocols for physicians and lay persons.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to establish programs to gather information from health care practitioners and make such information publicly available regarding off-label uses of new drugs and surgical procedures.Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Center for Complementary and Alternative Medicine to establish a program to gather information on alternative medicine from health care practitioners and make such information publicly available. Requires the Director of the Center to include information that relates to the effects of dietary supplements and food on diseases and disorders.</summary>
</bill>
