<bill session="110" type="h" number="4928" updated="2013-07-19T21:47:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fountain Creek Watershed Feasibility Study Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Chief of Engineers to conduct a feasibility study relating to the construction of a multipurpose project in the Fountain Creek watershed located in the State of Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2007-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2650"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2384"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2384"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Multipurpose projects"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2007--Introduced.
Fountain Creek Watershed Feasibility Study Act of 2007 - Directs the Chief of Engineers to complete a study to determine the feasibility of constructing a multipurpose water resources project that shall: (1) be located in the Fountain Creek watershed, Colorado; (2) consist of one or more dams or other structures, other facilities, or management activities or one or more other reservoirs that are to be located on- or off-channel of the watershed; and (3) be designed, with respect to the area located in the watershed and the Arkansas River Valley and any residential or commercial activity therein, to provide more reliable flood control and better sediment control, to increase the water supply, to improve water quality, and to conserve fish and wildlife and preserve the ecosystem located close to the project.Requires the Chief to: (1) take into consideration the Supplemental Report on Fountain Reservoir and Reevaluation of Report on Review Survey for Flood Control and Allied Purposes, Arkansas River and Tributaries Above John Martin Dam, Colorado, dated May 15, 1970, and the Fountain Creek Watershed Study prepared by the Corps of Engineers; and (2) conduct the study independently from the Fountain Creek watershed, the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project, or the proposed Southern Delivery System Project.</summary>
</bill>
