<bill session="109" type="s" number="1259" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Employment and Transition Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend the requirement for reports from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on the disposition of cases recommended to the Secretary for equitable relief due to administrative error and to provide improved benefits and procedures for the transition of member of the Armed Forces from combat zones to noncombat zones and for the transition of veterans from service in the Armed Forces to civilian life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 1235, as amended, ordered to be reported.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1235"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2005--Introduced.
Veterans Employment and Transition Services Act - Extends through 2009 (currently, 2004) a requirement for annual reports from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to Congress on equitable relief provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to veterans and their dependents following a loss of benefits because of Department administrative error. Directs the Secretaries of Defense and Homeland Security to carry out a program to facilitate access of representatives of military and veterans' service organizations and agencies to provide preseparation counseling and services to members of the Armed Forces who are scheduled for discharge, release from active duty, or retirement. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a similar program for facilitating the access of such representatives to provide information and counseling to veterans on the care, benefits, and services offered through the Department. Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to ensure that preseparation counseling is provided by personnel and offices that are not responsible for encouraging service members to reenlist.</summary>
</bill>
