<bill session="109" type="h" number="470" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Electronic Voting Standards and Disclosure Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require the software used in the operation of an electronic voting machine to meet certain requirements as a condition of the use of the machine in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2005--Introduced.
Improving Electronic Voting Standards and Disclosure Act of 2005 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to: (1) establish specific requirements for software used in electronic voting machines in Federal elections; (2) prohibit Election Assistance Commission accreditation of a laboratory unless it meets standards the Commission may establish to prevent the existence or appearance of any conflict of interest in the testing of voting system hardware and software; (3) require the posting of notice of the availability of administrative complaint procedures for individuals who believe that a voting machine or other equipment used in the election is not working properly, or who otherwise believe that a State or jurisdiction is not in compliance with the requirements of this Act; and (4) prohibit an individual from filing a complaint with respect to an allegation that a voting machine or other equipment used in an election is not working properly unless the individual is eligible to cast a vote on or otherwise use the machine or equipment which is the subject of the complaint.</summary>
</bill>
