<bill session="113" type="s" number="1296" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:38-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemember's Electronic Health Records Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wounded Warrior Act to establish a specific timeline for the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to achieve interoperable electronic health records, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5688"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2590"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2013--Introduced.
Servicemember's Electronic Health Records Act of 2013 - Amends the Wounded Warrior Act to require the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs, in implementing electronic health record systems that provide for the full interoperability of personal health care information between the Department of Defense (DOD) and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), to ensure that: (1) a health data authoritative source that can be accessed by multiple providers and that standardizes the input of new medical information is created by the Departments within 180 days, (2) the ability of patients of both Departments to download their medical records is achieved within 180 days, (3) full interoperability of personal health care information between the Departments is achieved within one year, (4) acceleration of the exchange of real-time data between the Departments is achieved within one year, (5) the upgrade of the graphical user interface to display a joint common graphical user interface is achieved within one year, and (6) current members of the Armed Forces and their dependents may elect to receive an electronic copy of their health care records beginning not later than June 30, 2015. Requires the Secretaries to assess the feasibility and advisability of establishing a secure, remote, network-accessible computer storage system (commonly referred to as cloud storage) to: (1) provide members of the Armed Forces and veterans the ability to upload their health care records, and (2) allow DOD and VA medical providers of the Departments to access such records.</summary>
</bill>
