<bill session="111" type="h" number="1417" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safety for Americans from Nuclear Weapons Testing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect public health and safety, should the testing of nuclear weapons by the United States be resumed.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="600"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2009--Introduced.
Safety for Americans from Nuclear Weapons Testing Act - Deems each of the following actions undertaken by a federal agency to be a major federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for which a detailed environmental impact statement is required in conformance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969: (1) any action having as a purpose the resumption of testing of one or more nuclear weapons (including other nuclear explosive devices producing a nuclear yield) at the Nevada Test Site; or (2) use of any other location for such testing. Outlines information required to be included in such statement, including: (1) the possibility of radiation containment failure and the effects of such failure; (2) possible long-term effects on the water table from underground radiation leakage; and (3) information with respect to certain kiloton categories of weapons. Prohibits the United States from resuming any such testing unless authorized by a law enacted after the enactment of this Act. Requires: (1) advance public notice of each test by the President; (2) notice of each release of radiation beyond the boundaries of the Nevada Test Site by the Secretary of Energy within one hour of detection of such radiation; and (3) public meetings in southern Utah, Arizona, and Nevada after each test to discuss test results. Directs the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study on the safety and health of citizens in the vicinity of the Nevada Test Site. Directs the Secretary to establish a Nevada Test Site Citizens Review Board. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants to institutions of higher education to acquire and operate, for ten years, radiation detection equipment and sensors. Directs the Secretary of Energy, through the Department of Energy (DOE) and Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to monitor the nature and extent of any radiation released into the atmosphere as a result of such testing. Requires: (1) DOE radiation containment assessment; and (2) public notice of monitoring data. Requires the: (1) Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to make a grant to establish the National Center for the Study of Radiation and Human Health; and (2) Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study of individuals exposed to nuclear weapons tests.</summary>
</bill>
