<bill session="109" type="h" number="3895" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06T20:51:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-06T20:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Housing Hurricane Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Rural Housing Hurricane Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title V of the Housing Act of 1949 to provide rural housing assistance to families affected by Hurricane Katrina.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title V of the Housing Act of 1949 to provide rural housing assistance to families affected by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2005-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Baker moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8668-8670" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3895.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8706-8707" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-10-06T20:51:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="513" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 335 - 81 (Roll no. 513).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8668-8669" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Passed House amended.
Rural Housing Hurricane Relief Act of 2005 - Amends the Housing Act of 1949, in the event of a presidential-declared disaster, to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to counties designated as disaster areas in connection with Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, and the counties contiguous to such counties and for any residents of such counties, to: (1) convert rental assistance into housing voucher assistance or rural housing vouchers; and (2) waive rural area requirements. States that such authority shall last for six months after enactment of this Act. Authorizes additional appropriations for such assistance. Authorizes the Secretary, during the six-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, to assist low-income families and persons under the rural housing voucher program if: (1) such family or person resided, on August 25, 2005, in any area designated as a disaster or emergency area in connection with Hurricane Katrina, or resided, on September 24, 2005, in any area designated as a disaster or emergency area in connection with Hurricane Rita; and (2) the residence of such family or person became uninhabitable or inaccessible as result of such a disaster or emergency. Eliminates the rural housing voucher program fiscal year unit limit. Amends the Doug Bereuter section 502 single family housing loan guarantee program to permit loan and refinancing guarantees for home repair or rehabilitation.</summary>
</bill>
