<bill session="110" type="h" number="5844" updated="2013-07-19T21:54:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the transfer of the decommissioned Naval Security Group Activity, Skaggs Island, in Sonoma County, California, from the Department of the Navy to the Department of the Interior for conversion into a wildlife refuge for inclusion in the National Wildlife Refuge System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2008-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2008--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Navy to transfer the decommissioned Naval Security Group Activity, Skaggs Island, in Sonoma County, California, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior to permit such Secretary, acting through the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, to administer the transferred property as a wildlife refuge in the National Wildlife Refuge System.Requires the Secretary of the Navy, before completing the transfer of the property, to demolish and remove all structures on the property identified by the Secretary of the Interior as appropriate for removal to facilitate the conversion of the property into a wildlife refuge. Permits the Secretary of the Navy to accept contributions from the state of California and other entities to help cover the costs of demolishing and removing structures on the property and conducting environmental remediation activities with respect to the property.Requires the Secretary of the Navy to submit reports on the progress made in connection with the remediation and transfer of the property.</summary>
</bill>
