<bill session="111" type="s" number="1469" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the administration of Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7651"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1044"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the Port Chicago National Memorial Act of 1992 to require the Secretary of the Interior to administer the Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial as a unit of the National Park System. Directs the Secretary of Defense to transfer a specified parcel of land as identified on the map entitled "Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial, Proposed Boundary," dated August 2005, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior if the land is excess to military needs. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the city of Concord, California, and the East Bay Regional Park District to establish and operate a facility for visitor orientation and parking, administrative offices, and curatorial storage for the Memorial. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should promptly remediate any remaining environmental contamination relating to the land. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretaries of Defense and the Interior should work together to: (1) repair storm damage to the Memorial; and (2) develop a process by which future repairs and necessary modifications to the Memorial can be achieved in as timely and cost-effective a manner as possible.</summary>
</bill>
