<bill session="111" type="h" number="1261" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Youth Prevention and Tobacco Harm Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the public health by establishing the Tobacco Harm Reduction Center within the Department of Health and Human Services with certain authority to regulate tobacco products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412267" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2009-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2009-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2009--Introduced.
Youth Prevention and Tobacco Harm Reduction Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Tobacco Harm Reduction Center within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Gives the Center's Administrator the authority to regulate tobacco products, including through disclosure, registration, and inspection. Sets forth criteria by which tobacco products are deemed adulterated or misbranded and prohibits the introduction or receipt of any such product in interstate commerce. Prohibits any person from using certain descriptors on packaging or advertising of any cigarette brand style. Allows the Administrator to adopt additional smoking article standards as appropriate to protect the public health. Sets forth provisions governing cigarette tar yield limits. Prohibits the Administrator from: (1) banning specific classes of tobacco products; (2) requiring the reduction of tar or nicotine yields to zero; or (3) establishing a minimum age of sale of smoking articles to any person older than 18. Requires premarket approval of all new tobacco products. Sets forth standards for the sale of modified risk tobacco products. Directs the Administrator to establish the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee. Revises tobacco product warning labels and advertising requirements. Requires the Administrator to establish standards requiring tobacco product manufacturers to publicly disclose a list of ingredients in each brand style. Directs the Administrator to study and report on illicit trade in tobacco products. Amends the Public Health Service Act to limit substance abuse funds for states that do not have in effect a statute setting forth specific provisions to prevent the sale of tobacco products to minors. Directs the Administrator to establish standards and procedures for ranking tobacco products based on the relative risks of serious or chronic tobacco-related diseases and adverse health conditions. Declares that no provision in this Act shall allow any person to require changes to traditional farming practices.</summary>
</bill>
