<bill session="112" type="h" number="4163" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Consumers' Mortgage Origination Choices Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend certain provisions of the Truth in Lending Act related to the compensation of mortgage originators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2012-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2012--Introduced.
Preserving Consumer's Mortgage Origination Choices Act of 2012 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act with respect to the prohibitions against: (1) steering incentives in connection with residential mortgage loan origination; and (2) the restructuring of a financing origination fee, except in certain circumstances. Declares that nothing in such prohibitions shall be construed as prohibiting a mortgage originator who receives compensation directly from a consumer from compensating another mortgage originator employee, mortgage originator agent, or mortgage originator contractor based on the principal amount of the loan, provided that the amount of compensation received by such employee, agent, or contractor may not vary based on any other terms of the loan. Allows a mortgage originator, at the consumer's request, to reduce the amount of compensation the originator is receiving to offset permitted settlement charges (other than those the originator controls) that exceed the amounts previously disclosed on the good faith estimate of the settlement charges given to that consumer, provided that the originator's compensation may not increase.</summary>
</bill>
