<bill session="111" type="h" number="4750" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Meat Contamination Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act and Poultry Products Inspection Act to improve food safety by supporting efforts by entities that purchase beef, pork, or poultry products to further examine the products to ensure they remain safe for human consumption and to prohibit interference with such examination efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412313"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412296" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2010--Introduced.
Meat Contamination Prevention Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to permit an entity that purchases carcasses, carcass parts, meat, or meat food products that have been inspected and found to be unadulterated to perform or cause to be performed at the entity's expense a further examination to ensure that the products remain unadulterated. Prohibits a person, firm, or corporation from preventing (by contract or any other means) such further examination. Subjects a violator of such prohibition to imprisonment and/or fine. Makes similar amendments to the Poultry Products Inspection Act.</summary>
</bill>
