<bill session="112" type="s" number="1126" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REAL Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energy Access through Leasing Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to insure loans for financing of renewable energy systems leased for residential use, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3442"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3442-3444" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Access Through Leasing Act of 2011 or the REAL Act of 2011- Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make loan guarantees for the financing of renewable energy systems leased for residential use. Prohibits the Secretary from insuring a loan unless the renewable energy system owner certifies that the systems financed will be leased only to homeowners that grant easements to install, maintain, use and otherwise access the system that include the right to sell electricity produced during the life of the renewable energy system to a wholesale or retail electrical power grid. Requires a renewable energy system lease to specify that it can be assumed by new homeowners. Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that a discount given under this Act does not adversely affect the homeowner's mortgage requirements; and (2) fix and collect premiums for insurance of loans under this Act that shall be paid for by the renewable energy system owner and that shall be adequate to cover the expenses and probable losses of administering the program. Prohibits the Secretary from assessing any other fee, premium, or charge in connection with such loan insurance. Establishes the Renewable Energy Lease Insurance Fund, into which the Secretary shall deposit any such premiums. Requires the Secretary&#160;to ensure that multifamily housing units are eligible for programs established by this Act. Terminates the Secretary's authority to insure and make commitments to insure new loans under this Act ten years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
