<bill session="112" type="h" number="1257" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect America from U.S. Military Expenses in Libya Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the President to recommend specific reductions in nonsecurity discretionary appropriations for fiscal year 2011 to offset the costs of Operation Odyssey Dawn.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400017"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2011-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1323"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Protect America from U.S. Military Expenses in Libya Act of 2011 - Directs the President, in order to ensure that the cost of Operation Odyssey Dawn (international military operation in Libya) (Operation) does not increase the federal deficit or reduce the capability of U.S. Armed Forces, to submit to Congress a list of recommendations for specific rescissions of nonsecurity discretionary appropriations for FY2011, for purposes of reappropriation to accounts of the Department of Defense (DOD) to replace amounts obligated for such Operation. Requires the aggregate amount of the recommended rescissions to be at least equal to the projected cost of such Operation. Directs the Secretary of Defense to prepare and submit to Congress and the President the projected cost of such Operation through May 15, 2011.</summary>
</bill>
