<bill session="112" type="s" number="1338" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Capture Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 5 of title 31, United States Code, to establish the Office of Regulatory Integrity within the Office of Management and Budget.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4453-4454"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-220.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2011--Introduced.
Regulatory Capture Prevention Act of 2011 - Establishes the Office of Regulatory Integrity in the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), to be headed by an Administrator. Requires the Administrator to investigate and report on the influence of concentrated economic interests on federal agencies that results in: (1) agency action or inaction that fails to advance the mission of the agency or is otherwise inimical to the public interest; (2) regulation, licensing, adjudication, grants, or other agency action that favors a limited number of economic interests or is otherwise inimical to the public interest; (3) enforcement priorities that are not reasonably calculated to accomplish regulatory goals; and (4) a loss of confidence in the integrity of the regulatory process. Grants certain powers to the Administrator to carry out this Act, including access to agency records, subpoena power, direct and prompt access to the head of a relevant agency and access to information and assistance by such agency. Requires the Administrative Conference of the United States to provide the Administrator with written guidance on the principal means by which concentrated economic interests wield influence on federal agencies, the most salient threats to regulatory integrity arising from such influence, and effective measures to minimize regulatory capture.</summary>
</bill>
