<bill session="111" type="s" number="1226" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paperless Enrollment for School Meals Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve paperless enrollment and efficiency for the national school lunch and school breakfast programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6457"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6457-6458" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2803"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2009--Introduced.
Paperless Enrollment for School Meals Act of 2009 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to allow schools and local educational agencies (LEAs) to receive special assistance payments for free or reduced price meals under the school lunch or breakfast programs that are based not on applications for such meals, but on estimates of the number of children eligible for such meals. Requires such estimates to be derived from recent data, such as survey, welfare, or tax data. Permits schools and LEAs from high poverty areas to receive special assistance payments for free or reduced price meals that are not based on applications, if they directly certify a specified minimum percentage of their students as eligible for free meals due to such students' eligibility for certain other public assistance. Reimburses such schools and LEAs pursuant to a formula that factors in the percentage of students directly certified as eligible for free meals. Requires schools and LEAs reimbursed on the basis of estimates or certifications to provide free meals to all their students under the school lunch and breakfast programs and cover, from nonfederal sources, the costs of serving such meals that exceed the assistance received under such programs.</summary>
</bill>
