<bill session="111" type="h" number="4898" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Preparedness Planning Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a competitive program to make emergency preparedness planning and implementation grants to local educational districts/agencies located in areas under a high threat of terrorist attacks, natural disasters, or public health emergencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412268" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2010-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2010-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2010--Introduced.
Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Preparedness Planning Act - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a competitive program to make grants for emergency preparedness planning and implementation to local educational agencies and districts located in areas under a high threat of terrorist attacks, natural disasters, or public health emergencies. Directs the Secretary, in awarding grants, to give priority to: (1) local educational agencies and districts located in areas with higher population densities that are under a higher threat of terrorist attacks, natural disasters, or public health emergencies; and (2) such agencies and districts that have demonstrated the ability to formulate and implement effective emergency preparedness plans. Requires a local educational agency or district receiving a grant to use such funds to formulate and implement an emergency preparedness plan, which shall provide for: (1) the creation in the office of the superintendent or other chief executive officer of the local educational agency or district of a School Emergency Response Center; (2) the creation of a Regional Advisory Council; and (3) the development of a plan specific to each school under the local educational agency's or district's authority for each type of emergency likely to occur in the area. Permits remaining funds to be used for any purpose relating to emergency preparedness planning or implementation.</summary>
</bill>
