<bill session="110" type="h" number="5442" updated="2013-07-19T21:51:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Technologies for Restoring Users' Security and Trust in Health Information Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TRUST in Health Information Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide individuals with access to health information of which they are a subject, to ensure personal privacy, security, and confidentiality with respect to health related information in promoting the development of a nationwide interoperable health information infrastructure, to impose criminal and civil penalties for unauthorized use of personal health information, to provide for the strong enforcement of these rights, to protect States' rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2008-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E199"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Labor, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Technologies for Restoring Users' Security and Trust in Health Information Act of 2008 or the TRUST in Health Information Act of 2008 - Sets forth rights of individuals to protect their personal health information, including the right to inspect and copy such information. Sets forth obligations of a person that discloses, uses, or receives an individual's personal health information, including notification if the security of such information is breached.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and disseminate guidelines for the establishment of safeguards and procedures for use under this Act.Prohibits a person from disclosing, accessing, or using personal health information except as authorized under this Act.Requires the Secretary to designate an Office of Health Information Privacy within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to investigate complaints of alleged violations of this Act.Requires the Secretary to establish and implement standards for health information technology products.Provides for whistleblower protection.Establishes: (1) the Office of the National Coordinator of Health Information Technology; (2) the public-private Partnership for Health Care Improvement to make recommendations concerning standards for the electronic exchange of personal health information; and (3) the American Health Information Community to make recommendations concerning policies to support the widespread adoption of health information technology.Provides for health information technology grants.Requires the Secretary to develop and use health care quality measures.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), to develop a Health Information Technology Resource Center to provide technical assistance and develop best practices for interoperable health information technology.Prohibits the expenditure of federal funds for the purchase of any new health information technology that is not consistent with applicable federal standards.</summary>
</bill>
