<bill session="112" type="s" number="2106" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Josh Miller HEARTS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Josh Miller Helping Everyone Access Responsive Treatment in Schools Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program for automated external defibrillators in elementary schools and secondary schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1377"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2012--Introduced.
Josh Miller Helping Everyone Access Responsive Treatment in Schools Act of 2012 or Josh Miller HEARTS Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to: (1) purchase automated external defibrillators (AEDs) for use in their schools, and/or (2) provide training to meet the grant requirement that at least five adult employees or volunteers at each school where an AED is to be used successfully complete training in its use and in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR). Requires LEA grant applicants also to demonstrate that: (1) the AEDs are integrated into the schools' emergency response procedures, and (2) emergency services personnel are notified of their locations. Gives grant priority to schools that: (1) lack an AED; (2) typically have a significant number of students, staff, and visitors present during the day; (3) generally have a longer wait for emergency medical services than other public facilities in the community; and (4) have not received funds under the Rural Access to Emergency Devices Act.</summary>
</bill>
