<bill session="112" type="s" number="1468" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to diabetes self-management training by authorizing certified diabetes educators to provide diabetes self-management training services, including as part of telehealth services, under part B of the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2787"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
Medicare Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2011 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to recognize state-licensed or -registered health care professionals who are certified diabetes educators in an outpatient setting as authorized providers of Medicare diabetes outpatient self-management training services, including as part of telehealth services, under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance). Directs the Comptroller General to study the barriers that exist for Medicare beneficiaries with diabetes in accessing diabetes self-management training services under the Medicare program. Directs the Director of the Agency for Health Care Research and Quality of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a series of recommendations on effective outreach methods to educate primary care physicians and the public about the benefits of diabetes self-management training.</summary>
</bill>
