<bill session="109" type="h" number="630" updated="2013-07-19T19:09:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal lands to the City of Yuma, Arizona, in exchange for certain lands owned by the City of Yuma, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, within two years of the enactment of this Act, to execute an agreement with the city of Yuma, Arizona, and pursuant to its terms, to convey to the City all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified Federal lands, subject to: (1) the City conveying by warranty deed to the United States specified lands owned by the City (known as the Railroad Parcels) to the United States; (2) the City and the Yuma County Water Users Association executing and fulfilling all the terms of a separately negotiated Letter of Agreement between the Association and the City with regard to the relocation of the Yuma County Water Users Association facility from certain of those Federal lands; and (3) the fulfillment of any other terms and conditions the Secretary considers appropriate to protect U.S. interests.</summary>
</bill>
