<bill session="110" type="h" number="554" updated="2013-07-19T21:08:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paleontological Resources Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Paleontological Resources Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the protection of paleontological resources on Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-18">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-18">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-670, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 20, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 18, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than July 18, 2008 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(k), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-18T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Aug. 1, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-18T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Aug. 1, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 12, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 12, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-12T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 26, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-12T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 26, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 28, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 28, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T20:27:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 29, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T20:27:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 29, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 2, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 2, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 3, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 3, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Jan. 3, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-03T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Jan. 3, 2009.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="320"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="320"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fossils"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2008--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Paleontological Resources Preservation Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate, to: (1) manage and protect paleontological resources on federal land, using scientific principles and expertise; and (2) develop plans for inventorying, monitoring, and deriving the scientific and educational use of such resources. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to establish a program to increase public awareness about such resources. (Sec. 5) Prohibits a person from collecting a paleontological resource from federal land without a permit issued under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to allow casual collecting of a reasonable amount of common invertebrate and plant paleontological resources for non-commercial personal uses without a permit on certain federal lands. Recognizes as valid permits issued before enactment of this Act. Sets forth criteria by which the Secretary may issue permits for paleontological resources. Requires that any paleontological resource and associated records collected under a permit be deposited in an approved repository. Allows the Secretary to modify, suspend, or revoke a permit under specified circumstances, including if there is a violation of a term or a condition of a permit. Declares that a permit shall be revoked if any person working under the authority of the permit is convicted of a criminal offense under this Act or assessed a civil penalty under this Act. (Sec. 6) States that the Secretary may enter into agreements with non-federal repositories regarding the curation of paleontological resources, data, and records. (Sec. 7) Prohibits: (1) evacuating, removing, or altering a paleontological resource located on federal lands, except in accordance with this Act; (2) exchanging or receiving a paleontological resource, or selling or purchasing a paleontological resource, if the person knew or should have known such resource was illegally removed from federal lands; or (3) making or submitting false records, accounts, or identification of any paleontological resource excavated or removed from federal lands. Imposes criminal penalties for violating this Act. (Sec. 8) Sets forth requirements for the assessment of civil penalties by the Secretary for violations of any prohibitions contained in regulations or permits issued under this Act. Requires any recovered amounts to be available for use: (1) to protect or restore paleontological resources and sites which were the subject of the action, or to acquire sites with equivalent resources, and to protect, monitor, and study the resources and sites; (2) to provide educational materials to the public about paleontological resources and sites; and (3) as a reward. (Sec. 9) Allows the Secretary to pay a reward from penalties collected under this Act to any person who furnishes information leading to the finding of a civil violation, or the conviction of criminal violation, with respect to which the penalty was paid. Subjects to civil or, as appropriate, criminal forfeiture all paleontological resources with respect to which a violation occurred and all vehicles and equipment that were used in connection with the violation. Allows the Secretary to transfer administration of seized paleontological resources to educational institutions for scientific or educational purposes. (Sec. 10) Requires that information on the nature and specific location of a paleontological resource that requires a permit under this Act or other federal law be withheld from the public, including under the Freedom of Information Act, except under specified conditions. (Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to issue such regulations as are appropriate to carry out this Act.(Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
