<bill session="113" type="s" number="832" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving the Lives of Children with Spina Bifida Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out pilot programs on furnishing case management services and assisted living to children of Vietnam veterans and certain Korea service veterans born with spina bifida and children of women Vietnam veterans born with certain birth defects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Improving the Lives of Children with Spina Bifida Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a three-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing contracted case management services (services) to individuals entitled to VA benefits as children of Vietnam and Korean War veterans born with spina bifida, and children of women Vietnam veterans born with certain birth defects who live in a rural area and have no access to such services through the VA or otherwise. Authorizes the Secretary to extend the program for an additional two years. Allows the services to include the coordination and management of needed health care, monetary, general care, and transportation services. Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify eligible individuals, and (2) contract with an appropriate entity for the provision of such services. Directs the Secretary to carry out an additional pilot program (for the same period and with the same authorized extension) to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing assisted living, group home care or similar services, and transportation to the individuals described above. Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify eligible individuals, and (2) consider entering into an agreement with the appropriate service providers. Requires preliminary and final reports with respect to, and provides funding for, each pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
