<bill session="109" type="s" number="2318" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Teen and Novice Driver Uniform Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STANDUP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide driver safety grants to States with graduated driver licensing laws that meet certain minimum requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2006-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1434-1435"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1435-1436" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="795"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Safe Teen and Novice Driver Uniform Protection Act of 2006 or the STANDUP Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to award incentive grants to states with graduated driver licensing laws that include for novice drivers under age 21: (1) a three-stage licensing process (including a learner's permit stage and an intermediate stage before an unrestricted driver's license is granted); (2) a prohibition on nighttime driving during the intermediate stage; (3) a prohibition (during the learner's permit and intermediate stages) against operating a motor vehicle with more than one non-familial passenger under age 21 if there is no licensed driver 21 years old or older present in the vehicle; (4) a prohibition (during the learner's permit and intermediate stages) on the use of a cellular telephone or any communications device in non-emergency situations; and (5) any other requirement that the Secretary may require. Directs the Secretary to withhold a certain amount of federal-aid highway funds from states that are not in compliance with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
