<bill session="111" type="s" number="3230" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NEPA Certainty Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the use of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to document, predict, or mitigate the climate effects of specific Federal actions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2010-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5342"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2010--Introduced.
NEPA Certainty Act - Declares that the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) should not be used to document, predict, or mitigate the climate effects of specific federal actions. Provides that compliance with NEPA does not include consideration of: (1) the greenhouse gas emissions, or any climate change effects of those emissions, of a proposed action and alternative actions; or (2) the relationship of climate change effects to a proposed action or alternatives, including the relationship to proposal design, environmental impacts, mitigation, and adaptation measures. Declares that this Act does not preempt or interfere with: (1) any authority to consider the climate change effects of proposed legislation or regulations specifically addressing greenhouse gas emissions; or (2) requirements to consider the potential effects of climate change on proposals for agency action during planning or design processes under provisions of law other than NEPA.</summary>
</bill>
