<bill session="110" type="s" number="1179" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Superfund Equity and Megasite Remediation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the financing for Superfund for purposes of cleanup activities with respect to those Superfund sites for which removal and remedial action is estimated to cost more than $50,000,000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4813"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1887"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1887"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Pollution taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2007--Introduced.
Superfund Equity and Megasite Remediation Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reinstate the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate and the corporate environmental income tax, except in certain calendar quarters in which the unobligated balance in the Hazardous Substance Superfund exceeds $5.7 billion. Provides for a 50% increase in the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate and the corporate environmental income tax between 2008 and 2013 to fund response actions at Superfund sites estimated to cost more than $50 million (megasites) or which pose high health risks.Establishes the Megasites and High Risk Sites Cleanup Account in the Hazardous Substance Superfund. Transfers to such Account revenues resulting from the temporary 50% increase in the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate and the corporate environmental income tax.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to report to Congress annually on the progress of response actions funded by the Hazardous Substance Superfund.</summary>
</bill>
