<bill session="111" type="h" number="6566" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preventing Sex Offenders Access to Children in Our Communities Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect children from registered sex offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2010-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="4029"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Introduced.
Preventing Sex Offenders Access to Children in Our Communities Act of 2010 - Amends the Sex Offender Notification and Registration Act to require jurisdictions subject to such Act (i.e., states, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and certain Indian tribes) to prohibit registered sex offenders from: (1) accepting a position of employment, including a volunteer position, which by the inherent nature of the position places such sex offender in direct and substantial contact with minors; or (2) obtaining a permit or permission to carry out an activity or performance that would present direct and substantial contact with minors. Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants and enter into contracts with public agencies or nonprofit private organizations to establish a community accessible sex offender tips and support program to provide for anonymous or confidential tips regarding sex offenders who are not complying with registration or other applicable requirements. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) coordinate with the head of each executive agency to determine which government publications could be made available on government web sites and no longer printed; (2) devise a strategy to reduce overall government printing costs by not less than $15 million over a five-year period beginning with FY2011; and (3) ensure that essential printed documents continue to be made available to Social Security and Medicare beneficiaries and individuals living in areas with limited Internet access or use.</summary>
</bill>
