<bill session="112" type="h" number="1042" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DELIST Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Discredit Eternal Listing Inequality of Species Takings Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require that certain species be treated as extinct for purposes of that Act if there is not a substantial increase in the population of a species during the 15-year period beginning on the date the species is determined to be an endangered species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2011-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2011-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2011-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2011-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2011--Introduced.
Discredit Eternal Listing Inequality of Species Takings Act or the DELIST Act - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) to treat a limited listed species as extinct for purposes of this Act upon the expiration of the 15-year period beginning on the date it is determined by the Secretary of the Interior to be an endangered species, unless the Secretary publishes a finding that: (1) there has been a substantial increase in the population of the species during that period; or (2) the continued listing of the species does not impose any economic hardship on communities located in the range of the species. Defines "limited listed species" as any species that is listed as an endangered species for which it is not reasonably possible to determine whether the species has been extirpated from the range of the species that existed on the date the species was listed because not all individuals of the species were identified at the time of such listing.</summary>
</bill>
