<bill session="109" type="s" number="2506" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Places Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require Federal agencies to support health impact assessments and take other actions to improve health and the environmental quality of communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2006-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2805"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5088"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2006--Introduced.
Healthy Places Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an interagency working group to discuss environmental health concerns, particularly concerns disproportionately affecting disadvantaged populations. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to establish a program at the National Center of Environmental Health at CDC focused on advancing the field of health impact assessment. Requires the Director to develop guidance for the assessment of potential health effects of land use, housing, and transportation policy and plans. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to: (1) establish a program to provide funding and technical assistance to state or local governments affected or potentially affected by an activity or proposed activity to prepare health impact assessments; and (2) establish and maintain a health impact assessment database. Requires the Director to establish a grant program to award grants to state or local communities for environmental health improvement activities. Requires grantees to: (1) establish a planning and prioritizing council; and (2) conduct environmental health assessment. Requires the Secretary to provide grants to public or private nonprofit institutions to conduct and coordinate research on the built environment and its influence on individual and population-based health.</summary>
</bill>
