<bill session="109" type="h" number="3919" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act to enhance the reliability of the electricity grid and reduce the threat of wildfires to electric transmission and distribution facilities on Federal lands by authorizing vegetation management on such lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to direct the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, with respect to public lands under their respective jurisdictions, to ensure that existing and future authorizations of rights-of-way and easements for electrical transmission and distribution facilities (facilities) on such lands include provisions for utility vegetation management activities that enhance the reliability of the electricity grid and reduce the threat of wildfires to such facilities. Directs such Secretaries to provide owners and operators of such facilities on such lands with the option to develop and submit an integrated vegetation management plan for approval. Outlines a plan review, approval, and implementation process. Allows such owners and operators to conduct vegetation management activities to meet facilities' clearance requirements. Provides a liability waiver when the appropriate Secretary fails to allow such owners and operators to manage vegetation within a right-of-way or easement on such lands, with an exception in the case of contributory negligence. Encourages such Secretaries to develop a program to train appropriate federal personnel involved in vegetation management decisions relating to such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
