<bill session="111" type="h" number="5789" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SDHV Energy Efficiency Standards for America Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create clean energy jobs and set efficiency standards for small-duct high-velocity air conditioning and heat pump systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400638"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2010--Introduced.
SDHV Energy Efficiency Standards for America Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to revise energy conservation standards for central air conditioners and central air conditioning heat pumps by requiring: (1) the seasonal energy efficiency ratio of small-duct, high-velocity systems to be no less than 11.00 for products manufactured on or after January 23, 2006; and (2) the heating seasonal performance factor of such systems to be 6.8 for products manufactured on or after such date. Defines "small-duct, high-velocity systems" to mean a heating and cooling product that contains a blower and indoor coil combination that: (1) is designed for, and produces, at least 1.2 inches of external static pressure when operated at the certified air volume rate of 220-350 cubic feet per minute per rated ton of cooling; and (2) when applied in the field, uses high velocity room outlets generally greater than 1,000 feet per minute that have less than 6.0 square inches of free area. Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to amend by rule the standards established for such systems. Prohibits amended standards from taking effect less than five years after the final rule making the amendment is published. Requires the Secretary to determine whether standards for such systems should be amended no later than June 30, 2011. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to include within the definition of "energy-efficient building property" for purposes of the tax credit for nonbusiness energy property a small-duct, high-velocity central air conditioning and heat pump system. Allow such credit through December 31, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
