<bill session="113" type="s" number="480" updated="2013-11-02T06:56:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NICS Reporting Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the effectiveness of the National Instant Criminal Background Check System by clarifying reporting requirements related to adjudications of mental incompetency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-03-18" withdrawn="2013-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2013--Introduced.
NICS Reporting Improvement Act of 2013 - Amends federal firearms provisions to define a person who has been adjudicated mentally incompetent or who has been committed to a psychiatric hospital as a person who is the subject of an order or finding issued by a court, board, commission, or other adjudicative body (after a hearing of which the person received actual notice and at which the person had an opportunity to participate with counsel) that found that the person, as a result of marked subnormal intelligence, mental impairment, or mental illness: (1) was an imminent danger to himself or others, (2) was guilty but mentally ill in a criminal case, (3) was not guilty in a criminal case by reason of insanity or mental disease or defect, (4) was incompetent to stand trial in a criminal case, (5) was not guilty only by reason of lack of mental responsibility under the Uniform Code of Military Justice, (6) required involuntary inpatient treatment by a psychiatric hospital, (7) required involuntary outpatient treatment by a psychiatric hospital based on a finding that the person was an imminent danger to himself or others, or (8) required involuntary commitment to a psychiatric hospital for any reason, including drug use. Excludes: (1) a person who is in a psychiatric hospital for observation or due to a voluntary admission, and (2) an order or finding that has expired, that has been set aside or expunged, or that is no longer applicable. Defines "psychiatric hospital" to include a mental health facility, mental hospital, sanitarium, psychiatric facility, and any other facility that provides diagnoses by licensed professionals of mental retardation or mental illness, including a psychiatric ward in a general hospital. Prohibits: (1) the sale or other disposition of a firearm or ammunition to any person knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that such person has been adjudicated mentally incompetent (currently, mental defective) or has been committed to a psychiatric hospital (currently, to any mental institution); and (2) the shipment, transport, or possession in interstate or foreign commerce of a firearm or ammunition by, or the receipt of a firearm or ammunition which has been shipped or transported in such commerce by, any such person. Makes conforming amendments to the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007.</summary>
</bill>
