<bill session="110" type="s" number="2789" updated="2013-07-19T22:45:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006 to authorize the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide additional assistance to State and local governments for utility costs resulting from the provision of temporary housing units to evacuees from Hurricane Katrina and other hurricanes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Disaster Recovery.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA11" subcommittee="Disaster Recovery (Ad Hoc)" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="858"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="517"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="523"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Public utility rates"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2008--Introduced.
Amends the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006 to extend the authority of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide funds to state and local governments for utility costs resulting from the provision of temporary housing units to evacuees from Hurricane Katrina and other hurricanes of the 2005 season where the state or local government has previously arranged to pay for such utilities on behalf of the evacuees, to cover the term of any leases for up to 36 months (currently, 24 months) contracted by or prior to February 7, 2006.</summary>
</bill>
