<bill session="112" type="s" number="823" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Public Schools Through Promoting Foreign Investment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permit aliens who lawfully enter the United States on valid visas as nonimmigrant elementary and secondary school students to attend public schools in the United States for longer than 1 year if such aliens reimburse the local educational agency that administers the school for the full, unsubsidized per capita cost of providing education at such school for the period of the alien's attendance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Public Schools Through Promoting Foreign Investment Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit a lawful alien who enters the United States on a nonimmigrant student visa (including Mexican and Canadian commuter students) to attend a U.S. public secondary school for longer than one year if such alien reimburses the local educational agency for the full, unsubsidized per capita cost of providing education at such school for the period of the alien's attendance.</summary>
</bill>
