<bill session="109" type="s" number="2007" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Commission on Health Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to examine the circumstances contributing to the problems facing the health care system of the United States and to develop public and private policies as appropriate to address rising health care costs and the number of uninsured Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2005--Introduced.
National Commission on Health Care Act - Establishes in the legislative branch the National Commission on Health Care to conduct a study that investigates: (1) problems within the sphere of health care; (2) the rising costs of health care; (3) the impact of such rising costs on American businesses; (4) the provision of health care by state and local health care agencies; (5) the effects of increases in insurance premiums on health care coverage for businesses; (6) the private health insurance industry; (7) public health programs; (8) innovations and reforms necessary to increase the provision of affordable, quality health care to all Americans; (9) the role of congressional oversight and resource allocation; and (10) other relevant areas of the public and private sectors. Directs the Commission to identify, review, evaluate, and report on the lessons learned from past legislative structuring of health care, coordination, management policies, and procedures of the federal government and, when appropriate, state and local governments and nongovernmental entities relative to administering, representing, implementing, and receiving health care .</summary>
</bill>
