<bill session="110" type="s" number="748" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center in New York, New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1455"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Anthropology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2007--Introduced.
African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center Act - Establishes the African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center at the African Burial Ground National Monument in the city of New York, New York. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service (NPS), to: (1) acquire for the Museum property that is located adjacent to the National Monument or in any other area of the African Burial Ground National Historic Landmark in the city other than the location adjacent to the Monument; (2) plan, design, and construct the Museum on the acquired property. Provides for operation of the Museum by the Secretary. Establishes within the Department of the Interior the African Burial Ground Advisory Council to: (1) make recommendations to the Secretary on the planning, design, and construction of the Museum; and (2) advise and assist the Secretary on all matters relating to the administration, operation, maintenance, and preservation of the Museum. Requires: (1) the Secretary to appoint a Director for the Museum; and (2) the Director of the Museum to manage such Museum.</summary>
</bill>
