<bill session="109" type="h" number="5363" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Natural Disaster Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to agricultural producers for crop and livestock losses resulting from recent, catastrophic natural disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400442" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2006-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2006-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2006-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2006-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5099"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2438"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Anthrax"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Horticulture"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Nuts"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2006--Introduced.
Natural Disaster Relief Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide emergency financial assistance to eligible agricultural producers (other than sugar cane and sugar beet producers) who have incurred qualifying: (1) 2005 crop losses due to weather or related conditions (including crop disease, insects, and delayed harvest); and (2) 2006 crop losses due to weather or related conditions (including crop disease, insects, and delayed harvest) with respect to which a natural disaster declaration has been made. Requires a producer who suffered qualifying losses to elect assistance for one but not both years. Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) payments through the 2002 livestock compensation program for livestock disaster losses during calendar years 2005 and 2006 for losses that occurred prior to of enactment of this Act (including wildfire disaster losses in Texas and other states); (2) livestock indemnity payments to producers who have incurred 2005 and 2006 livestock disaster losses prior to enactment of this Act (including wildfire disaster losses in Texas and other states), including losses due to hurricanes, floods, wildfires, and anthrax. Requires a livestock producer who suffered qualifying losses to elect assistance for one but not both years. Directs the Secretary to provide indemnity payments to poultry producers in hurricane-affected counties. Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) sugarcane and sugar beet disaster assistance for qualifying producers and first processors in Louisiana counties designated as disaster areas due to Hurricanes Katrina or Rita, or related conditions, or to qualifying producers and first processors in Florida for 2005 losses due to hurricanes, floods, rain, or storms; (2) assistance to sugarcane growers in Texas (for additional Baton Rouge demurrage costs and raw sugar transportation and storage costs) and Hawaii (for an agricultural transportation cooperative); (3) assistance to specialty and nursery crop producers in hurricane-affected counties; (4) assistance to tree producers (including Christmas, potted, ornamental, and nursery trees, shrubs, and vines), and fruit and nut tree producers in hurricane-affected counties; (5) assistance to dairy producers for production and spoilage losses in hurricane-affected counties; (6) assistance to producers and first handlers of cottonseed; (7) emergency watershed protection and emergency conservation program activities; and (8) assistance for additional conservation-related technical assistance in each state that has a disaster or hurricane-affected county. Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial and technical assistance to remove debris and animal carcasses that could adversely affect health and safety on non-federal land in hurricane-affected counties. Directs the Secretary to hire additional state and county Farm Service Agency personnel to assist in agricultural disaster and economic assistance programs. Defines "hurricane-affected county" as: (1) a county covered by a natural disaster designation related to Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, or Wilma, or related condition; and (2) a contiguous county.</summary>
</bill>
