<bill session="111" type="h" number="4896" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iran Proliferation Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the President to utilize the Proliferation Security Initiative and all other measures for the purpose of interdicting the import into or export from Iran by the Government of Iran or any other country, entity, or person of all items, materials, equipment, goods and technology useful for any nuclear, biological, chemical, missile, or conventional arms program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2010-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2010--Introduced.
Iran Proliferation Prevention Act - Authorizes the President to: (1) utilize the Proliferation Security Initiative and other measures to enforce all U.S. laws and Executive Orders, all United Nations (U.N.) Security Council resolutions, and all international, multilateral, and bilateral agreements, including the 2005 Protocol to the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts Against the Safety of Maritime Navigation to interdict the import into or export from Iran of materials, equipment, goods and technology useful to any nuclear, biological, chemical, missile, or conventional arms program; and (2) negotiate and utilize ship boarding and other interdiction agreements with countries determined to interdict the import or export of such items. Requires the President to report periodically to Congress on: (1) the identity of all known countries (including Iran), entities, and persons that have engaged in the import into or export from Iran of items useful to any nuclear, biological, chemical, missile, or conventional arms program; (2) any countries, entities, and persons that have violated U.S. laws, U.N. Security Council resolutions, international treaties, conventions, and other agreements prohibiting the import into or export from Iran of such items; (3) measures taken by the United States, or in cooperation with other countries or international organizations, to hold violators accountable; and (4) the interdiction assistance actions taken by foreign governments during the preceding 120-day period.</summary>
</bill>
