<bill session="110" type="h" number="6456" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for extensions of certain authorities of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7336" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6456.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-07-30T10:42:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7336" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-08">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8141" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-09-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2008-09-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-09-19">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-09-19" type="public" number="110-321">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-321.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2008--Public Law.
(Sec. 1) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to extend for one year the Secretary of State's authority to waive Foreign Service annuitant salary and full-time employment pension restrictions respecting assignment to: (1) consular posts with a substantial visa application backlog; and (2) Iraq and Afghanistan. (Sec. 2) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to permit rest and recuperation travel for Foreign Service members and family members to U.S. territories, including American Samoa, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the U.S. Virgin Islands. Specifies that required leave based upon continuous service abroad may be taken in the United States or its territories, including American Samoa, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the U.S. Virgin Islands. (Current law refers to the United States, its territories and possessions, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.) (Sec. 3) Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to specify that the Secretary may pay the subsistence expenses of Department of State special agents on authorized protective missions at or away from their duty stations. (Sec. 4) Amends the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 to extend grant authority for Radio Free Asia for one year. (Sec. 5) Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 to extend for one year the International Broadcasting Bureau personal services contracting pilot program under which U.S. citizens or aliens are hired as personal services contractors, without regard to Civil Service and classification laws.</summary>
</bill>
