<bill session="111" type="h" number="2369" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving the Quality of Mental and Substance Use Health Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve mental and substance use health care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2009--Introduced.
Improving the Quality of Mental and Substance Use Health Care Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish the Commission for Evidence-Based Mental and Substance Use Health Care; (2) convene an interagency collaborative group to coordinate mental health and substance use services and primary care services; (3) change Medicaid reimbusement rules to cover same-day visits for primary care services and mental health and substance use services; (4) implement a plan for ensuring that Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) activities promote health information technology that is accessible and pertinent to mental health and substance use health care providers and consumers; and (5) establish the Council on the Mental Health and Substance Use Health Care Workforce. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to make grants for a network of national centers of excellence in mental health and substance use health care. Requires specified federal programs that provide mental health and substance use care to pay for peer support and illness self-management programs and provide for appropriate payment and coverage reforms. Directs the Secretary to develop uniform methodologies related to payments for mental illnesses and substance use disorders. Requires the Comptroller General to study the use of publicly-supported mental health and addiction services by individuals with private health insurance coverage. Directs the Secretary to establish a five-year project to demonstrate the impact of creating delivery and financing structures that deliver high-quality, integrated, mental health and substance use health care. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require states to prohibit discrimination against patients being treated for, or health care providers providing treatment for, any medical condition, illness, or injury involving intoxication as a result of alcohol or other substance.</summary>
</bill>
