<bill session="112" type="s" number="3416" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stronger Enforcement of Civil Penalties Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance civil penalties under the Federal securities laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5259-5260"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5260-5262" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2012--Introduced.
Stronger Enforcement of Civil Penalties Act of 2012 - Amends the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, the Investment Company Act of 1940, and the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to increase the money penalties in administrative and civil actions involving securities laws violations. Prescribes a fourth tier penalty of triple monetary penalties for noncompliance with certain enforcement actions if the violator, within the five-year period preceding the prohibited act, was criminally convicted for securities fraud or became subject to a judgment or order imposing monetary, equitable, or administrative relief in any Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) action alleging fraud by such violator. Applies the treatment as a separate offense each day that a violation of an SEC cease-and-desist order is committed through continuing noncompliance to violation of any action to enforce a federal court injunction or certain SEC orders that bar, suspend, place limitations on the activities or functions of, or prohibit the activities of, a person.</summary>
</bill>
