<bill session="111" type="s" number="1638" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Amtrak Secure Transportation of Firearms Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permit Amtrak passengers to safely transport firearms and ammunition in their checked baggage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2009-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3789"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3789"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Amtrak Secure Transportation of Firearms Act - Requires Amtrak, at a station that accepts checked baggage for a specific Amtrak route, to allow a passenger holding a ticket for such route to place an unloaded firearm or starter pistol in a bag that has been checked at the station if: (1) before checking the bag or boarding the train, the passenger declares to Amtrak that an unloaded firearm is in his or her checked bag; (2) the firearm is carried in a locked hard-sided container; and (3) only the passenger has the key or combination to such container. Allows an Amtrak passenger to place small arms ammunition for personal use in a checked bag on an Amtrak route if the ammunition is securely packed in specified kinds of boxes or other packaging specifically designed to carry such ammunition. Prohibits the application of such requirements in any fiscal year in which Amtrak does not receive federal assistance.</summary>
</bill>
