<bill session="111" type="s" number="789" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tule River Tribe Water Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study on the feasibility and suitability of constructing a storage reservoir, outlet works, and a delivery system for the Tule River Indian Tribe of the Tule River Reservation in the State of California to provide a water supply for domestic, municipal, industrial, and agricultural purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-91.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1945"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Tule River Tribe Water Development Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to complete a feasibility study to evaluate alternatives for a domestic, commercial, municipal, industrial, and irrigation water supply for the Tule River Tribe of the Tule River Reservation, California. Prohibits any project constructed relating to that study from providing water supply for the casino of the Tule River Tribe or any other tribal casino or any lodging, dining, entertainment, meeting space, parking, or other similar facility in support of a gaming activity. Provides that a water supply provided by a project constructed relating to the feasibility study shall be available to serve: (1) the domestic, municipal, and governmental (including firefighting) needs of the Tribe; and (2) other commercial, agricultural, and industrial needs not related to gaming.</summary>
</bill>
