<bill session="112" type="s" number="170" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Responsible Homeowners Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the affordable refinancing of mortgages held by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S228"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Housing, Transportation and Community Development. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-382.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSBK09" subcommittee="Housing, Transportation, and Community Development" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="363"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Helping Responsible Homeowners Act -&#160;Directs the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government-sponsored enterprises or GSEs) each to carry out a one-year program providing for the refinancing of qualified single-family housing mortgages it owns through a refinancing mortgage (and for the purchase of and securitization of such refinancing mortgages) in accordance with this Act and the policies and procedures of the Federal Housing Finance Agency. Defines a qualified mortgage as one that: (1) is an existing first mortgage for purchase of, or refinancing another first mortgage on, a one- to four-family dwelling, including a condominium or a share in a cooperative ownership housing association, that is occupied by the mortgagor as principal residence; (2) is owned or guaranteed by the particular GSE; and (3) the mortgagor is current on payments due under the mortgage.&#160; Specifies the terms and conditions of a refinancing mortgage, including a 40-year term to maturity and a prohibition on borrower fees. Requires waiver or forgiveness of all fees and penalties related to any default or delinquency on the original mortgage. Prohibits the GSEs from charging a mortgagee any up-front fee beyond the standard guarantee fee for the refinancing of the qualified mortgage. Makes ineligible for purchase or guarantee by either GSE of any new mortgage originated by a servicer or creditor holding a second lien on a qualified mortgage who refuses to resubordinate that lien, and thereby prevents the refinancing of the qualified mortgage. Directs the GSEs to require each servicer of a mortgage owned or guaranteed by the GSE to inform each mortgage borrower of the refinancing program authorized and established under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
