<bill session="112" type="h" number="3611" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Job Opportunities and Business Success Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to increase business engagement and improve training opportunities for occupations that are in-demand in order to get Americans back to work.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-03-01" withdrawn="2012-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4297"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4297"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Introduced.
Local Job Opportunities and Business Success Act of 2011 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to limit the required composition of local workforce investment boards (local boards) to business representatives. Requires two-thirds of the members of a local board to be business owners or officers. Requires local boards to conduct and regularly update analyses of: (1) local economic conditions, (2) immediate and long-term skilled workforce needs in the area, (3) the knowledge and skills of the local workforce, and (4) local workforce development activities. Requires local boards to lead efforts to engage employers in the area to ensure that workforce investment activities meet their needs and support local economic growth. Includes as part of those efforts the development or implementation of industry or sector partnerships that lead to collaborative planning, resource alignment, and training efforts across multiple firms to address the immediate and long-term skilled workforce needs of the local economy. Requires local boards to develop strategies for using technological improvements to facilitate access to workforce development services. Eliminates the requirement that each local board appoint a youth council as a subgroup of the board and select providers of youth activities on the basis of its recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
