<bill session="112" type="s" number="1303" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Monroe National Historical Park Establishment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish Fort Monroe National Historical Park in the Commonwealth of Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2011-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-224.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2456"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2011--Introduced.
Fort Monroe National Historical Park Establishment Act of 2011 - Establishes the Fort Monroe National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park System in Virginia. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with the Commonwealth of Virginia or any other party under which the Secretary may identify, interpret, and provide assistance for the preservation of non-federal properties within the boundary of the Park or in the historic area. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a partnership agreement with the Fort Monroe Foundation that would benefit the preservation and interpretation of resources within the Park. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance and public interpretation of resources within the historic area and at any sites in close proximity to the Park outside of such area that are related to events or persons associated with the Fort , including encampments and cemeteries of formerly enslaved persons freed at the Fort during the Civil War. Allows the Secretary to provide for the coordination of interpretation between the Park and the Captain John Smith Chesapeake National Historic Trail for any resources within the Park that may relate to the Trail. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to enter into an interagency agreement for the long-term protection and public interpretation of the Old Point Comfort Lighthouse. Requires the Secretary to complete a general management plan for the Park.</summary>
</bill>
