<bill session="111" type="s" number="2961" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-05">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haiti Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Haiti Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Haiti Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide debt relief to Haiti, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2010-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with amendments. With written report No. 111-128.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-02-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="276">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 276.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-03-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1239-1240" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1239" label="text as reported in Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1239-1240" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09T19:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Haiti Recovery Act - Urges the Secretary of the Treasury to direct the U.S. Executive Director to each international financial institution to advocate: (1) the cancellation of all remaining debt obligations of Haiti, including obligations incurred before the date of enactment of this Act; (2) the provision of debt service relief for all payments of Haiti remaining on the date of enactment of this Act; and (3) that through February 1, 2012, new assistance to Haiti should be primarily grants. Expresses the sense of the Senate that international financial institutions should cancel any debt incurred by Haiti after the date of enactment of this Act and before February 1, 2012, so that Haiti can rebuild after the devastation of the January 2010 earthquake. Urges the Secretary to: (1) instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to advocate the use of certain proceeds to provide debt stock relief, debt service relief, loan subsidies, and grants for Haiti; (2) support the creation of a multilateral trust fund for Haiti that would leverage U.S. contributions and promote bilateral donations for investing in Haiti's future; and (3) require the U.S. Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank to seek to increase earnings transfer to the Fund for Special Operations and to a trust fund or grant facility for Haiti. Urges the Secretary and the Secretary of State to use all appropriate diplomatic influence to secure cancellation of all remaining bilateral debt of Haiti.</summary>
</bill>
