<bill session="111" type="s" number="1003" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Immunization Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase immunization rates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5287-5288"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5288-5290" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2009--Introduced.
Immunization Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) allow states to purchase vaccines recommended for routine use at rates negotiated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS); (2) require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish a demonstration program to improve the delivery of vaccines recommended for routine use; (3) reauthorize the program for free immunizations for children, adolescents, and adults; (4) require group health plans to provide coverage for routine immunizations without cost sharing (i.e., copayments or deductibles); and (5) require the improvement and expansion of immunization information systems as part of the health information technology infrastructure. Amends the Social Security Act to provide: (1) Medicare and Medicaid coverage for vaccines recommended for routine use; and (2) reimbursement to health care providers for administering vaccines to children under the Vaccines for Children program. Requires the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the CDC Director to jointly review and update the regional maximum charge for state vaccine administration established under the Vaccines for Children program.</summary>
</bill>
