<bill session="110" type="h" number="5463" updated="2013-07-19T21:51:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securities Litigation Attorney Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect investors by fostering transparency and accountability of attorneys in private securities litigation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2008-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3931"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3033"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal advertising and soliciting"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Securities Litigation Attorney Accountability and Transparency Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Securities Act of 1933 to state that, in any private action in which the court enters a final judgment against plaintiff on the basis of a motion to dismiss, motion for summary judgment, or a trial on the merits, the court shall, upon defendant's motion, determine whether: (1) the position of the plaintiff was not substantially justified; (2) imposition of fees and expenses on the plaintiff's attorney would be just; and (3) the cost of such fees and expenses to the defendant is substantially burdensome or unjust.Requires the court to award the defendant reasonable fees and other expenses, and impose such fees and expenses on the plaintiff's attorney, if the court makes positive determinations in such a case.Places the burden of persuasion upon the defendant as to whether or not the position of the plaintiff was substantially justified.Requires plaintiff and plaintiff's attorney to provide sworn, signed certifications that identify any actual or promised payment by the attorney to the plaintiff, beyond the plaintiff's pro rata share of any recovery.Requires similar plaintiff and plaintiff's attorney certifications regarding: (1) legal representations; (2) contributions; and (3) conflicts of interest.Requires the court, in exercising discretion over the approval of lead counsel, to employ a competitive bidding process as one of the criteria (unless the court determines that such a process is not feasible). Instructs the Comptroller General to study and report to certain congressional committees on average hourly fees in securities class actions.</summary>
</bill>
