<bill session="112" type="s" number="927" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agency Overreach Moratorium Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require congressional approval before implementation of certain agency actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2011--Introduced.
Agency Overreach Moratorium Act - Prohibits a federal agency from: (1) retroactively withdrawing any permit issued for federal land or any area of the outer Continental Shelf that would have been used to produce or harvest a domestic natural resource or to create one or more jobs, or (2) issuing a designation under any law that would restrict or prohibit access to those resources on such land or any such area, unless approved by an Act of Congress. Prohibits the implementation of a proclamation issued under the Antiquities Act of 1906 for the designation of a national monument unless approved by an Act of Congress. Bars a federal agency from taking any action to modify its authority with respect to issuing permits for natural resource development on federal lands or making federal land designations under any law until the Secretary of Commerce submits to Congress an economic analysis to determine: (1) whether the proposed action has the potential to reduce revenue to the Treasury, and (2) the potential impact of the action on property rights and existing contracts.</summary>
</bill>
