<bill session="109" type="h" number="4162" updated="2013-07-19T19:41:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-12T14:14:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-12T14:14:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an exchange of lands between the Secretary of Agriculture and the United Water Conservation District of California to eliminate certain private inholdings in the Los Padres National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Renzi moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3727-3728" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4162.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-06-12T14:14:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3737-3728" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T14:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2006--Passed House amended.
Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2005 - Authorizes an exchange of approximately 340 acres held by the United Water Conservation District of California (the District lands) and approximately 440 acres of National Forest System lands. Requires the land exchange to be conducted on an equal value basis, as determined by appraisal. Directs the Secretary to reserve easements in the conveyance of the National Forest System (NFS) lands for access to roads and trails that the Secretary considers to be necessary or desirable to provide for administrative purposes and to ensure public access to NFS lands. Requires the District, as a condition on the receipt of the NFS land, to agree to construct a gravel parking area upon the District lands to provide access to the Potholes trail of the Los Padres National Forest. Subjects the site design for the parking area to approval by the Secretary. Permits the District to reasonably regulate vehicular access to the parking area. Revokes certain public lands withdrawals insofar as they affect the conveyed NFS lands. Exempts water rights from this land exchange. Permits the the values of the lands to be exchanged to be equalized through the payment of a cash equalization payment in excess of the statutory limit specified under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. Requires the deposit of any cash equalization payment received by the Secretary under this Act into the fund established by the Sisk Act. Makes such payment available to the Secretary for expenditure for the acquisition, construction, or improvement of administrative or recreational facilities for the Los Padres National Forest in Ventura County, Santa Barbara County, and San Luis Obispo County, California, or for the acquisition of land or interests in land in such counties. Requires the costs of conducting the land exchange to be shared equally by the District and the Secretary. Adds the District lands acquired by the Secretary under this Act to the Los Padres National Forest.</summary>
</bill>
