<bill session="110" type="h" number="6574" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Russian Federation Nuclear Cooperation Agreement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement the United States-Russian Federation Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Introduced.
United States-Russian Federation Nuclear Cooperation Agreement Act of 2008 - States that Congress favors the United States-Russian Federation Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy, subject to certain requirements. Prohibits the issuance of a license for the export of nuclear material, equipment, or technology to the Russian Federation unless the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that: (1) the government of the Russian Federation has taken actions to prohibit and prevent the transfer of goods, services, or technology (excluding goods, services, or technology related to the Bushehr nuclear reactor) to the government of Iran; (2) for the preceding 12-month period there has been no cooperation regarding such activities between the government or any national of the Russian Federation and the government or any national of Iran; or (3) during such 12-month period the government of the Russian Federation has terminated any significant cooperation between any Russian national and the government or any national of Iran, has instituted effective measures to prevent a reoccurrence of such cooperation, or has prosecuted any such Russian national. (Limits such certification's use to not more than two consecutive fiscal years.) Prohibits the issuance of a license for the export of nuclear material, equipment or technology to the Russian Federation unless the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the government of the Russian Federation: (1) is fully supporting U.S. efforts to achieve international and U.N. Security Council sanctions on Iran in response to Iran's nuclear program; and (2) has ratified the Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage or has enacted domestic law that provides adequate liability protections for U.S. firms for civil nuclear commerce with the Russian Federation. Terminates such license provisions five years after enactment of this Act. Authorizes the President, with specified limitations, to make extraordinary payments in connection with the International Space Station to the Russian Federal Space Agency. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require joint congressional resolution of approval of peaceful nuclear cooperation agreements.</summary>
</bill>
