<bill session="113" type="s" number="1193" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Security and Breach Notification Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain entities that collect and maintain personal information of individuals to secure such information and to provide notice to such individuals in the case of a breach of security involving such information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1468"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Data Security and Breach Notification Act of 2013 - Requires commercial entities that acquire, maintain, store, or utilize personal information (covered entities) to take reasonable measures to protect and secure data in electronic form containing personal information. Directs a covered entity that owns or licenses such data to give notice of any breach of security that the entity reasonably believes has caused or will cause identity theft or other actual financial harm to each individual: (1) who is a U.S. citizen or resident; and (2) whose personal information was, or that the covered entity reasonably believes has been, accessed and acquired by an unauthorized person. Requires a covered entity to notify the Secret Service or the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) of a security breach of personal information involving more than 10,000 individuals. Requires a third-party entity contracted to maintain, store, or process data containing personal information to notify the covered entity of a breach of security of a system. Requires a service provider to notify the covered entity if it becomes aware of a breach of security involving personal information owned or possessed by a covered entity and if such covered entity can be reasonably identified. Allows delays of notifications to avoid interfering with a civil or criminal investigation or threatening national or homeland security. Sets forth the methods for notification under this Act. Preempts information security practices of the Communications Act of 1934 applicable to telecommunication carriers, satellite operators, and cable operators. Sets forth the enforcement authority for the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) along with civil monetary penalties for violations of this Act. Exempts certain financial institutions and entities subject to the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA).</summary>
</bill>
