<bill session="112" type="s" number="1434" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Data Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect information relating to consumers, to require notice of security breaches, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Data Security Act of 2011 - Prescribes security procedures which an entity that maintains or communicates sensitive account or personal information must implement and enforce in order to protect the information from an unauthorized use likely to result in substantial harm or inconvenience to the consumer. Grants exclusive enforcement powers to specified federal regulatory agencies with oversight of financial institutions. Denies a private right of action, including a class action, regarding any act or practice regulated under this Act. Prohibits any civil or criminal action in state court or under state law relating to any act or practice governed under this Act. Prescribes data security standards to be implemented by federal agencies. Preempts state law with respect to the responsibilities of any person to protect against and investigate such data security breaches and mitigate any losses or harm resulting from them.</summary>
</bill>
