<bill session="109" type="h" number="5992" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Choices in Child Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish demonstration projects to provide at-home infant care benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2006-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="3797"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Choices in Child Care Act - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to five to seven states for demonstration projects to provide at-home infant care benefits to low-income families. Allows grants to Indian tribes. Requires the Secretary to seek to ensure geographic diversity among participants and to give priority to states that demonstrate a commitment to improving the quality of infant care and the choices available to parents of infants, that have relevant experience, and that have a shortage of infant care. Requires states, to participate in the demonstration project, to certify to the Secretary that the state: (1) will not reduce expenditures for child care services while carrying out the project; (2) will not give priority or preference to low-income families seeking to receive at-home infant care benefits over other families on a waiting list for child care assistance through other state programs, but will select a combination of such families; and (3) will ensure that applicants are permitted to choose between receipt of at-home care subsidies and certificates for child care needed for employment. Sets forth eligibility requirements for families seeking assistance, including having a parent who had a recent work history prior to the application for benefits. Requires states to permit two-parent families to participate in the project, but prohibits states from limiting participation in the project to such families.</summary>
</bill>
