<bill session="109" type="s" number="3871" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a hazardous waste electronic manifest system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2006-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2006-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Superfund, Toxics and Environmental Health. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-1076.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEV09" subcommittee="Superfund and Waste Management" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2006--Introduced.
Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest Establishment Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a hazardous waste electronic manifest system that may be used by a hazardous waste generator or transporter, an owner or operator of a hazardous waste treatment, storage, recycling, or disposal facility, or any other entity that is required to use a manifest to comply with any federal or state requirement to track the shipment, transportation, and receipt of hazardous waste or other material that is shipped from the generation site to an off-site facility for treatment, storage, disposal, or recycling. Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) impose service fees on users to pay for developing, operating, maintaining, and upgrading the system; and (2) deposit the fees into the Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Fund (established by this Act). Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish the Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Governing Board; and (2) carry out this Act in each state unless the state program is fully authorized to do so.</summary>
</bill>
