<bill session="112" type="h" number="2807" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Leg-Up Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Lending to Entrepreneurs for Growth in Underserved Populations Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To transfer unobligated and repaid funds from the Small Business Lending Fund Program to the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund to continue the program of making capital investments in eligible community development financial institutions in order to increase the availability of credit for small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2011-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2011--Introduced.
Small Business Lending to Entrepreneurs for Growth in Underserved Populations Act of 2011 or the Small Business Leg-Up Act of 2011 - Requires, upon the expiration of investment authority for the Small Business Lending Fund Program provided in the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010, that all unobligated funds in the Small Business Lending Fund be transferred to the Community Development Financial Institutions (CDFI) Fund. Directs that all funds received in connection with certain purchases of preferred stock and other financial instruments pursuant to such authority be transferred to the CDFI Fund. Amends the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 to direct the Administrator of the CDFI Fund to carry out a Small Business Capital Investment (SBCI) Program (a small business revolving loan program) to continue making capital investments in eligible community development financial institutions in order to increase the availability of credit for small businesses. Requires that: (1) all funds the Administrator receives in connection with SBCI Program purchases be deposited in the CDFI Fund, and (2) the authority to make such capital investments continue so long as specified funding amounts are available. Allows eligible community development financial institutions (with maximum assets of $10 billion as reported in audited financial statements) to apply to receive a capital investment of up to 10% of total assets, or another appropriate percentage determined by the Administrator. Directs the Administrator, to the extent practicable and except as otherwise provided, to carry out the SBCI Program in the same manner as the Small Business Lending Fund Program.</summary>
</bill>
