<bill session="112" type="h" number="4034" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mentor-Mentee Teen Pregnancy Reduction Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title V of the Social Security Act to provide grants for school-based mentoring programs for at risk teenage girls to prevent and reduce teen pregnancy, and to provide student loan forgiveness for mentors participating in such programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2012--Introduced.
Mentor-Mentee Teen Pregnancy Reduction Act of 2012 - Amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award competitive grants to local educational agencies or community-based organizations for the creation of school-based programs that provide mentoring to at-risk teenage girls to prevent and reduce teen pregnancy. Requires program mentors to be individuals who: (1) have received at least a baccalaureate degree from an institution of higher education; (2) are mentoring no more than two program mentees; and (3) are trained and screened to encourage mentees to engage in responsible, goal-orientated behavior, delay their sexual activity, and increase their participation in school. Authorizes the Secretary to provide student loan forgiveness, under the Federal Family Education Loan, Direct Loan, or Perkins Loan programs of the Higher Education Act of 1965, to program mentors who serve for at least 200 hours in an academic year.</summary>
</bill>
