<bill session="110" type="h" number="3403" updated="2013-07-19T21:33:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">911 Modernization and Public Safety Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">911 Modernization and Public Safety Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">911 Modernization and Public Safety Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">NET 911 Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">New and Emerging Technologies 911 Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">NET 911 Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">New and Emerging Technologies 911 Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote and enhance public safety by facilitating the rapid deployment of IP-enabled 911 and E-911 services, encouraging the nation's transition to a national IP-enabled emergency network and improve 911 and E-911 access to those with disabilities.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">A bill to promote and enhance public safety by facilitating the rapid deployment of IP-enabled 911 and E-911 services, encourage the Nation's transition to a national IP-enabled emergency network, and improve 911 and E-911 access to those with disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400155"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2007-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2007-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2007-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 110-442.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-11-13T14:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="273">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 273.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Markey moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13554-13557" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3403.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T19:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13824" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13T19:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-11-13T19:26:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="1084" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 406 - 1 (Roll no. 1084).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13554-13555" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5665" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2008-06-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gordon moved that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5826-5828" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-06-23T16:54:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5826-5828" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23T16:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-07-23" type="public" number="110-283">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-283.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4982"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Public Law.
New and Emerging Technologies 911 Improvement Act of 2008 or the NET 911 Improvement Act of 2008 - Title I: Services and IP-Enabled Voice Service Providers - (Sec. 101) Amends the IP-Enabled Voice Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 to require IP-enabled voice service providers to provide 9-1-1 service, including enhanced 9-1-1 service, to their subscribers. Grants such providers, in meeting that requirement, the same rights, including rights of interconnection, on the same rates, terms, and conditions, as are provided to a provider of commercial mobile service. Allows a state or tribal fee for 9-1-1 or enhanced 9-1-1 services, provided it is used only for such services or related enhancements and provided that, for each class of IP-enabled voice services subscribers, the fee does not exceed the fee for the same class of subscribers to telecommunications services. Requires an annual report to the Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives detailing the status in each state of the collection and distribution of such fees. Authorizes the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to compile a list of public safety answering point (PSAP) contact information and other information concerning 911 elements to assist IP-enabled voice service providers in complying with requirements imposed by this Act, and to make any portion of the information available to telecommunications carriers, wireless carriers, IP-enabled voice service providers, or other emergency service providers to improve public safety. Requires the FCC to work cooperatively with public safety organizations, industry participants, and the E-911 Implementation Coordination Office to develop best practices that promote consistency, where appropriate, including procedures for defining PSAP geographic coverage areas, defining network diversity requirements for delivery of IP-enabled 9-1-1 and enhanced 9-1-1 calls, call-handling in the event of call overflow or network outages, PSAP certification and testing requirements, database validation, and the format for delivering address information to PSAPs. (Sec. 102) Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require grants for migration to an IP-enabled emergency network. Requires the E-911 Implementation Coordination Office to develop a national plan for migrating to a national IP-enabled emergency network. Title II: Parity of Protection - (Sec. 201) Amends the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 to require, for IP-enabled voice service carriers, IP-enabled voice users of 911 communications, and public safety answering points (facilities designated to receive 911 calls and route them to emergency personnel) (PSAPs), parity in liability protection with local exchange companies, non-wireless 911 service users, and non-wireless PSAPs, respectively. Title III: Authority to Provide Customer Information for 911 Purposes - (Sec. 301) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to authorize a telecommunications carrier to use, disclose, or permit access to call location information in emergencies. Requires IP-enabled voice service providers to provide subscriber list information to emergency service providers.</summary>
</bill>
