<bill session="112" type="h" number="3457" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cleaning Product Right to Know Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require ingredient labeling of certain consumer cleaning products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2011-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Cleaning Product Right to Know Act of 2011 - Requires a cleaning product manufactured or offered for sale, distributed in commerce, or imported into the United States to bear a label listing each of its ingredients: (1) by the name assigned by the International Nomenclature of Cosmetic Ingredients or, if there is no such name, by the name assigned by the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry or, if there is none, by its common chemical name; and (2) in descending order of predominance by weight, except that ingredients that constitute less than 1% of the product can be listed at the end in any order. Allows the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to exempt from such labeling requirement: (1) an ingredient that is present in a product at such low levels that detection is not technologically feasible, or (2) for five-year periods, an ingredient that a manufacturer demonstrates to be a trade secret. Sets forth required disclosures for, and limitations to, a manufacturer's claim that an ingredient is a trade secret. Requires a product that is not in conformity with the labeling requirements and not exempt to be treated as a misbranded hazardous substance under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (FHSA). Increases penalties for violations of FHSA. Authorizes any person to petition the CPSC to investigate claims that a product does not satisfy the labeling requirements. Requires: (1) each cleaning product manufacturer to make available on its website a complete list of ingredients for each product, including any potential adverse health effect of each ingredient; and (2) CPSC to provide on its website aggregated information that allows users to compare products made by different manufacturers.</summary>
</bill>
