<bill session="111" type="h" number="3063" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for payment to the survivor or surviving family members of compensation otherwise payable to a contractor employee of the Department of Energy who dies after application for compensation under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1306"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Compensation Program Act of 2000 to replace the current requirements for occupational illness compensation to the survivors of a Department of Energy (DOE) contractor employee. Requires payment to a survivor of the compensation the deceased contractor employee would otherwise have been paid, if the employee dies after applying for the compensation but before receiving it. Requires payment of the compensation, if no survivors exist, to a claimant's surviving family members. Requires a survivor eligible for contractor employee compensation under this Act as well as survivor compensation under the regular compensation schedule for survivors to elect one or the other. Prohibits any payment to a survivor of both kinds of compensation.</summary>
</bill>
