<bill session="112" type="hr" number="732" updated="2013-07-20T01:09:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling for the protection of the rights and freedoms of religious minorities in the Arab world.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412456" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412481" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2012-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2012-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2012--Introduced.
Recognizes, in light of the upheaval brought by the Arab Spring, that religious freedom is critical to democratization, so that: (1) all people can freely associate, speak, and peacefully participate equally in the political process; and (2) religious minorities are protected during the time of transition in the region. Calls upon the Arab League and the Organization of Islamic Cooperation to press all member nations to protect the rights of religious minorities within their borders and to treat such minorities as equal citizens. Calls for the prosecution of any crimes against such minorities. Urges the U.S. government to lead an international effort to support legal and political reforms for the equal protection of religious freedom as a foundation for a stable, peaceful, and lasting democracy in the region by: (1) making legal protection for the freedom of religion and for all who peacefully practice their faith a top priority in all meetings with senior foreign officials; (2) supporting and directing U.S. officials with international programs in the Middle East to work with officials, civil society actors, and ethno-religious communities to educate all sectors of society that religious freedom provides a foundation for democratic freedoms; (3) supporting Internet freedom throughout the region to provide access to information and the free exchange of ideas; and (4) encouraging the protection of places of worship and historic religious and cultural sites against terrorist attacks. Encourages the Supreme Council of the Armed Forces and the newly elected Egyptian President to ensure that the constituent assembly will draft a new constitution representing all parts of Egyptian society, including religious minorities. Calls on the Egyptian government and the local and federal governments of Iraq to prosecute acts of violence against Christians and to make the protection of religious minorities a priority.</summary>
</bill>
