<bill session="110" type="hr" number="639" updated="2013-07-19T20:56:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-17T16:16:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-09-17T16:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commending the actions of the Government of Germany and its cooperation with United States intelligence agencies in preventing a large-scale terrorist attack against locations in Germany, including sites frequented by Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Faleomavaega moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10400-10401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 639.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-09-17T16:16:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10400" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="sr" number="344"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2007--Passed House amended.
Commends the efforts of German law enforcement and intelligence authorities in preventing a large-scale terrorist attack on numerous targets in Germany, including sites frequented by Americans. Recognizes the role of U.S. intelligence agencies in providing critical information to German authorities and notes the continuing importance of U.S. intelligence efforts with Germany. Condemns those individuals who would use acts of violence against innocent civilians to spread a message of hate and intolerance. Urges U.S. allies in the global war against terrorism to remain steadfast in their efforts to defeat terrorism. Expresses readiness to provide necessary assistance to the government of Germany in its counter-terrorism efforts and to bring to justice those individuals involved in this terrorist plot.</summary>
</bill>
