<bill session="113" type="h" number="2652" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marijuana Businesses Access to Banking Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create protections for depository institutions that provide financial services to marijuana-related businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2013-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2013--Introduced.
Marijuana Businesses Access to Banking Act of 2013 - Prohibits a federal banking regulator from: (1) terminating or limiting the deposit insurance of a depository institution solely because it either provides or has provided financial services to a marijuana-related legitimate business; or (2) prohibiting, penalizing, or otherwise discouraging a depository institution from providing financial services to a marijuana-related legitimate business. Prohibits a federal banking regulator, in addition, from recommending, motivating, providing incentives, or encouraging a depository institution not to offer financial services to an individual, or to downgrade or cancel financial services offered to an individual, solely because the individual: (1) is or later becomes a manufacturer, producer, owner or operator of a marijuana-related legitimate business; or (2) the depository institution was not aware that the individual is the owner or operator of a marijuana-related legitimate business. Prohibits a federal banking regulator from taking any action on a loan to an owner or operator of: (1) a marijuana-related legitimate business, or (2) real estate or equipment that is leased to a marijuana-related legitimate business. Grants immunity from federal criminal prosecution or investigation to a depository institution providing financial services to a marijuana-related legitimate business. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from requiring a depository institution, and any director, officer, employee, or agent of a depository institution, to report a transaction as suspicious solely because a party to the transaction is a marijuana-related legitimate business.</summary>
</bill>
