<bill session="110" type="s" number="2036" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Access to Safe Mortgages Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to temporarily raise conforming loan limits in high cost areas and portfolio caps applicable to Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae, to provide the necessary financing to curb foreclosures by facilitating the refinancing of at-risk subprime borrowers into safe, prime loans, to preserve liquidity in the mortgage lending markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3777"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2007--Introduced.
Protecting Access to Safe Mortgages Act - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act to increase mortgage portfolio limitations placed upon: (1) the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae); and (2) the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), respectively. Instructs the Director of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight (OFHEO) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to lift: (1) the limitation on growth provision set forth in the Fannie Mae Consent Decree; and (2) the voluntary temporary growth limitation described in a certain Freddie Mac Letter. Requires 50% of such portfolio increase to be used on loans which have had or will have interest rate resets between June 2005 and December 2009.</summary>
</bill>
