<bill session="113" type="h" number="860" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biogas Investment Tax Credit Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make qualified biogas property eligible for the energy credit and to permit new clean renewable energy bonds to finance qualified biogas property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2013-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2013--Introduced.
Biogas Investment Tax Credit Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) an energy tax credit through 2018 for investment in qualified biogas property, and (2) financing of qualified biogas property with new clean renewable energy bonds. Defines "qualified biogas property" as property comprising a system which uses anaerobic digesters or other processes to convert biomas into a gas which consists of not less than 52% methane and which captures such gas for use as a fuel. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into an agreement with the National Renewable Energy Laboratory to undertake a study of biogas and to submit a report to Congress on such study.</summary>
</bill>
