<bill session="111" type="s" number="3298" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Kids from Day One Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a pilot program to reduce the increasing prevalence of overweight/obesity among 0-5 year-olds in child care settings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2010--Introduced.
Healthy Kids from Day One Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award competitive grants to five state health departments to help reduce and prevent obesity among children between birth and five years of age in child care settings outside of a child's place of residence through training on and implementation of healthy eating and physical activity policies and practices. Requires the Secretary to award grants to Prevention Research Centers or universities to evaluate programs carried out under such grants. Requires the Secretary to coordinate activities conducted under this Act with activities undertaken by the National Prevention, Health Promotion and Public Health Council, to the extent practicable, including by: (1) sharing current and emergent best practices concerning healthy eating, physical activity, and screen time limits that have a population-level impact in promoting nutrition and physical activity in child care settings; and (2) promoting the effective implementation and sustainability of such programs; and (3) avoiding unnecessary duplication of effort.</summary>
</bill>
