<bill session="111" type="h" number="5618" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01T15:27:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-01T15:27:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoration of Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Restoration of Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To continue Federal unemployment programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2010-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Levin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4921-4925" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5618.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4941-4942" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4921" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2010-06-29T15:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="398" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 261 - 155 (Roll no. 398).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1495 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5618 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment printed in this report shall be considered as adopted. The resolution waives all points of order against the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1495 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1495.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5321-5327" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5618 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment printed in this report shall be considered as adopted. The resolution waives all points of order against the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5618.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5327" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced that further consideration of H.R. 5618 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1 of Rule XIX, the House continued with further proceedings on H.R. 5618.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5327-5330" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Camp moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5327-5328" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5327-5328" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to use stimulus funds to offset spending in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Levin raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Camp appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Levin moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the chair Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 196 (Roll no. 422).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-01T15:27:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="423" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 270 - 153 (Roll no. 423).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5321" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Under clause 10(c)(3) of rule XXI, the Chair announced that the presiding officer was supposed to have put the question of consideration on H.R. 5618 but omitted to do so. That omission has been overtaken by the subsequent actions on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="459">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 459.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="1495"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3404"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3548"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3756"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4183"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4707"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4851"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5453"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5647"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6419"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1647"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1699"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2831"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3153"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3173"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3420"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3421"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3981"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3990"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h715"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Passed House amended.
Restoration of Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 with respect to the state-established individual emergency unemployment compensation account (EUCA). Extends the final date for entering a federal-state agreement under the Emergency Unemployment Compensation (EUC) program through November 30, 2010. Postpones the termination of the program until April 30, 2011. Amends the Assistance for Unemployed Workers and Struggling Families Act to extend until December 1, 2010, requirements that federal payments to states cover 100% of EUC. Amends the Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008 to exempt weeks of unemployment between enactment of this Act and April 30, 2011, from the prohibition in the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 against federal matching payments to a state for the first week in an individual's eligibility period for which extended compensation or sharable regular compensation is paid if the state law provides for payment of regular compensation to an individual for his or her first week of otherwise compensable unemployment. (Thus allows temporary federal matching for the first week of extended benefits for states with no waiting period.) (Sec. 3) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to apply to claims for EUC payments the terms and conditions of state unemployment compensation law relating to availability of work, active search for work, and refusal to accept work. Requires a state to determine whether an individual is to be paid EUC or regular compensation for a week of unemployment by using one of four specified methods if: (1) an individual has been determined to be entitled to EUC for a benefit year; (2) that benefit year has expired; and (3) such individual has remaining entitlement to EUC for that benefit year, and would qualify for a new benefit year in which the weekly benefit amount of regular compensation is at least either $100 or 25% less than the individual's weekly benefit amount in such benefit year. (Sec. 4) Declares that federal-state agreements under which the state agency makes EUC payments to certain individuals shall not apply (or shall cease to apply) with respect to a state whose method for computing regular compensation under such state's law has been modified in a manner that reduces the average weekly benefit amount of regular compensation payable on or after June 2, 2010, to less than the average weekly benefit amount of regular compensation otherwise payable under the state law as in effect on such date. (Thus prohibits states from reducing regular compensation in order to be eligible for federal funds under the EUC program.) (Sec. 5) Requires any state with an EUC agreement under the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to implement reasonable procedures to ensure that: (1) EUC benefits are not provided to persons who appear on any current list of known or suspected terrorists provided to the state by any government agency; (2) such benefits are not provided to individuals convicted of a sex offense against a minor; and (3) the state is enforcing requirements under the Act to bar unauthorized aliens from receiving EUC under this Act. (Sec. 6) Designates Sec. 2 and Sec. 3 as an emergency in the House of Representatives pursuant to the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 and in the Senate as an emergency requirement.</summary>
</bill>
