<bill session="110" type="h" number="939" updated="2013-07-19T21:11:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Defense to assign members of the regular or reserve components of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps, under certain circumstances and subject to certain conditions, to assist the Department of Homeland Security in the performance of border protection functions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2007-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2007-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2007--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Defense, upon request of the Secretary of Homeland Security, to assign regular and reserve members of the Armed Forces to assist the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection and the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement of the Department of Homeland Security in: (1) preventing the entry of terrorists, drug traffickers, and illegal aliens into the United States; and (2) the inspection of cargo, vehicles, and aircraft at U.S. points of entry to prevent the entry of weapons of mass destruction and their components, prohibited narcotics or drugs, or other terrorist or drug trafficking items. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to certify that such request is necessary to respond to a threat to national security. Requires the Secretaries to establish a training program that must be completed by military personnel serving in such capacity. Requires any member so serving to be accompanied by a civilian law enforcement officer from the agency concerned. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish ongoing joint task forces to respond to threats to national security posed by the entry of terrorists, drug traffickers, or illegal aliens. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to notify the governor and local governments of the state involved of the deployment of such members and the types of tasks to be performed.</summary>
</bill>
