<bill session="110" type="s" number="1875" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Tax Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a refundable and advanceable credit for health insurance, to amend the Social Security Act to provide for improved private health insurance access and affordability, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the alternative minimum tax, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1886"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2007--Introduced.
Healthy Tax Reform Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow uninsured individual taxpayers and their spouses and dependents a refundable tax credit for a limited amount of their health insurance costs; (2) direct the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for payment of health insurance costs by advancing health insurance tax credit amounts to insurance providers during the taxable year; (3) limit the availability of certain tax preferences for individuals eligible for the health insurance tax credit; and (4) repeal the alternative minimum tax after 2006. Amends the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to deem whether a state has taken efforts to provide its citizens with greater access to affordable private health insurance, including by establishing a state health insurance exchange, a high risk pool, a reinsurance mechanism, or other high risk solution. Sets forth requirements for certification of a state health insurance exchange.Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to expand Medicaid health opportunity accounts to all states as of January 1, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
