<bill session="113" type="h" number="2712" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Power Licensing Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide certain requirements for the licensing of commercial nuclear facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2013-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2013--Introduced.
Nuclear Power Licensing Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require, for a commercial license for an atomic power production or utilization facility, that: (1) the facility does not pose an unreasonable threat to persons or the environment because of safety or security vulnerabilities (including vulnerability to terrorist attacks), and (2) there exist adequate evacuation plans for emergency events which have been approved by the relevant federal agencies and states within 50 miles of the facility. Conditions renewal of any such license on the same criteria and requirements applicable to an original application for initial construction. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to ensure that any changes in the size or distribution of the surrounding population, or seismic or other scientific data not available at the time of original licensing, have not resulted in the facility's being located at a site at which a new facility would not be allowed to be built.</summary>
</bill>
