<bill session="113" type="h" number="2524" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Better Health Rewards Program Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program to provide incentive payments to participating Medicare beneficiaries who voluntarily establish and maintain better health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1228"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Medicare Better Health Rewards Program Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a three-year Better Health Rewards Program under which incentives are provided to Medicare beneficiaries who voluntarily agree to participate in the Program. Directs the Secretary to establish standards for measuring better health targets and points for achieving them for participating Medicare beneficiaries, including those for: (1) an annual wellness visit, (2) tobacco cessation, (3) Body Mass Index (BMI), (4) a diabetes screening test, (5) cardiovascular disease screening, (6) cholesterol level screening, and (7) screening tests and specified vaccinations. Requires the Secretary to make specified incentive payments to each participating Medicare beneficiary who achieves at least 20 points during a year. Authorizes Medicare Advantage Plans, "Section 1876" health maintenance organization and competitive medical cost plans, and programs of all-inclusive care for the elderly (PACE) to make incentives to their enrollees to participate in a Better Health Rewards Program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income any payment made under: (1) the Medicare Better Health Rewards Program, and (2) any other Better Health Rewards Program.</summary>
</bill>
