<bill session="109" type="s" number="781" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Right-to-Ride Livestock on Federal Land Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to preserve the use and access of pack and saddle stock animals on land administered by the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Forest Service on which there is a historical tradition of the use of pack and saddle stock animals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2006-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
Right-to-Ride Livestock on Federal Land Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage National Park System land in a manner that preserves and facilitates the continued use and access of pack and saddle stock animals on land where there is a historical tradition of using such animals. Requires such National Park System land to remain open and accessible to the use of such animals. Allows the Secretary of the Interior to implement a proposed reduction in the use and access of such animals on such land after complying with the full review process required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Makes the same amendments to other laws regarding other public land as follows: (1) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, with respect to Bureau of Land Management land; (2) the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, with respect to National Wildlife Refuge System land and (3) the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974, with respect to National Forest System land (with the Secretary directed to act in this case being the Secretary of Agriculture). Directs the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture to issue final rules to define the term "historical tradition of use of pack and saddle stock animals" for purposes of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
