<bill session="109" type="h" number="4594" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require certain reports with respect to the energy efficiency design performance of new Federal buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400155"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2580-2581"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to require federal agencies to include in annual budget requests and certain annual federal energy management reports submitted to the Secretary of Energy: (1) 18 months after completion of a new federal building, a report outlining the building's performance in achieving energy efficiency design goals, describing the reasons for any failure to meet such goals as well as corrective actions to be taken, and stating how performance was measured and an estimate of additional energy costs to be incurred by not meeting the design requirements; and (2) if a building fails to achieve design goals, a second report to Congress assessing the building's performance after corrective actions have been taken, which shall also state any reasons for failure to continue to meet the performance requirements.</summary>
</bill>
