<bill session="113" type="h" number="2677" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sequestration Tied to Member Pay (STOMP) Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the annual rate of compensation of Members of Congress by a percentage equal to the effective reduction in the average annual rate of pay of Federal employees who were subject to sequestration-related furloughs during the two most recent fiscal years.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2013--Introduced.
Sequestration Tied to Member Pay (STOMP) Act of 2013 - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 with respect to the annual rate of compensation of Members of Congress. Requires that if, during either of the two most recent fiscal years ending before a Congress, the effective annual rate of pay of federal employees is reduced because of a sequestration-related furlough, the annual rate of pay otherwise applicable for Members during the Congress be reduced by a percentage equal to the average percentage reduction in the effective annual rate of pay during the fiscal years for all federal employees. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), by December 15 of each even-numbered year, to determine and publish the percentage (if any) by which the Members' annual rate of pay otherwise applicable shall be reduced during the next Congress.</summary>
</bill>
