<bill session="110" type="h" number="207" updated="2013-07-19T21:05:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Depleted Uranium Screening and Testing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for identification of members of the Armed Forces exposed during military service to depleted uranium, to provide for health testing of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioisotopes"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Depleted Uranium Screening and Testing Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) establish procedures for the predeployment notification to members of the Armed Forces of any known or likely use of depleted uranium in the theater of operation and any health risks associated with exposure to depleted uranium; (2) provide for training deploying members on the safe handling of depleted uranium contamination; (3) carry out a program to identify individuals exposed to depleted uranium during active service in the Armed Forces; (4) provide such individuals with bioassay testing and notification of test results; and (5) identify specified depleted uranium exposure events. Requires the Secretary of each military department to establish procedures for collecting, tracking, and maintaining information on the health status of individuals tested under this Act to assess long-term health consequences of exposure to depleted uranium. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to conduct an independent review of bioassay types and contamination thresholds for purposes of required testing. Requires the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide appropriate treatment for any illness of an individual resulting from depleted uranium contamination or exposure. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a survey of radioisotope identification equipment used by the Department of Defense (DOD) to assess the capability of DOD facilities to identify concentrations of different radioisotopes in naturally occurring levels of uranium and to report survey findings to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
