<bill session="112" type="sr" number="98" updated="2013-07-20T02:11:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to express the sense of the Senate regarding the school breakfast program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1566" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2011--Introduced.
Recognizes the importance of the school breakfast program and its overall positive effect on the lives of low-income children and families, as well as its effect on helping to improve a child's overall classroom performance. Expresses the support of the House of Representatives for states that have successfully implemented school breakfast programs in order to improve the test scores and grades of their participating students. Encourages states to: (1) strengthen their school breakfast programs by improving student access, (2) promote improvements in the nutritional quality of breakfasts served, and (3) inform students and parents of healthy nutritional and lifestyle choices. Recognizes: (1) that the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act of 2010 provides low-income children with greater access to nutritious breakfasts; (2) the role nonprofit and community organizations play in increasing awareness of, and access to, breakfast programs for low-income children; and (3) that National School Breakfast Week helps draw attention to the need for, and success of, the school breakfast program.</summary>
</bill>
