<bill session="110" type="s" number="3736" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 417 of title 49, United States Code, to require air carriers and ticket brokers to notify consumers of taxes, fees, charges, and fuel surcharges in a timely manner, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Transportation rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2008--Introduced.
Makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for: (1) a domestic or foreign air carrier or ticket broker to display (including to an online purchaser) the airline ticket price without simultaneously displaying all applicable ticket taxes, fees, charges, and fuel surcharges; and (2) a domestic or foreign air carrier to fail to provide certain information to an online ticket purchaser, including fees for checked baggage, seating assignments, and optional in-flight goods and services. Makes it an unfair or deceptive practice, as well, for any domestic or foreign air carrier to increase ticket prices through a fuel surcharge that is not correlated to the price of fuel paid or the amount of fuel used by the air carrier. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to: (1) carry out this Act; and (2) establish a procedure to calculate whether a domestic or foreign air carrier's fuel surcharges are sufficiently related to its fuel costs.</summary>
</bill>
