<bill session="111" type="h" number="2386" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to include American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands in certain efforts to reduce diesel emissions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) make states (including American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands) that represent or provide pollution reduction or educational services to persons or organizations that own or operate diesel fleets, or that have the promotion of transportation or air quality as their principal purpose, eligible for grants and loans for diesel emission reductions; and (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to allocate to American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands funding for a grant and loan program that is designed to achieve significant reductions in diesel emissions if such states have an approved application for such program.</summary>
</bill>
