<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1721" updated="2013-07-19T23:11:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18T11:52:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-11-18T11:52:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1722) to require the head of each executive agency to establish and implement a policy under which employees shall be authorized to telework, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412224"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17T18:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-657, by Mr. Arcuri.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17T18:48:00-05:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table the bill H.R. 1722, with the Senate amendment thereto, and, in the House, for the Chair of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform or his designee to move that the House concur in the Senate amendment. The Senate amendment shall be considered as read and be debatable for not to exceed one hour, equally divided and controlled. The rule also provides suspension authority through the legislative day of November 19, 2010.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-11-17T18:48:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="244">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 244.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T10:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7553-7560" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T10:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1721.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T11:43:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 171 (Roll no. 576).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7558-7559" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7558-7559" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-11-18T11:52:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="577" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 235 - 171 (Roll no. 577).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7553" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T11:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1722 (Telework Enhancement Act of 2010). Makes it in order at any time through the legislative day of November 19, 2010, for the Speaker of the House of Representatives to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</summary>
</bill>
