<bill session="111" type="s" number="3544" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Visa Waiver Program Updated Framework and Enhanced Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to modify the requirements of the visa waiver program and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2010--Introduced.
Visa Waiver Program Updated Framework and Enhanced Security Act of 2010 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act regarding the visa waiver program to: (1) authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), in consultation with the Secretary of State, to designate program countries; (2) replace visa refusal rates with visa overstay rates in determining program participation; (3) set a maximum 3% visa overstay rate for program countries; (4) require an annual program compliance report to Congress; and (5) revise probationary status and program termination provisions. Directs the Comptroller General to review the Secretary of Homeland Security's methods for: (1) tracking aliens entering and exiting the United States; and (2) detecting visa overstays. Requires: (1) program countries to have agreements in place to share information on lost and stolen passports within 180 days of enactment of this Act; and (2) DHS to make information on all aliens who have overstayed their visas available electronically to state and local law enforcement agencies.</summary>
</bill>
