<bill session="109" type="s" number="1020" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Collaborative Opportunities to Mobilize and Promote Education, Technology, and Enterprise Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">COMPETE Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make the United States competitive in a global economy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2005-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5109-5111"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5111-5114" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2005--Introduced.
Collaborative Opportunities to Mobilize and Promote Education, Technology, and Enterprise Act of 2005 - COMPETE Act of 2005 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide tax incentives for research and education by: (1) extending a research credit; (2) increasing rates of an alternative incremental credit for research; (3) establishing an alternative simplified credit for qualified research expenses; (4) providing a credit for information and communications technology education; and (5) setting an alternative percentage limitation for corporate charitable contributions to the mathematics and science partnership program. Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation to award grants to partnerships of institutions of higher education (IHEs) and other entities to establish 10 regional training and research Making America Competitive (MAC) Centers to help maintain U.S. workforce and education investment and infrastructure in the sciences, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to make partnership bonus grants annually to a certain number of elementary and of secondary schools in each state that show the most improvement in mathematics and in science, respectively. Authorizes the Director of the Office of Science of the Department of Energy to award matching grants to IHEs to: (1) provide stipends or other financial assistance for students enrolled in graduate programs in the sciences, technology, engineering, or mathematics; and (2) support outreach and mentoring activities to increase the participation of underrepresented groups in the sciences, technology, engineering, or mathematics at all or any level of education, including elementary, secondary and postsecondary education. Amends federal patent law to require the Director of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, for any fiscal year when estimated fee collections exceed appropriations to the Office, to reduce fees under the Trademark Act of 1946 for that fiscal year or its remainder so that estimated collections equal the amount appropriated.</summary>
</bill>
