<bill session="112" type="hc" number="86" updated="2013-07-20T02:09:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make corrections in the enrollment of H.R. 2061.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7381" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-11-04T14:10:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7381" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES" datetime="2011-12-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8466" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2061"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make corrections in the enrollment of H.R. 2061 (authorizing the presentation of a U.S. flag for federal civilian employees who die of injuries in connection with their employment) to: (1) authorize the head of an executive agency, upon the request of an agency employee's widow or widower, child, sibling, or parent (instead of the employee's "next of kin") to give a U.S. flag (instead of to pay the expenses incident to the presentation of a U.S. flag) to an individual who was an employee of the agency and who died of injuries incurred in connection with such individual's federal employment; (2) add the qualification that such injuries were suffered as a result of a criminal act, an act of terrorism, a natural disaster, or other circumstance as determined by the President; and (3) modify the definition of "employee" to remove individuals who perform volunteer services at the discretion of an agency head.</summary>
</bill>
