<bill session="109" type="s" number="2263" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom From Foreign Oil Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require that automobiles and light trucks manufactured after model year 2007 be able to operate on a fuel mixture that is at least 85 percent ethanol, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="587"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2006--Introduced.
Freedom From Foreign Oil Act of 2006 - Amends federal transportation law to require that passenger automobiles, automobiles capable of off-highway operation, or light trucks that are manufactured after model year 2007 be capable of operating on a flexible fuel mixture (mixture containing at least 85% of ethanol by volume with gasoline). Requires the Secretary of Transportation to prescribe regulations requiring such automobiles or trucks to display prominently (including in the owner's manual of each vehicle) information indicating that such vehicles are capable of operating on a flexible fuel mixture. Directs the Secretary to promote the use of a mixture containing at least 85% of ethanol by volume with gasoline in motor vehicles in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
