<bill session="110" type="h" number="7037" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Activity for Lifelong Energy Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to each State health department for community action teams to promote healthier lifestyles through physical activity and good nutrition and thereby prevent obesity and chronic disease, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400030"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
Healthy Activity for Lifelong Energy Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to enable state health departments to maintain community action teams to work within the local community to promote healthier lifestyles through physical activity and good nutrition and thereby prevent obesity and chronic disease. Requires such departments to collect data on the effectiveness of the community action team program.Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct training institutes to jump-start the work of such teams; (2) provide the teams with access to national experts in ongoing community change; and (3) disseminate information about success achieved through the teams to communities across the nation.</summary>
</bill>
