<bill session="113" type="s" number="1206" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage benchmarking and disclosure of energy information for commercial buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to revise exceptions to the requirement that federal agencies must lease space in buildings that have earned the Energy Star label. Requires a space leased by an agency in a building that has not earned the Energy Star label to be benchmarked under a nationally recognized, online, free benchmarking program, with public disclosure. Exempts from such requirement a space for which owners cannot access whole building utility consumption data. Requires an agency that is a tenant of a space that has not earned such label to provide to a building owner, or authorize the owner to obtain from the utility, the energy consumption information of the space for the benchmarking and disclosure requirements. Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to study and report on: (1) the impact of state and local performance benchmarking and disclosure policies, and any associated building efficiency policies, for commercial and multifamily buildings and the impact of programs and systems in which utilities provide aggregated information regarding whole building energy consumption and usage information to owners of multitenant commercial, residential, and mixed-use buildings; and (2) best practice policy approaches that have resulted in the greatest improvements in building energy efficiency. Requires the Secretary to modify and maintain existing databases or create and maintain a new database platform to store and make publicly available energy-related information on commercial and multifamily buildings. Authorizes the Secretary to make awards to utilities, utility regulators, and utility partners to develop and implement programs to provide aggregated whole building energy consumption information to multitenant building owners.</summary>
</bill>
