<bill session="111" type="h" number="4630" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corporate Politics Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the securities laws to require that registration statements, quarterly and annual reports, and proxy solicitations of public companies include a disclosure to shareholders of any expenditure made by that company in support of or in opposition to any candidate for Federal, State, or local public office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/22/2010--Introduced.
Corporate Politics Transparency Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require that quarterly and annual reports of an issuer, any proxy solicitation or consent or authorization in respect of any security, and the issuer's registration statement disclose total independent expenditures in support of or in opposition to any candidate for federal, state, or local public office made by the issuer during the preceding six-year period. Requires such disclosures to include: (1) the name and political party affiliation of each candidate in support of whom or in opposition to whom an independent expenditure was made; (2) the amount of each such expenditure; (3) the public office that such candidate was or is seeking; (4) the relevant state, city, or district; and (5) a statement of the issuer's interest in and reason for making such expenditure.</summary>
</bill>
