<bill session="109" type="s" number="2455" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Electronic Surveillance bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Terrorist Surveillance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Terrorist Surveillance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide in statute for the conduct of electronic surveillance of suspected terrorists for the purposes of protecting the American people, the Nation, and its interests from terrorist attack while ensuring that the civil liberties of United States citizens are safeguarded, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-02">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Specter without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="607">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 607.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="3874"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3874"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Information leaking"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Senate Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2006--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Terrorist Surveillance Act of 2006 - Allows the President to authorize a Terrorist Surveillance Program (Program) of electronic surveillance without a court order for periods of up to 45 days if: (1) the President determines that the surveillance is necessary to protect the United States, its citizens, or its interests, whether inside or outside the United States; (2) there is probable cause to believe that a surveillance subject is an agent or member of a group or organization on the Terrorist Surveillance List (established in this Act); (3) the surveillance is initiated and conducted in a manner reasonably designed to acquire only communications to or from the United States where at least one party to the surveillance is located outside the United States, or the communications appear to originate or terminate outside the United States; (4) there is not a substantial likelihood that the surveillance will acquire the substance of any communication where every party thereto is located within the United States; (5) a significant purpose of the surveillance is to obtain foreign intelligence information; and (6) procedures are in place for the minimization of privacy infringement standards outlined under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA). Requires the Attorney General (AG) to establish such minimization procedures within 30 days after the enactment of this Act, and to update such procedures at least annually. Directs the President to establish and maintain a Terrorist Surveillance List. Requires the AG: (1) after the end of each Program period, to review and recommend to the President whether the program should be reauthorized; and (2) to review the surveillance of individual targets within the United States under each Program. Authorizes, as an alternative to surveillance under a Program, continued court-ordered surveillance under FISA. Provides for the creation of Senate and House intelligence subcommittees to oversee and monitor surveillance conducted by the President under each Program. Requires: (1) the President to submit to the intelligence committees a current Terrorist Surveillance List, a report on the management and operational details of each Program, and semiannual reports on surveillance conducted under each Program; and (2) the subcommittees to prepare annual reports on each Program conducted. Amends federal criminal law to provide criminal penalties for the unauthorized disclosure of information collected under each Program.</summary>
</bill>
