<bill session="112" type="s" number="473" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to extend the chemical facility security program of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2011-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1223-1224"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="194">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 194.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-20">
      <text>By Senator Lieberman from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 112-90.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="908"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="916"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2011 - Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 to extend until October 4, 2014, the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to issue interim final regulations establishing risk-based performance standards for security of chemical facilities and requiring vulnerability assessments and the development and implementation of site security plans for such facilities. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and in coordination with the Under Secretary for National Protection and Programs, to: (1) establish a voluntary chemical security training program to enhance the capabilities of covered chemical facilities (chemical facilities subject to the Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards [CFATS]) to prevent, prepare for, respond to, mitigate against, and recover from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other man-made disasters; and (2) develop a voluntary chemical security exercise program to offer voluntary testing and evaluation of the capabilities of the federal government, state governments, commercial personnel and management, emergency response providers, and the private sector to prevent, prepare for, mitigate against, respond to, and recover from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other emergencies at covered chemical facilities. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection and in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, to establish a voluntary technical assistance program under which the Secretary may, upon request, provide the owner or operator of a covered facility nonbinding assistance or recommendations to: (1) reduce the risk or consequences associated with a successful act of terrorism against a covered chemical facility, or (2) aid in compliance with the risk-based performance standards applicable to that facility under CFATS. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a repository for information and data on best practices and cost-effective technologies for implementing CFATS and the voluntary technical assistance program, (2) submit a report regarding lessons learned from that program, and (3) establish a Chemical Facility Security Advisory Board to advise the Secretary on CFATS implementation. Terminates this Act on October 4, 2014.</summary>
</bill>
