<bill session="113" type="h" number="1576" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dollar Bill Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To stimulate the economy, provide for a sound United States dollar by defining a value for the dollar, to remove the authority of Federal Reserve banks to pay earnings on certain balances maintained at such banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2013--Introduced.
Dollar Bill Act of 2013 - Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board) to: (1) designate a "Target Week"; (2) employ a random process to select a specific day, hour, minute, and second during such Target Week as "Target Moment" (which shall not be publicly disclosed); (3) make the value of the U.S. dollar at the Target Moment equal to the price of gold on the exchange operated by the Commodities Exchange, Inc. (COMEX) of the New York Mercantile Exchange, Inc.; and (4) maintain the value of the U.S. dollar within plus or minus 2% of such price ("Target Range") thereafter. Instructs the Board maintain the value of the United States dollar within the Target Range directly, via open market operations, and not indirectly, as in the current practice of targeting the Federal Funds rate. Requires the Board to use its banking and bank regulatory powers to maintain and promote stable and effective financial markets during and after the transition to a defined value for the U.S. dollar. Entitles all entities that depreciate capital assets for tax purposes to 100% expensing of all capital investment for tax purposes in the year that the investment is made. Requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), in addition to the scoring CBO will do of the tax changes provided in this Act, to calculate the impact on federal revenues on a present value basis. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to remove Federal Reserve Bank authority to pay earnings on reserves.</summary>
</bill>
