<bill session="112" type="h" number="5711" updated="2013-07-20T01:59:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Substance Abuse Treatment Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants for treatment of heroin, cocaine, methamphetamine, 3,4-methylenedioxymethamphetamine (ecstasy), and phencyclidine (PCP) abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400638"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2012--Introduced.
Access to Substance Abuse Treatment Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to: (1) increase the availability of treatment for abuse of heroin, cocaine, methamphetamine, 3,4-methylenedioxymethamphetamine (ecstasy), and phencyclidine (PCP); (2) provide vouchers to individuals in underserved populations for authorized services related to such treatment; and (3) establish programs to provide for and coordinate the provision of wrap-around services, such as medical services, job training services, and housing assistance, to affected by such substances. Revises the grant program to provide residential substance abuse treatment to pregnant and postpartum women to: (1) make caregiver parents eligible for such program, (2) make Indian tribes and tribal organizations eligible for grants, and (3) set forth the priority for allocation of grants. Requires the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse to conduct research on the effectiveness of the use of agonist and antagonist drugs to reduce the problems associated with stimulant abuse, including cocaine and methamphetamine abuse. Requires the Secretary to seek to enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine to complete a literature review on the effectiveness of agonist and antagonist drugs for the treatment of stimulant abuse, including cocaine and methamphetamine abuse. Requires the Comptroller General to study: (1) the impact of the programs authorized by this Act on the effectiveness and availability of treatment for abuse of heroin, cocaine, methamphetamine, 3,4-methylenedioxymethamphetamine, and phencyclidine; (2) how the level of federal funding available for such treatment compares to the amount necessary to provide adequate treatment; and (3) the impact of effective treatment on cost savings due to the reduced need for criminal justice and other services. Requires additional amounts authorized by this Act, prior to being appropriated, to be fully offset by a reduction to one or more other appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
