<bill session="109" type="s" number="3985" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Outer Continental Shelf Royalty Reform and Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the recovery of oil and gas revenues on the Outer Continental Shelf, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10604-10605"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Outer Continental Shelf Royalty Reform and Enhancement Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to place limitations based on market price on the royalty relief granted under any lease for the production of oil or natural gas entered into on or after enactment of this Act. Declares that Congress reaffirms the authority of the Secretary to vary, based on the price of production from a lease, the suspension of royalties under any lease subject to specified requirements of the Outer Continental Shelf Deep Water Royalty Relief Act. Instructs the Secretary to offer to enter into written agreements to amend the payment responsibilities under each lease that: (1) authorizes the production of oil or natural gas on the Outer Continental Shelf; (2) provides for relief from the payment of royalties; and (3) does not provide for suspension of royalty relief based on an increase in the price of oil or natural gas, respectively, above specified thresholds. Authorizes the Secretary to increase royalty rates on leases for oil or natural gas production on the Outer Continental Shelf. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to deposit certain percentages of Outer Continental Shelf revenues for: (1) disbursement to Gulf producing states; (2) financial assistance to states for land and water conservation as well as outdoor recreation purposes; and (3) deficit reduction. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to guarantee the repayment of 100% of the outstanding principal of a bond issued by the state of Louisiana for coastal wetland restoration projects and related storm protection infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
