<bill session="112" type="s" number="1746" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Visa Improvements to Stimulate International Tourism to the United States of America Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">VISIT USA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to stimulate international tourism to the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2011-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2011--Introduced.
Visa Improvements to Stimulate International Tourism to the United States of America Act or the VISIT USA Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide qualifying nationals of China (PRC) with a five-year multiple entry/exit visitor visa. Requires such persons to be screened through the automated electronic travel authorization system. Transfers authority to establish and collect the premium fee for employment-based petitions and applications from the Attorney General (DOJ) to the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS). Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) offer for a fee premium visitor visa processing; (2) develop, subject to security concerns, a pilot program for processing visitor visas using secure remote videoconferencing technology to conduct visa interviews; and (3) decrease nonimmigrant visa application and issuance fees in selected countries when there is a low demand from such countries for visitor visas. Establishes a W (nonimmigrant)-visa for: (1) a Canadian citizen who is older than 50 years of age and owns a U.S. residence or has rented a U.S. accommodation for the duration of his or her stay; and (2) such alien's accompanying spouse and children. Makes such visa renewable every three years with a maximum stay of 240 consecutive days in each authorized period. Revises the visa waiver program to: (1) authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate any country as a program country; (2) adjust visa refusal rate criteria, including addition of a 3% maximum overstay rate; and (3) revise probationary and termination provisions. Establishes an X (nonimmigrant)-visa for: (1) an alien who invests (and maintains) at least $500,000 in U.S. residential real estate, of which at least $250,000 must be for a U.S. primary residence where such person will reside for more than 180 days per year; and (2) such alien's accompanying spouse and children. Makes such visa renewable every three years. Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to include in the Global Entry Trusted Traveler Network individuals who meet security requirements and are employed and sponsored by an international organization which maintains a strong working relationship with the United States.</summary>
</bill>
