<bill session="113" type="s" number="700" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:29-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Troop Talent Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that the education and training provided members of the Armed Forces and veterans better assists members and veterans in obtaining civilian certifications and licenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412586" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1796"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2013--Introduced.
Troop Talent Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretaries of the military departments, to the maximum extent practicable, to make information on civilian credentialing opportunities available to members of the Armed Forces (members) beginning with, and at every stage of, their training for military occupational specialities, in order to permit such members to: (1) evaluate the extent to which such training correlates with skills and training required for various civilian certifications and licenses, and (2) assess the suitability of such training for obtaining and pursuing such certifications and licenses. Requires the information made available to: (1) be consistent with the Transition Goals Plans Success program, and (2) include information on the civilian occupational equivalents of military occupational specialties. Requires such Secretaries to make available to civilian credentialing agencies specified information on the content of military training provided to members. Allows members or veterans to use educational assistance provided through the Department of Defense (DOD) or the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) in pursuit of a civilian certification or license only if the successful completion of a curriculum fully qualifies such student to take the appropriate examination and be certified or licensed to meet any other academic conditions required for entry into that occupation or profession. Requires the military occupational specialties designated for a military skills to civilian credentialing pilot program under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to include those specialties relating to the military information technology workforce. Directs the VA Secretary to reestablish the Professional Certification and Licensure Advisory Committee (under current law, terminated on December 31, 2006). Provides additional Committee duties, including the development of: (1) guidance for audits of licensure and certification programs in order to ensure high-quality education to members and veterans, and (2) a plan to improve outreach to members and veterans on the importance of licensing and certification and the availability of educational benefits.</summary>
</bill>
