<bill session="110" type="h" number="3756" updated="2013-07-19T21:36:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2007--Introduced.
Colorado Wilderness Act of 2007 - Designates specified lands in Colorado, administered by the Bureau of Land Management or the U.S. Forest Service, as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Authorizes the Colorado Army National Guard, through the High Altitude ARNG Aviation Training Site, to conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over and upon the lands designated as potential wilderness by this Act. Provides for the obtaining, exercise, and protection of U.S. water rights for the wilderness and potential wilderness areas. Designates specified lands (proposed as Deep Creek Wilderness and Pisgah Mountain Wilderness) as potential wilderness areas. Requires such lands to be designated as wilderness upon publication of a notice that all nonconforming uses of those lands have ceased.</summary>
</bill>
