<bill session="109" type="h" number="5964" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Employment and Forest Restoration Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish management priorities for Federal forest lands in Oregon and Washington covered by the Northwest Forest Plan that will protect old growth timber while improving the health of young managed stands, increasing the volume of commercial timber available from these lands, and providing economic opportunities in rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Rural Employment and Forest Restoration Act of 2006 - Requires each Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management (BLM) administrative unit containing land managed under the Northwest Forest Plan to plan and implement projects to enhance the forest health of land managed by such administrative unit. Requires the resources of such administrative units to be prioritized so that the projects described in this Act are planned for treatment, and treatment has begun of significant acreage, before planning other projects. Sets forth priorities for such projects. Prohibits such administrative units from planning, advertising, contracting or implementing any harvest of timber in an old growth stand, except for noncommercial use or noncommercial purposes in an emergency situation. Directs the Forest Service and BLM to: (1) consider how they plan, package, and offer contracts and sales to restore young managed stands to achieve maximum employment in rural areas; and (2) in awarding a federal contract for projects to enhance the forest health of land managed by such administrative units and in evaluating bids and proposals, consider local contractors who provide employment or training for workers in an economically disadvantaged rural area. Allows such administrative units to prepare programmatic environmental documentation pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to study the significant environmental effects of the major federal actions contemplated in projects authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
