<bill session="110" type="h" number="3181" updated="2013-07-19T21:31:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests Land Exchange Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the exchange of certain lands in the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests in the State of Colorado with the Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1621-1622"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="4249"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2007--Introduced.
Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests Land Exchange Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, upon receipt of acceptable title to specified land in Boulder county, Colorado, between the communities of Boulder and Nederland (the non-federal land) offered by the Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District to the United States, to convey to the District, in exchange for such non-federal land, National Forest System land within the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests in Colorado (the federal lands). Permits the District, pending completion of the land exchange, to commence modification of the fire stations on the federal land. Provides for the non-federal land to become part of the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests and modifies the boundary of such National Forests to incorporate such land. Revokes any public orders withdrawing any of the federal lands from appropriation or disposal under the public land laws to the extent necessary to permit conveyance of such lands.</summary>
</bill>
