<bill session="112" type="s" number="674" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Record Printing Savings Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 9 of title 44, United States Code, to limit the printing of the Congressional Record, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1626"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Congressional Record Printing Savings Act of 2011 - Revises requirements for printing the Congressional Record, specifying that it be made electronically available promptly as it is issued in daily form. Prohibits the Government Printing Office (GPO) from printing more than the minimum number of copies of the Record necessary for archival purposes. Requires the Public Printer to: (1) determine that minimum number of copies, and (2) ensure the most cost-effective printing of it. Requires GPO to make the Record publicly available on GPO's website in a format which enables it to be downloaded and printed by users. Repeals: (1) the authority of the Librarian of Congress to furnish a copy of the daily and bound Record to the Undersecretary of State for External Affairs of Canada in exchange for a copy of the Parliamentary Hansard, and (2) the Public Printer's requirement to honor the requisition. Repeals the authority of the Public Printer, under the direction of the Joint Committee, to sell: (1) subscriptions to the daily Record; and (2) current, individual numbers and bound sets of it.</summary>
</bill>
