<bill session="112" type="h" number="617" updated="2013-07-20T01:15:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Radioactive Import Deterrence Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the importation of certain low-level radioactive waste into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2011-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2011--Introduced.
Radioactive Import Deterrence Act - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from issuing a license authorizing the importation into the United States of: (1) low-level radioactive waste; or (2) specific radioactive waste streams exempted from regulation by the NRC. Exempts from such prohibition low-level radioactive waste: (1) being returned to a federal or military facility which is authorized to possess the material; or (2) resulting from the use in a foreign country of nuclear material obtained by the foreign user from an entity in the United States that is being returned to the United States for management and disposal.Authorizes the President to waive such prohibition and authorize the grant of a specific license to import materials only after finding that such importation would meet an important national or international policy goal, such as the use of waste for research purposes.Grandfathers certain licenses issued before the date of enactment of this Act, but prohibits their extension or amendment with respect to the amount of material permitted to be imported.</summary>
</bill>
