<bill session="112" type="s" number="437" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Taxpayer Receipt Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require the Secretary of the Treasury to provide each individual taxpayer a receipt for an income tax payment which itemizes the portion of the payment which is allocable to various Government spending categories.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1527"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2011--Introduced.
Taxpayer Receipt Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to provide every taxpayer who files an individual income tax return for any taxable year an itemized tax receipt showing: (1) the proportionate allocation of the taxpayer's payment in such year among major expenditure categories of the federal budget (e.g., social security, national defense, Medicare and other federal health programs, low-income assistance programs, unemployment benefits, net interest on the federal debt, and other federal programs); and (2) the amount of the federal debt at the end of the fiscal year and the amount of additional borrowing by the federal government in such fiscal year per each legal U.S. resident.</summary>
</bill>
