<bill session="113" type="h" number="1266" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 40, United States Code, concerning the calculation of transactions for the lease of land ports of entry and international bridges, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412383"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2013--Introduced.
Authorizes the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to enter into contracts for the lease of a land port of entry or an international bridge (covered facility) and its site for periods not exceeding 30 years. Requires the Administrator to transmit to Congress an analysis of the cost effectiveness of leasing the covered facility, as compared to directly purchasing or constructing it, before entering into any contract to lease, purchase, or build a covered facility.</summary>
</bill>
