<bill session="110" type="h" number="3666" updated="2013-07-19T21:36:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreclosure Prevention and Homeownership Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a bipartisan commission to perform a comprehensive examination of the current foreclosure and mortgage lending crisis and to make recommendations for legislative and regulatory changes to address such problems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Usury"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2007--Introduced.
Foreclosure Prevention and Homeownership Protection Act - Establishes the Commission to Preserve the American Dream (Commission) to study and report to Congress and the President on: (1) the adequacy of the existing legal and regulatory framework to address the current foreclosure and mortgage lending crisis and to prevent similar crises from happening in the future; (2) the role of the states versus the role of the federal government in ensuring homeowners are protected against unscrupulous lending practices; and (3) the effects of this crisis on the domestic and world economies. Requires the Commission to make recommendations regarding: (1) ways to assist homeowners currently in danger of losing their homes; (2) ways to encourage lenders and borrowers to work together to prevent foreclosure; and (3) legislative and regulatory changes to protect homeowners against unscrupulous lending practices and strengthen accountability for those involved in the mortgage lending market.</summary>
</bill>
