<bill session="112" type="s" number="774" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enduring Support for Defenders of Freedom and Their Families Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to appropriate funds for pay and allowances and support for members of the Armed Forces, their families, and other personnel critical to national security during a funding gap.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2359-2360" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1551"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="724"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2011--Introduced.
Enduring Support for Defenders of Freedom and Their Families Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, during a funding gap impacting the Armed Forces and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), to make available to the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Homeland Security (Secretaries) amounts necessary to continue to provide pay and allowances to: (1) members of the Armed Forces and the U.S. Customs and Border Protection who perform active service during the funding gap, and (2) DOD and DHS civilian and contractor personnel who provide support to the above personnel. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make available to such Secretaries amounts necessary to continue carrying out programs that provide direct support to members of the Armed Forces and DHS, including family support and medical treatment programs.</summary>
</bill>
