<bill session="112" type="s" number="1083" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Smoky Hill National Historic Trail Study Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the National Trails System Act to designate the route of the Smoky Hill Trail, an overland trail across the Great Plains during pioneer days in Kansas and Colorado, for study for potential addition to the National Trails System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-224.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Smoky Hill National Historic Trail Study Act - Amends the National Trails System Act to designate the Smoky Hill Trail in Kansas and Colorado, which was an overland trail route across the Great Plains during pioneer days beginning in 1859 and ending with the arrival of the railroad in Denver in 1870, for study for potential addition to the National Trails System as a national scenic trail. Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from considering specified alternatives related to private property protections. Requires such study to include an analysis and documentation regarding whether each alternative proposed has potential or actual impact on private property within or adjacent to the trail area. Requires private property owners whose land will be studied to be notified that such study will be conducted.</summary>
</bill>
