<bill session="113" type="s" number="1155" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:36-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Veterans Mental Health Care Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for advance appropriations for certain information technology accounts of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to include mental health professionals in training programs of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2013--Introduced.
Rural Veterans Mental Health Care Improvement Act - Amends appropriations authorities for veterans' benefits to provide advanced appropriations for information technology relating to medical services, support, compliance, and facilities of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA). Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to include, as a component of VHA health-care personnel education and training programs, education and training of marriage and family therapists as well as licensed professional mental health counselors. Amends the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010 to require the Secretary, through VA medical centers, to provide mental health services, including outpatient care, to the immediate families of certain veterans returning from Operation Enduring Freedom or Operation Iraqi Freedom. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress regarding telemedicine services (the use by a health care provider of telecommunications to assist in the diagnosis or treatment of a patient's medical condition) for veterans, including updates on VA teleconsultation and telemedicine initiatives, training, and partnerships with primary care providers.</summary>
</bill>
