<bill session="112" type="h" number="4274" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BPCA and PREA Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act and title V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to permanently extend the provisions of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act and the Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400342"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2012-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5651"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2012--Introduced.
BPCA and PREA Reauthorization Act of 2012 - Makes permanent the provisions of the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act (BPCA) and the Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003 (PREA). Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise provisions concerning pediatric research requirements and the granting of exclusivity. Extends the period for mandatory reporting of adverse events to the Office of Pediatric Therapeutics to 18 months after an approved label change. Requires a product sponsor to submit an Initial Pediatric Plan as part of the drug application process and sets forth the process for such submission. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) grant a deferral extension, and sets forth the conditions for such deferral; and (2) issue a non-compliance letter to a product sponsor failing to meet post-marketing requirements, and requires the product sponsor to respond in writing. Authorizes the Pediatric Review Committee to review deferral extensions. Requires the Office of Pediatric Therapeutics to include a neonatologist and pediatric epidemiologist. Reauthorizes the Pediatric Advisory Committee and the Pediatric Subcommittee of the Oncologic Drugs Advisory Committee.</summary>
</bill>
