<bill session="111" type="h" number="4237" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the courts of the United States may provide an impartial forum for claims brought by United States citizens and others against any railroad organized as a separate legal entity, arising from the deportation of United States citizens and others to Nazi concentration camps on trains owned or operated by such railroad, and by the heirs and survivors of such persons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="28"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Grants U.S. district courts original jurisdiction over any civil action for damages for personal injury or death that: (1) arose from the deportation of persons to Nazi concentration camps between January 1, 1942, and December 31, 1944; and (2) is brought by or on behalf of such person against a railroad that owned or operated the trains on which the persons were deported and that was organized as a separate legal entity.Provides that: (1) no law limiting the jurisdiction of the U.S. courts shall preclude any such action; and (2) no such action shall be barred because a statute of limitations has expired. Makes this Act applicable to any action pending on or commenced after January 1, 2002.</summary>
</bill>
