<bill session="109" type="h" number="5374" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ban it All, Ban it Now Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to ban soft money, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2006--Introduced.
Ban it All, Ban it Now Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 with respect to the ban on the use of soft money by political parties and candidates. Applies the ban to all activities of a national committee of a political party and its officers and agents, including the construction or purchase of an office building of facility, the influencing of a state's reapportionment decisions, and the financing of litigation relating to such reapportionment decisions. Reduces from $20,000 to $10,000 the maximum amount of donations by an individual to a tax-exempt organization for voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities. Subjects to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of such Act the use of soft money: (1) by corporations and labor organizations for nonpartisan voter registration and get-out-the vote activities; (2) by certain tax-exempt or 527 political organizations for get-out-the-vote activities; and (3) for any partisan voter registration activities.</summary>
</bill>
