<bill session="112" type="s" number="1289" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TAX GAP Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Taxpayer Advocacy and Government Accountability Promotion Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the tax gap, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2011--Introduced.
Taxpayer Advocacy and Government Accountability Promotion Act of 2011 or the TAX GAP Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) eliminate certain payment requirements for submitting offers-in-compromise of tax liability; (2) expand requirements for electronic filing of tax returns to certain large corporations and partnerships; (3) require additional information on tax returns relating to mortgage interest; (4) expand information reporting requirements for bank accounts, non-interest bearing deposits, and electronic filings by paid tax preparers; (5) expand withholding requirements with respect to payments to contractors and extend the continuous levy to cover payments to Medicaid and Medicare providers; (6) require the heads of the Federal Bureau of Prisons and state prisons to provide detailed information to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) on certain inmates; (7) grant the IRS access to information in the National Directory of New Hires for tax administration purposes; and (8) increase and expand criminal and civil penalties for failure to comply with tax reporting and filing requirements, including requirements for electronic filing. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to make an apology payment to a taxpayer for any action or inaction by the IRS that has caused the taxpayer excess expense or undue burden. Excludes the amount of any such apology payment from taxpayer gross income. Directs the Secretary to: (1) revise Schedule C of tax form 1040 (self-employment income) to require reporting of additional gross receipts and expense information by sole proprietors, and (2) report to Congress on efforts to improve voluntary compliance by sole proprietors. Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress: (1) a report on taxpayer assistance and tax simplification, (2) comprehensive and detailed reports on a strategy for reducing the tax gap, (3) a study on revenue increases and costs with respect to tax gap legislation, and (4) reports on worker misclassification (e.g., employees classified as independent contractors).</summary>
</bill>
