<bill session="112" type="s" number="1270" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible Electronics Recycling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the export from the United States of certain electronic waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4173"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2284"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Responsible Electronics Recycling Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to: (1) prohibit the export of restricted electronic waste to countries that are not members of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) or the European Union (EU), or Liechtenstein; (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop and promulgate procedures for identifying certain electronic equipment as well as additional restricted toxic materials contained in such equipment which poses a potential hazard to human health or the environment; and (3) establish criminal penalties for knowingly exporting restricted electronic waste in violation of this Act. Allows certain exceptions to such export ban. Defines "restricted electronic waste" to include electronic equipment (excluding parts of a motor vehicle), such as computers, televisions, printers, copiers, video game systems, telephones, and similar used electronic products, that contain cathode ray tubes, batteries, switches, and other parts containing lead, cadmium, mercury, organic solvents, hexavalent chromium, beryllium, or other toxic ingredients. Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require persons who handle restricted electronic wastes to permit appropriate EPA and state officials access to such wastes upon request. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish the Rare Earth Materials Recycling Research Initiative to provide grants for research in the recycling of rare earth materials found in electronic devices.</summary>
</bill>
