<bill session="109" type="s" number="1011" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Historic Country Store Preservation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a national historic country store preservation program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5073-5074"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5074-5075" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3689"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2005--Introduced.
National Historic Country Store Preservation Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a historic country store preservation program to: (1) collect and disseminate information on country stores; (2) promote State and regional partnerships among proprietors of historic country stores; and (3) sponsor and conduct research on the economic impact of historic country stores, best practices to improve profitability and protect such stores from foreclosure or seizure, and best practices for developing cooperative organizations that address economic and historic preservation needs of historic country stores. Allows the Secretary to make grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible applicants to carry out a project to: (1) rehabilitate or repair a historic country store; (2) identify, document, and conduct research on historic country stores; and (3) develop and evaluate appropriate techniques or best practices for protecting historic country stores. Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot project in Vermont under which the Secretary shall conduct demonstration activities to preserve historic country stores. Establishes in the Treasury the Historic Revolving Loan Fund. Provides for certain transfers to, and expenditures from, the Fund. Sets forth requirements for investment of amounts in the Fund. Authorizes the Secretary, using amounts in the Fund, to make loans to historic store proprietors and eligible applicants for projects to purchase, rehabilitate, or repair historic country stores.</summary>
</bill>
