<bill session="112" type="s" number="703" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HEARTH Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Expedite and Advance Responsible Tribal Homeownership Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Long-Term Leasing Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2012-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2051"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-32.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="205"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2011--Introduced.
Helping Expedite and Advance Responsible Tribal Homeownership Act of 2011 or HEARTH Act of 2011 - Extends to any Indian tribe the discretion granted under current law only to the Navajo Nation to lease restricted lands for business, agricultural, public, religious, educational, recreational, or residential purposes without the approval of the Secretary of the Interior. (The Secretary must still approve the tribal regulations under which those leases are executed and mining leases still require the Secretary's approval.) Sets forth the environmental review process required under tribal lease regulations before those regulations obtain the Secretary's approval. Requires the process to identify and evaluate any significant effects a proposed lease may have on the environment and allow public comment on those effects. Allows tribes to rely on a federal environmental review process rather than the tribal environmental review process if the project under review is federally funded. Directs the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) to report to Congress on the history and experience of Indian tribes that have chosen to assume the BIA's responsibility for operating the Indian Land Title and Records Office.</summary>
</bill>
