<bill session="112" type="h" number="2577" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Data Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secure and Fortify Electronic Data Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumers by requiring reasonable security policies and procedures to protect data containing personal information, and to provide for nationwide notice in the event of a security breach.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1707"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1841"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1207"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2011--Introduced.
Secure and Fortify Electronic Data Act or the SAFE Data Act - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations requiring any person engaged in interstate commerce that owns or possesses data containing personal information to establish and implement reasonable security policies and procedures to treat and protect such information. Requires such regulations to include specified policies and procedures, including: (1) a process for identifying and assessing vulnerabilities in the system, and (2) a process for taking preventive and corrective action to mitigate such vulnerabilities. Requires a person covered by this Act to establish a plan and procedures for minimizing the amount of personal information maintained. Exempts services providers from such requirements for any electronic communication by a third party that is transmitted, routed, or stored in intermediate or transient storage by the provider. Establishes notification procedures in the event of a breach of security of any system that contains personal information. Allows an exemption from notification requirements if a person subject to this Act determines that there is no reasonable risk of identity theft, fraud, or other unlawful conduct. Creates a presumption that no reasonable risk of such conduct exists following a breach of security if the data containing personal information is unusable, unreadable, or indecipherable to an unauthorized person by encryption or other security technology that is generally accepted by experts in the information security field. Directs a person subject to this Act to provide a credit report and credit monitoring if certain identifying information is breached. Sets forth provisions regarding enforcement of this Act by the FTC and by state attorneys general. Establishes civil penalties for violations. Exempts from the requirements of this Act any person subject to the information security requirements of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) or the Gramm-Leach Bliley Act.</summary>
</bill>
