<bill session="113" type="h" number="1919" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-03T16:34:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-03T16:34:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding America's Pharmaceuticals Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Safeguarding America's Pharmaceuticals Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the pharmaceutical distribution supply chain, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412534" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-93.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-03T15:58:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="65">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 65.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Latta moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2968-2984" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1919.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2013-06-03T16:34:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2969-2978" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T16:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Safeguarding America's Pharmaceuticals Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish requirements to facilitate the tracing of drug products through the pharmaceutical supply distribution chain. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish standards for the exchange of transaction information. Requires the Secretary to establish processes to: (1) provide waivers of requirements for undue economic hardship or emergency medical reasons; (2) provide waivers of requirements relating to product identifiers for prescription drug products packaged without sufficient space to bear the information; and (3) determine other prescription drug products or transactions that should be exempt from the requirements of this Act. Establishes requirements for drug manufacturers, wholesalers, dispensers, and repackagers to ensure that all prior transaction information is provided at each transfer of ownership. Requires such entities to maintain such transaction information for three years. Sets forth exceptions, including for dispensing to a patient and returns. Requires a manufacturer, wholesale distributor, dispenser, repackager, in the event of a recall or for the purpose of investigating a suspect prescription drug product or an illegitimate prescription drug product, to provide within two business days the applicable transaction documentation upon request by the Secretary or other appropriate federal or state official. Requires a manufacturer or repackager to affix or imprint a prescription drug product identifier on each package and homogenous case of a prescription drug product. Requires a manufacturer, wholesale distributor, dispenser, repackager, or third party logistics provider to ensure that each of its trading partners is authorized. Requires a manufacturer, wholesale distributor, dispenser, repackager, and third party logistics provider to implement systems to: (1) investigate suspected illegitimate prescription drug products or, for a third party logistics provider, notify the owner of a need for such an investigation, and (2) handle illegitimate prescription drug products, including through quarantine, disposal, and appropriate notice to the Secretary and, as necessary, trading partners. Requires manufacturers, wholesale distributors, repackagers to verify returned products before further distribution. Requires the Secretary to establish projects and hold public meetings to enhance the safety and security of the pharmaceutical distribution supply chain. Requires the Secretary to issue additional proposed regulations in 2027 to prevent a suspect, illegitimate or counterfeit product, or a product otherwise unfit for distribution from entering into or being further distributed in the supply chain. Requires the Secretary to establish standards for the licensing of wholesale distributors and third party logistics providers. Requires third party logistics providers to be licensed by the state from which the drug is distributed or by the Secretary. Preempts state and local requirements related to tracing drugs through the distribution system, and licensure of wholesale distributors or third party logistics provider licensure. Allows certain prescription drug labeling to be provided solely by electronic means.</summary>
</bill>
