<bill session="109" type="s" number="1784" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National MEDiC Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Medical Error Disclosure and Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to promote a culture of safety within the health care system through the establishment of a National Medical Error Disclosure and Compensation Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10599"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2005--Introduced.
National Medical Error Disclosure and Compensation Act or the National MEDiC Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Office of Patient Safety and Health Care Quality to improve patient safety and reduce medical errors across the health care system. Requires the Director of the Office to establish and maintain a National Patient Safety Database to receive nonidentifiable patient safety work product. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to establish the National Medical Error Disclosure and Compensation (MEDiC) Program to provide for the confidential disclosure of medical errors and patient safety events, reduce preventable medical errors, ensure patient access to fair compensation for medical injury due to medical error, negligence, or malpractice, and reduce the cost of medical liability for health care providers. Requires Program participants to: (1) spend savings from the Program on reducing medical liability premiums or on activities to reduce medical errors; (2) report to a patient safety officer any medical error or patient safety event or any legal action related to the medical liability of a health care provider; (3) report to the patient any medical error that resulted in harm; and (4) offer to negotiate compensation with the patient and offer to provide an apology. Requires the Director to award grants to facilitate the reporting, collection, and analysis of patient safety data and the development and dissemination of training guidelines and other recommendations to reduce medical errors and improve patient safety and quality of care. Requires the Director to analyze: (1) patient safety data to determine performance and systems standards, tools, and best practices for health care providers; (2) the medical liability insurance market to determine legal costs related to medical liability, factors leading to such legal costs, and the success of any state reforms; and (3) patient safety data to examine cases that were not successfully negotiated through the Program.</summary>
</bill>
