<bill session="113" type="h" number="2535" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To cause increased seigniorage for the United States Mint leading to enhanced revenue to the Treasury and increased offsets to annual budget deficits in perpetuity, to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue coins commemorating and celebrating American Liberty, "The Union", and the American values and attributes of freedom, independence, civil governance, enlightenment, peace, strength, equality, democracy, and justice, to provide for the continued and concurrent production and distribution of existing presidentially-themed circulating and numismatic coinage designs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412541"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study the estimated effect of coinage under this Act on the federal budget deficit over the 10-year period beginning on January 1, 2015. Directs the Secretary, if the study estimates a deficit reduction of $100 million or more, to mint and issue in calendar 2015 and every second ensuing year dime and numismatic half dollar coins, and in calendar 2016 and every second ensuing year quarter dollar coins, meeting specified criteria that commemorate and celebrate American liberty, "the Union," and the American values and attributes of freedom, independence, civil governance, enlightenment, peace, strength, equality, democracy, and justice. Authorizes the Secretary to mint and issue such coins with a content of .999 fine silver obtained from available resources, including stockpiles established under the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act.</summary>
</bill>
