<bill session="111" type="sr" number="453" updated="2013-07-20T00:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution supporting the goals and ideals of "National Public Health Week".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1464"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1463-1464" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1162"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2010--Introduced.
Expresses support for the goals and ideals of National Public Health Week. Recognizes: (1) the efforts of public health professionals, the federal government, states, municipalities, local communities, and individuals in improving the health of the people of the United States; and (2) the role of public health programs in preventing disease, promoting good health, protecting the food supply, protecting worker health and safety, ensuring access to clean air and water, promoting nutrition for children, and achieving the many other benefits of public health programs that promote the health of people of the United States. Encourages: (1) efforts to increase access to clinical and community-based preventive services, and to strengthen the public health system of the United States; (2) community planners to consider the health implications of planning decisions and to plan communities and transportation systems that enable all residents to access safe, affordable housing, nutritious foods, clean air and water, public transportation, safe sidewalks, streets, and public health services; and (3) each person in the United States to learn about the role of public health programs in improving the health of the people of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
