<bill session="112" type="s" number="1031" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicaid Improvement and State Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to empower States with programmatic flexibility and financial predictability to improve their Medicaid programs and State Children's Health Insurance Programs by ensuring better health care for low-income pregnant women, children, and families, and for elderly individuals and disabled individuals in need of long-term care services and supports, whose income and resources are insufficient to meet the costs of necessary medical services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2013"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2011--Introduced.
Medicaid Improvement and State Empowerment Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to add a new part B (Taxpayer Provided Pass-Through Funding of Health Care Grants to States for Pregnant Women, Low-Income Children, and Low-Income Families and for Long-Term Care Services and Supports for Low-Income Elderly or Disabled Individuals). Entitles each state that has submitted a plan for each 12-month period to receive a health grant from the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide: (1) medical assistance to pregnant women, low-income children, and low-income families with children whose income and resources are insufficient to meet the costs of medical, rehabilitation, and other services necessary to help them attain or retain capability for independence or self-care; and (2) long-term care services and supports for low-income elderly or disabled individuals with insufficient income and resources to meet the costs of services to help them attain or retain such capability. Directs the Secretary to award grants to assist eligible states in implementing state-based medical malpractice reforms. Terminates funding under SSA titles XIX and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP). Repeals the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the health care-related provisions in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010. Restores or revives the provisions of law amended or repealed by such Acts as if they had not been enacted. Directs the Secretary to establish a new formula for payments made to or received from states under parts D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) and E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of SSA title IV that are based on the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) applicable to the state under Medicaid.</summary>
</bill>
