<bill session="110" type="s" number="1114" updated="2013-07-19T22:29:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Improvement and Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reiterate the exclusivity of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 as the sole authority to permit the conduct of electronic surveillance, to modernize surveillance authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4491-4492"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4492-4494" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2007--Introduced.
Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Improvement and Enhancement Act of 2007 - Prescribes the federal law provisions governing domestic electronic surveillance. Amends title I (Electronic Surveillance) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to prohibit any provision of law from being construed to repeal or modify any provision of such title in any manner unless such provision of law, if enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act, expressly amends or otherwise specifically cites such title.Directs the President to brief each member of the congressional intelligence committees on: (1) the Terrorist Surveillance Program of the National Security Agency (NSA); and (2) any program which involves the electronic surveillance of U.S. persons in the United States for foreign intelligence purposes which is conducted by any federal department or entity without fully complying with the prescribed federal law provisions.Requires the Supreme Court to review at least one pending case concerning the constitutionality of the surveillance program. Revises FISA provisions concerning electronic surveillance to: (1) extend the period for the application for orders for emergency electronic surveillance; and (2) authorize the AG to appoint personnel within the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and NSA to authorize emergency surveillance.Provides for the implementation of a document management system for, and authorizes additional personnel for the preparation and consideration of, electronic surveillance applications.Authorizes the training of FBI and NSA personnel in foreign intelligence surveillance matters.Requires a FISA order authorizing electronic surveillance to be supported by a finding of probable cause that the surveillance target is a foreign power or agent thereof.</summary>
</bill>
