<bill session="110" type="h" number="5594" updated="2013-07-19T21:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vessel Discharge Evaluation and Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Commandant of the Coast Guard to conduct an evaluation and review of certain vessel discharges.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2008-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2645"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2645"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2008--Introduced.
Vessel Discharge Evaluation and Review Act - Directs the Coast Guard's Commandant to conduct an evaluation of vessel discharges, other than ballast water, and report to specified congressional committees. Amends the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to suspend, beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and notwithstanding any other provision of law, any requirement to obtain a permit for a discharge incidental to the normal operation of a vessel. Requires promulgation of a final rule establishing enforceable uniform national discharge standards modeled on the regulatory program for vessels of the Armed Forces and based upon the best available technology. Preempts related state and local laws regarding a discharge incidental to the normal operation of a vessel, subject to exception. Lists certain discharges that are unaffected by or excluded from this Act, including discharges from Armed Forces vessels, discharges of vessel sewage, and discharges from certain fishing and fish tender vessels. Makes this Act, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the exclusive statutory authority for federal regulation of vessel discharges to which these provisions apply.</summary>
</bill>
