<bill session="112" type="h" number="1354" updated="2013-07-20T01:22:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Jobs Matter Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 10 and 41, United States Code, to allow contracting officers to consider information regarding domestic employment before awarding a Federal contract, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2011-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO30" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1363"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2011--Introduced.
American Jobs Matter Act of 2011 - Requires an executive agency to state in a solicitation for competitive proposals that the agency may consider information that the offeror may include on the effects awarding the contract to the offeror would have on employment within the United States (jobs impact statement). Allows such statement to include a guarantee that jobs created or retained in the United States will not be moved outside the United States after award of the contract. Requires each agency to: (1) assess, annually, the accuracy of such a statement submitted by an offeror awarded a contract; (2) submit an annual report on the frequency of use of such statements in evaluating competitive proposals; and (3) track the number of jobs created or retained during the performance of a contract awarded to an offeror that submitted such a statement. Authorizes an agency to evaluate whether a contractor should be proposed for debarment if the number of jobs that the agency estimates will be created based on such statement significantly exceeds the number created or retained. Sets forth analogous provisions for defense contracts. Requires revision of the Federal Acquisition Regulation to implement the amendments made by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
