<bill session="111" type="h" number="1531" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate the export of United States agricultural products to Cuba as authorized by the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, to remove impediments to the export to Cuba of medical devices and medicines, to allow travel to Cuba by United States legal residents, to establish an agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2009-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, Agriculture, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4645"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1089"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3112"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2009--Introduced.
Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2009 - Prohibits the President from restricting direct transfers from a Cuban depository institution to a U.S. depository institution in payment for a product authorized for sale under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide information and technical assistance to U.S. agricultural producers, cooperative organizations, or state agencies to promote U.S. agricultural exports products to Cuba. Authorizes the issuance of temporary entry visas to Cuban nationals to facilitate purchase of U.S. agricultural products. Amends the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to repeal the prohibition on enforcement of rights to certain U.S. intellectual properties and such properties' transfer. Prohibits the President from regulating or prohibiting travel to or from Cuba by U.S. citizens or legal residents, or any of the transactions ordinarily incident to such travel, and any regulation restricting or prohibiting such travel shall have no effect, relating to: (1) accompanied personal baggage; (2) payment of living expenses and the acquisition of personal-use goods or services; (3) travel arrangements; (4) nonscheduled air, sea, or land voyage transactions, (such provision does not permit the carriage of articles other than accompanied baggage into Cuba or the United States); and (5) normal banking transactions. States that such provision shall not apply in time of war or armed hostilities between the United States and Cuba, or of imminent danger to the public health or the physical safety of U.S. travelers. Amends the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 to repeal the requirement for onsite verification of certain medical exports to Cuba. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the airport ticket tax for transportation between the United States and Cuba by $1; and (2) establish in the Treasury the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
