<bill session="111" type="h" number="1650" updated="2013-07-19T23:26:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Troubled Asset Relief Program Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the oversight authority of the Comptroller General of the United States with respect to expenditures under the Troubled Asset Relief Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400270"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="340"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
Troubled Asset Relief Program Enhancement Act - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to require the Comptroller General to oversee the performance of the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) in meeting EESA purposes involving public accountability for the exercise of its authority. Grants the Comptroller General access, upon request, to any information, data, schedules, books, accounts, financial records, reports, files, electronic communications, or other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the TARP, any entity established by the Secretary under EESA, or any entity participating in a program established under EESA, and to any of their officers, employees, directors, independent public accountants, financial advisors and any and all other agents and representatives. Requires the Comptroller General to be afforded full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances or securities held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians. Prohibits the Comptroller General from disclosing publicly any proprietary or trade secret information obtained under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
