<bill session="109" type="sr" number="494" updated="2013-07-19T20:11:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the creation of refugee populations in the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf region as a result of human rights violations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2006-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2006-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2006-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2006-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2006-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5257-5259" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab countries"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Christianity"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States deplores the past and continuing violation of the human rights and religious freedoms of minority populations in Arab and Muslim countries throughout the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf; and (2) with respect to Jews, Christians, and other displaced populations from countries in the region any comprehensive Middle East peace agreement must resolve all outstanding issues, including the legitimate rights of all Middle East refugees. Urges the President to instruct the U.S. Representative to the United Nations and all U.S. representatives in bilateral and multilateral fora that, when the United States considers resolutions that refer to Middle East refugees, the U.S. delegation should ensure that: (1) relevant text refers to multiple refugee populations that have been caused by the Arab-Israeli conflict; and (2) any explicit reference to the resolution of the Palestinian refugee issue is matched by a similar reference to the resolution of the issue of Jewish, Christian, and other refugees from Arab countries. Urges the President to make clear that the United States supports the position that, as an integral part of any comprehensive peace, the issue of refugees and the mass violations of human rights of minorities in Arab and Muslim countries throughout the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf must be resolved in a manner that includes: (1) consideration of the legitimate rights of all refugees displaced from Arab countries; and (2) recognition of the losses incurred by Jews, Christians, and other minority groups as a result of the Arab-Israeli conflict.</summary>
</bill>
