<bill session="111" type="s" number="2926" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Economic Fairness for Seniors Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the application of a consistent Medicare part B premium for all Medicare beneficiaries in a budget neutral manner for 2010, to provide an additional round of economic recovery payments to certain beneficiaries, and to assess the need for a consumer price index for elderly consumers to compute cost-of-living increases for certain governmental benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-12-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/23/2009--Introduced.
Economic Fairness for Seniors Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to keep the same Medicare part B premium for 2010 that was in effect for 2009. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Tax Act of 2009 (ARRA) to require an additional economic recovery payment (of $250) in calendar 2010 to certain beneficiaries of SSA title II (Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI), railroad retirement, or veterans benefits. Makes appropriations to fund such payments. Directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) of the Department of Labor to study and report to Congress on: (1) whether a consumer price index for elderly consumers (CPI-E) more accurately reflects the true costs of inflation for elderly Americans than the Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers (CPI-W); and (2) if the elderly are being financially disadvantged by the use of the CPI-W in the determination of current benefit levels. Requires the BLS to prepare such a CPI-E if elderly Americans are disadvantaged by the CPI-W. Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to offset the expenses of this Act through a reduction in Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) Funds.</summary>
</bill>
