<bill session="113" type="h" number="1499" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster-Affected Homeowners Notification Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that homeowners who have mortgages insured by the FHA, or owned or guaranteed by Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac, and whose homes are located in major disaster areas are notified of any forbearance relief in connection with such disaster that is offered or recommended by the FHA, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Federal National Mortgage Association, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412561"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Disaster-Affected Homeowners Notification Act of 2013 - Requires certain notifications if, in connection with any major disaster declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), the Director of the Federal Housing Agency, the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) makes available forbearance relief with respect to any covered mortgage, or any such agency head or enterprise issues any notice or guidelines to mortgagees or servicers recommending or requiring such relief. Directs the applicable agency head to provide: (1) to each mortgagor under a covered mortgage direct notification of the forbearance relief made available, required, or recommended; and (2) for areas subject to such disaster declaration, community-wide notification of such relief. Directs the applicable agency heads to issue guidelines regarding measures designed to provide notice and awareness of forbearance relief.</summary>
</bill>
