<bill session="112" type="hj" number="12" updated="2013-07-20T02:08:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Denouncing the practices of female genital mutilation, domestic violence, "honor" killings, acid burnings, dowry deaths, and other gender-based persecutions, expressing the sense of Congress that participation, protection, recognition, and equality of women is crucial to achieving a just, moral and peaceful society, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2011--Introduced.
Denounces and demands the cessation of the practices of female genital mutilation, domestic violence, honor killings, acid burning, dowry deaths, and other gender-based persecutions and crimes. Asserts that women are not chattel, should not be trafficked, exploited, or sold for services, and should not be denied the right to education, to ownership of property, or to participate in full, economic, social and political life. Demands the dismantling of social and institutional mechanisms which perpetuate systematic discrimination against women and girls. Calls on all governments to pass enforceable laws banning these practices, prosecute any individuals who persecute or violate women and girls with these acts, and pass measures to empower women and girls and afford them equal access to educational, social, and economic opportunities. Directs the President, in conjunction with fellow donor countries, to seek to promote the rights, health, empowerment of women in every aspect of their foreign assistance to developing countries, and discourage continued acts of violence against women and the impunity that often accompanies these acts. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) participation, protection, recognition, health, and equality of women and girls are crucial to achieving a just, moral, and peaceful society; and (2) regardless of religion, geography, or form of government, women should not be denied equal rights, which should be defended and enforced when they are abridged, challenged, or violated.</summary>
</bill>
