<bill session="113" type="h" number="2344" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TBI Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to carry out a pilot program for investigational treatment of members of the Armed Forces for traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2013-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E894-895"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2013--Introduced.
TBI Treatment Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to carry out a five-year pilot program to establish a process for providing payments to health care facilities for investigational treatments of traumatic brain injury or post-traumatic stress disorder received by members of the Armed Forces in facilities other than military treatment facilities. Subjects such payments to specified conditions, including approval of the treatment by the Secretary and demonstrated improvement by the patient. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop and maintain a database containing data from each patient case involving the use of such treatments, (2) establish a process to notify members of the Armed Forces of the opportunity to receive such treatments, and (3) report annually to Congress on the implementation of this Act and any available results of investigational treatment studies.</summary>
</bill>
