<bill session="111" type="h" number="944" updated="2013-07-19T23:20:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prisoner of War Benefits Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide improved benefits for veterans who are former prisoners of war.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2009--Introduced.
Prisoner of War Benefits Act of 2009 - Amends federal veterans' benefits provisions with respect to former prisoners of war (POWs) to repeal the currently required 30-day minimum period of internment prior to the presumption of service connection for certain listed diseases, for purposes of the payment of veterans' disability compensation. Adds diabetes (type 2) to the above listed diseases. Removes the requirement that, in order for osteoporosis to be included among the listed diseases, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs must determine that the veteran has post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Requires: (1) such presumption also with respect to any disease that the Secretary determines warrants such presumption by reason of having a positive association with the experience of being a prisoner of war; and (2) the Secretary to make such a determination within 60 days after a recommendation from the Advisory Committee on Former Prisoners of War that such presumption be established for a non-listed disease.</summary>
</bill>
