<bill session="111" type="h" number="5170" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sergeant Coleman S. Bean Individual Ready Reserve Suicide Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to provide members of the Individual Ready Reserve who served in Afghanistan or Iraq with information on counseling to prevent suicide.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3678"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
Sergeant Coleman S. Bean Individual Ready Reserve Suicide Prevention Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to ensure that each of the following individuals receive, at least once every 90 days, a telephone call from properly-trained DOD personnel to determine their emotional, psychological, medical, and career needs and concerns: (1) members of the Individual Ready Reserve who deployed to Afghanistan or Iraq in support of a contingency operation; or (2) a member of a reserve component who the Secretary determines is an individual mobilization augmentee who has so deployed. Requires the person making the call to refer a member identified as being at-risk of self-caused harm to the nearest military medical treatment facility or accredited TRICARE (a DOD managed health care program) provider for immediate evaluation and necessary treatment. Requires annual reports from the Secretary to Congress on the number of members so referred, as well as their health and career status.</summary>
</bill>
