<bill session="113" type="hr" number="380" updated="2013-11-02T06:18:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-11T15:53:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-11T15:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Relating to consideration of the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 2642) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes, providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 378) expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding certain provisions of the Senate amendment to H.R. 2642 relating to the Secretary of Agriculture's administration of tariff-rate quotas for raw and refined sugar, and providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 379) expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding certain provisions of the Senate amendment to H.R. 2642 relating to crop insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400643"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-244, by Ms. Foxx.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-11T14:01:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="67">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 67.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6505-6514" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T14:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 380.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T15:42:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 193 (Roll no. 543).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6513" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="544" datetime="2013-10-11T15:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 189 (Roll no. 544).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6505" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="378"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="379"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2642"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of: H.Res. 378 (Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives regarding certain provisions of the Senate amendment to H.R. 2642 [Federal Agriculture Reform and Risk Management Act of 2013] relating to the Secretary of Agriculture's administration of tariff-rate quotas for raw and refined sugar), and H.Res. 379 (Expresses the sense of the House regarding certain provisions of the Senate amendment to H.R. 2642 relating to crop insurance).</summary>
</bill>
