<bill session="112" type="hc" number="34" updated="2013-07-20T02:09:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15T14:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-04-15T14:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2012 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2013 through 2021.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-11T23:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on The Budget reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-58, by Mr. Ryan (WI).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-11T23:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="30">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 30.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T20:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 223 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 34 with 4 hours of general debate. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution. The resolution waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of this report. The resolution permits the Chairman of the Budget Committee to offer amendments in the House pursuant to section 305(a)(5) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to achieve mathematical consistency. Finally, the resolution provides that the concurrent resolution shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question of its adoption.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T13:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 223 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 223.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2804-2811, H2812-2815, H2815-2851" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2837-2843" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 34 with 4 hours of general debate. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution. The resolution waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of this report. The resolution permits the Chairman of the Budget Committee to offer amendments in the House pursuant to section 305(a)(5) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to achieve mathematical consistency. Finally, the resolution provides that the concurrent resolution shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question of its adoption.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 223 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 4 hours of general debate on H. Con. Res. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T21:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 223, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Cleaver substitute amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T22:12:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cleaver substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cleaver demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T22:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T22:14:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14T22:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 34 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2861-2862, H2862-2870, H2870-2901" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T09:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message from the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T09:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Subsequently, the Committee resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T09:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 223, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Grijalva substitute amendment no. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T10:04:00-04:00">
      <text>WORDS TAKEN DOWN - During the course of debate, exception was taken to certain words used and a demand was made to have words taken down. Mr. Brooks asked unanimous consent to withdraw the words. Without objection the words were withdrawn. The Committee of the Whole resumed with debate on the Grijalva substitute amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grijalva substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message from the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Subsequently, the Committee resumed it's sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 223, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Garrett(NJ) substitute amendment no. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T11:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T11:11:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 223, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Van Hollen substitute amendment no. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 223, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of general debate on H. Con. Res. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H. Con. Res. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2901" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-04-15T14:22:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="277" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 193 (Roll no. 277).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Budget discharged pursuant to Section 300 of the Congressional Budget Act.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-05-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="36">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 36.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 40 - 57. Record Vote Number: 77.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3331-3332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hc" number="37"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hc" number="112"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="223"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="18"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="19"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="20"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sc" number="21"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="General taxation matters"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h256"/>
    <amendment number="h257"/>
    <amendment number="h258"/>
    <amendment number="h259"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2012, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2013-FY2021. Title I: Recommended Levels and Amounts - (Sec. 101) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2012-FY2021 with respect to: (1) federal revenues, (2) new budget authority, (3) budget outlays, (4) deficits (on-budget), (5) debt subject to limit, and (6) debt held by the public. (Sec. 102) Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority and outlays for specified major functional categories for FY2012-FY2021. Title II: Recommended Levels and Amounts for FY2030, FY2040, and FY2050 - (Sec. 201) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2030, FY2040, and FY2050 as a percent of the federal gross domestic product (GDP) with respect to: (1) federal revenues, (2) budget outlays, (3) deficits, and (4) debt held by the public. Title III: Reserve and Contingencies - (Sec. 301) Authorizes adjustment of allocations to the House Committee on Appropriations for the costs of the global war on terrorism and other activities for FY2012 if legislation makes appropriations for such costs and it is designated under this resolution. (Sec. 303) Authorizes certain reserve funds for legislation for health care reform and the sustainable growth rate of the Medicare program. (Sec. 305) Authorizes certain deficit-neutral reserve funds for revenue measures and for rural counties and schools. Title IV: Budget Enforcement - (Sec. 401) Establishes specified discretionary spending limits in the House for FY2012-FY2021. Makes it out of order to consider in the House any legislation that would cause the discretionary spending limits in this section to be exceeded. (Sec. 402) Prohibits House legislation that would require advance appropriations, except certain FY2013 programs, projects, activities, or accounts. (Sec. 404) Authorizes the chairman of the House Committee on the Budget, under specified conditions, to adjust allocations and aggregates in this resolution for the budgetary effects of: (1) measures extending the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001; (2) measures extending the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003; (3) measures that adjust the Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) exemption amounts to prevent a larger number of taxpayers as compared with tax year 2008 from being subject to the ATM or of allowing the use of nonrefundable personal credits against it, or both as applicable; (4) extending the estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer tax requirements of title III of the Tax Relief, Unemployment Insurance Reauthorization, and Job Creation Act of 2010; (5) measures implementing trade agreements; (6) repealing or reforming the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Health Care and Education Affordability Reconciliation Act of 2010; and (7) measures reforming the tax code and lower tax rates. Disqualifies measures from such adjustments that increase: (1) the federal deficit between FY2012-FY2021; or (2) revenues over such period, other than by repealing or modifying the individual mandate or by modifying the subsidies to purchase health insurance (both codified in the Internal Revenue Code). Declares that, if a committee other than the Committee on Appropriations reports legislation that decreases direct spending (budget authority and outlays) for any fiscal year and also that authorizes appropriations for the same purpose, upon the enactment of such measure, the chairman of the Committee on the Budget may decrease the allocation to such committee and increase the allocation of discretionary spending to the Committee on Appropriations for FY2012 and the applicable discretionary spending limits by an amount equal to the new budget authority and outlays provided for in legislation making appropriations for the same purpose. (Sec. 405) Makes it out of order in the House to consider legislation reported out of committee (other than the Committee on Appropriations) if it has the net effect of increasing mandatory spending in excess of $5 billion for any of the first four consecutive 10-fiscal-year periods beginning with the first fiscal year following the last fiscal year for which the applicable budget resolution sets forth appropriate budgetary levels. (Sec. 406) Requires the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any budget resolution to include in its allocation to the House Committee on Appropriations amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration (SSA) and of the Postal Service. Authorizes the chairman to adjust allocations and aggregates for legislation reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform that reforms the federal retirement system, but does not cause a net increase in the deficit for FY2012-FY2021. (Sec. 408) Requires any CBO estimate prepared for a measure under the Federal Credit Reform Act also to provide, as a supplement, and to the extent practicable, upon the request of the chairman or ranking member of the Committee on the Budget, an estimate of the current actual or estimated market values representing the "fair value" of assets and liabilities affected by such measure. Authorizes the chairman to use such estimate to determine compliance with the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 and other budgetary enforcement controls. (Sec. 409) Terminates the force and effect of H.Res. 5 (112th Congress) provisions relating to: (1) advance appropriations, (2) the treatment of off-budget administrative expenses, and (3) a long-term spending point of order. Title V: Policy - (Sec. 501) Declares the policy on this resolution on: (1) Medicare reform, (2) Social Security, and (3) budget enforcement. Title VI: Sense of the House Provisions - (Sec. 601) Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives on: (1) a responsible deficit reduction plan must consider all programs, including those at the Pentagon and other national security agencies; and (2) the importance of child support enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
