<bill session="110" type="h" number="2801" updated="2013-07-19T21:28:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Refuge and Wilderness Enhancement and King Cove Safe Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the inclusion of certain non-Federal land in the Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Wildlife Refuges and Wilderness in the State of Alaska and for the granting of a right-of-way for safe and reliable access for the Native Village of King Cove, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-04-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1680"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1680"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2007--Introduced.
Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Refuge and Wilderness Enhancement and King Cove Safe Access Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the state of Alaska King Cove Road and Sitkinak Island upon: (1) conveyance by the state and other owners of specified non-federal land, including King Cove Corporation, to the Secretary of title to such non-federal land; and (2) certification by the governor of the state that the state-owned land at Kinzaroff Lagoon has been designated under state law as a state refuge. Requires the King Cove Road conveyance to be used for construction of a state road. Provides, upon conveyance of the non-federal land to the Secretary, for the designation of the wilderness additions to the Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Wildlife Refuges as wilderness.</summary>
</bill>
