<bill session="111" type="h" number="6514" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Jobs in Your State Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the use of certain stimulus and disaster relief funds for business relocation incentives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2010-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2010--Introduced.
Protecting Jobs in Your State Act of 2010 - Prohibits a state or a political subdivision from using funds made available under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA), the Hiring Incentives to Restore Employment Act, Public Law 111-226 (relating to education jobs and Medicaid payments to states), the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010, or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, or funds for disaster relief administered by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), as an incentive for a business to: (1) relocate a plant, facility, or other operation from one state to another; or (2) expand an operation in a state in a manner that will result in a reduction in such an operation in another state. Authorizes a political subdivision to submit to the state governor a petition stating that it has been adversely affected by a violation of such prohibition and requesting that the governor submit to the Secretary of Commerce a petition for an investigation. Provides that if the Secretary determines that a violation has occurred, the state in which such a violation was committed shall be liable to the United States for the amount of funds involved. Prohibits such a state from receiving any other funds under such Acts until it fully repays such amount to the United States. Directs the Comptroller General, biannually during the period that ends five years after this Act's enactment, to submit to specified committees a report on the impact of such provisions, including: (1) a statement of the number of petitions received by the Secretary of Commerce and a summary of the disposition of such petitions; (2) a list of U.S. claims that arose, were outstanding, or were collected; and (3) a list of any funds withheld.</summary>
</bill>
