<bill session="110" type="s" number="1508" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Energy Production Tax Incentives Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and expand various tax incentives for production of renewable energy and clean energy sources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax havens"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Clean Energy Production Tax Incentives Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the rate of the tax credit for producing electricity from renewable resources and extend such credit through 2018; (2) extend the national limitation amount for clean renewable energy bonds through 2017; (3) extend the advanced coal project tax credit; and (4) extend through 2018 the tax credit for investment in qualified fuel cell and microturbine property and solar property.Allows new tax credits for the capture and storage or use of carbon dioxide and for investment in clean coal energy bonds, carbon dioxide capture bonds, and electric transmission property and bonds.Treats certain controlled foreign corporations created or organized under the laws of a tax haven country (as identified by the Secretary of the Treasury) as domestic corporations for income tax purposes.Includes in foreign base company income, for purposes of determining the foreign trade income of controlled foreign corporations, imported property income (income attributable to property manufactured outside of the United States and imported for sale into the United States). Changes the effective date of certain loss deferral rules applicable to leases entered into with a foreign person or entity on or before March 12, 2004. Sets forth rules for the application of the economic substance doctrine in evaluating transactions with tax implications. Imposes a penalty for understatements of tax due to transactions lacking economic substance. Denies a tax deduction for interest on underpayments of tax due to transactions lacking economic substance.</summary>
</bill>
