<bill session="111" type="h" number="4749" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stand By Every Ad Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require personal disclosure statements in all third-party communications advocating the election or defeat of a candidate, to require the disclosure of identifying information within communications made through the Internet, to apply disclosure requirements to prerecorded telephone calls, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2010--Introduced.
Stand By Every Ad Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require the identification of funding and authorizing sources in communications expressly advocating the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate (as under current law) or which consist of the functional equivalent of express advocacy. Prescribes special rules for express advocacy radio and television communications which are not authorized by a candidate, an authorized political committee of a candidate, or its agents. Requires individual disclosure statements about the head of the entity paying for the communication and about any other person that disbursed funds to the entity to finance the communication. Requires disclosure of such identifying information within audio and video communications made through the Internet or e-mail. Applies such disclosure requirements to prerecorded telephone calls.</summary>
</bill>
