<bill session="112" type="h" number="3976" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Exports Through Entrepreneurship Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide exporting assistance to small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Small Business, Financial Services, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA20" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2012--Introduced.
Enhancing Exports Through Entrepreneurship Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a small business export expansion credit of 25% of export expansion expenses. Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Office of International Trade (Office) to compile and update annually, for small businesses and their partner entities, a document that contains: (1) the tariff schedules of all foreign countries; and (2) for each of the 50 foreign countries to which the highest total value of U.S. goods and services are exported, specified information on the demand for goods and services in that country. Requires the Office to identify and advertise programs and services to small businesses, including federal programs and services, that facilitate the matching of foreign customers to small businesses. Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to increase, from 20% to 30% of the aggregate annual loan authority available to the Export-Import Bank, the amount to be used to finance small business exports. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to increase the proportion and percentage of projects and assistance financed for small businesses by the Overseas Private Investment Corporation. Provides limitations on duties under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule that apply to certain goods and services imported into the United States for use by small businesses in their regular operations.</summary>
</bill>
