<bill session="112" type="hr" number="434" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Celebrating the 10-year commemoration of the Underground Railroad Memorial, comprised of the Gateway to Freedom Monument in Detroit, Michigan and the Tower of Freedom Monument in Windsor, Ontario, Canada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412440" joined="2011-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/2011--Introduced.
Celebrates the 10-year commemoration of the Underground Railroad Memorial, comprised of the Gateway to Freedom Monument in Detroit, Michigan, and the Tower of Freedom Monument in Windsor, Ontario, Canada. Supports the designation of an International Freedom Corridor and the nomination of the Detroit River as an International World Heritage Site. Recognizes that a National Park Service (NPS) special resource study may establish national significance, suitability, and feasibility of a National Freedom Corridor. Acknowledges that the National Heritage Areas and Corridors are examples of recognitions that do not involve establishing a new unit of the National Park System, and for which the role of the NPS is primarily to assist state and local initiatives to preserve resources.</summary>
</bill>
