<bill session="109" type="h" number="3712" updated="2013-07-19T19:37:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gas Stamps Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program for gas stamps and to impose a windfall profits tax on crude oil, natural gas, and products thereof.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2005-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2005-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Excess profits tax"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2005--Introduced.
Gas Stamps Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) establish a program for the equitable allocation among the states of gas stamps for distribution to individuals eligible to receive food stamps who can demonstrate a need for gasoline; and (2) provide for the distribution of gas stamps in conjunction with the distribution of food stamps, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture. Sets a $330 million limit for such national distribution in each of the first three months after enactment of this Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax upon the sale in the United States of any crude oil, natural gas, and any fuel which is a product of crude oil or natural gas, equal to the windfall profit on such sale. Defines "windfall profit" as so much of the profit on such sale as exceeds a 15 percent pretax rate of return. Imposes liability for the windfall profits tax upon the seller.</summary>
</bill>
