<bill session="111" type="h" number="5941" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anti-Redlining and Anti-Mortgage Fraud Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce fraud and abusive practices in the origination of residential mortgages by establishing a clearinghouse of mortgage application information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Anti-Redlining and Anti-Mortgage Fraud Act of 2010 - Makes it unlawful for any person or entity to extend credit, provide funds, or collect any payments in connection with an extension of credit secured by a single-family residence unless the originator has recorded the credit application with the clearinghouse established under this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) of the Department of the Treasury, to: (1) establish a mortgage application recordation system which includes a clearinghouse, managed by a private sector entity, to record single-family residence mortgage applications; and (2) require mortgage originators to record such credit applications with the clearinghouse. Prescribes criteria for the clearinghouse operator, which shall bear all clearinghouse costs. Authorizes the Secretary to guarantee repayment of principal and interest on a loan to the clearinghouse operator sufficient to cover clearinghouse costs. Requires the clearinghouse to collect information using an Internet-based electronic system. Makes all information collected by the clearinghouse is property of the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
