<bill session="111" type="h" number="455" updated="2013-07-19T23:16:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in the State of Vermont for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="146"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="22"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/2009--Introduced.
Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2009 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a specified segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in Vermont for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) analyze any potential impacts on the possession or use of a weapon, trap, or net, including a concealed weapon, on the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers or on lands adjacent to that area; (2) include in the study an assessment of any effect a wild and scenic designation in the study area is likely to have on energy production, transmission, or conveyance; and (3) analyze the potential impact of the designation on private lands within the Rivers or adjacent to that area.</summary>
</bill>
