<bill session="110" type="h" number="2589" updated="2013-07-19T21:26:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Pharmaceuticals for Children Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize and amend the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act and the Pediatric Research Equity Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2007--Introduced.
Improving Pharmaceuticals for Children Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise provisions relating to market exclusivity for pediatric drug studies on new or already approved drugs to: (1) require that appropriate labeling changes are timely made; and (2) prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from extending the period of market exclusivity later than one year prior to the expiration of such period. Directs the Secretary to: (1) publish a notice identifying any drug for which a pediatric formulation was developed, studied, and found to be safe and effective in the pediatric population if such formulation is not introduced onto the market within one year; and (2) order the labeling of a drug to include information about the results of a pediatric study. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Heath (NIH), to develop, publish, and revise a priority list of needs in pediatric therapeutics. Revises requirements for the submission of pediatric assessments of the safety and effectiveness of a drug or biological product with a new drug or supplemental application to require an applicant seeking: (1) a deferral of such requirements to submit a timeline for the completion of such studies; and (2) a waiver of such requirements to submit documentation detailing why a pediatric formulation cannot be developed. Considers a supplement to any new drug or biological license application proposing a labeling change as a result of any pediatric assessment to be a priority application or supplement. Requires the Comptroller General to study the effectiveness of federal law in ensuring that medicines used by children are tested and properly labeled.</summary>
</bill>
