<bill session="110" type="h" number="4237" updated="2013-07-19T21:40:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Overseas Voting Practical Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to prohibit States from refusing to accept balloting materials solely because the materials are generated through the use of a computer program, are not printed on a specific type of paper, or do not otherwise meet similar extraneous requirements which are not clearly necessary to prevent fraud in the conduct of elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Postage stamps"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2007--Introduced.
Overseas Voting Practical Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (UOCAVA) to rename the official post card form containing both an absentee voter registration application and an absentee ballot application the Federal Voter Registration and Ballot Application. Prohibits states from refusing to accept balloting materials on any of specified grounds, including that the materials are not printed on a post card, do not include certain information, are not notarized or witnessed by an authorized official, are not delivered by the U.S. Postal Service, or do not meet certain other nonessential requirements. Amends federal postal law with respect to postage markings on certain balloting materials mailed by the states. Amends UOCAVA to: (1) permit voters to request absentee ballots in all subsequent elections; (2) repeal the requirement to provide absentee ballots in subsequent elections to individuals with unknown addresses; (3) apply UOCAVA to individuals who have never resided in the United States (whose parents are overseas voters); (4) require prompt notification of rejection of a voter registration or absentee ballot request; and (5) provide for use of a U.S. State Department diplomatic pouch for returning completed absentee ballots.</summary>
</bill>
