<bill session="113" type="s" number="889" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemembers' Choice in Transition Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3167"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3167" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="631"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2013--Introduced.
Servicemembers' Choice in Transition Act of 2013 - Amends provisions concerning the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense (DOD) (employment and job training assistance and related services for members of the Armed Forces being separated from active duty, and for their spouses) to require such Program to include: (1) information about disability-related employment and education protections, (2) instruction in the use of educational assistance entitlements, (3) testing to determine academic readiness for post-secondary education and appropriate courses, (4) instruction on the financing of post-secondary education, and (5) information on benefits provided under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and in other subjects determined by the Secretary concerned. Requires the VA Secretary to submit to the congressional veterans committees the results of a study to determine the feasibility of providing veterans' benefits instruction at all overseas locations where such instruction is provided through a joint contract with the Secretary of Labor.</summary>
</bill>
