<bill session="110" type="h" number="7038" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Services Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Independent Health Record Trust Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Health Care Services Commission to enhance the quality, appropriateness, and effectiveness of health care services, and access to such services, through the establishment of a broad base of scientific research and through the promotion of improvements in clinical practice and in the organization, financing, and delivery of health care services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2991"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
Health Care Services Commission Act - Establishes a Health Care Services Commission to enhance the quality, appropriateness, and effectiveness of health care services and access to such services. Directs the Commissioners to conduct research, demonstration projects, evaluations, training, guideline development, and the dissemination of information on health care services and on systems for the delivery of such services.Establishes within the Commission the Office of the Forum for Quality and Effectiveness in Health Care to be lead by a Director. Requires the Commissioners, acting through the Director, to establish the Forum for Quality and Effectiveness in Health Care program. Requires the Director to arrange for the development of, and make recommendations for, standards of quality, performance measures, and medical review criteria. Directs the Commissioners to adopt such recommendations.Terminates the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.Independent Health Record Trust Act of 2008 - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to prescribe standards for the establishment, certification, operation, and interoperability of independent health record trusts (IHRTs).Sets forth penalties for any knowing or reckless breach of the fiduciary duty of an IHRT to participants and the IHRT. Sets forth permitted uses for an electronic health record, including for self-care and public health research.Prohibits: (1) any person from requiring that an individual participate in, or authorize access to information from, an IHRT; and (2) an IHRT from charging a fee for the transmittal of information from a health care provider to be included in an independent electronic health record.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an Interagency Steering Committee to coordinate the implementation of this Act. Requires the National Committee for Vital and Health Statistics to serve as an advisory committee for IHRTs.</summary>
</bill>
