<bill session="111" type="h" number="5698" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 and the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to protect employees from retaliation for notifying government officials of violations of those Acts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400635"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 and the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit any person or employer from discharging any employee or discriminating against any employee with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or other employment privileges because the employee (or any person acting for the employee): (1) notified the appropriate federal official, a federal or state law enforcement or regulatory agency, or the employee's employer of an alleged violation of such Acts; (2) refused to participate in any conduct that the employee reasonably believed to be in noncompliance with requirements of such Acts if the employee identified the alleged noncompliance to the employer; (3) testified before or otherwise provided information relevant for Congress or for any federal or state proceeding regarding any provision of such Acts; (4) commenced or testified in a proceeding under such Acts; or (5) assisted or participated in any manner in such a proceeding or or in any other action to carry out such Acts. Authorizes an employee who alleges discrimination by an employer in violation of this Act to seek relief by filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor.</summary>
</bill>
