<bill session="113" type="h" number="2118" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Sports Concussion Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce sports-related concussions in youth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1014"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
Youth Sports Concussion Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress concerning the reduction of sports-related concussions in youth and completion of the National Academies' report on such injuries. Directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to review the National Academies' report within five months after the report is completed. Authorizes the CPSC to make recommendations to protective equipment manufacturers regarding whether voluntary standards should be adopted to: (1) reduce the risk of sports-related injury for youth athletes wearing protective equipment, (2) improve the safety of reconditioned protective equipment, and (3) modify protective equipment warning labels. Permits the CPSC to initiate the promulgation of a consumer product safety rule if no voluntary standard is adopted within a one-year period. Makes it unlawful to sell or offer for sale in interstate commerce, or import into the United States for such purposes, athletic sporting equipment for which the seller or importer makes any false or misleading claim with respect to the safety benefits of such item. Requires violations to be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Sets forth the enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Authorizes the FTC to promulgate regulations to carry out this Act. Authorizes states to bring civil actions in federal court to obtain injunctive relief on behalf of state residents unless a civil or administrative action has already been instituted by the FTC. Allows the FTC to intervene and appeal in state actions.</summary>
</bill>
