<bill session="112" type="s" number="257" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Broadband and Emerging Information Technology Enhancement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve certain programs of the Small Business Administration to better assist small business customers in accessing broadband technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S483-484"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S484-485" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2011--Introduced.
Small Business Broadband and Emerging Information Technology Enhancement Act of 2011 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to assign an SBA employee to coordinate SBA programs and activities relating to broadband and emerging information technology (BEIT). Requires the Administrator to provide SBA employees BEIT training in order to assist small businesses in the use of such technologies. Requires reports from the coordinator to the congressional small business committees on coordinator activities and on federal programs that provide BEIT assistance to small businesses. Includes accessing and using BEIT as an authorized activity of small business development centers. Authorizes the use of capital provided under certain SBA loans for the purchase of equipment for BEIT. Directs the Administrator to report on ways to assist with the development of broadband and wireless technology that would benefit small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
