<bill session="111" type="s" number="561" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Land Assistance, Management and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FLAME Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize a supplemental funding source for catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities on Department of the Interior and National Forest System lands, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a cohesive wildland fire management strategy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1404"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2009--Introduced.
Federal Land Assistance, Management and Enhancement Act or FLAME Act - Establishes in the Treasury the Federal Land Assistance, Management, and Enhancement Fund (Flame Fund). Requires amounts in the Flame Fund to be made available to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretaries) to pay the costs of catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities that are separate from amounts annually appropriated for the predicted annual workload for such activities. Makes amounts in the Flame Fund available to the Secretaries only after such Secretaries issue a declaration that a wildland fire suppression activity is eligible for funding through the Fund. Directs such Secretaries to establish an accounting and reporting system for the Flame Fund.Requires such Secretaries to: (1) report annually to Congress on the use of the funds from the Flame Fund, together with recommendations to improve administrative control and oversight of the Fund; and (2) submit a report to Congress that contains a cohesive wildland fire management strategy, consistent with the recommendations of Comptroller General reports. Requires the Secretaries to conduct a review of wildfires for which expenses exceeding $10 million were incurred. Authorizes the Secretaries to make grants to fire-ready communities, as defined by this Act, to carry out activities to reduce risks from wildfires.</summary>
</bill>
