<bill session="111" type="h" number="4409" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community-Based Residency Training Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a program for the training of medical residents in community-based settings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2009-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2009--Introduced.
Community-Based Residency Training Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a program for the training of medical residents in community-based settings. Requires the Secretary to make grants to, or enter into contracts with, eligible entities (i.e., entities designated as eligible to receive payment for the direct costs of medical education under provisions of the Social Security Act pertaining to payment to nonhospital providers) to: (1) plan and develop a new primary care residency training program; and (2) operate or participate in an established primary care residency training program. Directs the Secretary to give preference to entities that: (1) support teaching programs that address the health care needs of vulnerable populations; (2) are a federally qualified health center or a rural health clinic; or (3) have a demonstrated record of training a high or significantly improved percentage of health professionals who provide primary care, individuals who are from disadvantaged backgrounds, or individuals who practice in settings having the principal focus of serving underserved areas or populations experiencing health disparities.</summary>
</bill>
