<bill session="111" type="h" number="3015" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Detainee Photographic Records Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">OPEN FOIA Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that certain photographic records relating to the treatment of any individual engaged, captured, or detained after September 11, 2001, by the Armed Forces of the United States in operations outside the United States shall not be subject to disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act), to amend section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act) to provide that statutory exemptions to the disclosure requirements of that Act shall specifically cite to the provision of that Act authorizing such exemptions, to ensure an open and deliberative process in Congress by providing for related legislative proposals to explicitly state such required citations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400655"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2712"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2875"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1100"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1285"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2009--Introduced.
Detainee Photographic Records Protection Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Defense to: (1) certify any photograph taken between September 11, 2001, and January 22, 2009, that relates to the treatment of individuals engaged, captured, or detained after September 11, 2001, by the U.S. Armed Forces in operations outside of the United States if the Secretary determines that disclosure of such photograph would endanger U.S. citizens or members of the Armed Forces or U.S. government employees deployed outside the United States; and (2) submit timely notice of such certification to Congress. Authorizes the Secretary to submit a renewal of a certification at any time. Provides that a certification or a renewal shall expire after three years. Exempts such a certified photograph from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), but does not preclude voluntary disclosure. OPEN FOIA Act of 2009 - Amends FOIA to require statutory exemptions to its disclosure requirements to specifically cite its provision that authorizes such exemptions.</summary>
</bill>
