<bill session="112" type="s" number="2016" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fresh Regional Eating for Schools and Health Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to increase access to healthy food for families, to amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act and the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to increase access to credit for small and new farmers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8736-8737"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2011--Introduced.
Fresh Regional Eating for Schools and Health Act of 2011 - Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (formerly known as the Food Stamp Act of 1977) regarding the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly food stamp program) to: (1) authorize pilot programs that will assist SNAP beneficiaries in meeting federal nutrition guidelines and promote innovative local projects, (2) implement smartphone and tablet technology for acceptance of electronic benefit transfers, (3) require retail stores with gross annual SNAP sales in excess of $1 million to report food purchased by program recipients to the Department of Agriculture (USDA), and (4) include qualifying online food retailers within SNAP. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 regarding the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children program (WIC) to: (1) implement smartphone and tablet technology for acceptance of electronic benefit transfers; and (2) permit retail stores to receive alternative program training, including through videoconferencing. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to permit schools to use 50% of USDA funds for agricultural commodities to purchase locally grown food for food service programs under such Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act regarding direct agricultural real estate loans to: (1) extend eligibility to a new farmer who has obtained a baccalaureate degree related to farm management (including horticulture and agricultural business management), and (2) suspend loan time limits. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to extend operating loan eligibility to food banks and other nonprofit hunger assistance organizations.</summary>
</bill>
