<bill session="112" type="h" number="319" updated="2013-07-20T01:13:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Day Off Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require employers to provide veterans with time off on Veterans Day.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/2011--Introduced.
Veterans Day Off Act - Entitles veterans who have been employed by an employer for at least 12 months, except those employed by a public agency, to leave from such employer on Veterans Day upon request if such veteran would otherwise be required to work on Veterans Day. Authorizes employers who employ 50 or more employees to deny leave if providing leave to veterans would negatively impact public health or safety or cause the employer significant economic or operational disruption. Authorizes leave granted to consist of unpaid leave. Authorizes an employee to elect, or an employer to require the employee, to substitute accrued paid vacation leave or personal leave for leave provided under this Act. Prohibits: (1) such employers from interfering with, restraining, or denying the taking of any leave provided under this Act; (2) such employers from discharging or discriminating against individuals for opposing practices made unlawful by this Act; and (3) any person from discharging or discriminating against individuals for filing any charge or instituting any proceeding under this Act, giving any information in connection with inquiries or proceedings relating to such leave, or testifying in inquiries or proceedings related to such leave. Gives the Secretary of Labor investigative authority with respect to the provisions of this Act in the same manner and under the same terms and conditions as the investigative authority provided under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993. Requires such employers to post in conspicuous places on their premises a notice with information pertaining to the filing of a charge under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
