<bill session="109" type="h" number="3596" updated="2013-07-19T19:36:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Participation in Railroad Operations Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the quality of life and safety of persons living and working near railroad tracks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400346"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad mergers"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Local Participation in Railroad Operations Act - Amends federal transportation law to prohibit rail carriers from constructing, developing, or expanding railroad maintenance facilities, intermodal rail transfer facilities, railroad sidings, railroad bridges, railroad yards, or other railroad facilities unless the Surface Transportation Board determines that the carrier has: (1) provided affected local communities with notice and an opportunity to be heard with respect to such activities; and (2) conducted an assessment of negative environmental impacts and appropriate mitigation actions pursuant to state or local law. Prohibits a rail carrier from constructing an at-grade crossing over a public road without first obtaining approval from the local governmental entity with jurisdiction over the location of the proposed grade crossing. Prohibits the Board from approving the consolidation, merger, and acquisition of control of a rail carrier by one or more rail carriers unless it has received assurances that the rail carriers have addressed adequately and will continue to address adequately problems identified with respect to the quality of life and safety of persons who live, work, or are for any other reason near railroad tracks. Repeals a section of the Noise Control Act of 1972 regarding railroad noise emission standards upon the issuance of the final regulations under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
