<bill session="113" type="h" number="1103" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Alaska, is and shall be recognized as an eligible Native village under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) to recognize Alexander Creek, Alaska, as a Native village eligible for land and benefits under the Act. Requires Alexander Creek to file any amendments to its corporate charter in Alaska that are necessary to convert from a Native group to a Native Village Corporation. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to negotiate an agreement with Alexander Creek to settle aboriginal land claims and any other claims of such Native Village Corporation against the United States fairly and equitably. Requires Alexander Creek to notify each member of the Native village that: (1) all of them will cease to receive benefits from Cook Inlet Region Incorporated (CIRI) individually as at-large shareholders, and (2) all future resource payments from the Region will be made to the Village Corporation. Relieves CIRI from liability under any state, federal, or local law for damages related to that payment cessation.</summary>
</bill>
