<bill session="111" type="s" number="1150" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advance Planning and Compassionate Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve end-of-life care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5862-5863"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5863-5872" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2911"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Advance Planning and Compassionate Care Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to establish and operate directly, or by grant, contract, or interagency agreement, a 24-hour toll free telephone hotline to provide consumer information regarding advance care planning. Directs the Secretary to develop an online clearinghouse to provide comprehensive information regarding: (1) advance care planning; and (2) pediatric advance care planning. Directs the Secretary to develop an online advance care planning toolkit for availability on specified websites. Directs the Secretary, acting through the CDC Director, directly or through grants, contracts, or interagency agreements, to develop a national campaign to inform the public of the importance of advance care planning and of an individual's right to direct and participate in his or her health care decisions. Directs the Secretary to update the online version of the "Planning Ahead" section of the Medicare &amp; You Handbook to include information about advanced care planning and advance directives. Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to update the online version of the Social Security Handbook for beneficiaries to include such information, as well as all paper and online versions subsequently published. Amends the Legal Services Corporation Act to authorize financial and legal assistance for advanced care planning. Directs the Secretary to award grants to states for certain state health insurance assistance programs to provide advance care planning services to Medicare beneficiaries, their personal representatives, and their families. Authorizes Medicaid transformation grants for advance care planning and advanced care planning community training grants. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to establish new or expand existing programs for orders regarding life sustaining treatment in states or localities. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to establish a website for providers under the Medicare, Medicaid, and the Children's Health Insurance Program, the Indian Health Service, and other public health providers on each individual's right to make decisions concerning medical care, including the right to accept or refuse medical or surgical treatment, and the existence of advance directives. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of Health Resources and Services Administration, to develop a curriculum for continuing education that states may adopt for physicians and nurses on advanced care planning and end-of-life care. Amends titles XVIII (Medicare), XIX (Medicaid), and XXI (Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) of the Social Security Act with respect to the portability of advance directives. Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary, acting through the CDC Director, to award competitive grants to eligible entities to establish and operate state advance directive registries. Requires various specified studies and reports to Congress by the Comptroller General and by the Secretary. Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary to establish within the National Health Service Corps a National Geriatric and Palliative Care Services Corps. Exempts palliative medicine fellowship training from Medicare graduate medical education caps. Directs the Secretary to establish guidelines for the imposition by medical schools of a minimum amount of end-of-life training as a requirement for obtaining a Doctor of Medicine degree in the field of allopathic or osteopathic medicine. Authorizes coverage of advance care planning under Medicare, Medicaid, and CHIP. Revises Medicare requirements for hospice payments and related matters. Makes hospice care a required Medicaid and CHIP benefit. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to designate an entity to develop requirements, standards, and procedures for accreditation of hospital-based palliative care programs. Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish, within the National Institutes of Health, a National Center on Palliative and End-of-Life Care. Directs the Secretary to establish a demonstration program for the use of telemedicine services in advance care planning.</summary>
</bill>
