<bill session="109" type="s" number="345" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Prescription Drug Savings and Choice Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to deliver a meaningful benefit and lower prescription drug prices under the medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2006-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1272-1273"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1273" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10525-10526"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="752"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="873"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2005--Introduced.
Medicare Prescription Drug Savings and Choice Act of 2005 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) offer one or more Medicare operated prescription drug plans nationally that offer qualified prescription drug coverage and access to negotiated prices, while allowing the plan to offer supplemental prescription drug coverage in the same manner as other qualified prescription drug coverage offered by other prescription drug plans; and (2) enter into negotiations with pharmaceutical manufacturers to reduce the purchase cost of covered Medicare part D drugs for eligible part D individuals, and encourage the use of more affordable therapeutic equivalents. Requires the monthly beneficiary premium charged under such a plan to be uniform nationally. Makes the premium for months in 2006 $35. Bases the premium for months in succeeding years on the average monthly per capita actuarial cost of offering the Medicare operated prescription drug plan for the year involved, including administrative expenses. Allows for adjustment of such premium amount in case of supplemental prescription drug coverage.</summary>
</bill>
