<bill session="111" type="h" number="4613" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Blackfoot River Land Settlement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To settle land claims within the Fort Hall Reservation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2802"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2010--Introduced.
Blackfoot River Land Settlement Act of 2010- Extinguishes all claims and all right, title, and interest in and to specified Indian and non-Indian land with respect to resolution of the disputes within the Fort Hall Indian Reservation of the Shoshone and Bannock Indian Tribes located in Idaho, resulting from the realignment of the Blackfoot River by the Corps of Engineers in 1964. Requires the non-Indian land to be held in trust for the Tribes. Transfers the Indian land to Blackfoot River Flood Control District No. 7 for conveyance to the non-Indians acquiring Indian land. Establishes a tribal trust fund account from which amounts shall be distributed to the Tribes, which they may use for activities related to: (1) construction of a natural resources facility; (2) water resources needs; (3) economic development; and (4) land acquisition. Establishes an allottee trust account into which amounts shall be deposited into individual Indian money accounts for the allottees. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to pay to the Tribes and the non-Indian landowners such attorneys fees as are approved by them. Limits the total amount of such fees to be paid to 2% of the amounts distributed to the Tribes, allottees, and the non-Indian landowners.</summary>
</bill>
