<bill session="112" type="h" number="1147" updated="2013-07-20T01:20:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Recovery and Enhancement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CRE Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction for certain payments made to reduce debt on commercial real property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2011-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2011--Introduced.
Community Recovery and Enhancement Act of 2011 or the CRE Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax deduction for payments made to reduce debt on eligible commercial property. Limits the amount of such deduction to the lesser of: (1) 50% of the excess of the amount of qualified debt secured by such property, (2) 50% of the fair market value of such property, (3) $10 million, or (4) the adjusted basis of such property at the close of the taxable year. Defines "eligible commercial property" as any commercial real property if: (1) the amount of the qualified indebtedness secured by such property is at least 85% of the fair market value of the property, or (2) such property is, or is reasonably expected to be, treated as being in an in-substance foreclosure by the Comptroller of the Currency. Denies a tax deduction for debt reduction payments that are debt-financed. Requires a recapture in income of tax deduction amounts allowed by this Act if additional indebtedness is incurred within three years after a qualified debt reduction payment is made.</summary>
</bill>
