<bill session="110" type="h" number="3031" updated="2013-07-19T21:30:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advanced Design in Energy for Living Efficiently Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the construction of green buildings in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Education and Labor, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buildings"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Green products"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Professional education"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2007--Introduced.
Advanced Design in Energy for Living Efficiently Act of 2007 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) coordinate and provide information on green building design and practices; (2) establish a program to create and distribute information on green building design principles; and (3) establish criteria for education and training of architects, engineers, and developers in green building design and application.Requires the National Institute of Building Sciences (NIBS) to establish a blue ribbon panel to: (1) provide independent counsel to the Administrator on policy issues associated with green building design and practices; (2) report on the results of a study to determine best practices for quantifying the information necessary to make informed property investment decisions; (3) report on funding necessary for research and development on green building design; and (4) establish standards for the construction of new buildings that will reduce carbon emissions.Requires the U.S. Comptroller General to study the use of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development's program for energy efficient mortgages insured under the National Housing Act.Authorizes the Administrator, acting through NIBS, to award grants to state educational agencies to provide sub-grants to local educational agencies for planing and preparing for healthy, high-performance school building projects.Requires the Administrator: (1) acting through NIBS, to assist local education agencies on sustainable designs; and (2) to establish a program to make loan guarantees available to public institutions of higher education for the construction or renovation of permanent buildings that meet the greenhouse gas emission standards.Requires federal agencies to: (1) increase the energy efficiency of their facilities and operations; (2) annually report on the associated energy efficiency increases and carbon emission reductions; and (3) reward employees who make significant contributions to the reduction of agency carbon emissions.Requires federal agencies' energy managers to receive training on green building design, construction, use, and decommissioning.Requires the Comptroller General to transmit to Congress a report comparing the energy efficiency budget request by the President for each federal agency for FY2006-2007 with each agency's request.Requires the Administrator to make block grants to state and local governments for: (1) renovating existing buildings to achieve NIBS standards; (2) redesigning existing plans to enable new buildings to meet such standards; (3) researching and developing technologies to enable and support green building design and the achievement of such standards; and (4) educating and training on green buildings and their construction, use, and decommissioning.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase and extend the energy efficient commercial building deduction.</summary>
</bill>
