<bill session="109" type="h" number="2039" updated="2013-07-19T19:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Land Recreational Visitor Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to undertake a program to reduce the risks from and mitigate the effects of avalanches on recreational users of public land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2006-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2006-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="225"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="225"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Artillery"/>
    <term name="Avalanches"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military weapons"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Ordnance"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skiing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Federal Land Recreational Visitor Protection Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish an avalanche protection program to: (1) provide early identification of the potential for avalanches that could endanger the safety of recreational users of public land and visitors to units of the National Park System (NPS); and (2) reduce the risks and mitigate the effects of avalanches on visitors, recreational users, neighboring communities, and transportation corridors. Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) use the resources of the National Avalanche Center of the Forest Service to carry out this Act; and (2) establish an advisory committee to assist in the development and implementation of the program. Directs such Secretaries and the Secretary of the Army to establish a central depository for weapons, ammunition, and parts for avalanche control purposes, including an inventory that can be made available to Federal and non-Federal entities. Authorizes the Secretaries of Interior and Agriculture to make grants to carry out projects and activities under the program to: (1) assist in the prevention, forecasting, detection, and mitigation of avalanches; (2) maintain essential transportation and communications; (3) assist avalanche artillery users to ensure the availability of adequate supplies of artillery and other explosives required for avalanche control in or affecting NPS units, other Federal land used for recreation, and adjacent communities, and essential transportation corridors; and (4) assist research and development activities for alternatives to minimize reliance on military weapons for avalanche control.</summary>
</bill>
