<bill session="111" type="s" number="3731" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Next Generation Public Safety Device Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to conduct a competition to award grants for the development of nonstationary radio over Internet protocol devices that support mission-critical broadband voice and data communications of public safety personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5907"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Next Generation Public Safety Device Act of 2010 - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to conduct a competition to award grants to eligible entities for the development of nonstationary radio over Internet protocol (RoIP) devices that support mission-critical broadband voice and data communications of public safety personnel. Establishes a working group to provide the Assistant Secretary with advice and technical assistance in conducting the competition. Requires the Assistant Secretary to establish: (1) requirements for the RoIP devices developed, in whole or in part, using a grant awarded under this Act; and (2) a three-stage process under which to award such grants to eligible entities. Allows the award of a grant in a stage only to an eligible entity that: (1) submits a bid meeting the specifications developed for that stage; and (2) provides an assurance that the grant funds will be used to develop an RoIP device in accordance with the specifications included in that bid. Sets forth additional factors for the Assistant Secretary to consider when making a grant. Requires the Comptroller General to conduct an audit of such competition. Directs the FCC to establish a voluntary labeling program for the identification of nonstationary RoIP devices that meet such criteria as considered appropriate to support mission-critical broadband voice and data communications of public safety personnel.</summary>
</bill>
