<bill session="112" type="s" number="556" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the securities laws to establish certain thresholds for shareholder registration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1965"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4088"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1941"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934&#160;regarding registration of securities to modify the registration threshold for an issuer that is either a bank or a bank holding company as well as for an issuer that is neither a bank nor a bank holding company. Raises from $1 million to $10 million the threshold for total assets of an issuer that requires registration of a certain class of equity security. Divides the holding threshold that requires registration of such a class of equity security, however, into: (1) 2,000 holders of record if the issuer is a bank or a bank holding company, and (2) 500 holders of record if the issuer is neither. Requires termination of a security registration in the case of a bank or a bank holding company if the the number of holders of record of the class of security is reduced to less than 1,200. Directs the Chief Economist and the&#160;Director of the Division of Corporation Finance of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to study and make a cost-benefit analysis of shareholder registration thresholds.</summary>
</bill>
