<bill session="113" type="h" number="2230" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Track It to Prevent It Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To address the prevalence of sexual harassment and sexual assault in the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400356"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2013--Introduced.
Track It to Prevent It Act - Directs: (1) the Secretary of Defense to ensure that the results of command climate assessments are provided to the relevant individual commander and to the next higher level of command, (2) the Secretary of each military department to include in performance evaluations and assessments used by each Armed Force a designated form where senior commanders can indicate whether the commander has conducted the required climate assessments and to require that any failure to do so be noted in the commander's performance evaluation and considered a serious factor for any subsequent promotion, and (3) the Inspector General of the Department of Defense (DOD) to develop a system to track whether commanders are conducting such climate assessments. Requires unit commanders, working with the Inspector General, to gather all climate assessments from the unit and develop a compliance report that includes: (1) a comprehensive overview of the concerns members of the unit expressed, (2) data showing how leadership is perceived in the unit, and (3) a detailed strategic plan on how leadership plans to address the expressed concerns. Directs the Defense Secretary to require commanders to include letters of reprimand, non-punitive letters of actions, and counseling statements involving substantiated cases of sexual harassment or sexual assault in the performance evaluation report of a member of the Armed Forces for the purpose of: (1) providing commanders increased visibility of the background information of unit members, (2) identifying and preventing trends of bad behavior early and effectively disciplining repeated actions which hinder units from fostering a healthy climate, and (3) preventing the transfer of sexual offenders. Requires the Secretary of each military department to: (1) develop an assessment program modeled after the current Department of the Army Multi-Source Assessment and Feedback Program, (2) include individual counseling as part of the performance evaluation process, and (3) conduct health welfare inspections on a monthly basis and provide the results to both the commander and senior commander. Directs the Defense Secretary to: (1) conduct a review of security measures and identify security gaps on military installations; (2) evaluate the feasibility and effectiveness of using 24-hour electronic monitoring or placing security personnel at all points of entry into barracks and multi-family residences; and (3) conduct a review of the Office of Diversity Management and Equal Opportunity to identify and evaluate the resource and personnel gaps in the Office, identify and evaluate the Office's role in sexual harassment cases, and evaluate how the Office works with the Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Office to address sexual harassment in the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
