<bill session="109" type="sr" number="400" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-13">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the constitutional reform process in Bosnia and Herzegovina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2006-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-03-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2049" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2049" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2042-2043" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) it is time for Bosnia and Herzegovina to work toward creation of a state with more self-sustaining institutions; (2) any agreement on constitutional reform should advance the principles of democracy and tolerance, and bring the country closer to European Union (EU) membership; (3) the United States supports the development of Bosnia and Herzegovina as a unified, democratic state on the path toward Euro-Atlantic integration; (4) all parties to negotiations on the reforms of the Constitution of Bosnia and Herzegovina should work together so that a first set of revisions to the Constitution can take effect before national elections in October 2006; (5) all groups responsible for past violence and atrocities in Bosnia and Herzegovina must accept responsibility for their actions and promote reconciliation; and (6) all levels of government in Bosnia and Herzegovina must comply with the directives of the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia (ICTY), arrest persons indicted for war crimes, and turn over fugitives to face justice at the International Criminal Tribunal.</summary>
</bill>
