<bill session="113" type="h" number="2544" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CEASE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conditioning Economic Assistance and Support to Egypt Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit United States economic assistance and to oppose World Bank and International Monetary Fund assistance to the Government of Egypt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412399"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Conditioning Economic Assistance and Support to Egypt Act or CEASE Act - Prohibits specified U.S. economic assistance and opposes World Bank and International Monetary Fund (IMF) assistance to the government of Egypt unless the President certifies to Congress that the government of Egypt: (1) has implemented legal reforms to protect political, economic, and religious freedoms and human rights; (2) is demonstrating a commitment to free and fair elections; (3) is implementing all measures in the 1979 Egypt-Israel Peace Treaty; (4) is taking action to eliminate smuggling networks, destroy tunnels between Egypt and the Gaza Strip, and combat terrorism in the Sinai; (5) in consultation with the Department of Defense (DOD), has produced an analysis of Egypt's current security needs; and (6) has lifted restrictions in law and practice on the work and funding of Egyptian and international nongovernmental human rights and democracy organizations.</summary>
</bill>
