<bill session="112" type="s" number="1517" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century WPA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the creation of jobs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="417"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3105"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2011--Introduced.
21st Century WPA Act - Establishes within the Department of Labor a Works Progress Administration (WPA). Requires eligible federal departments to submit to the WPA proposals for works projects that produce a high number of employee hours per dollar of the total project cost, and meet certain other criteria. Permits such projects to include: (1) residential and commercial building weatherization projects; (2) residential and commercial water use efficiency improvement projects; (3) highway, bridge, and rail repair and maintenance projects; (4) manufacturing projects; (5) school, library, and firehouse construction projects; (6) soil erosion and pesticide runoff prevention projects; and (7) trail maintenance projects. Makes an employer who is unable to hire an individual to fill a job position that has been vacant for 90 days eligible to enter into an agreement with the WPA to provide training to a WPA fellow in order to become qualified to fill such position. Prescribes WPA fellowship program requirements. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to transfer amounts appropriated under this Act to the Attorney General and to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for grants for the hiring of eligible public safety individuals. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a 5.4% surcharge on individual taxpayers whose modified adjusted gross income exceeds $1 million ($2 million for joint returns). Dedicates amounts collected from such surcharge to federal deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
