<bill session="111" type="h" number="2779" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defined Contribution Plan Fee Transparency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide transparency with respect to fees and expenses charged to participant-directed defined contribution plans, and to improve participant communication.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1355-1356"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4146"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2009--Introduced.
Defined Contribution Plan Fee Transparency Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a penalty tax on employers maintaining defined contribution pension plans for the failure of their plan administrators to provide plan participants or beneficiaries, prior to enrollment in a plan, with certain notices and disclosures pertaining to fees and charges, investment alternatives, and the manner for making elections among designated investment alternatives. Sets forth the types of information about investment alternatives required in a plan notice or disclosure. Requires plan administrators to provide plan participants and beneficiaries, after enrollment, with quarterly notices describing the investment alternatives and associated fees and charges in their plans. Imposes a penalty tax on a provider of services to a defined contribution plan for failure to provide a plan administrator with certain disclosures, including the total fees and expenses expected to be paid by a plan and any relationships of such service provider with third parties offering investment products. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to issue final regulations on the written formats allowed for providing the notices and disclosures required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
