<bill session="110" type="h" number="7006" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24T19:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-24T19:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide disaster assistance relief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412260" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412197" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rangel moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9312-9319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9365" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-24T19:07:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="635" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 419 - 4 (Roll no. 635).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9312-9314" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-08">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1129">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1129.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Expense accounts"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide tax relief in federally declared disaster areas.(Sec. 2) Waives the 10% adjusted gross income limitation on personal casualty losses for losses sustained from a federally declared disaster occurring after December 31, 2007, and before January 1, 2012. Defines "federally declared disaster" as any disaster determined by the President to warrant federal assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. Increases the standard tax deduction by a taxpayer's net disaster loss (i.e., personal casualty losses in a disaster area over personal casualty gains). Increases the threshold for deductible casualty losses from $100 to $500 for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2008, and before January 1, 2012. (Sec. 3) Allows the expensing of business-related costs incurred due to a federally declared disaster for: (1) the abatement or control of hazardous substances; (2) removal of debris or demolition of damaged structures; or (3) repair of damaged property.(Sec. 4) Provides for a five-year carryback period for net operating losses attributable to a federally declared disaster. Allows such losses as a deduction in computing alternative minimum taxable income.(Sec. 5) Waives certain restrictions on mortgage revenue bond financing for principal residences destroyed due to a federally declared disaster occurring between January 1, 2008, and December 31, 2011.(Sec. 6) Increases, until December 31, 2011, the standard mileage rate used to compute the tax deduction for the use of a passenger automobile for charitable purposes to the same rate used for deducting travel expenses related to medical care (currently, 27 cents per mile). (Sec. 7) Authorizes additional allocations to states (up to $190 million) of the low-income housing tax credit for federally declared disasters occurring between January 1, 2008, and December 31, 2011. Prohibits allocations after December 31, 2012.(Sec. 8) Expands tax-exempt private activity bonds to include qualified disaster bonds used to finance the replacement, repair, reconstruction or renovation of depreciable property damaged or destroyed as a result of a federally declared disaster occurring between January 1, 2008, and December 31, 2011. Grants priority in allocating bond amounts to business loss disaster areas (i.e., areas sustaining damages from a disaster of at least the lesser of $50 million or 5% of all business property in the disaster area). Requires all allocations to be made prior to December 31, 2012.(Sec. 9) Waives limitations on individual and corporate charitable contributions for qualified disaster contributions. Defines "qualified disaster contribution" as any charitable contribution paid prior to January 1, 2010, to a public charity for relief efforts related to a federally declared disaster.</summary>
</bill>
