<bill session="112" type="h" number="1023" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No More Excuses Energy Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">American-Made Energy and Good Jobs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To secure unrestricted reliable energy for American consumption and transmission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2011-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2011-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="49"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="909"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1292"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1682"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3407"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2011--Introduced.
No More Excuses Energy Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow the issuance of tax-exempt facility bonds for the financing of domestic use oil refinery facilities, (2) extend the tax credit for a facility using wind to produce electricity, (3) set the rate of the excise tax on liquefied natural gas to 24.3 cents per energy equivalent of a gallon of diesel, (4) extend through 2012 the excise tax credit for alternative fuel, (5) allow tax credits for the production of electricity from nuclear energy and the production of fuel from certain onshore wells, and (6) repeal the minimum gas capture requirement for purposes of the carbon dioxide sequestration tax credit. Requires the President to designate at least 10 sites for oil or natural gas refineries on federal lands and make such sites available to the private sector for construction of refineries. Prohibits the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from denying an application for nuclear waste disposal on the grounds of present or future insufficient capacity. American-Made Energy and Good Jobs Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program in the Coastal Plain of Alaska. Repeals the prohibition against producing oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge. Sets forth requirements for the sale of oil and natural gas leases in the Coastal Plain, environmental protection, transportation easements, and royalty payments to Alaska. Establishes in the Treasury the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund to assist Alaska jurisdictions that are directly impacted by oil and gas exploration and production in the Coastal Plain. Amends the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 to repeal the moratorium on oil and gas leasing in certain areas in the Gulf of Mexico. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to include the areas removed from such moratorium within the areas available for leasing under the 2007-2012 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing program. Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) exclude from the meaning of "air pollutant" carbon dioxide, water vapor, methane, nitrous oxide, hydrofluorocarbons, perfluorocarbons, or sulfur hexafluoride; and (2) declare that nothing in such such Act shall be treated as authorizing or requiring the regulation of climate change or global warming.</summary>
</bill>
