<bill session="109" type="hr" number="688" updated="2013-07-19T19:00:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require that legislation and conference reports be available on the Internet for 72 hours before consideration by the House, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400631" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2006-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2006-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Amends rule XIII (Calendars and Committee Reports) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to make it out of order, with certain exceptions, for the House to consider a measure or matter until 72 hours after its text (and any accompanying reports) have been made available to Members and the general public (excluding Saturdays, Sunday and holidays when the House is not in session). Requires such text to be posted continuously, during the 72 hours, on the Internet in an accessible, searchable format. Prohibits the House from considering a general appropriations bill, with certain exceptions, until at least 72 hours (currently, three calendar days) after the printed hearings of the Committee on Appropriations related to it have been available to Members. Requires privileged reports to be made available to the general public before their consideration in the House. Amends rule XXII (House and Senate Relations) to require, before House consideration, the same 72 hour availability to Members and the general public, including Internet accessibility, of the text of conference reports, accompanying joint explanatory statements, and Senate amendments reported by a conference committee in disagreement. Declares that nothing in this resolution shall be interpreted to require or permit the declassification or posting on the Internet of classified information. Requires such classified information to be made available to Members in a timely manner. Expresses the sense of the House that the House Committee on Rules should develop standardized policies and procedures to require that proposed amendments major in size, scope, or cost (except those offered under an open rule) be posted on the Internet for an appropriate number of hours.</summary>
</bill>
