<bill session="111" type="h" number="2823" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to enhance and improve certain procedures relating to voting by absent members of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to: (1) require states to accept and process, with respect to any election for federal office, any otherwise valid voter registration application, absentee ballot application, and absentee ballot submitted by an absent uniformed services voter without any requirement for notarization of the document; and (2) permit the submittal of the official post card form (for simultaneous voter registration application and absentee ballot application) by electronic means. Expresses the sense of Congress concerning encouragement by states and the Department of Defense (DOD) of the use of electronic means to submit absentee ballots.</summary>
</bill>
