<bill session="110" type="h" number="4033" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Golf Course Preservation and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a long-term ground lease for the operation and maintenance of Rock Creek, Langston, and East Potomac as golf courses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2294-2295"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5773"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in public facilities"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Golf"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Segregation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2007--Introduced.
Golf Course Preservation and Modernization Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service (NPS), to ensure that month-to-month concessions contracts are continued for the operation and maintenance of the Rock Creek, Langston, and East Potomac golf courses until the lease in force for East Potomac expires, at which time the lease entered into pursuant to this Act for the continued operation and maintenance of Rock Creek, Langston, and East Potomac as golf courses commences. Requires that such lease include the three golf courses in one lease agreement, and that they be operated and maintained in a manner that: (1) retains their historic nature; (2) at least two of the courses require fees related to use of the courses to be affordable; (3) may allow fees collected at one course to subsidize the maintenance and operation of at least one of the other courses; and (4) allows for a long-term ground lease on all three courses. Instructs the Secretary to solicit proposals, through a competitive process, to procure such lease. Authorizes the Secretary, after such solicitation, to enter into agreements to procure the lease. Specifies that the request for proposals be solicited in such a manner: (1) to provide that the lease be entered into not later than 180 days after this Act's effective date or not later than 30 days after expiration of the concession contract for East Potomac; and (2) which ensures the participation of disadvantaged business enterprises among the equity partners of the sponsors of the proposals.</summary>
</bill>
