<bill session="112" type="h" number="2290" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Caregiver Credit Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to credit prospectively individuals serving as caregivers of dependent relatives with deemed wages for up to five years of such service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
Social Security Caregiver Credit Act of 2011 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act with respect to determining entitlement to and the amount of any monthly benefit, including any lump-sum death payment, payable under OASDI on the basis of the wages and self-employment income of any individual. Deems such an individual to have been paid a wage (according to a specified formula) during each month during which the individual was engaged for at least 80 hours in providing care to a dependent relative without monetary compensation for up to five years of such service. Makes this Act inapplicable in the case of any monthly benefit or lump-sum death payment if a larger benefit or payment would be payable without its application.</summary>
</bill>
