<bill session="111" type="s" number="2836" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Asset Management Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the Operating Fund for public housing of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12414-12415"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1048"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2009--Introduced.
Asset Management Improvement Act of 2009 - Prohibits the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) from imposing restrictions or limitations on the amount of management and related fees for a public housing project which the public housing agency (PHA) determines reasonable, unless such restriction or limitation: (1) is determined pursuant to a negotiated rulemaking convened by the Secretary no earlier than April 1, 2010, with representatives from interested parties; and (2) is effective only on or after January 1, 2012. Allows any PHA that owns or operates fewer than 500 public housing units under the United States Housing Act of 1937 to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by the Secretary. Prohibits the Secretary from imposing any requirement relating to asset management restricting the use by PHAs of amounts for Capital Fund assistance for costs of any PHA central office. Requires the Secretary to ensure that PHAs encourage the reasonable efforts of residents to organize.</summary>
</bill>
