<bill session="111" type="h" number="1962" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Space Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Space Shuttle to be flown from 2010 through 2015, and to authorize appropriations for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for this purpose.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
American Space Access Act - Requires the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to annually fly at least two Space Shuttle missions for crew transport into space, instead of purchasing Russian crew and cargo services, for the period beginning in 2010 and ending: (1) in 2015; (2) when the Orion crew exploration vehicle is operational; or (3) when NASA has certified the safe operation of an available U.S. commercial capability, whichever occurs first. Directs NASA, not later than March 31, 2011, to investigate areas of reduced operations and enhanced cost savings and implement those that do not impinge on the safe operation of the Space Shuttle program. Requires NASA to report to Congress on: (1) the costs and actions needed to extend the operation of the Space Shuttle in accordance with this Act; and (2) the amount of funding needed to expedite the schedule of the Orion crew exploration vehicle and the Ares I crew exploration vehicle and associated ground support systems under the Constellation program.</summary>
</bill>
