<bill session="110" type="s" number="3383" updated="2013-07-19T22:51:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Harriet Tubman National Historical Park and Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Harriet Tubman National Historical Park in Auburn, New York, and the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park in Caroline, Dorchester, and Talbot Counties, Maryland, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7926-7927"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7927-7929" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6693"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Harriet Tubman National Historical Park and Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park Act - Establishes in the City of Auburn, New York, the Harriet Tubman National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park System. Establishes in Caroline, Dorchester, and Talbot Counties, Maryland, the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park System. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide grant funding and enter into cooperative agreements with certain entities for the historic preservation, rehabilitation, interpretation, and maintenance of such historical parks. Requires the Secretary to complete a general management plan for them.</summary>
</bill>
