<bill session="111" type="h" number="3152" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Seniors Choose their Medicare Drug Plan Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure that low-income beneficiaries have improved access to prescription drugs under the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2009--Introduced.
Helping Seniors Choose their Medicare Drug Plan - Amends Part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to the process for enrolling a full-benefit dual eligible individual (eligible for both Medicare and Medicaid benefits), who has otherwise failed to enroll in a prescription drug plan (PDP) or in an MedicareAdvantage-Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plan, in a PDP with a beneficiary premium that does not exceed a full premium subsidy. Repeals the requirement that the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) enroll such an individual on a random basis among all plans in the PDP region. Requires the Secretary to enroll the individual in the most appropriate plan based on guidelines, established by the Secretary, that account for the individual's previous prescription drug utilization.</summary>
</bill>
