<bill session="111" type="h" number="1553" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mutual Savings Association Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Home Owners' Loan Act to provide equitable remedies to mutual savings institutions to defend against individuals acting as a de facto corporation attempting to implement a hostile takeover of the institution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Competition Policy" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2009--Introduced.
Mutual Savings Association Preservation Act - Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act to: (1) prohibit any company or subsidiary, or any director, officer, employee, or person with voting power or holding proxies representing more than 25% of the voting shares of such company or subsidiary, from holding, soliciting, or exercising any proxies in respect of a mutual savings association in an attempt to control the association; and (2) allow an aggrieved association to bring a civil action to prevent such takeover attempts.</summary>
</bill>
