<bill session="111" type="h" number="5822" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-28T19:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-28T19:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2011, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400118"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-559, by Mr. Edwards (TX).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-22T17:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="320">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 320.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1559 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5822 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Specified amendments are in order. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1559 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1559.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6216-6249" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6228-6235" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5822 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Specified amendments are in order. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1559 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Donna F. Edwards to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5822.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buyer amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buyer amendment No. 3, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buyer amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cuellar amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hill amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gingrey amendment No. 9, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gingrey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Halvorson amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bilirakis amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peters amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peters amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1559, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:40:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment No. 14, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinshed business was the question on adoption amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5822.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6248" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6228-6235" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-28T19:37:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="482" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 411 - 6 (Roll no. 482).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="494">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 494.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="1559"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3082"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="American Battle Monuments Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h729"/>
    <amendment number="h730"/>
    <amendment number="h731"/>
    <amendment number="h732"/>
    <amendment number="h733"/>
    <amendment number="h734"/>
    <amendment number="h735"/>
    <amendment number="h736"/>
    <amendment number="h737"/>
    <amendment number="h738"/>
    <amendment number="h739"/>
    <amendment number="h740"/>
    <amendment number="h741"/>
    <amendment number="h742"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/28/2010--Passed House amended.
Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2011 - Title I: Department of Defense - Appropriates funds for FY2011 for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military construction for the Army, Navy and Marine Corps, and Air Force (military departments), DOD, the Army and Air National Guard, and the Army, Navy, and Air Force reserves; (2) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (3) family housing construction and related operation and maintenance for the military departments and DOD; (4) the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund; (5) the Homeowners Assistance Fund; (6) chemical demilitarization construction; and (7) the Department of Defense Base Closure Accounts of 1990 and 2005. Specifies restrictions and authorizations regarding the use of funds appropriated in this title and in other military construction appropriations Acts. (Sec. 110) Prohibits appropriated funds from being used to initiate a new installation overseas without prior notification to the congressional appropriations committees. (Sec. 113) Directs the Secretary of Defense to notify the appropriate congressional committees 30 days in advance of the plans and scope of any proposed military exercise involving U.S. personnel if construction costs are anticipated to exceed $100,000. (Sec. 120) Requires the Secretary of the military department concerned, at least 60 days prior to issuing any solicitation for a contract with the private sector for military family housing, to notify the appropriations committees of any guarantees (including the making of mortgage or rental payments) proposed to be made to the private party in the event of: (1) the closure or realignment of the installation for which the housing is provided; (2) a reduction in force of units stationed at such installation; or (3) the extended deployment overseas of units stationed at such installation. (Sec. 121) Authorizes the transfer of DOD funds for expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program under the Metropolitan Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966. (Sec. 124) Places specified restrictions and limitations on the obligation or expenditure of funds made available in this title or in any other military construction appropriations Act to carry out a military construction, land acquisition, or family housing project at or for a military installation approved for closure, or for supporting a function that has been approved for realignment to another installation, in 2005 under the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990. (Sec. 125) Provides for the transfer of lapsed unobligated military construction and family housing funds into the Foreign Currency Fluctuations, Defense account. (Sec. 126) Prohibits this Act's funds from being used for any action that relates to or promotes the expansion of the boundaries or size of the Pinon Canyon Maneuver Site, Colorado. Title II: Department of Veterans Affairs - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration; (2) readjustment benefits; (3) veterans insurance and indemnities; (4) the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund; (5) the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program; (6) the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program; (7) the Veterans Health Administration (including for medical and prosthetic research and information technology systems); (8) the National Cemetery Administration; (9) the Office of the Inspector General; (10) construction for major and minor projects; and (11) grants for the construction of state extended care facilities and veterans cemeteries. Specifies restrictions and authorizations regarding the use of funds appropriated in this title. (Sec. 210) Makes funds from this title available to reimburse expenses of the Office of Resolution Management and the Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication, within specified limits. (Sec. 216) Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary, for purposes of this title) to enter into agreements with certain Indian tribes and tribal organizations in rural Alaska to provide health care, including behavioral health and dental care. (Sec. 219) Directs the Secretary to report quarterly to the appropriations committees on the financial status of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA). (Sec. 224) Authorizes the Secretary to use specified funds for cooperative agreements to conduct outreach to ensure that veterans in underserved areas receive the care and benefits for which they are eligible. (Sec. 225) Allows certain VA funds to be used to fund operations of the Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center. (Sec. 229) Authorizes appropriations for VA general operating expenses, to be used to increase VA workforce capacity and capabilities. (Sec. 230) Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriations committees on: (1) the planned funding allocation from each of the VHA accounts to the National Reserve Fund and any subsequent increase of 10% or more in these allocations; and (2) all bid savings in major construction projects that total at least $5 million or 5% of the programmed amount, whichever is less. (Sec. 233) Earmarks specified funds authorized under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 for renewable energy projects at medical facility campuses constructed, altered, or acquired by the VA. Title III: Related Agencies - Appropriates funds for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; (3) cemeterial expenses; and (4) the Armed Forces Retirement Home. Title IV: Overseas Contingency Operations - Appropriates funds for overseas contingency operations for military construction for the Army, the Air Force, and DOD. Title V: General Provisions - Specifies restrictions and authorities regarding the use of funds appropriated in this Act. (Sec. 508) Prohibits this Act's funds from being used for: (1) a project or program named for an individual serving as a Member, Delegate,or Resident Commissioner of the U.S. Congress; (2) funding the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN); (3) in contravention of certification requirements of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996; (4) maintaining or establishing a computer network unless such network blocks the viewing, downloading, and exchanging of pornography; (5) the processing of new enhanced use leases at the National Homes for Disabled Volunteer Soldiers located in Milwaukee, Wisconsin; (6) the payment of first-class travel by an agency employee in contravention of specified sections of the Code of Federal Regulations; (7) exercising the power of eminent domain without the payment of just compensation; and (8) renovating or constructing any facility in the continental United States for the purpose of housing any individual detained at any time after September 11, 2001, at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</summary>
</bill>
