<bill session="109" type="hc" number="444" updated="2013-07-19T20:05:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-13T20:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-13T20:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Extending the thanks of Congress and the Nation to the Defense POW/Missing Personnel Office, the Joint POW/MIA Accounting Command of the Department of Defense, the Armed Forces DNA Identification Laboratory, the Air Force Life Sciences Equipment Laboratory, and the military departments and to the Socialist Republic of Vietnam for their efforts to achieve the fullest possible accounting of all Americans unaccounted for as a result of the Vietnam War.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Extending the appreciation of Congress and the Nation to the Department of Defense organizations, military departments, and personnel engaged in the mission to achieve the fullest possible accounting for all Americans unaccounted for as a result of the Nation's wars, to the POW/MIA families and veterans who support the mission, and to foreign nations that assist in the mission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2006-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simmons moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6509-6511" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 444.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-13T20:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6509-6510" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Postal facilities"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Vietnamese Conflict"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2006--Passed House amended.
Recognizes that National POW/MIA Recognition Day is one of six days specified by law on which the National League of Families POW/MIA flag is to be flown over specified federal facilities and national cemeteries, military installations, and post offices.Applauds the personnel of the Defense POW/Missing Personnel Office, the Joint POW/MIA Accounting Command (JPAC) of the Department of Defense (DOD), the Armed Forces DNA Identification Laboratory, the Air Force Life Sciences Equipment Laboratory, and the military departments for seeking the fullest possible accounting of Americans unaccounted for as a result of the nation's previous wars and conflicts.Extends the appreciation of Congress and the people of the United States to the personnel of those offices, commands, and laboratories in the United States. the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, the Lao People's Democratic Republic, and the Kingdom of Cambodia for their efforts to achieve the fullest possible accounting of Americans who remain unaccounted for as a result of the Vietnam War.Encourages and recognizes the efforts of the U.S. government, POW/MIA families and veterans, and host nations in supporting efforts to account for missing Americans. Extends the appreciation of Congress to Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia for continued assistance and cooperation in the humane recovery, identification, and repatriation of the remains of American personnel remaining unaccounted for from the Vietnam war. Encourages host nations to assist and cooperate in such recovery efforts.</summary>
</bill>
