<bill session="109" type="h" number="4893" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-13T14:23:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-13T14:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Restricting Indian Gaming to Homelands of Tribes Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 20 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to restrict off-reservation gaming.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 9.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-650.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-13T11:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="386">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 386.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T12:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pombo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T12:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6446-6453" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6446" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T12:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4893.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6460-6461" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2006-09-13T14:23:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="439" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 247 - 171 (Roll no. 439).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2006--Reported to House amended.
Restricting Indian Gaming to Homelands of Tribes Act of 2006 - Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to revise requirements for gaming on lands taken in trust for the benefit of a newly recognized, restored, or landless Indian tribe. Allows one Indian tribe to host another, invited tribe to participate in or benefit from consolidated class II and class III gaming within the boundaries of the host tribe's reservation. Requires the Indian tribe, in order to mitigate the direct impact of gaming activities on the affected county or parish infrastructure and services, to negotiate and sign, during negotiations for a tribal-state gaming compact, a memorandum of understanding concerning mitigation with the county or parish government. Requires the Secretary to appoint an arbitrator to establish mitigation requirements if such a memorandum is not signed within one year after a request to initiate negotiations has been made. Provides that any gaming authorized by this Act shall not be conducted unless it is: (1) consistent with the tribal-state compacting laws of the state in which the gaming activities will be conducted; and (2) specifically identified as expressly authorized in a tribal-state compact of the invited Indian tribe approved by an Act of the legislature and the Governor of the state in which the gaming will be conducted. States that host tribe compacts shall not be affected by the amendments made by this Act. Prohibits an Indian tribe from conducting regulated gaming on Indian lands outside the state in which the Indian tribe is primarily residing and exercising tribal government authority upon the enactment of this Act, unless such lands are contiguous to those in the state where the tribe is primarily residing and exercising such authority. Declares that the gaming arrangement authorized by this Act shall not be conducted on any Indian lands within the state of Arizona.</summary>
</bill>
