<bill session="111" type="s" number="531" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy and Water Integration Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the conduct of an in-depth analysis of the impact of energy development and production on the water resources of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2830-2831"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2831-2832" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-19.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1462"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2009--Introduced.
Energy and Water Integration Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Energy (the Secretary) to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct an in-depth analysis of the impact of energy development and production on U.S. water resources. Requires the study to include a lifecycle assessment of the quantity of water withdrawn and consumed in the production of transportation fuels or electricity. Requires the Secretary to conduct a study to identify the best available technologies and related strategies to maximize water and energy efficiency in the production of electricity by each type of generation (coal, oil and natural gas, hydropower, thermal solar, and nuclear). Directs the Secretary of the Interior: (1) acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to conduct a study to evaluate the quantities of energy used in water storage and delivery operations in major reclamation projects; and (2) to operate, manage, and maintain the Brackish Groundwater National Desalination Research Facility in Otero County, New Mexico, to carry out research, development, and demonstration activities to develop technologies and methods that promote brackish groundwater desalination as a viable method to increase water supply in a cost-effective manner. Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to require the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration to conduct an assessment of energy consumption in various sectors of the economy that are associated with the acquisition, treatment, or delivery of water. Requires the Secretary to develop an Energy-Water Research and Development Roadmap.</summary>
</bill>
