<bill session="109" type="s" number="2063" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reservist Opportunities and Protection of Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to preserve the educational status and financial resources of military personnel called to active duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="199"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="College administration"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Reservist Opportunities and Protection of Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education, as a condition of their participation in the student aid program, to grant students who are called or ordered to active duty a military leave of absence while serving on active duty and for one year after conclusion of such service. Entitles students receiving such leave, upon release from active duty, to be restored to prior educational status attained without loss of academic credits earned, scholarships or grants awarded, or tuition or fees paid, unless those have been refunded. Requires institutions to give such students certain refunds of tuition or fees paid prior to active duty, or to credit such amounts to the next enrollment period after the student returns, at the student's option.</summary>
</bill>
