<bill session="112" type="h" number="2699" updated="2013-07-20T01:33:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Peace Corps Volunteer Service Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish policies and procedures in the Peace Corps to provide for the safety and security of volunteers from rape and sexual assault, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412456" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412415" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412010" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2011-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2337"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2583"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1280"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2011--Introduced.
Peace Corps Volunteer Service Improvement Act of 2011 - Requires the Director of the Peace Corps to establish a process for volunteers to make confidential reports of rape or sexual assault. Subjects any Peace Corps volunteer or member who breaches a duty of confidentiality regarding such a report to disciplinary action, including termination. Requires the Director to enter into with the Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security, and requires the Inspector of the Peace Corps to review, a memorandum of understanding that specifies the duties and obligations of the Peace Corps and the Department of State's Bureau of Diplomatic Security regarding the protection of Peace Corps volunteers and staff members serving in foreign countries. Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of Peace Corps funds for volunteers' invitations for service or to deploy trainees overseas if such agreement has not entered into force within nine months after enactment of this Act, unless the Director certifies that: (1) significant progress is being made toward finalizing such memorandum, and (2) the Peace Corps is using best efforts to provide volunteers with the training, support, and information they need to stay safe. Exempts such Inspector General and officers and employees of the Inspector General's Office from certain length of appointment, reappointment, and reassignment limitations applicable to the Foreign Service. Requires the Director to: (1) annually submit a report on the safety of Peace Corps volunteers; and (2) perform, at least once every three years, a review to evaluate the allocation and delivery of resources across the countries the Peace Corps serves. Requires the Inspector General to perform an audit every five years of Peace Corps implementation of safety and security protocols.</summary>
</bill>
