<bill session="112" type="h" number="3071" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Records Act Amendments of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 22 of title 44, United States Code, popularly known as the Presidential Records Act, to establish procedures for the consideration of claims of constitutionally based privilege against disclosure of Presidential records.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2011-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSGO27" subcommittee="Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2011--Introduced.
Presidential Records Act Amendments of 2011 - Amends the Presidential Records Act to require the Archivist of the United States, upon determining to make available any presidential record not previously made available publicly, to: (1) promptly provide written notice of such determination to the former President during whose term of office the record was created and to the incumbent President, and (2) make the notice available to the public.&#160; Requires a presidential record to be made available to the public 60 days after the Archivist gives notice, except any record with respect to which the Archivist receives notification from a former or incumbent President of a claim of constitutionally based privilege against disclosure.&#160; Prohibits the Archivist from making a record that is subject to a privilege claim asserted by the incumbent President publicly available unless: (1) the incumbent President withdraws the claim; or (2) the Archivist is otherwise&#160;directed to do so&#160;by a final court order that is not subject to appeal. Prohibits the Archivist from making available any original presidential records to anyone claiming access to them as a designated representative of a President or former President if that individual has been convicted of a crime relating to the review, removal, or destruction of the Archives' records.</summary>
</bill>
