<bill session="110" type="h" number="2399" updated="2013-07-19T21:24:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-22T16:43:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-22T16:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act and title 18, United States Code, to combat the crime of alien smuggling and related activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412197" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5576-5580" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2399.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5582-5583" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-05-22T16:43:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="400" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 0, 6 Present (Roll no. 400).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5576-5578" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-28">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2830.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2830"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2830"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2463"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Missionaries"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2007--Passed House amended.
Alien Smuggling and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to check against all available terrorist watchlists those alien smugglers and smuggled individuals who are interdicted at U.S. land, air, and sea borders. (Sec. 4) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to specify the following criminal penalties for individuals convicted of smuggling unlawful aliens into the United States (applicable to each alien for whom the offense applies): (1) fine and/or up to five years incarceration for smuggling; (2) fine and/or up to one year incarceration for transit of the defendant's spouse, child, sibling, parent, grandparent, or niece or nephew; (3) fine and/or up to 10 years incarceration for recruiting to enter, or harboring or transporting in the United States for profit, commercial advantage, or private financial gain; (4) fine and/or incarceration for 3 to 10 years for a first or second offense of knowingly bringing an illegal alien into the United States for profit, commercial advantage, or private financial gain, or if the offense was committed with the intent or reason to believe that the individual will commit a federal or state offense punishable by more than one year's incarceration, and 5 to 15 years incarceration for any subsequent violation; (5) fine and/or up to 20 years incarceration if the offense results in serious bodily injury or jeopardizes a person's life; (6) fine and/or up to 30 years incarceration if the defendant knew the individual was a terrorist or intended to engage in terrorist activity; and (7) fine and/or incarceration for any term of years/or life if the offense involves kidnaping or attempt to kidnap, the conduct required for aggravated sexual abuse, or an attempt to kill. Provides extraterritorial jurisdiction over such offenses. Limits a defense of necessity for knowingly bringing an illegal alien into the United States from the high seas. Exempts from certain of such violations (transporting or harboring in the United States) a bona fide nonprofit, religious organization in the United States (or its agents or officers) that encourages, invites, or enables an alien who is present in the United States to serve as a volunteer minister or missionary for such organization in the United States, provided the minister or missionary has been a member of the denomination for at least one year. (Sec. 5) Amends federal criminal law to specify the following maritime penalties (in addition to the current fine/five-year incarceration): (1) fine and/or up to 10 years incarceration for offenses committed in the course of smuggling, trafficking, shipping, stolen property, drug, and other offenses; (2) fine and/or up to 15 years incarceration for offenses resulting in serious bodily injury or transportation under inhumane conditions; or (3) fine and/or incarceration for any term of years/or life if the offense results in death or involves kidnaping or attempt to kidnap, the conduct required for aggravated sexual abuse or an attempt to commit such abuse, or an attempt to kill. Limits a defense of necessity with respect to such maritime enforcement. Defines "transportation under inhumane conditions" as the transportation of persons in an engine compartment, storage compartment, or other confined space, transportation at an excessive speed, transportation of a number of persons in excess of the rated capacity of the means of transportation, or intentionally grounding a vessel in which persons are being transported. (Sec. 6) Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to review and amend as appropriate sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to persons convicted of alien smuggling offenses and criminal failure to heave to or obstruction of boarding.</summary>
</bill>
