<bill session="112" type="s" number="1846" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nationwide Network of Support for Veterans and Their Families Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the National Veterans Support Foundation to carry out activities to support and supplement the mission of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3082"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2011--Introduced.
Nationwide Network of Support for Veterans and Their Families Act of 2011 - Establishes the National Veterans Support Foundation to, among other things: (1) analyze and organize resources that list and describe organizations, programs, events, and other activities that provide assistance specifically to veterans; (2) provide support and help align and scale resources that support veterans and their families; and (3) encourage and promote participation by private organizations in activities that serve and support veterans. Requires the Foundation to establish a direct community reintegration support program to award grants to create or expand community-based veterans reintegration and support programs. Prohibits the Foundation from accepting any federal funds. Requires annual Foundation audits and reports to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
