<bill session="113" type="h" number="400" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Energy Technology Manufacturing and Export Assistance Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a Clean Energy Technology Manufacturing and Export Assistance Fund to assist United States businesses with exporting clean energy technology products and services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2013-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Clean Energy Technology Manufacturing and Export Assistance Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a Clean Energy Technology Manufacturing and Export Assistance Fund, to be administered through the International Trade Administration, to ensure that U.S. clean energy technology firms have the information and assistance they need to be competitive and to create clean energy technology sector jobs; and (2) administer the Fund to promote policies that will reduce production costs and encourage innovation, investment, and productivity in the clean energy technology sector, and implement a national clean energy technology export strategy. Defines "clean energy technology" to mean a technology related to the production, use, transmission, storage, control, or conservation of energy that will contribute to a stabilization of atmospheric greenhouse gas concentrations through reduction, avoidance, or sequestration of energy-related emissions and that will: (1) reduce the need for additional energy supplies by using existing supplies with greater efficiency or by transmitting, distributing, or transporting energy with greater effectiveness through U.S. infrastructure; or (2) diversify the sources of the energy supply to strengthen energy security and to increase supplies with a favorable balance of environmental effects if the entire technology system is considered. Directs the Secretary, consistent with the National Export Initiative, to provide information, tools, and other assistance to U.S. businesses to promote clean energy technology manufacturing and facilitate the export of clean energy technology products and services. Requires such assistance to include: (1) developing critical analysis of policies to reduce production costs and promote innovation, investment, and productivity in the clean energy technology sector; (2) helping educate companies about how to tailor their activities to specific markets with respect to their product slate, financing, marketing, assembly, and logistics; and (3) helping U.S. companies learn about the export process and export opportunities in foreign markets, navigate foreign markets, and provide input regarding clean energy technology manufacturing and trade policy developments and trade promotion. Requires the Secretary to report on how funds will be used to: (1) focus on small and medium-sized U.S. businesses, (2) encourage the creation and maintenance of the greatest number of clean energy technology jobs in the United States, and (3) encourage the domestic production of clean energy technology products and services. Requires the Secretary to report t on whether the assistance program should be continued and an assessment of the extent to which it has been successful in: (1) developing critical analysis of policies to reduce production costs and promote innovation, investment, and productivity in the clean energy technology sector; (2) assisting businesses with exporting clean energy technology products and services; (3) creating jobs directly related to the clean energy technology sector; and (4) helping companies provide input regarding clean energy technology manufacturing and trade policy developments and trade promotion.</summary>
</bill>
