<bill session="110" type="hc" number="65" updated="2013-07-19T22:09:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Iraq War Policy resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Disagreeing with the plan announced by the President on January 10, 2007, to increase by more than 20,000 the number of United States combat troops in Iraq, and urging the President instead to consider options and alternatives for achieving success in Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400342"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1582"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military strategy"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2007--Introduced.
States that Congress disagrees with the plan announced by the President on January 10, 2007, to increase by more than 20,000 the number of U.S. combat troops in Iraq and urges the President to consider the options set forth in this resolution. States that Congress believes that: (1) the military rules of engagement must allow maximum opportunity for U.S. and coalition forces to pursue the enemy in Iraq; (2) U.S. Armed Forces fighting insurgents and al Qaida terrorists in Al Anbar Province need to be reinforced as determined by military commanders; (3) the Iraq reconstruction effort must focus on projects with a small security footprint; (4) one person in Iraq must have absolute authority and responsibility for reconstruction funding; (5) the United States and its Middle Eastern allies should develop an Iraqi repatriation program; (6) terrorism has been fueled by staggering unemployment rates in Iraq and that the United States with its allies should develop an economic development plan for Baghdad and Al Anbar Province; and (7) the U.S. government should develop a program to open and revitalize the several hundred shuttered state-owned enterprises in Iraq with primary focus on Baghdad and Al Anbar Province.</summary>
</bill>
