<bill session="112" type="h" number="4016" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carried Interest Fairness Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the proper tax treatment of personal service income earned in pass-thru entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E187"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="12"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5727"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1549"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2012--Introduced.
Carried Interest Fairness Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) set forth a special rule for the inclusion in gross income of partnership interests transferred in connection with the performance of services, (2) treat as ordinary income the net capital gain with respect to an investment services partnership interest except to the extent such gain is attributable to a partner's qualified capital interest, (3) exempt income from investment services partnership interests from treatment as qualifying income of a publicly traded partnership, (4) increase the penalty for underpayments of tax resulting from failure to treat income from an investment services partnership interest as ordinary income, and (5) include income and loss from an investment services partnership interest for purposes of determining net earnings from self-employment and applicable self-employment taxes. Defines "investment services partnership interest" as any interest in a partnership held by a person who provides services to a partnership by: (1) advising the partnership about investing in, purchasing, or selling specified assets; (2) managing, acquiring, or disposing of specified assets; or (3) arranging financing with respect to acquiring specified assets.</summary>
</bill>
