<bill session="113" type="s" number="120" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the number of scholarships available to Pakistani women under the Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="217">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 217.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) education and freedom from discrimination are fundamental human rights, and (2) educational exchanges increase people-to-people ties and promote institutional linkages between this country and other countries. Encourages the State Department and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to continue to support Pakistani education initiatives, especially those for women. Directs the USAID Administrator to increase the number of scholarships available under the Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program (Program) during each fiscal year from FY2013-FY2016 by 30% compared to the number of scholarships awarded during FY2012. Requires all the additional scholarships to be awarded to Pakistani women. Directs the USAID Administrator to make every effort to award 50% of the other scholarships available under the Program to Pakistani women.</summary>
</bill>
