<bill session="111" type="h" number="5186" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the chemical facility security program of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2010-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="2996"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2010--Introduced.
Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2010 - Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 to extend until October 4, 2015, the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to issue interim final regulations establishing risk-based performance standards for security of chemical facilities and requiring vulnerability assessments and the development and implementation of site security plans for such facilities. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and in coordination with the Under Secretary for National Protection and Programs, to: (1) establish a voluntary chemical security training program to enhance the capabilities of high-risk chemical facilities to prevent, prepare for, respond to, mitigate against, and recover from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other man-made disasters; and (2) develop a voluntary chemical security exercise program to offer voluntary testing and evaluation of the capabilities of the federal government, state governments, commercial personnel and management, emergency response providers, and the private sector to prevent, prepare for, mitigate against, respond to, and recover from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other emergencies at chemical facilities.</summary>
</bill>
