<bill session="111" type="h" number="2223" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for nationwide expansion of the pilot program for national and State background checks on direct patient access employees of long-term care facilities or providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="631"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program to identify efficient, effective, and economical procedures for long-term care facilities or providers to conduct background checks on prospective direct patient access employees on a nationwide basis under similar terms and conditions as the pilot program established under the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003. Sets forth requirements for states wishing to participate in the program, including requiring: (1) searches of neglect registries and databases; (2) searches of any proceedings that may contain disqualifying information; (3) searches of federal criminal history records, including a fingerprint check; and (4) methods that reduce duplicative fingerprinting. Sets forth program requirements. Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to evaluate the program under this Act. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require state claims processing and information retrieval systems to incorporate compatible methodologies of the National Correct Coding Initiative administered by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to identify and notify states as to which methodologies should be incorporated.</summary>
</bill>
