<bill session="111" type="h" number="2252" updated="2013-07-19T23:32:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Health Care Quality Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the Federal infrastructure for health care quality improvement in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="966"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2009--Introduced.
National Health Care Quality Act - Establishes within the Executive Office of the President the Office of National Health Care Quality Improvement, headed by a Director of National Health Care Quality. Sets forth the duties of the Director, including: (1) advising the President on the quality of health care in the United States; (2) determining national priorities for improving health care quality; (3) establishing annual benchmarks for federal agencies to achieve national priorities for health care quality improvement; (4) developing an annual report card on the nation's health; and (5) posting on a website public information relating to national priorities for health care quality improvement and other information relating to health care quality. Establishes within the Office the Quality Interagency Coordinating Council to coordinate health care quality improvement efforts across all federal agencies. Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) make the position of Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality a presidential appointment; and (2) require the Agency to incorporate health care quality improvement priorities into research conducted under the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), apply health care quality measures to HHS health programs, and conduct a public education campaign to educate health care providers and consumers about health care quality improvement. Establishes a National Quality Resource Center to assist health care providers in understanding and implementing health care quality improvement initiatives. Requires the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to award National Quality Support Extension grants to support and facilitate local health care quality improvement efforts throughout the United States.</summary>
</bill>
