<bill session="111" type="s" number="1611" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide collective bargaining rights for public safety officers employed by States or their political subdivisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="413"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3194"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3991"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act of 2009 - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to provide collective bargaining rights for public safety officers employed by states or local governments. Directs the Federal Labor Relations Authority (FLRA) to determine whether a state substantially provides for specified rights and responsibilities for public safety officers, including: (1) granting public safety employees the right to form and join a labor organization which excludes management, supervisory, and confidential employees, and which is, or seeks to be, recognized as the exclusive bargaining agent for such employees; and (2) requiring public safety employers to recognize and agree to bargain with the employees' labor organization. Requires the FLRA to issue, in accordance with the public safety employee rights and responsibilities, regulations establishing collective bargaining procedures for public safety employers and employees in states that do not substantially provide for such rights and responsibilities. Directs the FLRA, in such cases, to: (1) determine the appropriateness of units for labor organization representation; (2) supervise or conduct elections to determine whether a labor organization has been selected as an exclusive representative by a voting majority of the employees in an appropriate unit; (3) resolve issues relating to the duty to bargain in good faith; (4) conduct hearings and resolve complaints of unfair labor practices; and (5) resolve exceptions to arbitrators' awards. Grants a public safety employer, employee, or labor organization the right to seek enforcement of FLRA regulations and orders through appropriate state courts. Prohibits public safety employers, employees, and labor organizations from engaging in lockouts, sickouts, work slowdowns, or strikes. Waives federal preemption of state law governing strikes by public safety officers. Provides that existing collective bargaining units and agreements shall not be invalidated by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
