<bill session="111" type="h" number="2825" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safety in Defense Contracting Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Defense to debar from contracting with the Department of Defense any company found to have jeopardized the health or safety of Government personnel or found guilty of contract fraud, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6542"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2009--Introduced.
Safety in Defense Contracting Act - Requires the Secretary of Defense to debar from contracting with the Department of Defense (DOD) any defense contractor: (1) officially determined to have caused serious injury or death to any civilian or military personnel through gross negligence or reckless disregard for safety, or to have committed fraud; or (2) awarded a subcontract to a subcontractor officially determined to have caused or committed such actions. Directs the Secretary to also debar any subcontractor found to have caused or committed such actions. Requires a five-year minimum period for such a debarment. Authorizes a debarment waiver by the Secretary if it would jeopardize national security. Directs the Secretary, in the case of any defense contractor receiving a level III corrective action request from the Defense Contract Management Agency in a fiscal year, to withhold any contract award or incentive fees for that fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
