<bill session="109" type="hc" number="279" updated="2013-07-19T20:04:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress with respect to the 2005 presidential and parliamentary elections in Egypt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="hc" number="284"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Monopolies"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Parliamentary government"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public demonstrations"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/26/2005--Introduced.
Recognizes the importance of the September 2005 presidential election as a first step toward greater openness and political reforms in Egypt. Expresses concern over the lack of international election monitoring and irregularities during such election. Calls on the government of Egypt, during the 2005 parliamentary elections, to: (1) authorize the judiciary to supervise the election process; (2) authorize the presence of accredited representatives of all competing parties and independent candidates at polling stations and during the vote-counting; and (3) allow local and international election monitors full access and accreditation. Calls on the government of Egypt to: (1) separate the National Democratic Party apparatus from the operations of government, divest all government holdings in Egyptian media, and end the government newspaper monopoly; and (2) repeal the 1981 emergency law and, in the development of any future anti-terrorism legislation, allow constitutional political activities.</summary>
</bill>
