<bill session="113" type="h" number="2947" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Women's Freedom Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To express United States foreign policy with respect to, and to strengthen United States advocacy on behalf of, individuals persecuted and denied their rights in foreign countries on account of gender, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2013-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1200"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
International Women's Freedom Act of 2013 - Establishes within the Department of State an Office of International Women's Rights to be headed by an Ambassador at Large for International Women's Rights. Directs the Secretary of State to establish a women's rights Internet site and maintain prisoner lists and issue briefs on women's rights concerns. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to include instruction on the internationally recognized rights of women and the various aspects and manifestations of violations of women's rights in Foreign Service officer training. Establishes the United States Commission on International Women's Rights. Directs the President to take specified actions in response to women's rights violations, especially particularly severe rights violations. Prescribes criteria for the prohibition of economic, multilateral, military, and export assistance in instances of particularly severe women's rights violations. Prescribes requirements for the promotion of women's rights. Requires women's rights-related training with respect to refugee, asylum, and consular matters. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to declare inadmissible to the United States any foreign government officials who have engaged in particularly severe women's rights violations. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) transnational corporations operating overseas should adopt codes of conduct upholding the rights of their female employees, and (2) there should be within the staff of the National Security Council a Special Adviser to the President on International Women's Rights.</summary>
</bill>
