<bill session="112" type="h" number="2935" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defending Special Education Students and Families Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the full funding of part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act by making certain spending cuts to the Department of Defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2011-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2011--Introduced.
Defending Special Education Students and Families Act - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to reauthorize appropriations for the grant program to assist states, outlying areas, and Freely Associated States to provide special education and related services to children with disabilities. Authorizes specified appropriations for FY2012-FY2016, and sets forth a formula for determining the authorization of appropriations for FY2017 and thereafter. Terminates funding for the F-35B and F-35C Joint Strike Fighter Aircraft and the Expeditionary Fighting Vehicle. Limits the naval combat forces of the Navy, beginning on October 1, 2013, to no more than 10 operational aircraft carriers and 9 carrier air wings. Requires the Secretary of Defense to decommission the U.S.S. George Washington during 2016.</summary>
</bill>
