<bill session="110" type="h" number="6391" updated="2013-07-19T21:59:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2008--Introduced.
National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions of the National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program.Specifies how loss of earning is to be calculated for vaccine-related injuries to individuals under the age of 18.Increases the award for vaccine-related deaths.Allows compensation under the Program for expenses for family counseling and for establishing and maintaining a guardianship, conservatorship, or trust for an individual with a vaccine-related injury.Allows a special master to make an interim award of attorneys' fees and costs under certain circumstances. Allows such award to be payable directly to the petitioner's attorney.Extends the statute of limitation for vaccine-related injury or death to six years after the date of injury or onset of symptoms.Specifies who is to be a member of the Advisory Commission on Childhood Vaccines. Provides that the Commission shall meet at the call of the Chair (currently, the Commission must meet not less than four times a year).Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the amount of expenses for administering the Program that are allowed to be paid from the Vaccine Injury Compensation Trust Fund. Allows the payment from the Trust Fund of administrative and personnel expenses that the Bureau of Public Debt incurs for financial services for the Trust Fund.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to include a public service announcement in efforts to inform the public about the Program.</summary>
</bill>
