<bill session="109" type="s" number="4010" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Protection for Children Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Children's Environmental Protection and Right to Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Toxic Control Substance Act, the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liabilitiy Act of 1980, the Emergency Planning and Right-To-Know Act of 1986, and the Federal Hazardous Substances Act, and to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide grants to States to protect children and other vulnerable sub-populations from exposure to environmental pollutants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Bioaccumulation"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cadmium"/>
    <term name="Carcinogens"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Chromium"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Dioxins"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental estrogens"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fetus"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heavy metals"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Neurology"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Toys"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Environmental Protection for Children Act of 2006 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) ensure that environmental and public health standards for environmental pollutants protect children and vulnerable subpopulations from exposure; and (2) create lists of pollutants posing health risks to children as well as safer-for-children substances and products. Requires the EPA Administrator, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to support research into the health effects and toxicity of pesticides and pollutants on children. Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to require the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry (Agency) and the EPA Administrator to jointly: (1) develop a hazardous substance list; and (2) revise guidelines for the preparation of toxicological profiles of substances. Requires the Agency to prepare and revise such profiles every five years. Directs the Agency develop an environmental health education program focusing on the hazardous substance exposure of fetuses and children. Requires the Agency, in cooperation with states, to establish a registry of children exposed to significant levels of hazardous substances released at facilities on CERCLA's National Priorities List. Children's Environmental Protection and Right to Know Act - Amends the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 to require EPA to establish toxic chemical release form reporting thresholds for toxic chemicals that may present a significant risk to children's health or the environment. Amends the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (FHSA) to require EPA, acting jointly with the Chairman of the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), to publish a list of substances toxic to children because of their carcinogenic, neurotoxic, or reproductive toxic effects. Requires EPA to implement strategies for chemical testing and risk assessment. Requires manufacturers and importers of such substances to report to the CPSC on such substances. Authorizes private citizens to bring a civil action in the U.S. district court for specified violations of FHSA or this Act. Establishes a penalty fund. Requires EPA, in collaboration with HHS, to establish a block grant program for state testing and removal of pollutants from schools and day care centers.</summary>
</bill>
