<bill session="110" type="s" number="1138" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Safeguards and Supply Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Nuclear Safeguards and Supply Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance nuclear safeguards and to provide assurances of nuclear fuel supply to countries that forgo certain fuel cycle activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4678-4679"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-151.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="349">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 349.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Reactor fuel reprocessing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Nuclear Safeguards and Supply Act of 2007 - Title I: Nuclear Safeguards and Nuclear Fuel Supply - (Sec. 102) States that it shall be U.S. policy to discourage the development of enrichment and reprocessing capabilities in additional countries, encourage the creation of bilateral and multilateral assurances of nuclear fuel supply, and ensure that all supply mechanisms operate in strict accordance with International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) safeguards system and do not result in any additional unmet verification burdens for the system. (Sec. 103) Authorizes additional FY2008 appropriations for the refurbishment or possible replacement of the IAEA Safeguards Analytical Laboratory. Directs the Secretary of State to report to the appropriate congressional committees respecting such refurbishment or replacement. (Sec. 104) Authorizes the Secretary to pursue a program to: (1) strengthen technical safeguards research and development; (2) increase resources, identify near-term technology goals, formulate a technology roadmap, and improve interagency coordination on safeguards technology; and (3) examine proliferation resistance in design and development of all future nuclear energy systems. Title II: Nuclear Fuel Supply - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the President to create bilateral and multilateral mechanisms to provide a reliable supply of nuclear fuel to those countries and groups of countries that adhere to policies to prevent nuclear weapons proliferation and that decide to forgo a national uranium enrichment program and spent nuclear fuel reprocessing facilities. (Sec. 202) Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees respecting the feasibility of establishing an International Nuclear Fuel Authority. (Sec. 203) Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States should support, either in annual voluntary and off-budget contributions to the IAEA, or in the provision of nuclear fuel to the IAEA, a nuclear fuel bank within the IAEA; and (2) a combination of public and private efforts will be necessary to manage the growth of civilian nuclear power in a manner that does not result in undue burdens on the IAEA safeguards system.</summary>
</bill>
