<bill session="111" type="s" number="2965" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commission for Fiscal Sustainability Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Commission for Fiscal Sustainability, to assure the long-term fiscal stability and economic security of the Federal Government of the United States, and to create prosperity for all Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4646"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2853"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2010--Introduced.
Commission for Fiscal Sustainability Act of 2010 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to establish in the legislative branch the Commission for Fiscal Sustainability to address, and report to the President, the Vice President, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Majority and Minority Leaders of both chambers on, the nation's long-term fiscal imbalances, including federal expenditures and revenues and the current and long-term actuarial financial condition of the federal government. Provides for expedited legislative consideration of the Commission's recommendations. Requires the Commission to make recommendations that: (1) shall significantly improve the long-term fiscal imbalance of the federal governent solely through reductions in federal expenditures; and (2) shall not increase federal revenues through increased taxes.</summary>
</bill>
