<bill session="109" type="s" number="1050" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expedited Remedy for Persistent Dumping Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide for an expedited antidumping investigation when imports increase materially from new suppliers after an antidumping order has been issued, and to amend the provision relating to adjustments to export price and constructed export price.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2005-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2005--Introduced.
Expedited Remedy for Persistent Dumping Act of 2005 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to revise requirements for monitoring cases of suspected persistent dumping to: (1) provide for an expedited antidumping investigation of merchandise from an additional supplier country if the Department of Commerce discerns imports of merchandise from the additional supplier country have increased by 15 percent or more during a period of 90 days or longer; and (2) establish Department of Commerce and International Trade Commission procedures and deadlines for making determinations as to whether or not dumping and injury have occurred. Adds specific conditions for reducing the price used to establish export price or "constructed export price," meaning the amount at which the merchandise is first sold or agreed to be sold in the United States by or for the producer or exporter. Applies this Act to Canada and Mexico under the North American Free Trade Agreement and the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act.</summary>
</bill>
