<bill session="111" type="h" number="2580" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Empowering Medicare Patient Choices Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the establishment of shared decision making standards and requirements and to establish a pilot program for the implementation of shared decision making under the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1236"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1133"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Empowering Medicare Patient Choices Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) contract with an entity to establish consensus-based standards to certify patient decision aids; and (2) establish an expert panel to make recommendations about which patient decision aids should be implemented, appropriate training for health care providers on patient decision aids and shared decision making, and appropriate quality measures for use in the related pilot program Directs the Secretary to establish a pilot program to provide for the phased-in development, implementation, and evaluation of shared decision making under the Medicare program using patient decision aids to improve beneficiary understanding of medical treatment options. Directs the Secretary to provide financial assistance for establishment of Shared Decision Making Resource Centers to support adoption, implementation, and effective use of patient decision aids and shared decision making by eligible Medicare providers. Specifies the medical conditions for approved patient decision aids Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary to promulgate regulations that: (1) specify for which preference-sensitive conditions beneficiaries should participate in shared decision making; (2) require service providers and suppliers to make sure that beneficiaries receive appropriate patient decision aids; and (3) specify a process for beneficiaries to elect not to use such patient decision aids. Prescribes a penalty for service providers or item suppliers if a patient does not receive a patient decision aid before an item or service is furnished, unless the patient has elected not to use such an aid.</summary>
</bill>
