<bill session="110" type="h" number="6649" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foster Children Opportunity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to help alien children in the child welfare system apply for all available forms of immigration relief, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2008-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1603-1604"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2008--Introduced.
Foster Children Opportunity Act - Amends part E (Federal Payments for Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require state plans to have procedures to help alien children in the child welfare system achieve special immigrant juvenile status and lawful permanent resident status. Requires state child welfare agencies to document their efforts to pursue special immigrant juvenile status and legal immigrant status for eligible alien foster children. Requires the permanency hearing for an alien child who will not be returned to a parent to determine: (1) whether petitions for special immigrant juvenile status and lawful permanent resident status have been filed on the child's behalf; and (2) if no petition has been filed, whether it is in the best interests of the child to have such a petition filed or to have immigration counsel appointed. Authorizes the use of court improvement program grant funds to educate and train judges and lawyers to assist alien children in achieving special immigrant juvenile status and lawful permanent resident status.</summary>
</bill>
