<bill session="111" type="s" number="4039" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus SaVE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve education and prevention related to campus sexual violence, intimate partner violence, and stalking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2010-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6461"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2010--Introduced.
Campus Sexual Violence Elimination Act or Campus SaVE Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each institution of higher education (IHE) participating in a title IV program (except foreign schools) to include in its annual security report a statement of policy regarding its sexual assault and other intimate partner violence programs and the procedures it follows when such an offense occurs. Requires such procedures to include the provision, in writing, to students or employees that report to the IHE that they have been the victim of such an offense: (1) an explanation of their right to notify proper law enforcement authorities and their option to be assisted by campus authorities in doing so; (2) an explanation of their right to obtain protective orders or enforce protective orders that are already in existence, which the IHE must honor; and (3) contact information for victim services on-campus and in the locality. Requires an IHE's policy regarding sexual assault and other intimate partner violence to include: (1) education that promotes awareness of the offenses; (2) possible sanctions imposed following disciplinary action; (3) procedures victims should follow after such an offense occurs; (4) on-campus disciplinary procedures; and (5) the notification of victims regarding their options for, and assistance in, changing academic, living, transportation, and working situations. Directs the Secretary of Education to seek the Attorney General's counsel regarding the development, and dissemination to IHEs, of best practices for preventing and responding to sex offenses and other intimate partner violence.</summary>
</bill>
