<bill session="110" type="s" number="3630" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">AmericaView Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize a comprehensive program of nationwide access to Federal remote sensing data, to promote use of the program for education, workforce training and development, and applied research, and to support Federal, State, tribal, and local government programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6970"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
AmericaView Authorization Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey (USGS), to: (1) establish and maintain a nationwide AmericaView Program to advance the availability, distribution, and use of remote sensing data (information acquired from above the surface of the Earth by satellite or airplane) and technology in each state; (2) maintain AmericaView (the national nonprofit collaboration of StateView participants cooperating with the EROS Data Center to achieve the purposes of the AmericaView Program) in each state to develop publicly accessible remote sensing data archive and distribution infrastructure and expand remote sensing education, research, and knowledge; (3) award annual grants to sustain and develop StateView programs (the AmericaView programs of an individual states, comprised of educational institutions and state and local governments); and (4) maintain an advisory committee to advise the USGS Director about the AmericaView Program.</summary>
</bill>
