<bill session="113" type="sj" number="24" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to amend the Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 to make continuing appropriations for death gratuities and related survivor benefits for survivors of deceased members of the Coast Guard.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="91"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 (P.L. 113-44) to make appropriations, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for death gratuities and related benefits for survivors of deceased military service members of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate of operations as provided for FY2013 in the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2013 (division D of P.L 113-6), for the "Operating Expenses" account for continuing such death gratuities and survivor benefits with respect to members of the Coast Guard when not in the service of the Navy that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this joint resolution or the Pay Our Military Act (P.L. 113-39) and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2013. (Currently, such continuing appropriations for death gratuities and survivor benefits are provided only with respect to deceased military service members of the Department of Defense [DOD].) Revises the title of such resolution so that it is cited as the Armed Forces Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014.</summary>
</bill>
