<bill session="111" type="s" number="3216" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Rural Health Care Equity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure Medicare beneficiary access to physicians, to ensure equitable reimbursement under the Medicare program for all rural States, and to eliminate sweetheart deals for frontier States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2387-2388"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2010--Introduced.
Medicare Rural Health Care Equity Act of 2010 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), to revise the practice expense portion of the geographic adjustment applied in a fee schedule area for physicians' services furnished in 2010 and subsequent years. Reduces the employee wage and rent portions of the index for 2010 from 3/4 to 1/2 of the difference between the relative costs of employee wages and rents in each of the different fee schedule areas and the national average of such employee wages and rents. Reduces the same portions of the index for 2011 from 1/2 to 1/4 of such differences. Amends PPACA to repeal specified floors for frontier states: (1) on the area wage index for hospitals; (2) on the area wage adjustment factor for hospital outpatient department services; and (3) for the practice expense index for services furnished in such states.</summary>
</bill>
