<bill session="111" type="h" number="5513" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spilled Oil Royalty Collection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require payment of royalty on all oil and gas saved, removed, sold, or discharged under a lease under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412233" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2010-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4445"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2010--Introduced.
Spilled Oil Royalty Collection Act - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to declare that any royalty under an oil and gas lease on submerged lands of the outer Continental Shelf, except a deepwater lease, shall apply to all oil that is saved, removed, sold, or discharged, without regard to whether any of the oil is unavoidably lost or used on, or for the benefit of, the lease. Declares that: (1) royalty shall apply to all oil discharged under a deepwater lease, at a rate of not less than 12.5% fixed by the Secretary of the Interior in amount or value of any oil that is discharged; and (2) such royalty shall apply without regard to whether any of the oil is thereafter unavoidably lost. Declares April 15, 2010, the effective date of this Act (five days before the Deepwater Horizon drilling rig explosion in the Gulf of Mexico).</summary>
</bill>
