<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1249" updated="2013-07-19T23:06:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Raising a question of the privileges of the House.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>QUESTION OF THE PRIVILEGES OF THE HOUSE - Mr. Boehner rose to a question of the privileges of the House and offered a privileged resolution. The Chair announced that the resolution qualified and directed the Clerk to report the resolution to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2553-2554" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McGovern moved to refer to Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Chair recognized Mr. McGovern to proceed with one hour of debate on the motion to refer H. Res. 1249 to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to refer was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2553" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to refer Agreed to by recorded vote: 235 - 157, 17 Present (Roll no. 202).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2553" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1164"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2010--Introduced.
Directs the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to investigate fully which House Democratic leaders and members of their respective staffs had knowledge before March 3, 2010, of the allegations concerning former Representative Eric Massa, and what actions each leader and staffer having any such knowledge took after learning of the allegations. Requires the Committee to establish an Investigative Subcommittee regarding such matter, or report to the House of Representatives the reasons for its failure to do so. Requires the Chief Administrative Officer immediately to take all steps necessary to secure and prevent the alteration or deletion of any e-mails, text messages, voicemails, and other electronic records resident on House equipment that have been sent or received by Members and staff who are the subjects of such investigation until advised by the Committee that it has no need of any portion of such records. Requires the Committee to issue a final report by July 31, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
