<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1404" updated="2013-07-19T23:08:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-27T12:31:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-27T12:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5136) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2011 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes; waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26T23:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-498, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26T23:28:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 or rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an orginial bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Armed Services now printed in the bill. No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution and amendments en bloc described in section 3 of this resolution. The resolution waives a requirement with respect to consideration of certain resolutions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-05-26T23:29:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="201">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 201.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3876-3885" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1404.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3885" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1404, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceeding on agreeing to the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-05-27T12:31:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="307" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 178 (Roll no. 307).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3876" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="5136"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5136) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2011 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes; waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</summary>
</bill>
