<bill session="109" type="h" number="56" updated="2013-07-19T19:04:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Empowerment Zone Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish health empowerment zone programs in communities that disproportionately experience disparities in health status and health care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2005-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Health Empowerment Zone Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) and the Director of the Office of Minority Health, to: (1) designate health empowerment zones and make grants in accordance with this Act; and (2) establish a health empowerment zone coordinating committee for each zone. Authorizes the Secretary to designate a community as a health empowerment zone if a participating community partnership requests such designation and demonstrates that the community is a community of color experiencing disproportionate disparities in health status and health care. Directs the Secretary to make grants to community partnerships to establish health empowerment zone programs to improve the health or environment of minority individuals and eliminate racial and ethnic disparities in health status and health care. Requires at least one such grant to be made to a health empowerment zone in a U.S. territory or possession. Gives preference in awarding grants to indigenous community entities with expertise in providing culturally appropriate and linguistically responsive services to communities of color. Directs the Secretary, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to: (1) provide assistance for such programs; (2) identify programs that may be used to further the purposes of such zones; and (3) give priority in administering identified programs to a designated community if doing so would further the purposes of the empowerment program.</summary>
</bill>
