<bill session="110" type="s" number="133" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Fuels Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the national security and stability of the economy of the United States by reducing the dependence of the United States on oil through the use of alternative fuels and new technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S127-128"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S128-133" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2354"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compressed natural gas"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liquefied natural gas"/>
    <term name="Liquefied petroleum gas"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
American Fuels Act of 2007 - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the Office of Energy Security to oversee all federal energy security programs, including coordination of all federal agency efforts to assist the United States in achieving full energy independence. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide: (1) a tax credit, against both ordinary and alternative minimum tax, for production of qualified flexible fuel motor vehicles; and (2) an alternative fuel retail sales credit. Amends the Clayton Act and the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to prohibit restrictions on the installation of alternative fuel pumps within fuel franchise documents. Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations to ensure that diesel sold or introduced into commerce in the United States, on an annual average basis, contains specified percentages of alternative diesel fuel. Sets forth a credit program for the generation of diesel fuel. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an excise tax credit for: (1) production of cellulosic biomass ethanol; and (2) qualifying ethanol blending and processing equipment. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 (EPA) to treat a medium or heavy duty hybrid vehicle as an alternative fueled vehicle. Sets a deadline by which: (1) any federal property with at least one fuel refueling station must include at least one alternative fuel refueling station; and (2) any alternative fuel refueling station on federally-owned property must permit full public access for the purpose of refueling using alternative fuel. Amends federal transportation law to require that any bus purchased with funds from the Mass Transit Account of the Highway Trust Fund to be a clean fuel bus. Amends armed forces law governing energy-related procurement to direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy to use fuel produced from domestically produced fuel using starch, sugar, cellulosic biomass, plant or animal oils, or thermal chemical conversion, thermal depolymerization, or thermal conversion processes (covered fuel). Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts to: (1) develop and operate covered fuel production facilities; and (2) provide for construction or capital modification of such facilities. Amends the EPA to include among alternative fueled vehicles any vehicle propelled by electric drive transportation, engine dominant hybrid electric, or plug-in hybrid technology.</summary>
</bill>
