<bill session="110" type="s" number="2200" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal Water Resources Innovative Financing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the use of Federal funds for flexible financing of Indian tribal municipal, rural, and industrial water system construction projects by certain federally recognized Indian tribes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13090"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2007--Introduced.
Tribal Water Resources Innovative Financing Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to reimburse an Indian tribe for specified expenses and costs incurred by the tribe with respect to an eligible debt financing instrument. Defines "eligible debt financing instrument" to mean a bond or other debt financing instrument (including a note, certificate, mortgage, or lease agreement) issued by an Indian tribe, the proceeds of which are used for construction of an authorized Indian tribal municipal, rural, or industrial water project. Allows the Secretary to reimburse an Indian tribe for a project funded by an eligible debt financing instrument if the project is being carried out by the Indian tribe pursuant to a contract or cooperative agreement with the Secretary in accordance with the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act. Limits the federal cost share for a project under this Act to the federal cost share for the project as determined under the authorizing statute.</summary>
</bill>
