<bill session="112" type="h" number="2765" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sunshine on Conflicts Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to clarify the requirement that permit applications for the discharge of pollutants be approved by disinterested board members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2011-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2011--Introduced.
Sunshine on Conflicts Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue a rule within 60 days to prohibit any member of a board or body that approves permit applications for the discharge of pollutants from seeking to influence the approval of any permit in which that member has a financial interest. Provides that the requirement that state national pollutant discharge elimination system programs ensure that any board or body that approves permits excludes as a member any person who receives or has received during the previous two years a significant portion of income from permit holders or applicants shall have no force or effect after the earlier of the date on which such rule is issued or 120 days after this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
