<bill session="113" type="s" number="717" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nonprofit Energy Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a pilot program to award grants to nonprofit organizations for the purpose of retrofitting nonprofit buildings with energy-efficiency improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Nonprofit Energy Efficiency Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish a pilot program to award grants to nonprofit organizations for the purpose of retrofitting buildings owned by such organizations with energy-efficiency improvements. Directs the Secretary, in determining whether to award a grant, to apply performance-based criteria, which shall give priority to applications based on: (1) the cost-effectiveness of the energy-efficiency improvement; and (2) an effective plan for evaluation, measurement, and verification of energy savings. Limits each grant award to: (1) an amount equal to 50% of the energy-efficiency improvement, and (2) $200,000. Authorizes appropriations for such grants for FY2014-FY2017. Requires the Secretary to use amounts otherwise made available for the Building Technologies Program to carry out such pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
