<bill session="112" type="h" number="3800" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-31">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the funding and expenditure authority of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund, to amend title 49, United States Code, to extend authorizations for the airport improvement program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2012-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Petri moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H135-137" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3800.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-01-24T13:19:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H135" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24T13:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-01-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S136" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-01-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-01-31" type="public" number="112-91">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-91.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2887"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2012--Public Law.
Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2012 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through February 17, 2012, increased excise taxes on aviation fuels, the excise tax on air transportation of persons and property, and the expenditure authority for the Airport and Airway Trust Fund. (Sec. 4) Extends through February 17, 2012: (1) the authorization of appropriations for airport planning and development and noise compatibility planning projects (known as airport improvement projects [AIPs]), and (2) the authority of the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to make new AIP grants. (Sec. 5) Extends through February 17, 2012: (1) the pilot program for passenger facility fee authorizations at non-hub airports, and (2) disclosure requirements for large and medium hub airports applying for AIP grants. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary through February 17, 2012, to make agreements to provide small community air service assistance to underserved airports. Directs the Secretary to extend through February 17, 2012, the termination date of insurance coverage for domestic or foreign-flag aircraft. Grants the Secretary discretionary authority to further extend such coverage through May 17, 2012. Extends through May 17, 2012, the authority of the Secretary to limit air carrier liability for claims arising out of acts of terrorism. Extends through February 17, 2012: (1) grant eligibility for airports located in the Marshall Islands, Micronesia, and Palau; (2) grants to state and local governments for land use compatibility AIPs; and (3) authority for approving an application of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority for an airport development grant or for permission to impose a passenger facility fee. Amends the Vision 100-Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act to extend through February 17, 2012: (1) the temporary increase to 95% of the federal government's share of certain AIP costs, (2) funding for airport development at Midway Island Airport, and (3) the effective period of final orders of the Secretary regarding the eligibility of small communities for essential air service subsidies. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) for the period from October 1, 2011, through February 17, 2012, for: (1) FAA operations; (2) air navigation facilities and equipment; and (3) civil aviation research, engineering, and development. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations out of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for the period from October 1, 2011, through February 17, 2012, for the essential air service (EAS) program.</summary>
</bill>
