<bill session="109" type="s" number="2152" updated="2013-07-19T20:32:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sales Tax Fairness and Simplification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote simplification and fairness in the administration and collection of sales and use taxes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14190-14191"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14191-14193" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2005--Introduced.
Sales Tax Fairness and Simplification Act - Grants the consent of Congress to the Streamlined Sales and Use Tax Agreement, the multistate agreement for the administration and collection of sales and use taxes adopted on November 12, 2002. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Agreement provides sufficient simplification and uniformity to warrant federal authorizations to states that are parties to it (member states) to require remote sellers (sellers without a physical presence in the taxing state) to collect and remit the sales and use taxes of such states and their local taxing jurisdictions. Authorizes each member state, after 10 states (comprising at least 20% of all states imposing a sales tax) have petitioned for and become member states, to require all sellers, except those sellers with gross remote taxable sales nationwide of less than $5 million, to collect and remit sales and use taxes on remote sales owed to such member state under the terms of the Agreement. Allows any person affected by the Agreement to petition the Governing Board established by the Agreement for a determination of any issue arising under the Agreement. Provides for judicial review of Governing Board determinations by the U.S. Court of Federal Claims. Sets forth minimum simplification requirements for the Agreement. Expresses the sense of Congress that member states should work with each other to prevent double taxation where a foreign country has imposed a transaction tax on a digital good or service.</summary>
</bill>
