<bill session="113" type="s" number="1562" updated="2013-11-05T04:46:50-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Older Americans Act Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Older Americans Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1028"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2013--Introduced.
Older Americans Act Reauthorization Act of 2013 - Reauthorizes the Older Americans Act of 1965 (OAA) and funding for its programs for FY2014-FY2018. Requires the Director of the Office of Long-Term Care Ombudsman Programs (in the Administration on Aging [AOA] of the Department of Health and Human Services [HHS]) to collect, analyze, and report on best practices related to elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation in long-term care facilities. Requires the Assistant Secretary for Aging of the AOA to focus: (1) on the health and economic needs and welfare of older individuals; and (2) ensure that authorized programs include appropriate training in the prevention of abuse, neglect, and exploitation and provision of services that address elder justice and the exploitation of older individuals. Reauthorizes appropriations for FY2014-FY2018, and revises requirements, for the AOA, the Eldercare Locator Service, pension counseling and information programs, supportive services, congregate nutrition services, disease prevention and health promotion services, family caregiver support, the nutrition services incentive program, the Community Service Senior Opportunity Act, grants for Native Americans. Revises requirements for the national family caregiver support program and the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman program, revising conflict-of-interest requirements and prohibitions for the latter. Requires health programs for older individuals to cover behavioral health. Directs the Comptroller General to study the transportation services for older individuals. Directs the Assistant Secretary to issue guidance to applicable to states, area agencies on aging, and providers of services for older individuals, with respect to serving Holocaust survivors.</summary>
</bill>
