<bill session="110" type="s" number="1644" updated="2013-07-19T22:34:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Byrd. With written report No. 110-84.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="204">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 204.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Patrol aircraft"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2008 - Title I: Department of Homeland Security Departmental Management and Operations - Makes appropriations for FY2008 for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for the Offices of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Under Secretary for Management, the Chief Financial Officer, the Chief Information Officer, the Federal Coordinator for Gulf Coast Rebuilding, and the Inspector General.Title II: Security, Enforcement, and Investigations - Makes appropriations for: (1) Customs and Border Protection (CBP), including for border security fencing, infrastructure, and technology, air and marine interdiction, maintenance, procurement, and construction; (2) Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), including for the Federal Protective Service; (3) the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), including for transportation threat assessment and credentialing and the Federal Air Marshals; (4) the Coast Guard, including for environmental compliance and restoration, reserve training, acquisition, construction, and improvements, and retired pay; and (5) the Secret Service.Title III: Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery - Makes appropriations for: (1) the National Protection and Programs Directorate; (2) the Office of Health Affairs; and (3) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), including for state and local programs for terrorism prevention, firefighter assistance grants, emergency management performance grants, the radiological emergency preparedness program, the U.S. Fire Administration, and disaster assistance and flood-related activities and funds. Sets restrictions on the obligation of funds for the U.S. Visitor and Immigrant Status Indicator Technology (U.S.-VISIT). Title IV: Research and Development, Training, and Services - Makes appropriations for citizenship and immigration services (CIS), the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, the Office of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office. Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 501) Sets forth prohibitions and restrictions on funds provided under this Act, including with respect to availability, reorganization authority, reprogramming, intelligence activities, federal law enforcement training, protection of agency heads, and Coast Guard operations. (Sec. 507) Designates the Federal Law Enforcement Training Accreditation Board to lead the federal law enforcement training accreditation process.(Sec. 510) Requires the Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to schedule basic or advanced law enforcement training at all four training facilities under the Center's control to ensure that these centers are operated at the highest capacity. (Sec. 513) Prohibits: (1) the obligation of funds for deployment or implementation of the Secure Flight program or other passenger prescreening program, on other than a test basis, until the Secretary of Homeland Security has certified and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) has reported that specified requirements have been met; and (2) the use, during the testing phase, of information gathered from passengers, foreign or domestic air carriers, or reservation systems to screen aviation passengers or to delay or deny boarding, except where passenger names are matched to a government watch list.(Sec. 514) Prohibits the funds made available in this Act from being used to amend the oath of allegiance required by the Immigration and Nationality Act.(Sec. 515) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this Act to process or approve a competition under Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular A-76 for services provided as of June 1, 2004, by employees of CIS who are known as Immigration Information Officers, Contact Representatives, or Investigative Assistants. (Sec. 517) Directs the Secretary to research, develop, and procure new technologies to inspect and screen air cargo carried on passenger aircraft at the earliest date possible. Requires existing checked baggage explosive detection equipment and screeners to be used to screen air cargo carried on such aircraft to the greatest extent practicable at each airport until the new technologies are available. Requires TSA to report to the Appropriations Committees on air cargo inspection statistics by airport and air carrier.(Sec. 525) Requires: (1) FEMA to submit a quarterly report to the Appropriations Committees detailing the allocation and obligation of funds for disaster relief; and (2) the Secretary, at least quarterly, to obtain and report to those committees on actual obligation and expenditure data of agencies performing mission assignments.(Sec. 530) Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to extend the date for implementation of the Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative.(Sec. 531) Amends the DHS Appropriations Act, 2007 to allow a state or political subdivision to adopt or enforce a regulation, requirement, or standard of performance regarding chemical facility security that is more stringent than the federal standard, unless there is an actual conflict.(Sec. 534) Permits the transfer of specified funds from prior year balances currently available to TSA for the Secure Flight program.(Sec. 535) Provides specified disaster assistance for schools damaged by Hurricanes Katrina and Rita.</summary>
</bill>
