<bill session="109" type="h" number="5861" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-25T14:52:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-25T14:52:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Historic Preservation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Historic Preservation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Historic Preservation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Historic Preservation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T20:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-641.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-06T20:41:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="381">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 381.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6945-6946" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5861.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-25T14:52:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6945-6946" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2006--Passed House amended.
National Historic Preservation Act Amendments of 2006 - Amends the National Historic Preservation Act (NHPA) to prohibit a State Historic Preservation Officer from having any authority to require an applicant for federal assistance, permit, or license to identify historic properties outside the undertaking's area of potential effects. Declares that, if the State Historic Preservation Officer, Tribal representative, or Tribal Historic Preservation Officer fails to respond within 30 days after an adequately documented finding of either "no historic properties affected" or "no adverse effect," the federal agency may assume that the State Historic Preservation Officer or Tribal Historic Preservation Officer has no objection to the finding. Specifies additional criteria for certification of local governments to implement the NHPA. Extends through FY2015 the period of funding for the Historic Preservation Fund. Expands: (1) from five to eight the number of federal agencies on the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation (Council); and (2) from nine to eleven the number of Council members constituting a quorum. Permits the Governor serving on the Council to designate a substitute to serve in such Governor's capacity on the Council. Grants the Council discretion to reach an agreement with any federal agency other than the Department of the Interior, or with a private entity, to provide the Council with financial and administrative services. Authorizes the Council to enter into cooperative agreements with any federal agency that administers a grant or assistance program for the purpose of improving the effectiveness of program administration. Permits such cooperative agreements to: (1) modify the selection criteria for a grant or assistance program to further NHPA purposes; or (2) allow the Council to participate in the selection of recipients. Authorizes the Council to: (1) review the operation of any federal grant or assistance program to evaluate its effectiveness in meeting NHPA purposes and policies; (2) make recommendations to the head of the federal agency that administers such program to further the consistency of the program with NHPA purposes and policies and to improve its effectiveness in carrying out such purposes and policies; and (3) make recommendations to the President and Congress regarding the effectiveness of federal grant and assistance programs in meeting those purposes and policies, including recommendations with regard to appropriate funding levels.</summary>
</bill>
