<bill session="109" type="h" number="28" updated="2013-07-19T19:04:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-26T14:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-26T14:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">High-Performance Computing Revitalization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">High-Performance Computing Revitalization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">High-Performance Computing Revitalization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the High-Performance Computing Act of 1991.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2005-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E26"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 109-36.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-04-12T19:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="17">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 17.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26T14:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Biggert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26T14:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2483-2487" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26T14:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-04-26T14:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2483-2484" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Mathematical models"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Pollution"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space sciences"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2005--Passed House amended.
High-Performance Computing Revitalization Act of 2005 - Amends the High-performance Computing Act of 1991 to direct the President to implement a High-performance Computing Research and Development Program (current law provides for a National High-performance Computing Program) and revise program requirements. Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to: (1) establish the goals and priorities for Federal high-performance computing research, development, networking, and other activities; (2) establish Program Component Areas that implement such goals and identify the Grand Challenges (i.e., fundamental problems in science or engineering, with broad economic and scientific impact, whose solutions will require the application of high-performance computing resources) that the Program should address; and (3) develop and maintain a research, development, and deployment road map for the provision of high-performance computing systems. Revises requirements for annual reports by requiring that such reports: (1) describe Program Component Areas, including any changes in the definition of or activities under such Areas and the reasons for such changes, and describe Grand Challenges supported under the Program; (2) describe the levels of Federal funding and the levels proposed for each Program Component Area; (3) describe the levels of Federal funding for each agency and department participating in the Program for each such Area; and (4) include an analysis of the extent to which the Program incorporates the recommendations of the advisory committee on high-performance computing. Eliminates the requirement that such reports include reports from the Secretary of Energy on Department of Energy activities taken to carry out the National High-performance Computing Program. Requires such advisory committee to: (1) provide the Director with an independent assessment of the balance between components of the Program, including funding levels for the Program Component Areas and whether the research and development undertaken pursuant to the Program is helping to maintain U.S. leadership in high-performance computing and networking; and (2) conduct periodic evaluations of the funding, management, coordination, implementation, and activities of the Program, and report at least once every two fiscal years to specified congressional committees. Requires the Office of Management and Budget to identify each element of its high-performance computing activities which contributes directly to the Program Component Areas or benefits from the Program. Repeals requirements under the Act for the National Research and Education Network and the Next Generation Internet. Modifies provisions regarding responsibilities of the National Science Foundation (NSF), the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Department of Energy (DOE), the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</summary>
</bill>
