<bill session="112" type="s" number="972" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Construction Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, to establish procedures to advance the use of cleaner construction equipment on Federal-aid highway and public transportation construction projects, to make the acquisition and installation of emission control technology an eligible expense in carrying out such projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3122"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Clean Construction Act of 2011 - Requires all off-road diesel equipment and on-road diesel equipment operating for at least 80 hours over the life of a federal-aid highway construction project or public transportation construction project within a PM2.5 nonattainment or maintenance area to have diesel emission control technology installed. Applies the same requirement to all covered equipment used on a covered public transportation construction project within a PM2.5 nonattainment or maintenance area. Defines: (1) "off-road diesel equipment" as a vehicle (including covered equipment) that is powered by a nonroad diesel engine of at least 50 horsepower and not intended for highway use; and (2) "on-road diesel equipment" as any self-propelled vehicle that operates on diesel fuel, is designed to transport persons or property on a street or highway, and has a gross vehicle weight of at least 14,000 pounds. Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to approve as part of the federal share of cost of a federal-aid highway construction project or public transportation construction project an amount equal to the state expenditure for acquiring and installing diesel emission control technology, if the state expenditure meets certain criteria.</summary>
</bill>
