<bill session="111" type="h" number="4762" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Pay Cut for Debt Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the pay of Members of Congress and dedicate the annual savings to a reduction of the national debt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E309"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4761"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5146"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5927"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3158"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2010--Introduced.
Congressional Pay Cut for Debt Reduction Act - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to: (1) reduce the annual salary of Members of Congress to 90% of the mandatory rate determined for such positions; and (2) eliminate automatic pay adjustments for Members of Congress. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, as soon as practicable after the beginning of each fiscal year, to: (1) calculate the reduction in outlays expected to occur during the fiscal year as a result of the application of the amendments made by this Act; and (2) transfer an equivalent amount to a specified account in the Treasury to reduce the public debt.</summary>
</bill>
