<bill session="112" type="h" number="5927" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Interior to carry out projects and conduct research on water resources in the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin, to establish a Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412319"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1011-1012"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2012--Introduced.
Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Act of 2012 - Directs the President to: (1) establish the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission, in cooperation with the governors of the states included in the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin (New York, New Jersey, Vermont, Massachusetts, and Connecticut), to coordinate activities being undertaken by the states, advisory committees, local governments, institutions of higher education, and nongovernmental organizations to address environmental, economic, and cultural issues associated with the management and use of resources in the Hudson-Mohawk Watershed; and (2) designate the Secretary of the Interior to serve as a member of the Commission and as coordinator of participation of relevant federal agencies in the Commission's activities. Requires the Commission to: (1) develop and implement plans, policies, and projects relating to the Basin's water resources; (2) adopt and promote uniform and coordinated policies for management and conservation of such resources; (3) coordinate and direct the development, implementation, operation, and financing of water resources projects consistent with its plans and policies; and (4) develop and adopt a comprehensive plan for the development and use of such resources, which shall address all projects and facilities required for development, conservation, use, management, and control of the Basin's water resources to meet present and future needs. Directs the Commission to adopt a water resources program on an annual basis, based upon the comprehensive plan, that identifies specific projects and facilities to be undertaken during the immediate five-year period.</summary>
</bill>
