<bill session="112" type="h" number="4238" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TBI Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Traumatic Brain Injury Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize certain programs for individuals with traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2012-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2012-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2012--Introduced.
Traumatic Brain Injury Act of 2012 or TBI Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize through FY2020 Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) projects for the prevention of traumatic brain injury (TBI). Adds recognition of and response to TBI within the scope of such projects. Extends until three years after the enactment of this Act the due date of a report from the Secretary on federal agency collaboration for collecting and disseminating studies on the incidence and prevalence of individuals with TBI who were formerly in the military and the treatment, prevention, and outreach provided to such individuals. Adds additional federal consultation requirements with respect to an HHS TBI study. Extends such study's report requirement. Authorizes appropriations for FY2013-FY2017 for HHS TBI projects. Allows state advisory boards established to recommend ways to improve services coordination regarding TBI to include state entities that administer funds provided to individuals with disabilities. Extends related demonstration projects. Directs the Secretary to establish and implement a national plan for carrying out activities regarding TBI in collaboration with other appropriate federal, state, and local agencies. Extends through FY2017 the authorization for such activities. Provides for the distribution and amount of grants for such activities for FY2013 and thereafter. Removes the requirement that a TBI protection and advocacy system, for which grant funds are provided by the Secretary, serve only one state. Requires the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and the Commissioner of the Administration on Developmental Disabilities to create a uniform model format for annual reports submitted by such systems. Extends through FY2017 the authorization for such systems. Requires in a current HHS program on basic and clinical trauma research the inclusion of studies specific to the needs of children and youth with TBI. Extends such program through FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
