<bill session="110" type="h" number="7178" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Servicemembers Access to Justice Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the enforcement of the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2008--Introduced.
Servicemembers Access to Justice Act of 2008 - Waives a state's sovereign immunity with respect to the enforcement of uniformed services members' employment or reemployment rights or benefits under the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 1994 (USERRA). Makes unenforceable agreements between an employer and employee requiring arbitration of disputes arising under USERRA. Provides exceptions. Requires the validity and enforceability of such an agreement to be determined by a court (as opposed to the arbitrator). Provides increased liquidated damages, and authorizes punitive damages, against state or private employer violations of USERRA. Provides a right to a jury trial in such cases. Requires (current law authorizes) the award of attorney fees in actions to enforce USERRA. Defines "successor in interest" for USERRA purposes. Prohibits: (1) any statute of limitations from applying to USERRA proceedings; and (2) wage discrimination against members covered under USERRA. Requires (current law authorizes) a court to use equitable relief, including injunctions and restraining orders when appropriate, for USERRA violations.</summary>
</bill>
