<bill session="111" type="s" number="921" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Information and Communications Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">U.S. ICE Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, to recognize the interconnected nature of the Internet and agency networks, improve situational awareness of Government cyberspace, enhance information security of the Federal Government, unify policies, procedures, and guidelines for securing information systems and national security systems, establish security standards for Government purchased products and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4818"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4824-4828" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4900"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2009--Introduced.
United States Information and Communications Enhancement Act of 2009 or the U.S. ICE Act of 2009 - Replaces two subchapters of federal law on information security with provisions to establish in the Executive Office of the President the National Office for Cyberspace (Office) to serve as the principal office for coordinating an assured, reliable, secure, and survivable global information and communications infrastructure and related capabilities. Requires the Office's director to develop and implement a comprehensive national cyberspace strategy. Authorizes the Office, not withstanding any provision of law or policy, to direct the sponsorship of security clearances for federal officers and employees whose responsibilities involve critical national security infrastructure. Requires the Office to: (1) oversee the implementation of policies, standards, and guidelines on information security; and (2) require agencies to identify and provide appropriate information security protections. Makes the head of each agency responsible for providing appropriate information security protections. Requires each agency to have an annual independent information security effectiveness evaluation. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to prescribe guidelines and compulsory standards for information systems, including national security systems. Allows the President to disapprove or change the guidelines and standards. Allows the Office and the head of an agency to use more stringent standards. Requires each agency to coordinate with the United States Computer Emergency Readiness Team (US-CERT). Allows US-CERT's director, notwithstanding any law or policy, to direct the sponsorship of the security clearances for federal officers and employees whose responsibilities involve critical national security infrastructure. Requires the components of each executive branch department or agency (except the Department of Defense or any such component performing any national security function) to establish an automated reporting mechanism allowing its chief information security officer and security operations center at the agency level to implement and monitor the component's security policies, procedures, and controls.</summary>
</bill>
