<bill session="113" type="h" number="3136" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Competency-Based Education Demonstration Project Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a demonstration program for competency-based education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2013--Introduced.
Advancing Competency-Based Education Demonstration Project Act of 2013 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to select institutions of higher education (IHEs) for voluntary participation in Competency-Based Education Demonstration Programs that provide participating IHEs with the ability to offer competency-based education that does not meet certain statutory and regulatory requirements that would otherwise prevent them from participating in federal student aid programs. Defines "competency-based education" as an education process that is characterized by the direct assessment and measurement of student learning instead of, or in addition to, measuring students' credit or clock hours. Deems IHEs to be eligible to participate in a Program if they are eligible to participate in title IV programs or have been approved by the Secretary to offer programs that measure student learning through direct assessments rather than credit or clock hours. Requires Program applicants to provide the Secretary with a description of the statutory and regulatory requirements they would like waived and the reasons for seeking each waiver. Directs the Secretary to conduct an annual evaluation of each of the up to 20 Programs authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
