<bill session="111" type="s" number="2838" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Health Access and Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to give critical access hospitals priority in receiving grants to implement health information technology, to expand participation in the drug pricing agreement program under section 340B of the Public Health Service Act, to provide for a study and report on pharmacy dispensing fees under Medicaid, to provide for continuing funding for operation of State offices of rural health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2009--Introduced.
Rural Health Access and Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to give priority to critical access hospitals in awarding grants to facilitate and expand the electronic movement and use of health information among organizations according to nationally recognized standards. Expands the 340B drug discount program to allow participation as a covered entity by certain children's hospitals, critical access hospitals, rural referral centers, sole community hospitals, and rural health clinics. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report on the cost in each state of dispensing prescription drugs under the Medicaid program. Requires states to use the report to assess the adequacy of Medicaid pharmacy dispensing fees. Repeals provisions terminating the grant program for the operation of state offices of rural health.</summary>
</bill>
