<bill session="111" type="h" number="2865" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arctic Marine Shipping Assessment Implementation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure safe, secure, and reliable marine shipping in the Arctic including the availability of aids to navigation, vessel escorts, spill response capability, and maritime search and rescue in the Arctic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5770"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1514"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1514"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Denmark"/>
    <term name="Iceland"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Norway"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2009--Introduced.
Arctic Marine Shipping Assessment Implementation Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to work through the International Maritime Organization to establish agreements to promote coordinated action among the United States, Russia, Canada, Iceland, Norway, and Denmark and other seafaring and Arctic nations to ensure in the Arctic: (1) placement and maintenance of aids to navigation; (2) appropriate icebreaking escort, tug, and salvage capabilities; (3) oil spill prevention and response capability; (4) maritime domain awareness, including long-range vessel tracking; and (5) search and rescue. Directs the Committee on the Maritime Transportation System to coordinate the establishment of domestic transportation policies in the Arctic necessary to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations, to enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements with, or make grants to, individuals and governments to carry out this Act or any agreements. Directs the Secretary to promote safe commercial maritime navigation by means of icebreaking when necessary. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into such agreements or contracts with, or make such grants to, individuals to conduct demonstration projects to reduce emissions or discharges from vessels operating in the Arctic.</summary>
</bill>
