<bill session="109" type="s" number="620" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Assault Weapons Ban Reauthorization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reinstate the Public Safety and Recreational Firearms Use Protection Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2005-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2654-2655"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="645"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Assault weapons"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2005--Introduced.
Assault Weapons Ban Reauthorization Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal criminal code to reinstate, for ten years, the Public Safety and Recreational Firearms Use Protection Act's assault weapons ban to prohibit the manufacture, transfer, or possession of a semiautomatic assault weapon or a large capacity ammunition feeding device. Specifies models and features of banned weapons. Sets forth exceptions to such ban, including: (1) firearms or devices lawfully possessed under Federal law on the date of enactment of this Act; (2) certain firearms, replicas, or duplicates listed in an appendix as they were manufactured on October 1, 1993; (3) any firearm that is manually operated by bolt, pump, lever, or slide action and that has been rendered permanently inoperable or that is an antique firearm; (4) any semiautomatic rifle that cannot accept a detachable magazine that holds more than five rounds of ammunition; (5) any semiautomatic shotgun that cannot hold more than five rounds in a fixed or detachable magazine; and (6) firearms manufactured for, transferred to, or possessed by a Federal, State, or local government agency or for law enforcement. Requires the serial number of any weapon or device manufactured after enactment of this Act to clearly show the date of manufacture. Directs the Attorney General to study and report to Congress on the effects of this Act on violent and drug trafficking crime.</summary>
</bill>
