<bill session="110" type="s" number="3127" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Select Agent Program and Biosafety Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Select Agent Program by amending the Public Health Service Act and the Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act of 2002 and to improve oversight of high containment laboratories.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Smallpox"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Virus diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2008--Introduced.
Select Agent Program and Biosafety Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act and the Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act of 2002 to reauthorize appropriations for the Select Agent Program, which lists and controls biological agents and toxins that have the potential to pose a severe threat to public health and safety. Requires appropriate training of individuals handling or using such agents and toxins.Includes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) among the federal agencies limited in the disclosure of information related to listed agents or toxins.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review and make recommendations for improving the Select Agent Program.Sets forth additional factors that the Secretary must consider in determining whether to list an agent or toxin, including whether the agent or toxin is endemic to the United States.Requires the Secretary to issue guidance on inventorying and monitoring listed biological agents.Directs the Attorney General to issue guidance regarding the scope of the statutory definition of "variola virus." Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop guidelines for how laboratories and laboratory personnel that do not regularly test for listed agents and toxins may be rapidly accessed and utilized during emergencies; and (2) evaluate national needs of, and oversight of, high containment biological laboratories.Provides for the development of minimum standards for laboratory biosafety and biosecurity training for relevant personnel of high containment biological laboratories.Requires the Secretary to establish a Biological Laboratory Incident Reporting System.</summary>
</bill>
