<bill session="110" type="h" number="5648" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Wildland Fire Response Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to establish a Federal wildland fire emergency suppression fund to facilitate accountable fire suppression activities by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to unanticipated large fire events, to encourage enhanced management efficiencies and cost controls of wildland fire suppression, and to reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfire to communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2008-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2008-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2008-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E415-416"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2008--Introduced.
Emergency Wildland Fire Response Act of 2008 - Establishes a Federal Wildland Fire Emergency Suppression Fund to cover the costs of federal wildland fire suppression activities associated with a declared emergency wildland fire incident. Sets forth the criteria for which declarations of emergency wildland fire incidents may be made under this Act. Requires a declaration of such an incident to only be made by the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, or a designee of the Secretary concerned at the subcabinet level. Allows the Secretary concerned to only access the Fund if the President's annual budget requested funds for wildland fire operations amounting to at least the ten-fiscal year average of expenditures for wildland fire operations. Requires the Secretaries to jointly report every six months on expenditures from and deposits to the Fund. Permits any excess funds for wildland fire operations to be transferred to support reforestation and rehabilitation of forests following wildland fires. Limits the areas in which such funds may be expended. Requires review of wildfire incidents resulting in expenses greater than $10 million. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a national map of landscape areas most at risk of wildfire and in need of hazardous fuel treatment and maintenance. Authorizes such Secretary to: (1) provide cost-share grants to fire-ready communities to increase their capacity to defend against wildland fire; and (2) enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with a State Forester or equivalent official to implement good neighbor projects on such lands.</summary>
</bill>
