<bill session="113" type="s" number="1005" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conservation Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish more efficient and effective policies and processes for departments and agencies engaged in or providing support to, international conservation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2935"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
Conservation Reform Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of State to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study of, and report to Congress on, U.S. international conservation programs to determine the extent to which such programs are: (1) advancing conservation in the world's most ecologically and economically important terrestrial and marine ecosystems; (2) addressing natural resource challenges; (3) advancing U.S. foreign policy priorities in areas such as security, democratization, sustainable food production, and clean water; (4) enhancing economic and wildlife conservation benefits derived from properly managed international hunting and angling tourism; and (5) addressing poaching, illegal logging, fishing, and wildlife trafficking. Directs the President: (1) to establish the Interagency Working Group on Global Conservation; and (2) through such Working Group, to establish the International Conservation Strategy to strengthen the capacity of the United States to collaborate with other countries, international organizations, the private sector, and private voluntary organizations to conserve natural resources and enhance biodiversity. Requires: (1) the Strategy to provide a comprehensive plan of action that identifies specific and measurable benchmarks, goals, and time frames; and (2) the Working Group to ensure that the Strategy is appropriate to local needs and conditions and incorporates the views of partner countries. Establishes the International Conservation Public Advisory Board to: (1) advise the Working Group on matters related to U.S. international conservation policies and programs and the implementation of the Strategy; and (2) ensure that the best scientific, policy, economic security, and business expertise are reflected in U.S. international conservation strategies and policies. Prohibits any provision in this Act from being construed as restricting, limiting, or otherwise impairing: (1) properly managed recreational hunting and angling, or (2) the ability of any foreign jurisdiction or authority to authorize regulated programs supporting wildlife for local consumption and commercialization. Urges the President to work with foreign assistance donor countries to: (1) develop a comprehensive international conservation assistance strategy consistent with the United States International Conservation Strategy, (2) identify multilateral mechanisms to coordinate international action, and (3) agree on a timetable for achieving the goals of the United States International Conservation Strategy.</summary>
</bill>
