<bill session="110" type="h" number="3971" updated="2013-07-19T21:38:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-23T15:00:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-01-23T15:00:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage States to report to the Attorney General certain information regarding the deaths of individuals in the custody of law enforcement agencies.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To encourage States to report to the Attorney General certain information regarding the deaths of individuals in the custody of law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400364"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-01-18T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-512.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-01-18T10:32:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="313">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 313.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T14:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Scott (VA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T14:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H428-431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T14:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3971.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-01-23T15:00:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H428" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T15:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1087">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1087.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2908"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7227"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2008 - Requires states that receive criminal justice assistance grants under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to report to the Attorney General on a quarterly basis information on the death of any person who is detained, under arrest, or incarcerated in a municipal or county jail, state prison, state-run boot camp, contract facility, or other state or local correctional facility (including any juvenile facility). Requires such information to include: (1) the name, gender, race, ethnicity, and age of the deceased; (2) the date, time, and location of death; (3) the law enforcement agency that detained or arrested the deceased; and (4) a description of the circumstances surrounding the death. Grants states 120 days from the enactment of this Act to comply with such reporting requirements. Permits the Attorney General to grant additional time to states to comply with reporting requirements and to waive such requirements in states where compliance would be unconstitutional.Grants the Attorney General discretion to reduce by up to 10% the amount of the criminal justice assistance grants of states that fail to comply with the reporting requirements of this Act. Requires the Attorney General to collect information and provide for a study on the deaths of persons held in custody and to report to Congress on the findings within two years after the enactment of this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
