<bill session="110" type="h" number="6006" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of a military department, and the Secretary of Defense with respect to the Defense Agencies, to participate in conservation banking programs and in-lieu-fee mitigation programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land banking"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2008--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of a military department, and the Secretary of Defense for a Defense Agency, when engaged or proposing to engage in military testing, operations, training, or another military readiness activity or military construction that may or will result in an adverse impact to one or more species protected (or pending protection) under any applicable provision of law, or habitat for such species, to make payments to a conservation banking program or "in-lieu-fee" mitigation sponsor approved in accordance with the Federal Guidance for the Establishment, Use and Operation of Mitigation Banks, the Guidance for the Establishment, Use, and Operation of Conservation Banks or any successor or related administrative guidance or regulation. Allows such payments to a conservation banking program or "in-lieu-fee" mitigation sponsor for military construction to be treated as eligible costs of the construction project.</summary>
</bill>
