<bill session="111" type="s" number="3010" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Flight 3407 Memorial Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Federal Aviation Administration to implement the recommendations issued by the National Transportation Safety Board following the Board's investigation of the loss of control of Colgan Air Flight 3407 on February 12, 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2010--Introduced.
Flight 3407 Memorial Act - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to implement the recommendations of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) contained in the Aircraft Accident Report on the Loss of Control on Approach of Colgan Air, Incorporated, Operating as Continental Connections Flight 3407 at Clarence Center, New York, on February 12, 2009 (NTSB/AAR-10-01). Requires the FAA Administrator, within 180 days after the NTSB makes a safety recommendation to the Administrator, to notify Congress: (1) whether or not the Administrator has determined to implement it; and (2) what actions the Administrator plans to take to implement it, or what reasons the Administrator has for not doing so. Requires the Administrator, within 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to send Congress such a notification with respect to each NTSB recommendation made before the enactment of this Act which has not been implemented.</summary>
</bill>
