<bill session="109" type="h" number="6272" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Emergency and Enforcement Authority Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide additional emergency and enhanced enforcement authority to the Securities and Exchange Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Enhanced Emergency and Enforcement Authority Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to empower the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to reduce, eliminate, or prevent substantial disruption by an emergency of the ability of market participants to conduct securities activities or comply with obligations under the securities laws in a timely, orderly, or efficient manner. Amends the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, and the Investment Company Act of 1940 to provide that, in any action or proceeding instituted by the SEC in federal district court for any judicial district, subpoenas issued by or on behalf of such court to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documents or tangible things (or both) may be served in any other district (thus granting the SEC nationwide service of process).</summary>
</bill>
