<bill session="110" type="s" number="2669" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Green Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the implementation of a Green Chemistry Research and Development Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2850"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Chemical engineering"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemical research"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Chemists"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Green products"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial costs"/>
    <term name="Industrial engineering"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Industry-university relations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal research"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Social science research"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2008--Introduced.
Green Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2008 - Directs the President to establish a Green Chemistry Research and Development Program to promote and coordinate federal research, development, education, and technology transfer activities related to green chemistry. Defines "green chemistry" as chemistry and chemical engineering to design chemical products and processes that reduce or eliminate the use or generation of hazardous substances while producing high quality products through safe and efficient manufacturing processes. Requires the President to establish an Interagency Working Group to oversee the planning, management, and coordination of the Program. Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to provide for the Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology to enhance productivity and technological performance in U.S. manufacturing through the enabling of supply chain manufacturers to continuously make improvements with the aim of reducing or eliminating the use or generation of hazardous substances. Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation to carry out a program to award grants to institutions of higher education to support their efforts to revise their undergraduate curriculum in chemistry and chemical engineering to incorporate green chemistry concepts and strategies. Requires such Director to enter into an arrangement with the National Research Council to conduct a study of, and report on, the factors that constitute barriers to the successful commercial application of promising results from green chemistry research and development. Directs the agencies participating in the Program to carry out a joint, coordinated program to award grants to institutions of higher education to establish partnerships with companies in the chemical industry to retrain chemists and chemical engineers in the use of green chemistry concepts and strategies.</summary>
</bill>
