<bill session="111" type="h" number="5467" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Turning Around Low-Performing Public High Schools Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to award contracts to nonprofit organizations with national experience that enter into partnerships with local educational agencies to turn around low-performing public high schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/2010--Introduced.
Turning Around Low-Performing Public High Schools Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award five-year contracts to nonprofit school district partnership organizations that: (1) have a record of success in improving the secondary school graduation and postsecondary attendance and completion rates of disadvantaged students; and (2) partner with local educational agencies (LEAs) that serve a substantial number or percentage of disadvantaged students to implement comprehensive high school turnaround models that are customized to meet the needs of the LEAs and their schools. Requires such models to include: (1) a college preparatory instructional program; (2) a student support structure that provides students with a caring, safe, and supportive learning environment; (3) a staffing structure that creates strong, long-term connections between students and teachers; (4) standards of professional practice that guide the professional development of school personnel and build their sense of collective responsibility for student and school outcomes; (5) an extended day and extended school year that supports challenging, college-preparatory curricula; (6) an expectation that parents will take an active role in school activities; and (7) the use of multiple mechanisms to assess schools' organizational and program effectiveness. Directs: (1) the Secretary to select an independent entity to conduct a triennial evaluation of the performance of students who attend turnaround schools; and (2) school district partnership organizations to report annually on the implementation of comprehensive high school turnaround models and student achievement in partner schools. Requires copies of such evaluations and reports to be provided to the Secretary and Congress.</summary>
</bill>
