<bill session="109" type="h" number="6366" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CTR Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend sections 5313 and 5318 of title 31, United States Code, to reform certain requirements for reporting cash transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2006--Introduced.
CTR Modernization Act - Amends federal law governing mandatory reports on currency transactions to exempt depository institutions from the requirement that all domestic financial institutions file a report on every domestic coin and currency transaction. Requires such a depository institution to file a currency transaction report, however, if the transaction involves at least $30,000. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury after a certain date from requiring a depository institution to file a currency transaction report regarding a transaction of less than $30,000. Directs the Secretary to: (1) review at least every five years the threshold for reporting currency transactions; and (2) adjust the threshold amount for inflation. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations that exempt any depository institution from reporting a currency transaction with a qualified customer. Defines qualified customer as any person that: (1) is incorporated or organized under federal or state law, or registered and eligible to do business within the United States or a state; (2) has maintained a deposit account with the depository institution for at least 12 months; and (3) has engaged, using such account, in multiple currency transactions subject to reporting requirements. Requires the Secretary to prescribe regulations that: (1) provide guidance on identifying currency transactions involving illegal or suspicious activities; and (2) create a list of information that may be disclosed to customers before the reporting of suspicious activity.</summary>
</bill>
