<bill session="112" type="h" number="3549" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Blind Trust Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require Members of Congress to place their stocks, bonds, commodities futures, and other forms of securities in a blind trust.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412488" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3550"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2011--Introduced.
Congressional Blind Trust Act of 2011 - Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require each Member of Congress to place all of his or her stocks, bonds, commodities futures, and other forms of securities, including securities held jointly with a spouse, in a qualified blind trust. Exempts from such requirement any financial interests in or income derived from: (1) the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), including the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP); (2) any other federal retirement system for U.S. officers and employees, including the President, or for members of the uniformed services; or (3) benefits received under the Social Security Act. Requires new Members to comply with this Act within 30 days after taking office, and incumbent Members within 30 days after enactment of this Act. Allows a Member to file, as appropriate, with the Clerk of the House of Representative or the Secretary of the Senate for an additional 30-day extension in order to comply. Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action against any Member of Congress for noncompliance.</summary>
</bill>
