<bill session="109" type="h" number="4103" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Advantage and Prescription Drug Accountability Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for improved accountability in the Medicare Advantage and prescription drug programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2005-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2005--Introduced.
Medicare Advantage and Prescription Drug Accountability Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require the contract with an Medicare Advantage (MA) organization to provide for a minimum loss ratio (aggregate average benefits that are at least a minimum ratio of the aggregate average revenues collected under the contract) and a maximum administrative cost ratio (aggregate average administrative costs that do not exceed a maximum ratio of the aggregate average revenues collected under the contract). Requires each contract with a Medicare+Choice organization to grant the Secretary of Health and Human Services the right to audit and inspect any books and records of the organization for compliance with such ratio and related administrative cost requirements. Applies such requirements to contracts with prescription drug sponsors under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program). Prescribes requirements for financial transparency of MA plans. Renders an election to enroll with an MA plan ineffective unless the election form is signed by the individual and specifically acknowledges specified plan features. Applies such requirements to prescription drug plans under Medicare part D. Directs the Secretary to transmit to Congress annual MA accountability and prescription drug accountability reports. Requires periodic audits by the departmental Inspector General of the Secretary's determinations about the acturial equivalency of MA plans. Requires each prescription drug plan sponsor with respect to a prescription drug plan, and each MA organization with respect to an MA-PD plan, to report annually to the Inspector General on drug claims rejections and reversals on appeal. Directs the Secretary to appoint a Medicare prescription drug ombudsman.</summary>
</bill>
