<bill session="112" type="h" number="3650" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Zero Tolerance of Child Sexual Abuse Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit institutions of higher education and nonprofit organizations that fail to report incidents of sexual abuse of a minor from receiving Federal funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8914"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2011--Introduced.
Federal Zero Tolerance of Child Sexual Abuse Act of 2011 - Prohibits the provision of federal funding to nonprofit organizations that deal with children and to institutions of higher education if the Attorney General determines that an officer or employee of such entity has failed to report known or suspected incidents of child sexual abuse to law enforcement. Excepts federal student financial aid from that prohibition. Sets the duration of the funding prohibition at from one to five years. Allows the Attorney General to reduce the duration of the prohibition or eliminate it altogether if there is good cause for taking such action and the nonprofit organization or school is enforcing policies to comply with this Act's reporting requirements. Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require states receiving grants for child abuse or neglect prevention and treatment to require individuals employed in any position that involves direct contact with children to report known and suspected instances of child abuse and neglect.</summary>
</bill>
