<bill session="113" type="h" number="1718" updated="2013-11-02T06:33:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Postal Service Shipping Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, and title 39, United States Code, to provide the United States Postal Service the authority to mail wine and beer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="630"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="316"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2013--Introduced.
United States Postal Service Shipping Equity Act - Authorizes the mailing of wine or malt beverages by licensed wineries or breweries in accordance with the law of the state, territory, or district of the United States where the addressee or duly authorized agent takes delivery. Directs the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) to prescribe regulations: (1) requiring such mailing to be through a means established by the USPS to ensure direct delivery to the addressee or a duly authorized agent at a postal facility; (2) requiring the addressee and any agent to be at least 21 years of age and to present a valid, government-issued photo identification at the time of delivery; (3) prohibiting such wine or malt beverages from being for resale or any other commercial purpose; and (4) requiring such wineries or breweries to certify that the mailing is not in violation of applicable laws or USPS regulations and to provide other information as directed by the USPS, including with respect to the prepayment of state alcohol beverage taxes. Revises the federal criminal code to allow for the mailing of wine and malt beverages pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
