<bill session="111" type="hc" number="193" updated="2013-07-20T00:14:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the need to pass meaningful legislation to protect commercial and government data from data breaches.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412298" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that Congress should: (1) enact into law a meaningful national standard to protect commercial and government data, including a robust definition of encryption tied to the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST); and (2) adopt legislation that requires that sensitive data be protected through meaningful encryption technology and require government subcontractors having access to sensitive and personally identifiable information to comply with the same standards as federal agencies and departments; and (3) encourage leaders of government agencies and private enterprises to actively manage and rigorously protect the data collected and stored within their institution by making data security a priority within the institution.</summary>
</bill>
