<bill session="111" type="h" number="6013" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to increase plot allowances for certain veterans buried in Department of Veterans Affairs cemeteries or State cemeteries and to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide a plot allowance for spouses and children of certain veterans who are buried in State cemeteries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412264"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Increases from $300 to $500 the plot allowances for veterans who die in a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) hospital, nursing home, or domiciliary care facility and are buried in a national or state cemetery. Directs the Secretary to pay to a state or an agency or political subdivision thereof a plot allowance of $500 for each spouse and child of certain veterans who are eligible for interment in a national cemetery but are buried in a state cemetery. Directs the Secretary to annually adjust the $500 plot allowance by an amount equal to the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index. Prohibits any such adjustment with respect to FY2011.</summary>
</bill>
