<bill session="109" type="s" number="364" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a program within the National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration to integrate Federal coastal and ocean mapping activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2005-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1303"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1303-1305" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Stevens with amendments. With written report No. 109-102.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-07-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="161">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 161.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Submarine cables"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act - (Sec. 2) Directs the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish a program to develop, in coordination with the Interagency Committee on Ocean and Coastal Mapping (established by this Act), a coordinated and comprehensive federal ocean and coastal mapping plan for the Great Lakes and Coastal State waters, the territorial sea, the exclusive economic zone, and the continental shelf of the United States that enhances ecosystem approaches in decision-making for conservation and management of marine resources and habitats, establishes research priorities, supports the siting of research and other platforms, and advances ocean and coastal science. Prescribes program parameters. (Sec. 3) Establishes an Interagency Committee on Ocean and Coastal Mapping (Committee) comprising senior representatives from federal agencies with ocean and coastal mapping and surveying responsibilities, and chaired by the representative from the NOAA. (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator, in consultation with the Committee, to develop and submit to Congress a plan for an integrated ocean and coastal mapping initiative within NOAA that: (1) identifies all NOAA coastal and ocean mapping programs; (2) encourages the development of innovative coastal and ocean mapping technologies and applications through research and development (R&amp;D) cooperative agreements at joint institutes; and (3) documents available and developing technologies, best practices in data processing and distribution, and leveraging opportunities with other federal agencies, non-governmental organizations, and the private sector. Prescribes plan requirements. Authorizes the Administrator to operate up to three joint ocean and coastal mapping centers, including a joint hydrographic center, to serve as hydrographic centers of excellence and to conduct activities to implement this Act. Directs the Administrator to continue developing a strategy for expanding contracting with private entities in fulfilling NOAA's mapping and charting responsibilities and to report such strategy to Congress. (Sec. 5) Requires the Chairman of the Committee to report bi-annually to Congress on progress made in implementing the provisions of this Act. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-FY2013.</summary>
</bill>
