<bill session="111" type="s" number="1463" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center, to authorize grants for State organ and tissue donor registries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412328"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7643"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3071"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to establish a National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center, which shall: (1) advance the development, expansion, and evaluation of state organ and tissue donor registries; (2) facilitate timely access to, and the exchange of accurate donor information between, such registries; (3) ensure that registries funded through this Act comply with applicable requirements; (4) provide technical assistance to states for such registries; and (5) maintain a registry information clearinghouse to collect, synthesize, and disseminate best practices information. Requires the Secretary to award grants or cooperative agreements to states for the development, enhancement, expansion, and evaluation of organ and tissue donor registries. Sets forth requirements for registries, including that such registries: (1) allow a donor to include a statement or symbol that the donor has made, amended, or revoked an anatomical gift; (2) allow organ procurement organizations to access that information, at or near the donor's death; and (3) bar the use or disclosure of personally identifiable information for any other purpose without the donor's consent. Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the feasibility of establishing a living donor database to track health effects for donors associated with living organ donation.</summary>
</bill>
