<bill session="111" type="h" number="2868" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06T16:50:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-06T16:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Chemical and Water Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Drinking Water System Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Wastewater Treatment Works Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to extend, modify, and recodify the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to enhance security and protect against acts of terrorism against chemical facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance security and protect against acts of terrorism against chemical facilities, to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to enhance the security of public water systems, and to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to enhance the security of wastewater treatment works, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-13T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 111-205, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-13T19:18:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 31, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-13">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than July 31, 2009 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and the amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(k), rule x.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 30, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 30, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 23, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 23, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 10 .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 18.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 111-205, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-10-23T16:03:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="178">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 178.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03T17:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 885 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2868 with 1 hour and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The rule provides that in lieu of the amendments in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committees on Homeland Security and Energy and Commerce now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report to accompanying this rule shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 885 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 885.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12407-12426" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2868 with 1 hour and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The rule provides that in lieu of the amendments in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committees on Homeland Security and Energy and Commerce now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report to accompanying this rule shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 885 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T15:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jay Inslee to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T15:25:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with ninety minutes of general debate on H. R. 2868.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T17:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Johnson, E. B. moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T17:12:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05T17:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2868 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T13:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12498-12535" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T13:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T13:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thompson (MS) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T13:49:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Thompson (MS) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Barton (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T13:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Barton (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Barton (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Barton (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings (FL) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dent amendment number 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:24:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Dent amendment number 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Dent demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dent amendment number 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:38:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Dent amendment number 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Dent demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schrader amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCaul amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T15:03:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCaul amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McCaul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T15:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Halvorson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 885, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foster amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T15:18:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2868.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12498-12515" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Dent moved to recommit with instructions to Homeland Security.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12533-12534" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12533" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dent motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to insert a new paragraph which states that in implementing methods to reduce consequences of a terrorist attact on a chemical facility, such implementation must not significantly or demonstrably reduce the operations of the covered chemical facility or result in any net reduction in private sector employment when national unemployment is above 4 percent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12534" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:43:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 236 (Roll no. 874).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12534" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-11-06T16:50:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="875" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 230 - 193 (Roll no. 875).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T16:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2868.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-370.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="700">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 700.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="885"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3599"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h499"/>
    <amendment number="h500"/>
    <amendment number="h501"/>
    <amendment number="h502"/>
    <amendment number="h503"/>
    <amendment number="h504"/>
    <amendment number="h505"/>
    <amendment number="h506"/>
    <amendment number="h507"/>
    <amendment number="h508"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/16/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Continuing Chemical Facilities Antiterrorism Security Act of 2010 - Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 to extend for three years (until October 4, 2013) the authority of the the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to issue regulations establishing risk-based performance standards for the security of chemical facilities that require vulnerability assessments and the development and implementation of site security plans (Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards or CFATS). Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (HSA) to require the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) in coordination with the Under Secretary for National Protection and Programs, to: (1) establish a voluntary chemical security training program to enhance the capabilities of high-risk chemical facilities to prevent, prepare for, respond to, mitigate against, and recover from threatened or actual acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other man-made disasters; and (2) develop a voluntary chemical security exercise program to offer voluntary testing and evaluation of the capabilities of the federal government, state governments, commercial personnel and management, governmental and nongovernmental emergency response providers, and the private sector to prevent, prepare for, mitigate against, respond to, and recover from acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other emergencies at chemical facilities. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, to establish a voluntary technical assistance program to provide nonbinding assistance or recommendations to the owner of a covered chemical facility to: (1) reduce the risk or consequences associated with a successful terrorist attack on the facility; and (2) aid in compliance with the performance standards applicable to the facility under CFATS. Provides that the decision to participate or to implement any assistance or recommendations provided by the Secretary shall be at the sole discretion of the owner or operator. Requires the Secretary, upon request, to advise such owner or operator of the overall effect that implementing all categories of assistance or recommendations provided by the Secretary would have on the Secretary's determination regarding: (1) the placement of the facility in a risk-based tier under CFATS, or (2) whether the facility would no longer present a high level of security risk. Provides that no act or failure to act by the owner or operator relating to assistance or a recommendation provided by the Secretary shall be interpreted or applied to create any liability or cause of action for compensation that may result from a terrorist act or incident at the facility, with an exception for intervening acts or omissions. Directs the Secretary to develop a repository for information and data on best practices and cost-effective technologies for implementing CFATS and the voluntary technical assistance program. Provides for the protection of information that may reveal: (1) vulnerabilities or other details of the security capabilities of a covered facility that may be exploited by terrorists, and (2) trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is not customarily in the public domain. Directs the Secretary, by October 4, 2013, in coordination with a nine-member Chemical Facility Security Advisory Board established by this Act, to submit a report regarding lessons learned from the voluntary technical assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
