<bill session="112" type="h" number="912" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorectal Cancer Prevention, Early Detection, and Treatment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a national screening program at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States the option to increase screening in the United States population for the prevention, early detection, and timely treatment of colorectal cancer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2011-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2011-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="494"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2011--Introduced.
Colorectal Cancer Prevention, Early Detection, and Treatment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to make grants to states and Indian tribes to carry out programs to increase quality colorectal cancer screening. Requires such a program to include: (1) providing recommended colorectal cancer screening to individuals who are over 50 years of age or at high risk for such cancer; (2) providing case management and referrals for medical treatment; (3) ensuring the full continuum of follow-up and cancer care for individuals screened; (4) carrying out activities to improve the education, training, and skills of health professionals to ensure the use of evidence-based recommended and quality screening and follow-up in the prevention, detection, and control of colorectal cancer; and (5) developing and disseminating public information and education programs for the prevention, detection, and control of colorectal cancer and promoting the benefits of receiving screenings through this program. Gives priority to low-income individuals who lack adequate coverage under health insurance and health plans with respect to screenings for colorectal cancer. Allows the Secretary to provide training and technical assistance with respect to the planning, development, and operation of programs funded by a grant under this Act. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow states to provide medical assistance to individuals who have been screened for colorectal cancer under this Act and who need treatment for complications due to screening or colorectal cancer. Applies provisions related to breast and cervical cancer programs to programs under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
