<bill session="112" type="s" number="508" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Chimney Rock National Monument in the State of Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2011-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-124.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2621"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2011--Introduced.
Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act - Designates the Chimney Rock National Monument in Colorado to preserve, protect, and restore the cultural, historic, natural, educational, and scenic resources of Chimney Rock and adjacent land and to provide for public interpretation and recreation consistent with the protection of such resources. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make minor adjustments to the boundaries of the Monument to reflect the inclusion of significant archaeological resources discovered on adjacent National Forest System land. Permits only such uses of the Monument that would further the purposes specified above. Allows for continued use of the Monument by Indian tribes for traditional ceremonies and as a source of traditional plants and other materials. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out vegetation management treatments within the Monument, with the exception of timber harvesting which shall only be used when necessary for ecosystem restoration or the control of fire, insects, or diseases. Authorizes the construction of an education and interpretive center to interpret the Monument's scientific and cultural resources for the public. Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Monument.</summary>
</bill>
