<bill session="111" type="h" number="1462" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Study of Ways to Improve the Accuracy of the Collection of Federal Oil, Condensate, and Natural Gas Royalties Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a study by the National Academy of Engineering regarding improving the accuracy of collection of royalties on production of oil, condensate, and natural gas under leases of Federal lands and Indian lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E657-658"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Study of Ways to Improve the Accuracy of the Collection of Federal Oil, Condensate, and Natural Gas Royalties Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to arrange with the National Academy of Engineering to study and report to the Secretary regarding whether the accuracy of collection of royalties on production of oil, condensate, and natural gas under leases of federal lands (including submerged, deep water, and Indian lands) would be improved by implementing certain prescribed measures. Requires the Secretary to award a contract under which the contractor shall: (1) compare royalty payments made under federal oil and gas lease provisions for covered lands against data supplied to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC); (2) make such comparison retroactive to June 1, 1974; (3) determine whether the correct production standard volume and heating content analysis was used to calculate such payments; and (4) determine whether such payments were adequate under the terms of the oil and gas leases.</summary>
</bill>
