<bill session="110" type="h" number="4050" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Levee-Like Structure Consideration Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Levee-Like Structure Consideration Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to issue guidance providing a process for consideration of the flood protections afforded by certain structures for purposes of the national flood insurance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04T16:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-466.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-12-04T16:46:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="290">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 290.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2007--Reported to House without amendment.
Levee-Like Structure Consideration Act of 2007 - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to issue and make effective notice or guidance providing, for purposes of determining flood plain areas and flood-risk zones under the national flood insurance program: (1) a specified process by which a community may request and obtain from the Administrator a determination, including provisional accreditation, of the nature and extent of any flood protection afforded by any structure or feature that was recognized as having some mitigating effect on flood risk on the applicable flood insurance rate map in effect on January 1, 2003, but that does not meet federal requirements for recognition as a levee offering protection from the base flood for purposes of such program; and (2) that any flood protections so determined to be afforded by such structure or feature shall be recognized on and incorporated in updated flood insurance rate maps for any area whose flood risk is affected.</summary>
</bill>
