<bill session="111" type="s" number="539" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Renewable Energy and Economic Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to require the President to designate certain geographical areas as national renewable energy zones, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2838-2839"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2839-2845" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2009--Introduced.
Clean Renewable Energy and Economic Development Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to require the President to designate as national renewable energy zones areas that have: (1) the potential to generate in excess of one giawatt of electricity from renewable energy; (2) insufficient electric transmission capacity to achieve such potential; and (3) the capability to contain additional renewable energy generating facilities if there were a sufficient transmission capacity. Excludes specified areas from such zones, including national parks, wilderness areas, and historic sites. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the certification by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) of regional planning entities to coordinate planning efforts to integrate renewable energy resources from such zones into the interstate electric transmission grid and to make such resources fully deliverable to electricity consuming areas; (2) interconnection-wide green transmission grid project plans (grid project plans) and cost allocation plans; (3) the participation of specified federal transmitting utilities in the planning process; and (4) a federal transmission surcharge to generate revenue to enable entities and states to recover costs of planning activities. Authorizes FERC to issue construction permits, that may permit the acquisition of a necessary right-of-way through eminent domain, for interconnection-wide green transmission grid projects (projects) that meet specified conditions. Directs the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to make grants to states and planning entities that submit or implement grid project plans for specified activities. Requires the Bonneville Power Administration and the Western Area Power Administration (WAPA) to establish: (1) wind integration programs; and (2) a joint geothermal integration program. Requires each of the Federal Power Marketing Administrations and the Tennessee Valley Authority to establish a solar integration program. Requires: (1) federal transmitting utilities to undertake geographically diverse projects within their service territories to acquire and demonstrate electric and hybrid vehicles and related technologies as part of their fleets; and (2) the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army to study reregulating facilities and pumped storage units at federal dams. Authorizes WAPA to fund a wind-hydro or solar-hydro integration demonstration project. Sets forth provisions concerning the creation and development of solar energy reserves on federal land. Expands the purpose of incentive-based rate treatments for the transmission of electric energy by public utilities to include integrating renewable energy resources into the transmission system. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) increase the maximum amount the Secretary may accept for transmission investments in WAPA and the Southwestern Area Power Administration territories; and (2) revise provisions concerning the Federal Permit Streamlining Pilot Project, including requiring the Secretary of the Interior to designate Bureau of Land Management (BLM) field offices in specified states to serve as Renewable Energy Pilot Project Offices for coordination of federal permits for renewable energy projects and renewable energy transmission involving federal land.</summary>
</bill>
