<bill session="113" type="h" number="660" updated="2013-11-02T06:24:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to create a National Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium to provide grants and coordinate research with respect to the causes of, and risk factors associated with, neuromyelitis optica, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to establish, administer, and coordinate a National Neuromyelitis Optica (NMO) Consortium to: (1) award grants of not fewer than five years duration to conduct research with respect to the causes of, and the risk factors and biomarkers associated with, NMO (a neurological disease leading to blindness and paralysis); (2) assemble a panel of experts to provide ongoing guidance and the recommendations on research design and protocols, and (3) designate a central laboratory to collect, analyze, and aggregate data with respect to such research and to make such data and analysis available to researchers. Establishes eligibility requirements for a consortium (a partnership of two or more universities, health care organizations, or government agencies, or any combination of such entities), including that: (1) it has the capability to enroll a minimum of 25 individuals with a diagnosis of NMO as research participants from the designated catchment area (geographical area), and (2) that the catchment area does not overlap with any other consortium receiving a grant under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
