<bill session="113" type="s" number="245" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Communications Commission Collaboration Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to authorize a bipartisan majority of Commissioners of the Federal Communications Commission to hold nonpublic collaborative discussions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="539"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2013--Introduced.
Federal Communications Commission Collaboration Act of 2013 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to allow a bipartisan majority of Commissioners of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), notwithstanding a specified open meeting provision, to hold a meeting that is closed to the public to discuss official business if: (1) no agency action is taken, (2) each person present is an FCC Commissioner or employee or a member or person on the staff of a joint board to which the FCC has referred a matter under such Act, and (3) an attorney from the FCC's Office of General Counsel is present. Defines "bipartisan majority of Commissioners" as at least three Commissioners including at least one Commissioner for each political party of which any Commissioner is a member and at least one unaffiliated Commissioner if any Commissioner has no political affiliation. Requires public disclosure of the meeting, attendees, and matters discussed.</summary>
</bill>
