<bill session="112" type="h" number="1715" updated="2013-07-20T01:25:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Multilingual Services Accounting Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to end speculation on the current cost of multilingual services provided by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400643"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2011-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2012-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2011--Introduced.
Multilingual Services Accounting Act - Requires federal agency Chief Financial Officers to include multilingual services accounting information in their mandatory annual reports to the agency head and to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). Defines multilingual services to include: (1) services provided by interpreters hired by an agency; (2) services resulting in additional expenses which an agency provides to assist its employees or contractors to learn a non-English language; (3) agency preparation, translation, printing, or recordation of materials in a language other than English; and (4) services provided or performed for the federal government by agency employees or contractors that require speaking a non-English language that result in wage differentials or benefits provided by the agency. Requires the OMB Director's annual financial management status report to certain congressional committees to contain a Multilingual Services Expenses Report that includes: (1) a summary and analysis of the multilingual services accounting information prepared by each agency Chief Financial Officer, and (2) a description of any changes to the existing financial management structure of the federal government needed to establish an integrated individual agency accounting of all multilingual services conducted by each agency. Requires the OMB Director to issue guidance that an agency Chief Financial Officer must follow in compiling multilingual services accounting information.</summary>
</bill>
