<bill session="113" type="s" number="39" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Lifestyles and Prevention America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HeLP America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Saving Lives by Lowering Tobacco Use Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the health of Americans and reduce health care costs by reorienting the Nation's health care system toward prevention, wellness, and health promotion.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2179"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="531"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Healthy Lifestyles and Prevention America Act or HeLP America Act - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990, the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, the Public Health Service Act, and other specified health law to establish or expand programs for children's nutrition and physical activity in schools and with child care providers, expanding the free fresh fruit program, promoting equal opportunities for students with disabilities to participate in schools and colleges, revising the definition of "core academic subject" to include physical education, and including the promotion of healthy, active lifestyles by students within educational grant programs.Sets forth requirements to expand healthy activities in the community, permitting use of schools for recreational and nutritional purposes during nonschool hours, awarding grants for sports and athletic programs for individuals with disabilities, awarding grants to establish community gardens, requiring physical activity guidelines for the general public, and promoting healthy foods and physical activity at national parks. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the excise tax on tobacco products. Establishes a program to assist federal departments and agencies in integrating health goals into their activities. Addresses workplace wellness, allowing a wellness program credit for employers, excluding from an employee's income the fees paid by an employer to an athletic or fitness facility on the employee's behalf, and promoting breastfeeding among working mothers. Establishes requirements for federal buildings, including those for: (1) application of menu labeling requirements to food establishments and nutritional standards for food provided in such buildings, (2) prompts encouraging individuals to use stairs, and (3) installation of bicycle storage areas. Sets forth requirements to reduce the sodium content of processed food and restaurant food, expand nutritional labeling requirements, establish a front-label food guidance system, and strengthen health literacy.Disallows a deduction for expenses relating to advertising or marketing of any tobacco product. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to impose an industry-wide penalty on manufacturers of cigarettes for failure to achieve youth tobacco use reduction goals. Expands coverage of preventive services through title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act and the Federal Employees Health Benefits program. Establishes a training program for health professionals related to the prevention, identification, and treatment of overweight patients, obesity, and eating disorders. Requires the Secretary to: (1) award grants for training in integrative medicine, (2) establish a national consortium on breastfeeding research, and (3) implement public health monitoring measures to address mental health and substance use disorders.</summary>
</bill>
