<bill session="112" type="h" number="637" updated="2013-07-20T01:15:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness for Military Recruiters Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the procedures regarding military recruiter access to secondary school student recruiting information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2011-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412010" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2011-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E195-196"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2011--Introduced.
Fairness for Military Recruiters Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to revise the process for blocking the access of military recruiters or institutions of higher education (IHEs) to secondary school student information. Requires ESEA-assisted local educational agencies (LEAs) to notify each secondary school student's parent of the option to submit a written request to the LEA that the student's name, address, and telephone listing not be released to military recruiters or IHEs without the parent's prior written consent. Prohibits LEAs from providing military recruiters or IHEs access to such information once they have received such a request, unless the student's parent provides written consent to such access. Gives students the rights accorded to their parents when they reach age 18. Requires the Secretary of Defense to notify the Governor of the LEA's state and the Secretary of Education when an LEA denies access to military recruiters. Requires the Secretary of Education, upon receiving such notice, to determine whether: (1) the LEA has failed to comply substantially with the requirement to provide military recruiters with access to students and student information unless the parents have filed a prior consent request under this Act, and (2) the imposition of a penalty or remedy against the LEA is warranted. Makes these requirements inapplicable to private secondary schools that maintain a religious objection to military service.</summary>
</bill>
