<bill session="113" type="h" number="221" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART SALE Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Mergers, Acquisitions, and Risky Takeovers Supplied by American Labor and Entrepreneurship Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require reports on the acquisitions by certain foreign persons of companies that have received American taxpayer research and development funding, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-14">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-14">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2013--Introduced.
Stop Mergers, Acquisitions, and Risky Takeovers Supplied by American Labor and Entrepreneurship Act of 2013 or the SMART SALE Act of 2013 - Requires any person, company, institution, or other entity engaged in interstate commerce that owns, licenses, or otherwise holds an interest in a federally-funded technology, or to which federal energy research and development funding has been obligated by a federal agency (covered entity), to notify the Secretary of Energy (DOE) not later than seven days after entering into negotiations for any proposed or pending merger, acquisition, takeover, or other transfer that could result in control of such covered entity by: (1) the government of the Peoples's Republic of China, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, or a country that is a state sponsor of terrorism or that provides sanctuary to a foreign terrorist organization; (2) a citizen of such a country who owes permanent allegiance to such country; or (3) a corporation or other legal entity which is 50% owned by a citizen of such a country.</summary>
</bill>
