<bill session="110" type="h" number="3667" updated="2013-07-19T21:36:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-10T18:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-10T18:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in the State of Vermont for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-04-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-668.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-05-22T18:24:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="420">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 420.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-08T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>PERMISSION TO FILE A SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT - Mrs. Capps asked unanimous consent that the Natural Resources Committee be allowed to file a supplemental report on H.R. 3667. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-08T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Natural Resources, H. Rept. 110-668, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1419 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3667 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources. No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1419 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1419.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7970-7980" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7977" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3667 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources. No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1419 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John T. Salazar to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3667.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H.Res. 1419, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grijalva amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1419, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1419, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved that the Committee rise.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7980" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by recorded vote: 221 - 193 (Roll no. 580).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3667 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7980-7984" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of an amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3667.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7981" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sali moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7981-7982" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7981" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sali motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment purporting to add a new title entitled "American Energy Act".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Grijalva stated that the provisions contained in the motion to recommit were not germane to the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sali appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7982-7983" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 187 (Roll no. 582).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehner moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7983-7984" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7983" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boehner motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to add a new paragraph requiring an assessment of any effect a wild and scenic designation in the study area is likely to have on jobs, including agricultural employment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to recommit with instructions withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-10T18:49:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="583" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 299 - 118 (Roll no. 583).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3667.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="1419"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2093"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2093"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2093"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1168"/>
    <amendment number="h1169"/>
    <amendment number="h1170"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/10/2008--Passed House amended.
Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2008 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a specified segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in Vermont for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) analyze any potential impacts on the possession or use of a weapon, trap, or net, including a concealed weapon, on the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers or on lands adjacent to that area; (2) include in the study an assessment of any effect a wild and scenic designation in the study area is likely to have on energy production, transmission, or conveyance; (3) analyze the potential impact of the designation on private lands within the Rivers or adjacent to that area; and (4) complete the study of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers and submit a report describing the results of the study. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as authorizing appropriations to designate or otherwise create a new component of the national wild and scenic rivers system.</summary>
</bill>
