<bill session="112" type="s" number="1173" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ambulatory Surgical Center Quality and Access Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modernize payments for ambulatory surgical centers under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3690"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3690-3692" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2108"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2011--Introduced.
Ambulatory Surgical Center Quality and Access Act of 2011 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require alignment of updates for ambulatory surgical center (ASC) services under a revised prospective payment system (PPS) with updates for hospital outpatient department (OPD) services. Revises requirements for the reporting of quality measure data by ASCs and hospital OPDs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish an ASC value-based purchasing program under which each ASC that the Secretary determines meets (or exceeds) performance standards established, with respect to selected quality measures, for the performance period for a calendar year is eligible for shared savings in the form of a payment increase determined according to a specified formula. Revises requirements for the composition of the expert outside advisory panel the Secretary of HHS is required to consult during the annual review of the clinical integrity of the groups and payment weights in the PPS for hospital OPD services. Requires the panel to include suppliers subject to the PPS as well as at least one ASC representative. States that the conditions for coverage of ASC services specified by the Secretary shall not prohibit ASCs from providing individuals with any notice of rights or other required notice on the date of a procedure if more advanced notice is not feasible under the circumstances, including when a procedure is scheduled and performed on the same day.</summary>
</bill>
