<bill session="109" type="s" number="2644" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Perform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Platform Equality and Remedies for Rights Holders in Music Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to harmonize rate setting standards for copyright licenses under sections 112 and 114 of title 17, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2006-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300045" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2006-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3509-3510"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3510-3511" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5361"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2006--Introduced.
Platform Equality and Remedies for Rights Holders in Music Act of 2006 or the Perform Act of 2006 - Requires Copyright Royalty Judges (CRJs) to establish rates for a statutory license for the transmission of sound recordings by organizations that most clearly represent the fair market value of the rights licensed. Replaces the different processes for setting rates and terms of royalty payments for subscription transmissions by preexisting subscription services, satellite digital radio services, and eligible nonsubscription transmission services with one process for all such transmissions. Directs CRJs, when setting such rates and terms, to consider: (1) the fair market value of the rights licensed; and (2) the degree to which reasonable recording affects the potential market for sound recordings and the additional fees that are required to be paid by services for compensation. Conditions statutory licensing of transmissions on the transmitting entity using technology that is reasonably available, technologically feasible, and economically reasonable to prevent the making of copies or phonorecords embodying the transmission in whole or in part, except for reasonable recording. (Current law provides for limits on phonorecords of the transmission directly in a digital format.) Allows a performing rights society or a mechanical rights organization to monitor public performances or other uses of copyrighted works contained in transmissions. Requires the Register of Copyrights to convene a meeting among affected parties to discuss whether to recommend creating a new category of limited interactive services within certain statutory licenses for subscription transmissions.</summary>
</bill>
