<bill session="112" type="s" number="1130" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Trade Laws Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to strengthen the United States trade laws and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3444"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4071"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1267"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Trade Laws Act - Allows, under specified conditions, certain U.S. persons supportive of the government's position before a dispute settlement panel or Appellate Body of the World Trade Organization (WTO) to participate in consultations and panel or Appellate Body proceedings. Establishes the Congressional Advisory Commission on WTO Dispute Settlement to provide advice to Congress on the operation of the WTO dispute settlement system. Amends the Uruguay Round Agreements Act to require congressional approval before any modification of an agency regulation or practice that has been adversely affected by a WTO decision. Directs the United States to negotiate with the WTO to determine clarification of its obligations under the Uruguay Round Agreement due to an adverse WTO decision if the United States, Congress, or Commission finds that such decision created obligations never agreed to by the United States. Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to make specified changes to strengthen the Act's antidumping and countervailing duty provisions. Requires congressional approval for revocation of nonmarket economy country determinations made by the administering authority. Expands the authority of the administering authority or the International Trade Commission (ITC) to impose countervailing duties on products from a nonmarket economy country that have been provided a countervailable subsidy. Includes exchange-rate manipulation by a country as a countervailable subsidy. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require a recommendation from the ITC before the President can impose a duty on an imported Chinese product that causes or threatens market disruption to a like U.S. product. Applies the amendments made by this Act to goods from Canada and Mexico.</summary>
</bill>
