<bill session="109" type="h" number="4889" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Separate Enrollment and Line Item Veto Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To grant the power to the President to reduce budget authority.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400151"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2006-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2443"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Item veto"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Senate Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax expenditures"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2006--Introduced.
Separate Enrollment and Line Item Veto Act of 2006 - Prohibits the congressional appropriations committees from reporting any appropriations measure that fails to contain the same level of detail on the allocation of a proposed item of appropriations set forth in the accompanying committee report. Prohibits any congressional committee from reporting an authorization measure that contains new direct spending or a new limited tax benefit unless it presents each as a separate item, and the accompanying committee report contains a level of detail clearly indentifying its allocation. Prohibits a conference committee from filing a conference report that fails to contain the level of detail and the separate itemization of each direct spending or limited tax benefit required by this Act. Makes it out of order in the House to consider any measure reported or presented in violation of this Act. Provides for separate enrollment of each item of every appropriation and authorization measure containing new direct spending or new targeted tax benefits passed by Congress in the same form. Requires the Joint Committee on Taxation toidentify any limited tax benefits contained in any revenue or reconciliation measure amending the Internal Revenue Code that is being prepared for filing by a conference committee. Makes it out of order to consider any measure containing an emergency designation if it also provides an appropriation or direct spending for any other item or contains any other matter. Allows the measure to contain rescissions of budget authority or reductions of direct spending, or reduce amounts for that emergency. Provides for expedited judicial review of this Act. Requires the President to submit legislation for the periodic review, reauthorization, and sunset of tax expenditures with his FY2008 budget. Makes it out of order in the House to consider any measure containing a tax expenditure unless it terminates the tax expenditure within 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
