<bill session="110" type="s" number="837" updated="2013-07-19T22:27:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">I LEAD Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving the Leadership and Effectiveness of Administrators for Districts Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to develop a generation of school leaders who are committed to, and effective in, increasing student achievement and to ensure that all low-income, under-performing schools are led by effective school leaders who are well-prepared to foster student success.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2974-2975"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3523"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2007--Introduced.
Improving the Leadership and Effectiveness of Administrators for Districts Act of 2007 or the I LEAD Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (the Act) to direct the Secretary of Education to establish a national competitive grant program awarding grants to partnerships, each composed of a state and a consortium of high-need local educational agencies (LEAs), to: (1) contract with experienced external agencies for research-based evaluations of the effectiveness of state school leader certification or licensure requirements in recruiting, training, and retaining effective school leaders who improve student achievement at schools receiving improvement funds under part A of title I of the Act; (2) use such evaluations, if the certification or licensure requirements are shown to be ineffective, to develop plans to improve such requirements and the training, incentives, and support offered current and prospective school leaders; and (3) if they were required to develop a plan, create model school leadership zones by implementing such plans in an urban and a rural high-need LEA participating in their partnerships. Requires the Secretary to: (1) contract with an experienced external agency to evaluate the effectiveness of school leadership zones in recruiting, training, and retraining school leaders and improving student achievement; and (2) award an additional grant to partnership grantees that successfully create model school leadership zones so that they can revise school leader certification or licensure requirements in order to replicate the practices of such zones in other LEAs within their states.</summary>
</bill>
