<bill session="112" type="h" number="6639" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wildfire Suppressing Aircraft Transfer Act of 1996 to facilitate inter-agency agreements with the Air National Guard and the Air Force Reserve to secure Defense Support to Civil Authority (DSCA) missions in the initial airborne response to fighting wildfires.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Wildfire Suppressing Aircraft Transfer Act of 1996 to provide that provisions permitting an agency to order goods or services from that or another agency only if such goods or services cannot be provided as conveniently or cheaply by a commercial enterprise shall not limit the use of interagency agreements with the Air National Guard or Air Force Reserve to procure the services of a unit of the Guard or Reserve to conduct Defense Support to Civil Authority missions utilizing military fixed wing aerial firefighting aircraft, including Modular Airborne Firefighting System (MAFFS) units, in the initial airborne response to fighting wildfires. Makes such limitation inapplicable only when the Incident Commander determines: (1) that privately contracted fixed-wing aerial firefighting aircraft are unavailable, (2) it is necessary for military fixed-wing aerial firefighting aircraft including MAFFS units to perform an initial airborne response, or (3) that military fixed-wing aerial firefighting aircraft including MAFFS units are needed to supplement privately contracted fixed-wing aerial firefighting aircraft.</summary>
</bill>
