<bill session="109" type="h" number="3650" updated="2013-07-19T19:36:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow United States courts to conduct business during emergency conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2005-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7689-7692" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3650.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7695-7696" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-09-07T17:31:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="456" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 409 - 0 (Roll no. 456).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7689-7690" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-09-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9774-9776" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-09-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-09-09" type="public" number="109-63">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-63.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1634"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2005--Public Law.
Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005 - Allows federal circuit courts of appeals, district courts, bankruptcy courts, and magistrate judges to hold special sessions outside their circuits or districts upon a finding by a chief judge or judicial council that, because of emergency conditions, no location within the courts' regular circuits or districts is reasonably available. Authorizes such courts to transact any business, except certain district court criminal proceedings, at a special session outside their circuits or districts which they might transact at a regular session. Requires special session courts, through the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts, to notify the Judiciary Committees of Congress of any order issued in a special session. Requires the Administrative Office to report to such congressional committees describing the reasons for the issuance of a special session order, the duration of such order, the impact of such order on litigants, and the costs to the judiciary resulting from such order. Requires special session courts to provide reasonable notice to the U.S. Marshals Service before the commencement of any special session. Prohibits a criminal trial from being conducted at a special session outside the state in which the crime was committed unless the defendant consents to trial outside the state. Restricts criminal jury pools to the district in which a crime was committed unless the defendant consents to be tried by jurors from the district in which the trial court is holding a special session.</summary>
</bill>
