<bill session="112" type="s" number="854" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sober Truth on Preventing Underage Drinking Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STOP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for programs and activities with respect to the prevention of underage drinking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1562"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Sober Truth on Preventing Underage Drinking Reauthorization Act or the STOP Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize the program to reduce underage drinking for FY2012-FY2016. Makes revisions to such program, including by: (1) revising reporting requirements on state programs on underage drinking; (2) expanding the national media campaign to prevent underage drinking; (3) requiring the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to make grants to professional pediatric provider organizations to increase effective practices, including the screening of children and adolescents for alcohol use,&#160;to reduce the prevalence of alcohol use among individuals under the age of 21, including college students; and (4) expanding state public health surveillance of alcohol use and alcohol-related conditions among individuals between the ages of 18 and 20.</summary>
</bill>
