<bill session="110" type="h" number="1318" updated="2013-07-19T21:15:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to repeal the authority for agent or attorney representation in veterans benefits cases before the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400241"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E465"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2007--Introduced.
Veterans' Benefits Protection Act - Repeals the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to prescribe qualifications and standards of, and to set fees charged by, agents or attorneys representing veterans in claims before the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). Authorizes the Secretary to require that such individuals show that they are of good moral character, and qualified and competent to assist claimants. Removes some instances under which the Secretary may suspend or exclude an agent or attorney from such representation.Repeals the Secretary's authority to review and order a reduction in the fee charged to a claimant by an agent or attorney.Imposes fines and criminal penalties for soliciting, contracting for, charging, or receiving any part of a benefit or claim allowed to a claimant (or attempting such acts).</summary>
</bill>
