<bill session="109" type="h" number="1509" updated="2013-07-19T19:17:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Recreational Boaters Streamlined Inspection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create an inspection program that uses videophone systems at certain points of entry in Florida to satisfy customs and immigration reporting requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Video telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2005--Introduced.
Recreational Boaters Streamlined Inspection Act - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish an inspection program that uses a videophone system at specified points of entry in Florida through which: (1) a master of a recreational vessel may report to an appropriate official of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for purposes of the Tariff Act of 1930; and (2) a master and the passengers of such a vessel may report to an appropriate DHS official to satisfy requirements for lawful entry into the United States under immigration laws. Requires the program to be used only in a case in which the master of, and each passenger on, a recreational vessel is a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident. Provides that the program shall not affect the Secretary's authority to require such individual to wait for a customs inspection or to report the arrival of the vessel to the nearest customs facility or such other place as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations.</summary>
</bill>
