<bill session="112" type="hr" number="686" updated="2013-07-20T01:08:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Republic of Argentina's membership in the G20 should be conditioned on its adherence to international norms of economic relations and commitment to the rule of law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="457"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Argentina"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2012--Introduced.
Calls on Argentina to fulfill its membership responsibilities in the Group of Twenty Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors (G20). Calls on the President and the Secretary of the Treasury to work with the G20 members to: (1) terminate Argentina's G20 participation until Argentina has reversed efforts to expropriate foreign investment in Argentina, satisfied all outstanding U.S. court judgments against it, honored all awards of international arbitral panels against it, and complied with the recommendations of the Financial Action Task Force; (2) condition Argentina's future G20 membership on its adherence to international norms of economic relations and commitment to the rule of law; and (3) identify other countries that could replace Argentina in the G20 by virtue of their adherence to international economic norms and respect for the rule of law.</summary>
</bill>
