<bill session="110" type="h" number="1723" updated="2013-07-19T21:18:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair FHA Appraisals Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Housing Act to ensure fair appraisals in connection with mortgages insured under the FHA single family mortgage insurance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2007--Introduced.
Fair FHA Appraisals Act of 2007 - Amends the National Housing Act to subject to civil money penalties actions that improperly influence appraisals for an FHA insured mortgage for a small-family residence by compensating, instructing, inducing, coercing, or intimidating any person who conducts an appraisal in connection with such mortgage in order to cause the appraised value to be based on any other factor other than the independent judgment exercised in accordance with professional standards. Modifies FHA mortgage insurance appraisal standards to require that: (1) the appraisal be conducted by an appraiser selected by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development on a rotating basis, mortgage-by-mortgage, from a list of appraisers (blind draws) developed by the Secretary; and (2) an authorized mortgagee use only appraisers selected in accordance with such list. Restricts use by a qualified appraiser of the assistance of others to cases where a limited number of appraisals is conducted within a limited rural area.</summary>
</bill>
