<bill session="111" type="h" number="6032" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chiropractic Membership in the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize appointment of Doctors of Chiropractic to regular and reserve corps of the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Chiropractic Membership in the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to make chiropractic personnel eligible for appointment in the United States Public Health Service Commissioned Corps. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the Surgeon General to ensure that Doctors of Chiropractic are trained, equipped, and otherwise prepared to fulfill public health and emergency response service responsibilities in the Commissioned Corps. Requires the President to appoint no fewer than six Doctors of Chiropractic into the commissioned Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps. Directs the Surgeon General to submit a quarterly report to the relevant congressional committees on measures taken by the President, Surgeon General, and the Secretary to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
