<bill session="110" type="s" number="2639" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Assured Funding for Veterans Health Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for an assured adequate level of funding for veterans health care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2514"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Assured Funding for Veterans Health Care Act - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to make available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for programs, functions, and activities of the Veterans Health Administration for FY2008 130 percent of the amount obligated during FY2006. Adjusts the amount provided for fiscal years after FY2008 based on the number of enrolled veterans and the number of other persons eligible but not enrolled who are provided care, multiplied by the per capita baseline amount for FY2006, as increased by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index. Prohibits the availability of such funds for: (1) construction, acquisition, or alteration of veterans' medical facilities (other than for repairs provided for before the date of enactment of this Act); or (2) grants for the construction of state home facilities for the furnishing of veterans' domiciliary, nursing home, and hospital care.</summary>
</bill>
