<bill session="112" type="h" number="2188" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">LESS Government Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require government-wide application of continuous process improvement methods to reduce waste and improve the effectiveness of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2011--Introduced.
LESS Government Act - Requires the head of each federal agency to describe the implementation of continuous process improvement in the agency's periodic update on agency performance. Defines "continuous process improvement" as a management methodology (commonly referred to as lean six sigma) that combines tools to improve process speed, reduce waste, and incorporate requirements with data driven project analysis to provide products and services with improved quality at lower cost. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) make available on the OMB website a description of the results of the government-wide implementation of such process, and (2) appoint an expert on such process as a member of the Performance Improvement Council to advise on its implementation across agencies. Requires: (1) each agency's Chief Operating Officer to implement such process, and (2) each agency's Performance Improvement Officer to advise and assist the agency head and Chief Operating Officer in implementing such process. Requires the Director to designate a center of excellence for process training, from within the Department of Defense (DOD).</summary>
</bill>
