<bill session="109" type="s" number="1131" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-11-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Idaho Land Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Idaho Land Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Idaho Land Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Idaho Land Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Idaho Land Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the exchange of certain Federal land within the State of Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6027-6028"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-157.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 04/07/2006 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-232.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="394">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 394.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10528-10530" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10528-10530" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-09-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13T14:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8584-8586" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1131.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-11-13T14:23:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8584-8585" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-11-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-11-27">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-11-27" type="public" number="109-372">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-372.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2718"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5108"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/27/2006--Public Law.
Idaho Land Enhancement Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, if the State of Idaho offers to convey specified state land to the United States, to accept the offer, and on receipt of title to such land, simultaneously convey to the State specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and National Forest System land (the federal land). Requires the value of the exchanged federal and state lands to be equal or made equal by cash payment to the United States or Idaho. Sets forth requirements for: (1) the appraisal of the value of such lands, including that the appraisals be reviewed by an interdepartmental review team comprised of representatives of federal and state agencies; and (2) the disposition and use of proceeds from cash equalization payments received by the United States. Extends the term of approval of such appraisals by the interdepartmental review team to September 13, 2008. Requires the conveyance of certain easements or rights-of-way. Directs the city of Boise, Idaho, to pay the administrative costs associated with such land exchange. (Sec. 4) Transfers administrative jurisdiction over specified BLM land in Shoshone County, Idaho, from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Agriculture. Requires any land designated as a Wilderness Study Area that is transferred to the Secretary of Agriculture to be managed in a manner that preserves the suitability of land for designation as wilderness until Congress determines otherwise. Provides for the administration of transferred or conveyed lands. Considers the boundaries of the Idaho Panhandle National Forests and Clearwater National Forest, as modified by the exchange authorized by this Act, to be the boundaries of such Forests as of January 1, 1965. (Sec. 5) Revokes any public land orders withdrawing any of the federal land from appropriation or disposal under the public land laws necessary to permit disposal of such land. Withdraws the federal and state land from: (1) location, entry, and patent under the mining and public land laws; and (2) disposition under the mineral leasing laws and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970.</summary>
</bill>
