<bill session="111" type="s" number="1503" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">IMPACT Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improved Nutrition and Physical Activity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish grants to provide health services for improved nutrition, increased physical activity, obesity and eating disorder prevention, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2276"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2009--Introduced.
Improved Nutrition and Physical Activity Act or the IMPACT Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to expand an existing grant program for training for health profession students to include training on the treatment of individuals who are overweight, obese, or have eating disorders. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants for the training of primary care physicians and other health professions on how to identify, properly refer, treat, and prevent obesity or eating disorders and aid individuals who are overweight or obese or who suffer from eating disorders. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants for programs to: (1) promote healthy eating behaviors, physical activity, emotional wellness, and healthy living; and (2) prevent eating disorders, obesity, being overweight, and related serious and chronic medical conditions. Allows the Secretary, acting through the National Center for Health Statistics, to provide for: (1) data collection of fitness levels and physical activity and nutritional behaviors of students from grades 1-12; (2) collection and analysis of data determining the connection between children's and youth's physical and emotional health; and (3) analysis of data collected as part of the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Requires the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to review research under this Act to determine if particular information may be important for the health disparities report. Permits states to use preventive health and health services block grants for activities and community education programs designed to address and prevent overweight, obesity, and eating disorders through programs to promote healthy eating, exercise habits, and behaviors and emotional and social wellness.</summary>
</bill>
