<bill session="113" type="h" number="2512" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulation of Mortgage Servicing Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish clear regulatory standards for mortgage servicers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Regulation of Mortgage Servicing Act of 2013 - Requires a mortgage servicer to assign one case manager to each borrower that seeks a mortgage loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Requires the case manager to: (1) manage the communication between the servicer and the borrower, and (2) make decisions about the borrower's eligibility for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Prohibits a servicer from initiating a covered foreclosure action against a borrower unless the servicer has performed specified tasks related to offering the borrower, if eligible, a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Requires a servicer to suspend a covered foreclosure action initiated before the enactment of this Act until such tasks have been performed. Prohibits a servicer, during the suspension period, from: (1) sending the borrower a notice of foreclosure, (2) conducting or scheduling a sale of the real property securing the mortgage, or (3) causing final judgment to be entered against the borrower. Prescribes requirements a servicer must meet in order to be deemed to have made a reasonable effort to obtain necessary information to determine a borrower's eligibility for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Requires a servicer, before notifying a borrower of his or her ineligibility for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure, to obtain the services of an independent reviewer to review the borrower's file and determine whether or not the borrower is eligible. Makes a violation of this Act a bar to a covered foreclosure action. Allows a servicer in compliance with this Act, however, to bring or proceed with a foreclosure action, regardless of any prior violation. Makes any servicer that fails to comply with any requirement of this Act liable to a borrower in the same manner that a creditor who fails to comply with any requirement is liable to a person.</summary>
</bill>
