<bill session="110" type="s" number="1911" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TCE Reduction Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Toxic Chemical Exposure Reduction Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">TCE Reduction Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Toxic Chemical Exposure Reduction Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to protect the health of susceptible populations, including pregnant women, infants, and children, by requiring a health advisory, drinking water standard, and reference concentration for trichloroethylene vapor intrusion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 110-486. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1057">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1057.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5527"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Toxic Chemical Exposure Reduction Act of 2008 or the TCE Reduction Act of 2008 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to publish a health advisory for trichloroethylene that fully protects, with an adequate margin of safety, the health of susceptible populations (including pregnant women, infants, and children), taking into consideration body weight, exposure patterns, and all routes of exposure.Requires the Administrator to promulgate a national primary drinking water regulation for trichloroethylene: (1) that is protective of susceptible populations; and (2) the maximum contaminant level of which is as close to the maximum contaminant level goal for trichloroethylene, and as protective of those susceptible populations, as is feasible. Requires consumer confidence reports to disclose the presence of, and the potential health risks to susceptible populations from exposure to, trichloroethylene in drinking water.Requires the Administrator to: (1) publish a health advisory for trichloroethylene that fully protects the health of susceptible populations from vapor intrusion; (2) establish an integrated risk information system reference concentration of trichloroethylene vapor that is protective of susceptible populations; and (3) apply such reference concentration with respect to any potential vapor intrusion-related investigations or actions to protect public health with respect to trichloroethylene exposure carried out pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 and the Safe Drinking Water Act.</summary>
</bill>
