<bill session="109" type="h" number="2401" updated="2013-07-19T19:25:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Insurance Competitive Pricing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the antitrust exemption applicable to the business of insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2005-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2005-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Monopolies"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Territorial arrangements (Antitrust law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2005--Introduced.
Insurance Competitive Pricing Act of 2005 - Amends the McCarran-Ferguson Act to eliminate the antitrust exemption applicable to the business of insurance where the conduct involves: (1) price fixing; (2) allocating with a competitor a geographical area in which, or persons to whom, insurance will be offered for sale; (3) unlawfully tying the sale or purchase of one type of insurance to the sale or purchase of another type of insurance or any other service or product; or (4) monopolizing, or attempting to monopolize, any part of such business. Retains such exemption for conduct involving the making of a contract, or engaging in a combination or conspiracy, to: (1) collect or disseminate historical loss data; (2) determine a loss development factor applicable to such data; (3) perform actuarial services if such contract, combination, or conspiracy does not involve restraint of trade; or (4) determine a trend factor (an adjustment to reflect a change in inflation or any other change in the estimated loss costs incurred by certain persons engaged in the business of insurance) during a specified transition period.</summary>
</bill>
