<bill session="109" type="s" number="1211" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Science and Technology Assessment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an Office of Foreign Science and Technology Assessment to enable the United States to effectively analyze trends in foreign science and technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6312-6313"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6313" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2005--Introduced.
Foreign Science and Technology Assessment Act of 2005 - Establishes within the Department of State an Office of Foreign Science and Technology Assessment to assess foreign science and technologies that have the capability to cause a loss of high technology industrial leadership in the United States. Places at the head of the Office of Foreign Science and Technology Assessment a Director, who shall be the Science Advisor to the Secretary of State. Directs the Secretary of State to establish a Foreign Science and Technology Assessment Panel to provide advice on assessments performed by the Office of Foreign Science and Technology Assessment, including review of foreign science and technology assessment reports, methodologies, subjects of study, and the means of improving the quality and timeliness of such Office.</summary>
</bill>
