<bill session="109" type="h" number="5954" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intelligence Oversight Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to specify conditions under which the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives shall be required to exercise its authority to make classified information in its possession available to certain standing committees of the House, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2006-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Covert operations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Intelligence"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Senate Intelligence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Intelligence Oversight Act - Amends Rule X (Organization of Committees) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit the Select Committee on Intelligence from rejecting a request by one of certain standing committees to make classified information in the Intelligence Committee's possession about lawful intelligence or intelligence-related activities of a federal agency available to such committee if the information relates to any matter within the committee's jurisdiction, unless the information reveals sensitive intelligence sources and methods or reveals sensitive information related to a covert action. Requires the Intelligence Committee to notify appropriate standing committees of any classified information received by it that falls within such a committee's jurisdiction. Requires Intelligence Committee members who also serve on the standing committee, in coordination with its chairman, to brief the entire membership on such classified information. Provides for Intelligence Committee assistance to standing committees requesting a briefing on classified information held by executive branch offices. Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to conform to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
