<bill session="112" type="h" number="3642" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to document operational requirements, assist with national voluntary consensus standards, and conduct technology research to advance a nationwide interoperable public safety broadband network, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2011-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2011--Introduced.
Public Safety Broadband Network Enabling Act - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to: (1) document operational requirements for a nationwide interoperable public safety broadband network; (2) if necessary and practical, help accelerate the development of national voluntary consensus standards for such network; (3) conduct research and assist with the development of technologies and applications to advance wireless public safety communications; and (4) continue to develop and maintain a demonstration testbed for use by manufacturers, providers of commercial mobile services, and public safety agencies to evaluate advanced broadband communications equipment and software for use by the public safety community. Directs the Director to: (1) coordinate with federal agencies, the private sector, and public safety organizations; and (2) convene any appropriate working groups of government and commercial stakeholders. Requires that a specified amount be made available to the Director from any trust fund established in the Treasury after October 1, 2011, consisting of proceeds from the auction of electromagnetic spectrum.</summary>
</bill>
