<bill session="111" type="s" number="2779" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote Department of the Interior efforts to provide a scientific basis for the management of sediment and nutrient loss in the Upper Mississippi River Basin, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-707.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Missouri River"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2009--Introduced.
Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey (USGS), to establish a nutrient and sediment monitoring network for the Upper Mississippi River Basin. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish guidelines for related data collection and storage activities; (2) inventory the sediment and monitoring efforts of governmental and nongovernmental entities for the purpose of creating a baseline understanding of overlap, data gaps, and redundancies; and (3) collaborate with other public and private monitoring efforts in establishing the monitoring program.Directs the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a water resources assessment of the Basin. Requires the Director of the USGS to establish: (1) a computer modeling program of nutrient and sediment sources in the Basin; and (2) an Internet-based system to distribute information about nutrient and sediment loss reduction projects and nutrient and sediment levels in the Upper Mississippi River and its tributaries.</summary>
</bill>
