<bill session="109" type="s" number="3595" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Emergency Management Authority Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the United States Emergency Management Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2006-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6717-6721" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2006--Introduced.
United States Emergency Management Authority Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to replace provisions concerning the Directorate of, and the Under Secretary for, Emergency Preparedness and Response in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) with provisions establishing a United States Emergency Management Authority to lead the nation's efforts to prepare for, respond to, recover from, and mitigate the risks of natural and man-made disasters, including catastrophic incidents. Directs the Authority's Administrator to: (1) provide federal leadership necessary to prepare for and respond to disasters; (2) develop a National Emergency Management System capable of responding to catastrophic incidents; (3) establish 10 Regional Offices; and (4) promote public and community preparedness. Transfers functions of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the Directorate to the Authority. Requires the Authority to be maintained as a distinct entity within DHS. Establishes within the Authority a Director for Preparedness and a Director for Response and Recovery. Requires: (1) each Regional Administrator to establish multi-agency strike teams; and (2) the Secretary of DHS to establish the National Advisory Council on Emergency Preparedness and Response. Establishes within the Authority a National Incident Management System Integration Center, a Chief Medical Officer, a National Search and Rescue Response System, and a Metropolitan Medical Response System. Establishes within DHS a National Operations Center, a System Assessment and Validation for Emergency Responders Program, an Assistant Secretary for Cybersecurity and Telecommunications, and an Office for the Prevention of Terrorism. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to make grants to administer and improve the Emergency Management Assistance Compact.</summary>
</bill>
