<bill session="109" type="h" number="4514" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Homesteading Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist low-income families, displaced from their residences in the States of Alabama, Louisiana, and Mississippi as a result of Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, by establishing within the Department of Housing and Urban Development a homesteading initiative that offers displaced low-income families the opportunity to purchase a home owned by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400634"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400038" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2005-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2088"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Homestead law"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2005--Introduced.
Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Homesteading Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to transfer, without payment, federally owned (including property transferred to the Secretary from other agencies) or otherwise donated suitable residential property to state or local governments for use in an approved homestead program carried out by such governments in Alabama, Louisiana, and Mississippi in areas designated disaster areas due to Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Authorizes reimbursement to agencies transferring property. Sets forth approval criteria for a homestead program, including: (1) selection criteria that gives priority to displaced low-income families; (2) occupancy only pursuant to a written agreement which must be for a period of at least five years and which requires the occupant to make certain repairs. Requires the Secretary to audit authorized activities and permits monetary and other penalties penalties for noncompliance. Permits the waiver of certain environmental requirements. Prohibits the transfer, acceptance, or conveyance of property under this Act five years after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
