<bill session="109" type="hc" number="9" updated="2013-07-19T20:02:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Entitled the "English Plus Resolution".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2005-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bilingualism"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Declares that the U.S. Government should pursue English-plus policies that: (1) encourage all residents of this country to become fully proficient in English by expanding educational opportunities and access to information technologies; (2) conserve and develop the Nation's linguistic resources by encouraging all residents of this country to learn or maintain skills in languages other than English; (3) assist Native Americans, Native Alaskans, Native Hawaiians, and other peoples indigenous to the United States in their efforts to prevent the extinction of their languages and cultures; (4) continue to provide services in languages other than English as needed to facilitate access to essential functions of government, promote public health and safety, ensure due process, promote equal educational opportunity, and protect fundamental rights; and (5) recognize the importance of multilingualism to vital American interests and individual rights, and oppose English-only measures and other restrictionist language measures.</summary>
</bill>
