<bill session="109" type="h" number="1332" updated="2013-07-19T19:16:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-16T22:29:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-16T22:29:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection of Incapacitated Persons Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for the removal to Federal court of certain State court cases involving the rights of incapacitated persons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400202" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2005-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-16T21:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-16T21:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1599-1604" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-16T21:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1332.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-03-16T22:29:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1599" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-03-16T22:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1151"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1334"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1334"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="539"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="539"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="653"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="686"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Living wills"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Right to die"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2005--Passed House amended.
Protection of Incapacitated Persons Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal judicial code to authorize an incapacitated person (person), or the person's next friend, to remove to the U.S. district court, for the district in which it arose or was heard, within 30 days after available State remedies have been exhausted, any claim or cause of action in which the State court authorizes or directs the withholding or withdrawal of food or fluids or medical treatment necessary to sustain the person's life. Defines: (1) incapacitated person as a born individual presently incapable of making relevant decisions concerning the provision, withholding, or withdrawal of food, fluids or medical treatment under applicable law; and (2) next friend as an individual who has some significant relationship with the real party in interest, including a parent. Exempts from such removal authority any claim or cause of action in which no party disputes, and the court finds, that the incapacitated person, while having capacity, had executed a written advance directive valid under applicable law that clearly authorized the withholding or withdrawal of food or fluids or medical treatment in the applicable circumstances. Requires the U.S. district court, in hearing and determining such a claim or cause of action removed under this Act, to consider only whether authorizing or directing the withholding or withdrawal of food or fluids or medical treatment necessary to sustain the person's life constitutes a deprivation of any right, privilege, or immunity secured by the Constitution or laws of the United States. Declares that: (1) the court shall determine any such claim or cause of action de novo; and (2) no bar or limitation based on abstention, res judicata, collateral estoppel, procedural default, or any other doctrine of issue or claim preclusion shall apply.</summary>
</bill>
