<bill session="109" type="h" number="3747" updated="2013-07-19T19:37:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to assist victims of Hurricane Katrina and other major disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400634"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2005--Introduced.
Authorizes the President, with respect to individuals and households receiving assistance for damages suffered as a result of Hurricane Katrina, to waive the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act limitations on financial assistance of a maximum $5,000 (increased below to $25,000) per household for repairs, $10,000 per household for replacement of an owner-occupied private residence, and $25,000 per individual or household for a single disaster.Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to double from 7.5% to 15% of the estimated aggregate amount of federal disaster relief grants to be made with respect to a major disaster the limit on the total amount of contributions the President may make for cost-effective hazard mitigation measures in the disaster area. Increases from $5,000 to $25,000 the maximum amount of assistance per household allowable for repairs.Directs the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to: (1) administer state management costs in a consistent manner, in accordance with certain federal guidelines; and (2) implement a process under which the Director will approve or disapprove such costs within 30 days after they are submitted.</summary>
</bill>
