<bill session="112" type="s" number="3327" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Russian World Trade Organization Commitments Verification Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the United States Trade Representative to take action to obtain the full compliance of the Russian Federation with its commitments under the protocol on the accession of the Russian Federation to the Agreement Establishing the World Trade Organization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2012-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="6149"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2012--Introduced.
Russian World Trade Organization Commitments Verification Act of 2012 - Directs the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), within 90 days after the effective date of an Act of Congress authorizing the extension of permanent normal trade relations treatment to products of the Russian Federation, to report to Congress on: (1) Russian Federation commitments under the protocol on the accession of the Russian Federation to the World Trade Organization (WTO) Agreement, and (2) the date by which that protocol requires each such commitment to be implemented. Requires the USTR to report annually to Congress on: (1) actions taken by the Russian Federation to comply with its commitments under the protocol that has a significant effect on U.S. commerce, (2) any commitment the Federation is not implementing or is not making progress toward implementing in a timely manner, and (3) any actions taken by the USTR to obtain Russian Federation compliance with its commitments. Directs the USTR to take appropriate action to obtain Russian Federation compliance with commitments it is not implementing or is not making progress toward implementing in a timely manner. Authorizes the USTR, however, not to take any action if it is not in the U.S. national interest. Requires the USTR to seek public participation in developing such reports and in determining what action, if any, to take with respect to any commitment the Russian Federation is not implementing or is not making progress toward implementing in a timely manner.</summary>
</bill>
