<bill session="109" type="h" number="811" updated="2013-07-19T19:11:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Soda Ash Royalty Reduction Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce temporarily the royalty required to be paid for sodium produced on Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400088"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="203"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2603"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Feedstock"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2005--Introduced.
Soda Ash Royalty Reduction Act of 2005 - Sets, for a five-year period, the royalty rate on the quantity or gross value of the output of sodium compounds and related products at the point of shipment to market from Federal land at two percent. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to report to Congress, after four years, on the effects of such royalty reduction, including: (1) the amount of sodium compounds and related products at the point of shipment to market from Federal land during such four-year period; (2) the number of jobs that have been created or maintained during the royalty reduction period; (3) the total amount of royalty paid to the United States on the quantity or gross value of the output of sodium compounds and related products at the point of shipment to market produced during that four-year period, and the portion of such royalty paid to States; and (4) a recommendation of whether the reduced royalty rate should apply after the end of the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
