<bill session="112" type="h" number="423" updated="2013-07-20T01:13:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Member Address Privacy and Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prevent the addresses of the residences of Members of Congress from appearing on the computerized Statewide voter registration lists required to be maintained by States under such Act, and to permit a Member of Congress who seeks to be a candidate for election for public office in a State to meet any requirement under State law to provide the appropriate election official with the address of the Member's residence by providing the chief State election official with an affidavit certifying that the Member is a resident of the State.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2011-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Member Address Privacy and Protection Act - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require the appropriate state or local official to provide adequate technological security measures to prevent the addresses of the residences of Members of Congress from appearing on the computerized statewide voter registration lists required to be maintained by states under such Act. Authorizes&#160;a Member&#160;seeking election for public office to meet any state law requirement to provide the appropriate election official with the Member's home address by filing an affidavit with the chief election official certifying that the Member is a state resident.</summary>
</bill>
