<bill session="111" type="h" number="2040" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize a process by which the Secretary of the Interior shall process acquisitions of certain real property of the Samish Indian Nation into trust, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400232"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, for the purpose of processing acquisitions of real property of the Samish Indian Nation, to process as on-reservation acquisitions any property in the islands within Skagit County, Washington, as described in this Act, which the Samish Indian Nation both acquires and requests to deed to the Secretary. Prohibits real property taken into trust under this Act from being used for gaming. States that the proclamation of a reservation for the Samish Indian Nation pursuant to the Indian Reorganization Act or the establishment of an initial reservation for them shall not alter such prohibition with regard to the lands taken into trust pursuant to this Act.Bars this Act from granting, restoring, or diminishing any hunting, fishing, trapping, or gathering treaty right of the Samish Indian Nation.</summary>
</bill>
