<bill session="113" type="h" number="3007" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require States to recognize the military experience of veterans when issuing licenses and credentials to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="492"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Requires a state, as a condition for receipt of a grant or contract from the Department of Labor for support of disabled veterans' outreach specialists and local veterans' employment representatives, to: (1) establish a program that issues a license or credential to a veteran without requiring any training or apprenticeship if such veteran receives a satisfactory score on completion of an examination administered by that state and has at least 10 years of experience in a military occupational specialty that is similar to the civilian occupation for which such license or credential is required; and (2) submit a report each year on the exams administered that includes the number of veterans who completed such exams and a description of the results of such exams, disaggregated by occupational field.</summary>
</bill>
