<bill session="113" type="h" number="1168" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management, to convey to the City of Carlin, Nevada, in exchange for consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States, to any Federal land within that city that is under the jurisdiction of that agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412500"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-220.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-20T12:54:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="160">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 160.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2013--Reported to House amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if an offer is received from the city of Carlin, Nevada, to purchase certain federal land within the city, through the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey to the city all interest of the United States in such land in exchange for consideration equal to the fair market value of the land. Permits the city to pay or reimburse the Secretary, as appropriate, for reasonable transaction and administrative personnel costs associated with such conveyance. Prohibits a conveyance or combination of conveyances under this Act from being considered a major federal action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Releases the United States from all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product (or derivative of a petroleum product) solid waste, mine materials, or mining related features existing on the federal land. Withdraws the federal land identified for conveyance from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
</bill>
