<bill session="109" type="h" number="2761" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Screening Mammography Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act and Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require that group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans provide coverage for annual screening mammography for any class of covered individuals if the coverage or plans include coverage for diagnostic mammography for such class and to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of annual screening mammography under the Medicaid Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2005-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-07">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mammography"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2005--Introduced.
Screening Mammography Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group coverage, that provides coverage for diagnostic mammography for any class of participants or beneficiaries to also provide coverage for annual screening mammography for that class under terms that are not less favorable. Prohibits: (1) denying screening coverage on the basis that the screening is not medically necessary or is not pursuant to a referral or recommendation; (2) denying eligibility, enrollment, or renewal solely to avoid this requirement; (3) providing monetary incentives to participants or beneficiaries to encourage them to accept less than such minimum protections; (4) penalizing providers because they provide such care; or (5) providing incentives to induce providers to provide such care. Declares that this Act does not preempt any state laws providing at least these protections. Applies such requirements and prohibitions to health coverage offered in the individual market. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to mandate coverage of annual screening mammographies.</summary>
</bill>
