<bill session="113" type="h" number="239" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zero-based Budgeting Ensures Responsible Oversight (ZERO) Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require zero-based budgeting for departments and agencies of the Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2013-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2013--Introduced.
Zero-based Budgeting Ensures Responsible Oversight (ZERO) Act of 2013 - Requires the President to submit with materials related to&#160;each federal budget transmitted to Congress by January 1, 2015, a budget for each agency that contains: a description of each activity for which an agency receives an appropriation in the current fiscal year or for which the agency requests an appropriation for the budget year; the legal basis for each activity; for each activity, three alternative funding levels for the budget year (at least two of which shall be below the funding level for the current fiscal year), a summary of the priorities that would be accomplished within each level, and the additional increments of value that would be added by the higher funding levels; and for each activity one or more measures of its cost efficiency and effectiveness. Requires the&#160; Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to&#160;publish guidelines to carry out this Act&#160;that shall require: (1) the baseline budget of each agency to be assumed to be zero, and (2) each proposed expenditure to be justified as if it were a new expenditure.</summary>
</bill>
