<bill session="111" type="s" number="4019" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Made in America Promise Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to clarify the applicability of the Buy American Act to products purchased for the use of the legislative branch, to prohibit the application of any of the exceptions to the requirements of such Act to products bearing an official Congressional insignia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2039"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2010--Introduced.
Congressional Made in America Promise Act of 2010 - Amends the Buy American Act to apply Buy American requirements to articles, materials, and supplies acquired for the use of any legislative branch office, including the House of Representatives and the Senate, in the same manner as the Act applies with respect to articles, materials, and supplies acquired for the use of a department or independent establishment. Prescribes a special rule in the case of any product which bears a congressional official insignia (including a mark resembling an official seal) that is acquired for the use of a legislative branch office. Prohibits the head of such office from making a determination under the Act that: (1) it is inconsistent with the public interest to enter into a contract in accordance with the Act; or (2) an article, material, or supply is not mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available commercial quantities and of satisfactory quality. Applies this prohibition to otherwise exempted manufactured articles, materials, or supplies procured under any contract the award value of which is less than or equal to the micro-purchase threshold.</summary>
</bill>
