<bill session="111" type="h" number="6448" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spending Control Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Grace Commission II to review and make recommendations regarding cost control in the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3988"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/29/2010--Introduced.
Spending Control Act of 2010 - Establishes the Grace Commission II to conduct a review of cost control in the federal government every two years with respect to improving management and reducing costs. Directs the Commission to conduct in-depth studies to evaluate potential improvements in the operations of executive agencies and to develop recommendations regarding: (1) opportunities for increased efficiency and reduced costs that can be realized by executive action or legislation; (2) areas where managerial accountability can be enhanced and administrative control can be improved; (3) opportunities for managerial improvements over the short and long terms; (4) specific areas where further study can be justified by potential savings; and (5) ways to reduce governmental expenditures and indebtedness and improve personnel management. Requires the Commission to submit final reports within 18 months after enactment of this Act and every two years thereafter until it submits its third final report. Requires such reports to contain the Commission's findings, conclusions, and recommendations for legislative and administrative actions and proposed legislation to carry out those recommendations. Sets forth congressional procedures for considering such legislation.</summary>
</bill>
