<bill session="109" type="s" number="1235" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Increase Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans' Housing Opportunity and Benefits Improvement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Veterans' Housing Opportunity and Benefits Improvement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapters 19 and 37 of title 38, United States Code, to extend the availability of $400,000 in coverage under the servicemembers' life insurance and veterans' group life insurance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve and extend housing, insurance, outreach, and benefits programs provided under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, to improve and extend employment programs for veterans under laws administered by the Secretary of Labor, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve and extend housing, insurance, outreach, and benefits programs provided under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, to improve and extend employment programs for veterans under laws administered by the Secretary of Labor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6484-6485"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6485-6486" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably (As approved by the Committee, the substitute amendment incorporated related provisions of S. 1235, as introduced, S. 552, S. 917, S. 151, S. 1259, S. 1271, and S. 423).</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Craig with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 109-139.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-09-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="218">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10620-10622" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10620-10622" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29T10:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2970-2982" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1235.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2988" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE" datetime="2006-05-22T18:59:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="177" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 372 - 0 (Roll no. 177).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2970-2976" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-05-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5285-5295" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5285-5291" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-06-15" type="public" number="109-233">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-233.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2046"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3665"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="151"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="423"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="552"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="917"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1235"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1259"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Hypertension"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stroke"/>
    <term name="Variable rate mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2006--Public Law.
Veterans' Housing Opportunity and Benefits Improvement Act of 2006 - Title I: Housing Matters - (Sec. 101) Permits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary), in the case of a service-disabled veteran who is residing, but does not intend to permanently reside, in a residence owned by a member of the veteran's family, to assist the veteran in acquiring such adaptations determined reasonably necessary due to the veteran's disability. Provides assistance limits. Terminates such assistance five years after the enactment of this Act. Prohibits any veteran from receiving more than three grants of assistance. Requires an interim and final implementation report from the Comptroller General to Congress. (Sec. 102) Allows the Secretary, with respect to hybrid adjustable rate mortgages offered to veterans under provisions of the National Housing Act, to increase or decrease the interest rate in any single adjustment by such percentage points as the Secretary may prescribe. (Currently, the Secretary is limited to an increase of one percentage point in any single adjustment.) (Sec. 103) Amends provisions directing the Secretary to establish and implement a pilot program for making direct housing loans to Native American veterans to: (1) make such program a permanent program rather than a pilot program; and (2) require the Secretary to include information on loans so provided as part of the annual benefits report of the Veterans Benefits Administration. (Sec. 104) Extends eligibility for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) direct loans for Native American veterans to a non-Native American veteran who is the spouse of a Native American veteran, as long as there is joint possession or ownership on trust land. Title II: Employment Matters - (Sec. 201) Requires, as additional duties of the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans' Employment and Training (Assistant Secretary), the: (1) furnishing of information to employers with respect to the training and skills of veterans and disabled veterans; and (2) facilitation of employment of such veterans through participation in labor exchanges and other means. (Sec. 202) Renames the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment and Training as the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach. Expands the duties of the Assistant Secretary to include outreach activities to employers with respect to the training and skills of veterans and the advantages offered by their employment. Revises Committee membership. Directs that a currently-required annual report from the Committee also be transmitted to the congressional veterans' committees, and include a special emphasis on disabled veterans. Requires additional information within the annual reports, including an assessment of veterans' employment outreach activities carried out by the Secretary of Labor. (Sec. 203) Extends through FY2009 the authorization of appropriations for homeless veterans reintegration programs. Title III: Life and Health Insurance Matters - (Sec. 301) Extends the period of Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance (SGLI) coverage for totally disabled veterans following separation from active duty or active duty for training to the earlier of: (1) the date on which the insured ceases to be totally disabled; (2) two years after separation or release, in the case of a separation or release during the period beginning one year before the enactment of this Act and ending on September 30, 2011; and (2) 18 months after separation or release, in the case of a separation or release on or after October 1, 2011. Makes identical changes with respect to certain reserve assignments in which the individual performs active duty or volunteers for assignment to a mobilization category. (Sec. 302) Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to prohibit a premium increase for reinstated civilian health insurance for a servicemember who is released from active duty. (Sec. 303) Provides for the preservation (reinstatement) of employer-sponsored health coverage for reserve members who acquire coverage under TRICARE (a Department of Defense (DOD)-managed health care plan) by reason of active-duty service, and then later return to civilian employment. Title IV: Other Matters - (Sec. 401) Adds atherosclerotic heart disease or hypertensive vascular disease, stroke, and their complications to the list of diseases or conditions presumed to be associated with prisoner-of-war status, and therefore compensable under veterans' disability compensation. (Sec. 402) Consolidates and recodifies the veterans outreach services program. Requires the Secretary to prepare a plan for VA outreach activities for each two-fiscal-year period. Changes from annually to biennially a required report from the Secretary to Congress on outreach activities. (Sec. 403) Extends through 2009 (currently, 2004) a requirement for annual reports from the Secretary to Congress on VA equitable relief provided to veterans and their dependents following a loss of benefits because of VA administrative error. Title V: Technical Amendments - (Sec. 501) Makes technical and clarifying amendments to provisions concerning SGLI traumatic injury protection coverage. (Sec. 502) Makes typographical corrections, stylistic changes, and other revisions in provisions relating to eligibility for veterans' disability compensation or dependency and indemnity compensation.</summary>
</bill>
