<bill session="109" type="s" number="2000" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide for equitable allotment of land to Alaska Native veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2005--Introduced.
Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act - Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) with respect to the open season during which certain Alaska Native Vietnam veterans are eligible to file for allotments of up to two parcels of federal land totaling up to 160 acres. Ends such open season three years after regulations have been issued under this Act. Revises the requirements for selection of such allotments. Allows allotments to be selected from land that is selected by or conveyed to the State of Alaska or a Native Corporation if the State or Native Corporation voluntarily relinquishes or conveys to the United States the land for the allotment. Limits the prohibition against the conveyance of certain allotments to: (1) lands within the right-of-way granted for the TransAlaska Pipeline; or (2) the inner or outer corridor of such right-of-way. Expands the eligibility for allotment to veterans who served between August 5, 1964, and May 7, 1975. Allows an heir (currently, only the personal representative or special administrator for the benefit of heirs) to apply for and receive an allotment on behalf of the estate of a deceased eligible individual. Prescribes criteria for the approval of allotment applications. Permits any person who made an allotment selection under this Act to withdraw it and reselect land in accordance with this Act, if the land originally selected: (1) was selected before enactment of this Act; and (2) as of the enactment of this Act, was not conveyed to the person.</summary>
</bill>
