<bill session="112" type="s" number="314" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unborn Child Pain Awareness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that women seeking an abortion are fully informed regarding the pain experienced by their unborn child.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2011--Introduced.
Unborn Child Pain Awareness Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require an abortion provider who knowingly performs an abortion of a pain-capable unborn child (defined as an unborn child who has reached a probable stage of development of 20 weeks or more after fertilization), to first: (1) inform the woman of the probable age of the child, (2) provide to the woman an Unborn Child Pain Awareness Brochure (unless she waives receipt), (3) provide information that pain medicine administered to the mother may not prevent pain in the child, but in some cases anesthesia or pain-reducing drugs can be administered directly to the child, (4) give the woman the provider's best medical judgment of the risks and costs of such anesthesia or analgesic, and (5) obtain the woman's signature on the Unborn Child Pain Awareness Decision Form and her explicit request for or refusal of the administration of drugs to the child. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop the Unborn Child Pain Awareness Brochure that includes a statement that there is substantial evidence that the process of being killed in an abortion will cause the unborn child pain and that the mother has the option of having pain-reducing drugs administered directly to the child. Creates an exception to save the life of the mother. Establishes civil penalties for willfully failing to comply with this Act. Authorizes: (1) the U.S. Attorney General (DOJ) to bring a civil action under this Act, and (2) private rights of action for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
