<bill session="112" type="h" number="2512" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-05T17:25:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-05T17:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in Clark County, Nevada, for the environmental remediation and reclamation of the Three Kids Mine Project Site, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2011-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2011-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 17.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-01T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-512.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-01T13:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="360">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 360.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05T17:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05T17:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3434-3437" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05T17:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2512.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-06-05T17:25:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3434-3435" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05T17:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1492"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2012--Passed House amended.
Three Kids Mine Remediation and Reclamation Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Henderson Redevelopment Agency of the city of Henderson, Nevada, the Three Kids Mine Federal Land (the parcel or parcels of federal land consisting of approximately 948 specified acres, as depicted on the map entitled "Three Kids Mine Project Area"). Directs the Secretary to administratively adjust the fair market value of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land by deducting from the fair market value of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land the reasonable approximate assessment, remediation, and reclamation costs for the Three Kids Mine Project Area. Directs the Secretary to determine the fair market value of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land based on an appraisal without regard to any existing contamination. Requires the Henderson Redevelopment Agency to reimburse the Secretary for appraisal costs. Directs the Secretary to prepare a reasonable approximate estimation of the costs to assess, remediate, and reclaim the Three Kids Mine Project Site (the Three Kids Mine Federal Land and the adjacent approximately 314 acres of non-federal land, together comprising approximately 1,262 acres, as depicted on the map entitled "Three Kids Mine Project Area"). Requires the Henderson Redevelopment Agency to pay the fair market value, if any for the Three Kids Mine Federal Land. Requires the Mine Remediation and Reclamation Agreement to be an enforceable consent order or agreement administered by the state. Requires the Henderson Redevelopment Agency to notify the Secretary in writing that is prepared to accept conveyance of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land. (Sec. 4) Withdraws the Three Kids Mine Federal Land, for a 10-year period, following enactment, or on the date of conveyance, from: (1) entry, appropriation, operation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and the geothermal leasing laws. Relinquishes and revokes, subject to valid existing rights, any withdrawal of public land for reclamation project purposes that includes all or any portion of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land for which the Bureau of Reclamation has determined that it has no further need to the extent necessary to exclude from the withdrawal the land no longer needed and to allow for the immediate conveyance of the Three Kids Mine Federal Land. Prohibits anything in this Act from diminishing, hindering, or interfering with the exclusive and perpetual use by existing rights holders of the operation, maintenance, and improvement of water conveyance infrastructure and facilities situated on the Three Kids Mine Federal Land that were constructed or permitted by the Bureau of Reclamation prior to the effective date of this Act. (Sec. 5) Adjusts the boundary of the River Mountains Area of Critical Environmental Concern. (Sec. 6) Releases the United States, upon making the conveyance, from any and all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product, solid waste, or mining related materials at the Three Kids Mine Project Site. (Sec. 7) Makes the provisions of the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998 non-applicable to land conveyed under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
