<bill session="111" type="h" number="2755" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">High Quality Teaching Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to assist underperforming schools to recruit, support, and retain highly qualified and effective teachers by providing grants for participation in the Targeted High Need Initiative program of the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2009-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1341"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Introduced.
High Quality Teaching Act of 2009 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive five-year grants to up to 250 local educational agencies (LEAs) to recruit, support, and retain highly qualified and effective teachers through participation in the Targeted High Need Initiative program of the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards. Gives priority to LEAs that have: (1) the highest number of disadvantaged students; (2) the highest number of schools identified for school improvement, corrective action, or restructuring; and (3) the lowest number of teachers certified by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards. Requires LEAs to use such grants to: (1) partner with institutions of higher education or other appropriate entities in conducting grant activities; (2) provide teachers participating in the Targeted High Need Initiative program with training, mentoring, and technological resources; (3) cover the assessment fee for teachers who apply for certification by such Board and agree to teach at the participating school for at least three years after their certification; (4) provide specified monetary awards to teachers and their sponsoring schools after completion of the Targeted High Need Initiative program; and (5) conduct an independent evaluation of such program's affect on teaching quality and student performance.</summary>
</bill>
