<bill session="111" type="sr" number="196" updated="2013-07-20T00:18:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-19">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on freedom of the press, freedom of speech, and freedom of expression in Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412329"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2009-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-06-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6855" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6855" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6849-6850" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Respects: (1) the sovereignty, history, and culture of the Iranian people; and (2) the universal values of freedom of speech and freedom of the press in Iran and throughout the world. Supports: (1) the Iranian people as they take steps to peacefully express their voices, opinions, and aspirations; (2) journalists who take great risk to report on political events in Iran, including those surrounding the presidential election; and (3) efforts of the Broadcasting Board of Governors (BBG) to provide credible news within Iran through the Voice of America's (VOA) Persian News Network, and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty's (RFE/RL) Radio Farda. Condemns: (1) the detainment and intimidation of journalists in Iran and elsewhere throughout the world; and (2) restrictions on freedom of the press, freedom of speech, and freedom of expression in Iran and throughout the world.</summary>
</bill>
