<bill session="111" type="s" number="3331" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Economic Advisory Council Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Native American Economic Advisory Council, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3408"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3408-3409" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5452"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2010--Introduced.
Native American Economic Advisory Council Act of 2010 - Establishes the Native American Economic Advisory Council to assist the Executive Office of the President and federal agencies to ensure that Native Americans have: (1) the means and capacity to benefit from economic stimulus and growth; and (2) opportunities to participate in federal economic development and job growth programs. Directs the Council to: (1) prepare a compilation of successful business enterprises and joint ventures conducted by Native American organizations, including ventures of Native Corporations in Alaska; and (2) periodically sponsor and arrange conferences and training workshops on Native American business activities. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the head of a federal agency, in preparing the President's comments and recommendations to Congress about proposed legislation, to include an assessment of the legislation's economic impact on Native Americans.</summary>
</bill>
