<bill session="112" type="h" number="2486" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native Hawaiian and Other Pacific Islander Health Data Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for health data regarding Native Hawaiians and other Pacific Islanders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412418" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2011-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1282"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="71"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2011--Introduced.
Native Hawaiian and Other Pacific Islander Health Data Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the National Center for Health Statistics and other HHS agencies, to develop and implement an ongoing and sustainable national strategy for identifying and evaluating the health status and health care needs of Native Hawaiians and Other Pacific Islanders (NHOPI) populations living in the continental United States, Hawaii, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, Guam, the Republic of Palau, and the Republic of the Marshall Islands. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to conduct a preliminary health survey to identify the major areas and regions in which NHOPI people reside. Requires the survey to include health data and other data the Secretary determines to be: (1) useful in determining health status and health care needs, or (2) required for developing or implementing the national strategy. Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine to conduct a study on: (1) the standards and definitions of health care applied to health care systems in insular areas; (2) the status and performance of health care systems in such areas; (3) the effectiveness of donor aid in addressing health care needs and priorities in such areas; and (4) progress toward implementing recommendations of the Institute's Committee on Health Care Services in the United States-Associated Pacific Basin that are set forth in the 1998 report, "Pacific Partnerships for Health; Charting a New Course for the 21st Century."</summary>
</bill>
