<bill session="112" type="sr" number="466" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-22">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling for the release from prison of former Prime Minister of Ukraine Yulia Tymoshenko.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3287-3288" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-09-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="526">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 526.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2012 S6665-6666" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2012 S6666" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-22">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-09-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2113"/>
    <amendment number="s2863"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/22/2012--Passed Senate amended.
Condemns the politically motivated prosecution and imprisonment of former Prime Minister of Ukraine Yulia Tymoshenko. Expresses concern that: (1) the politicized prosecutions and detention of Ms. Tymoshenko and other members of her party took place in a country that is scheduled to assume chairmanship of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) in 2013, and (2) the politicized detention of Ms. Tymoshenko threatens to jeopardize ties between the United States and Ukraine. Calls for Ukraine to release Ms. Tymoshenko, to provide her with timely access to medical care, and to conduct the October parliamentary elections in a manner consistent with OSCE standards. Calls on the Department of State to institute a visa ban against those responsible for the imprisonment and mistreatment of Ms. Tymoshenko and the more than dozen political leaders associated with the 2004 Orange Revolution.</summary>
</bill>
