<bill session="111" type="s" number="1595" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deceptive Loan Check Elimination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit the distribution of any check or other negotiable instrument as part of a solicitation by a creditor for an extension of credit, to limit the liability of consumers in conjunction with such solicitations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9004"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Deceptive Loan Check Elimination Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act (TILA) to prohibit a person from extending any consumer credit through the use by the consumer of a check or other negotiable instrument sent by the creditor to solicit an extension of consumer credit, unless the consumer has requested it in writing. States that a nonnegotiable instrument that has the appearance of a negotiable instrument in connection with a solicitation for an extension of credit is not an application or request for purposes of this Act. Shields a consumer from liability for: (1) the principal amount of a negotiable instrument sent in violation of this Act; or (2) any interest, fee, or penalty charged in connection with such negotiable instrument. Prohibits any information relating to the liability of a consumer alleged by a creditor to have been established through a negotiable instrument sent in violation of this Act from being either reported to or received by any consumer reporting agency, or from being included in any consumer report.</summary>
</bill>
