<bill session="110" type="h" number="5878" updated="2013-07-19T21:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Troops to Nurse Teachers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize programs to increase the number of nurses within the Armed Forces through assistance for service as nurse faculty or education as nurses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2008-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2008-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2705"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2008--Introduced.
Troops to Nurse Teachers Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to carry out programs under which commissioned officers of the nurse corps: (1) serve as full-time faculty of accredited schools of nursing in exchange for additional service or in exchange for scholarships provided by the school to those accepting commissions in the nurse corps; (2) receive scholarships leading to a graduate degree in nursing in exchange for service as nursing school faculty and to undertake activities to encourage nurses to serve in the Armed Forces nurse corps; (3) receive nursing faculty career placement and continuing education assistance if they are retirement-eligible and have graduate degrees qualifying them as nurse instructors; or (4) receive, while serving after retirement as faculty at a nursing school, retired pay without reduction and a pay differential to ensure that compensation for faculty member service will not be less than the basic pay received before retirement.Requires: (1) any program established under this Act to last at least two years; and (2) the Secretary to assess each program to determine if it should be continued.</summary>
</bill>
