<bill session="111" type="s" number="3887" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a continuation and expansion of the Wounded Warrior Careers Demonstration program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Army to: (1) continue the Wounded Warrior Careers Demonstration (Careers) program being conducted in collaboration with the Army Wounded Warrior program at three locations pursuant to a memorandum of understanding between the Army and the National Organization on Disability; and (2) expand the Careers program to nine additional locations in FY2011. States that the purpose of the Careers program expansion shall be to identify and disseminate best practices related to employment counseling and job placement of severely wounded warriors into civilian communities and careers, and to assess various additional means to support the transition and reintegration of such warriors into such communities and careers. Requires: (1) all locations chosen under the expansion to have a large concentration of severely wounded warriors who are ready for career and employment counseling; and (2) the Careers program to be carried out at least until five years after the enactment of this Act. Allows Careers program services to be provided to severely wounded warriors of other branches of the Armed Forces pursuant to joint agreement. Directs the Secretary to continue to provide for the dissemination to other federal departments and agencies, state and local governments, and appropriate nonprofit organizations of lessons learned and best practices developed under the Careers program on the provision of benefits, services, and support to severely wounded warriors. Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to report on the Careers program to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
