<bill session="112" type="sr" number="243" updated="2013-07-20T02:12:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-29">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution promoting increased awareness, diagnosis, and treatment of atrial fibrillation to address the high morbidity and mortality rates and to prevent avoidable hospitalizations associated with the disease.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-07-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5051-5052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5051" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5077-5078" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="295"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Calls for the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to work with leaders in the medical community to explore ways to improve medical research, screening and prevention methods, and surveillance efforts to prevent and manage atrial fibrillation, including by: (1) advancing the development of process and outcome measures for the management of atrial fibrillation by national developers; (2) facilitating the adoption of evidence-based guidelines by the medical community to improve patient outcomes; (3) advancing atrial fibrillation research and education by encouraging basic science research to determine causes and optimal treatments, exploring development of screening tools and protocols to determine the risk of developing atrial fibrillation, and enhancing current surveillance and tracking systems to include atrial fibrillation; and (4) improving access to appropriate medical care for patients suffering from atrial fibrillation by encouraging education programs that promote collaboration among federal health agencies and that increase public and clinician awareness.</summary>
</bill>
