<bill session="110" type="s" number="177" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">McGee Creek Project Pipeline and Associated Facilities Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the McGee Creek Authority certain facilities of the McGee Creek Project, Oklahoma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-376.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2085"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2085"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
McGee Creek Project Pipeline and Associated Facilities Conveyance Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the McGee Creek Authority all U.S. rights to the pipeline and any associated facilities described in the Agreement Between the United States and McGee Creek Authority for the Purpose of Defining Responsibilities Related to and Implementing the Title Transfer of Certain Facilities at the McGee Creek Project, Oklahoma. Excludes the mineral estate from the conveyance. Provides that any rights and obligations under a specified contract between the Authority and the United States for the construction, operation, and maintenance of the McGee Creek Project shall remain in force. Requires the Secretary to complete any actions required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and the National Historic Preservation Act before such conveyance.</summary>
</bill>
