<bill session="111" type="s" number="1633" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to establish a program to issue Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2010-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9029"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9029" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="723">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 723.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3192"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the Secretary of State, to: (1) establish the APEC Business Travel Program, under which the DHS Secretary may issue Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards to eligible U.S. citizens, including business leaders and government officials actively engaged in Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) business, provided such an individual is first approved in one of the international trusted traveler programs of DHS, such as Global Entry, NEXUS, and SENTRI.; and (2) cease issuance of such cards in the interest of the United States. Authorizes the DHS Secretary to collect a fee for such cards, the revenues from which shall not exceed Program costs in a fiscal year. Establishes in the Treasury an APEC Business Travel Program Account, into which such fees shall be deposited.</summary>
</bill>
