<bill session="111" type="h" number="1727" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-30T12:50:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-30T12:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Managing Arson Through Criminal History (MATCH) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Managing Arson Through Criminal History (MATCH) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish guidelines and incentives for States to establish criminal arsonist and criminal bomber registries and to require the Attorney General to establish a national criminal arsonist and criminal bomber registry program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2009-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Schiff moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10094-10099" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1727.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-09-30T12:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10094-10097" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1684"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1684"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2009--Passed House amended.
Managing Arson Through Criminal History (MATCH) Act of 2009 - Directs the Attorney General to maintain at the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) a national database for each criminal arsonist or bomber (an individual convicted of an arson or bombing offense), to be known as the National Criminal Arsonist and Criminal Bomber Registry. Limits the use of such Registry and disclosures therefrom to law enforcement purposes. Requires the Attorney General to: (1) ensure that updated information about a criminal arsonist or bomber is immediately available to all relevant jurisdictions (i.e., states, the District of Columbia, territories and possessions, and federally recognized Indian tribes); (2) provide notification to a jurisdiction in which the criminal arsonist or bomber is an employee, a student, or a resident; (3) establish and maintain a national arsonist and bomber Internet site which includes relevant information for each criminal arsonist or bomber; (4) establish guidelines for correction of erroneous information in the Registry or Internet site; and (5) develop and support software to enable jurisdictions to participate in the Registry and Internet site. Prohibits access by the public to information on the Internet site. Sets forth the information required to be included in the Registry by the arsonist or bomber and by jurisdictions, including identifying information, physical descriptions, photographs, and fingerprints. Allows expungement of information from the Registry for juveniles after five years. Requires notification to criminal arsonists and bombers of registration requirements and the duty to register. Requires jurisdictions to participate in the Registry before the later of three years after the enactment of this Act or one year after software provided by the Attorney General is made available to such jurisdictions. Reduces criminal justice assistance grants for jurisdictions that fail to comply with the requirements of this Act. Allows federally recognized Indian tribes to elect to participate in the Registry. Grants the federal government and jurisdictions immunity from liability for good faith conduct under this Act. Directs the Attorney General to establish and implement a Criminal Arsonist and Bomber Management Assistance program to award grants to jurisdictions to offset the costs of implementing this Act. Allows increased grant payments to jurisdictions that exceed deadlines for compliance with this Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY2010-FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
