<bill session="112" type="s" number="3615" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Seafood Marketing and Development Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance national seafood marketing efforts through the creation of a National Seafood Marketing and Development Fund, Regional Seafood Marketing Boards and a National Coordinating Committee and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
National Seafood Marketing and Development Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish Regional Seafood Marketing Boards. Designates states eligible to have members appointed to Boards of the: (1) Northeast Atlantic, (2) Mid and South Atlantic, (3) Gulf and Caribbean, (4) Pacific, and (5) West and North Pacific. Requires the Secretary to solicit nominations for members of each Board from the public and to seek recommendations from the governors of states in the geographical area of each Board. Sets forth the seafood industry expertise requirements for Board members. Requires the establishment of a National Coordinating Committee. Authorizes each Board to prepare an annual marketing plan, including grant award requirements and plans to coordinate activities with those of other Boards. Permits plans to include marketing activities referencing a particular brand or trade name and addressing projects designed to promote the consumption or purchase of a specific seafood species or group of similar seafood. Directs each Board to make grants to carry out projects consistent with a Board marketing plan. Requires grantees to provide at least 50% of the total estimated cost of the project. Establishes within the U.S. Treasury the National Seafood Marketing and Development Fund to be used by the Secretary to make annual grants to Boards.</summary>
</bill>
