<bill session="111" type="h" number="6229" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Developing Innovative Partnerships and Learning Opportunities that Motivate Achievement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DIPLOMA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen student achievement and graduation rates and prepare young people for college, careers, and citizenship through innovative partnerships that meet the comprehensive needs of children and youth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3595"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Introduced.
Developing Innovative Partnerships and Learning Opportunities that Motivate Achievement Act or DIPLOMA Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award renewable five year grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local consortia that include a local educational agency (LEA) and other community partners to: (1) ensure the academic, physical, social, emotional, and civic development of disadvantaged youth; and (2) strengthen their families and communities. Requires each state grantee to develop and implement a state child and youth strategy that assesses children's needs and the assets within the state that can be mobilized, coordinated, and integrated to achieve quantifiable progress toward goals that include ensuring that: (1) children are ready for school; (2) students are engaged and achieving in school; (3) students are physically, mentally, socially, and emotionally healthy; (4) schools and neighborhoods are safe and provide a positive climate for learning; (5) families are supportive and engaged in their children's education; (6) students are ready for postsecondary education and 21st Century careers; and (7) students are contributing to their communities. Directs the consortia to develop and implement a local child and youth strategy that integrates multiple private and public services into a comprehensive, coordinated continuum of services directed toward achieving quantifiable progress toward such goals. Requires the Secretary to award competitive grants directly to local consortia if appropriated funds fall below a specified amount.</summary>
</bill>
