<bill session="113" type="h" number="2467" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Abandoned Mine Lands Cleanup and Taxpayer Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Abandoned Mine Reclamation and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Mining Reform and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that production of all locatable minerals from mining claims located under the general mining laws, or mineral concentrates or products derived from locatable minerals from such mining claims, shall be subject to a royalty of 12.5 percent of the gross income from mining, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Abandoned Mine Lands Cleanup and Taxpayer Fairness Act - Mining Reform and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013 - Applies this Act to any mining claim, millsite claim, or tunnel site claim located under the general mining laws or used for beneficiation or mineral processing activities, regardless of whether legal and beneficial title to the mineral is held by the United States. Subjects production of locatable minerals to a royalty of 12.5% of the gross income from mining. Prescribes a hardrock mining claim maintenance fee for each unpatented mining claim, mill, or tunnel site on federally owned lands. Designates certain wilderness study areas, areas of critical environmental concern, and related areas as not open to location of mining claims. Permits a state or local government or Indian tribe to petition the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) for withdrawal of specific federal land from operation of the general mining laws in order to protect specific values. Instructs the Secretary to ensure that mineral activities on federal land subject to a claim are carefully controlled to prevent undue degradation of public lands and resources. Prescribes requirements for the exploration permit process and for operations permits, including financial assurances. Requires restoration of lands to a condition capable of supporting prior uses or other beneficial uses. Amends the National Materials and Minerals Policy, Research and Development Act of 1980 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to initiate prompt actions to improve the availability and analysis of mineral data in public land use decision-making with respect to National Forest System lands. Repeals the Building Stone Act and the Saline Placer Act. Abandoned Mine Reclamation and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013 - Requires each operator of a hardrock mining operation to: (1) pay the Secretary a displaced material reclamation fee of 7 cents per ton of displaced material, and (2) submit a notarized statement of the amount of displaced materials produced during mineral activities during the previous calendar year. Requires the Secretary to adjust such fees every five years to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) of the Department of Labor (or more frequently if the Secretary determines an adjustment to be reasonable). Establishes the Abandoned Mine Cleanup Fund for: (1) deposit of such fees, and (2) use for grants to public entities for reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by past mineral activities on certain federal lands.</summary>
</bill>
