<bill session="111" type="s" number="1047" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Internet Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School And Family Education about the Internet Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote Internet safety education and cybercrime prevention initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
School And Family Education about the Internet Act of 2009 or the SAFE Internet Act - Authorizes the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to eligible entities to carry out an age-appropriate, research-based Internet safety education program and other activities relating to Internet safety. Defines "eligible entity" as: (1) a local educational agency, a nonprofit organization, or a partnership between a state educational agency and one or more local educational agencies; or (2) a consortium of elementary schools or secondary schools collaborating with such an entity. Requires the Director, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) enter into contracts with one or more private companies, government agencies, or nonprofit organizations to complete a study on Internet safety; and (2) provide technical assistance to recipients of such grants.</summary>
</bill>
