<bill session="109" type="hr" number="922" updated="2013-07-19T19:02:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning cross-border terrorism against Israel by Hamas and Hezbollah and the complicity in these acts of terrorist aggression by Syria and Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2006-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="921"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="923"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="926"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="1044"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sr" number="534"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2006--Introduced.
Declares unwavering support for Israel and affirms that as a sovereign state Israel is entitled to act appropriately in self-defense against Hezbollah, Hamas, and the states that support them. Finds that the cross-border attacks and kidnappings by Hezbollah and Hamas constitute acts of international terrorism and aggression. Endorses President George W. Bush's statements that: (1) "Israel has a right to defend herself. Every nation must defend herself against terrorist attacks and the killing of innocent life. It's a necessary part of the 21st century."; and (2) "If you really want the situation to settle down, the (Israeli) soldiers need to be returned." Condemns in the strongest terms: (1) the criminal and terrorist acts of aggression against Israel and its armed forces; (2) the terrorist groups Hezbollah and Hamas; and (3) the primary state sponsors of global terrorism and the patrons of Hezbollah and Hamas, Iran and Syria. Demands that Iran and Syria respect Lebanon's sovereignty and withdraw all military and security personnel from Lebanon and cease their support for international terrorism. Calls upon the government of Lebanon to: (1) condemn Hezbollah's actions and make the utmost effort to facilitate the safe and unconditional return of the kidnapped Israeli soldiers; and (2) enforce its sovereignty throughout the country, maintain effective border control, and take immediate action to begin disarming all Lebanese militias. Calls upon the international community to join with the United States in holding Iran and Syria accountable for their support for unprovoked terrorist aggression against Israel. Calls for the immediate and unconditional release of all the kidnapped Israeli soldiers. Expresses deepest condolences to the families of all the innocent victims of the recent violence.</summary>
</bill>
