<bill session="110" type="h" number="3910" updated="2013-07-19T21:38:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to allow any Federal employee who has performed sufficient service to entitle such employee to the maximum annuity percentage allowable under the Civil Service Retirement System to terminate retirement deductions from pay.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400415"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2007--Introduced.
Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to prescribe regulations to allow federal employees who have performed sufficient service to qualify for the maximum annuity available under the Civil Service Retirement System to elect to terminate retirement deductions from their basic pay.Declares that an employee who makes such an election does not, by virtue of such election: (1) cease to be subject to civil service retirement provisions; (2) forfeit the right to have any subsequently accruing sick leave taken into account for purposes of computing what unused sick days are included in an annuity; (3) cease to be eligible to continue contributing to the Thrift Savings Fund; or (4) cease to be eligible to make any deposit remaining due.</summary>
</bill>
