<bill session="111" type="h" number="6426" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Moving Outdoors in Nature Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out programs and activities for connecting children and families with the outdoors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
Moving Outdoors in Nature Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to develop and implement a five-year Moving Outdoors in Nature State Strategy for connecting children, youth, and families with the outdoors. Requires each Strategy to provide for: (1) local planning; and (2) subgrants to local entities for the implementation of the strategy through one or more of the programs, activities, or initiatives relating to outdoor recreation as described in this Act. Requires eligible entities receiving funds under this Act to submit annual reports on the implementation of their strategies. Directs the President to issue a national strategy for connecting children, youth, and families with the outdoors. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to conduct a study of national significance on the health impacts of the programs under this Act. Requires the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees and disseminate best practices that emerge from the state strategies funded by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
