<bill session="111" type="h" number="2660" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Capital Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require the appropriate Federal banking agencies to prescribe capital standards for certain special purpose entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2009--Introduced.
Regulatory Capital Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require each appropriate federal banking agency to prescribe capital standards, including a leverage limit and a risk-based capital requirement, for special purpose entities, or similar types of vehicles or entities, that are sponsored by insured depository institutions it regulates. Requires such capital standards to conform, to the extent practicable, with the capital standards prescribed under the Act. Authorizes an appropriate federal banking agency, by regulation, to establish any additional relevant capital measures for such entities or vehicles necessary to guard against the risk that they become undercapitalized. Requires the appropriate federal banking agencies to define jointly a "special purpose entity," with a focus on trusts and other legal entities established by or for an insured depository institution to fulfill narrow, specific, or temporary objectives, including: (1) the holding of financial assets transferred during a securitization process; (2) issuing applicable securities representing claims on such assets; (3) receiving and reinvesting cash flows from such assets; and (4) distributing proceeds to holders of the securities.</summary>
</bill>
