<bill session="113" type="h" number="2321" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia National Guard Home Rule Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend to the Mayor of the District of Columbia the same authority over the National Guard of the District of Columbia as the Governors of the several States exercise over the National Guard of those States with respect to administration of the National Guard and its use to respond to natural disasters and other civil disturbances, while ensuring that the President retains control of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to respond to homeland defense emergencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E839"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2013--Introduced.
District of Columbia National Guard Home Rule Act - Amends the District of Columbia Code to make the Mayor of the District of Columbia (under current law, the President of the United States) the Commander-in-Chief of the National Guard of the District. Provides that, notwithstanding the authority of the Mayor of the District of Columbia as such Commander-in-Chief, the President shall retain control over units and members of the District of Columbia National Guard to conduct necessary and appropriate homeland defense activities.</summary>
</bill>
