<bill session="111" type="s" number="3569" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Subsea Hydrocarbon Imagery and Planning Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the ability of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to respond to releases of subsea oil and gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5747-5748"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5748" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2010--Introduced.
Subsea Hydrocarbon Imagery and Planning Act of 2010 - Directs the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to conduct a comprehensive review of the current state of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and its capacity to monitor, map, and track subsea hydrocarbons. Sets forth required elements of the review, including reviews of technological capabilities relevant to identifying releases of oil or natural gas after a spill and recommendations for long-term monitoring and assessment. Requires the Under Secretary, not later than one year after enactment of this Act, to establish a hydrocarbon monitoring and assessment program based on the recommendations developed under the comprehensive review. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Secretary of Commerce, out of any funds in the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund not otherwise appropriated, $15 million to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
