<bill session="113" type="h" number="568" updated="2013-11-02T06:23:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require that the Office of Personnel Management submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 113-154.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-16T19:24:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="111">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 111.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2748"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1338"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2013--Reported to House amended.
Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), not later than March 31 of each year, to report to Congress on the use of official time by federal employees. Requires each federal agency, not later than December 31 of each year, to submit to OPM information required for OPM's report to Congress. Defines "official time" as any period of time granted to a federal employee to perform representational or consultative functions in labor-management relations during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status. Requires OPM's report to Congress to include: (1) the total amount of official time granted to employees, (2) the average amount of official time expended per bargaining unit employee, (3) the specific types of activities or purposes for which official time was granted and the impact which the granting of such official time had on agency operations, (4) the total number of employees to whom official time was granted and the total number of such employees who were not engaged in any work activities or purposes except those involving the use of official time, and (5) the total amount of compensation (including fringe benefits) afforded to employees in connection with activities or purposes for which they were granted official time. Requires the information submitted by OPM to be shown both agency-by-agency and for all agencies and to be accompanied by corresponding information in previous reports, together with appropriate comparisons and analyses.</summary>
</bill>
