<bill session="111" type="sr" number="502" updated="2013-07-20T00:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution eliminating secret Senate holds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2010-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2711" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3657"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2010--Introduced.
Amends Rule VII (Morning Business) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate (or their designees) to recognize a notice of intent of a Senator who is a member of their caucus to object to proceeding to a measure or matter only if the Senator: (1) submits the notice of intent in writing to the appropriate Leader (or designee) and grants in the notice permission for the Leader (or designee) to object in the Senator's name; and (2) within two session days after such submission, submits for inclusion in the Congressional Record and in the applicable calendar a specified notice of the Senator's intent to object to proceeding to such measure or matter. Requires the Secretary of the Senate to maintain for both the Senate Calendar of Business and the Senate Executive Calendar a separate section entitled "Notices of Intent to Object to Proceeding." Authorizes a Senator to have an item relating to that Senator removed from a calendar to which it was added by submitting for inclusion in the Congressional Record a notice specifying that the Senator does not object to proceeding to such measure or matter.</summary>
</bill>
