<bill session="113" type="s" number="765" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Indian Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to help provide relief to State education budgets during a recovering economy, to help fulfill the Federal mandate to provide higher educational opportunities for Native American Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1658"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2013--Introduced.
Native American Indian Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to pay institutions of higher education the out-of-state tuition of their Indian students if the schools are required to provide a tuition-free education, with the support of their state, to Native American Indian students in fulfillment of a condition under which the college or state received its original grant of land and facilities from the federal government. Limits that payment each fiscal year to the institution's total out-of-state tuition for Native American Indian students in academic year 2012-2013. Treats such payments as reimbursements to such institutions from their states. Rescinds unobligated discretionary appropriations to offset the costs of this program.</summary>
</bill>
