<bill session="112" type="s" number="1491" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PURPA PLUS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PURPA's Legislative Upgrade to State Authority Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to expand the electric rate-setting authority of States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5261-5262"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
PURPA's Legislative Upgrade to State Authority Act or PURPA PLUS Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA), with respect to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) authority to prescribe rules requiring electric utilities to offer to sell and purchase electric energy to and from any qualifying cogeneration or small power production facility. Permits state regulatory authorities or nonregulated electric utilities, acting under state authority, to set rates exceeding the incremental cost of alternative electric energy for purchases from any such qualifying facility of up to two megawatts capacity. (Current law requires FERC to set rates that do not exceed the incremental cost to the electric utility of alternative electric energy.)</summary>
</bill>
