<bill session="109" type="s" number="3725" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Sentencing Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce the disparity in punishment between crack and powder cocaine offenses, to more broadly focus the punishment for drug offenders on the seriousness of the offense and the culpability of the offender, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2006-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cocaine"/>
    <term name="Crack (Drug)"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2006--Introduced.
Drug Sentencing Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to to decrease mandatory minimum sentencing thresholds for powder cocaine and increase such thresholds for crack cocaine. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend federal sentencing guidelines to: (1) reflect changes to mandatory minimum sentences made by this Act; (2) provide increased sentences for defendants who use violence or weapons in the course of a drug trafficking offense or who play an active role in the commission of such offenses; and (3) limit sentencing for defendants who play a lesser role in the commission of drug offenses and who receive little or no compensation from their crime. Requires the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to carry out a pilot program for home detention of nonviolent prisoners age 65 or older.</summary>
</bill>
