<bill session="109" type="h" number="1127" updated="2013-07-19T19:14:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energy Production Incentive Reform and Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the renewable energy production incentive and to provide that a qualified renewable energy facility shall not be assigned a priority for eligibility or allocation of appropriated funds on the basis of the energy source used at such facility.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2005-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural wastes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Production Incentive Reform and Reauthorization Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to revise requirements for the program of renewable energy production incentive payments. Requires payment to the owner or operator of qualified renewable energy facilities by: (1) the Secretary of Energy for electric energy generated and sold from solar, wind, or geothermal energy; (2) the Secretary of Agriculture for electric energy generated and sold from biomass (unless the electric energy is generated from heat derived from landfill gases); and (3) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for electric energy generated and sold from heat derived from landfill gases. Prohibits such officials from establishing criteria or procedures that have the effect of assigning to an eligible, qualified renewable energy facility a higher or lower priority for eligibility or allocation of payments on the basis of the energy source used at such facility. Identifies the eligibility window for such payments as occurring before October 1, 2016. Increases the per kilowatt hour incentive payment. Extends the program through September 30, 2026.</summary>
</bill>
