<bill session="110" type="s" number="720" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Army Specialist Joseph P. Micks Federal Flag Code Amendment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Army Specialist Joseph P. Micks Federal Flag Code Amendment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 4, United States Code, to authorize the Governor of a State, territory, or possession of the United States to order that the National flag be flown at half-staff in that State, territory, or possession in the event of the death of a member of the Armed Forces from that State, territory, or possession who dies while serving on active duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2490"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="195">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="692"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="692"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="692"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Army Specialist Joseph P. Micks Federal Flag Code Amendment Act of 2007 - Amends federal law with regard to the flying of the national flag at half-staff to: (1) allow a governor of a state, territory, or possession of the United States (governor) to proclaim that the national flag be flown at half-staff upon the death of a member of the Armed Forces from the governor's state, territory, or possession who dies while serving on active duty; and (2) require, when a governor issues such a proclamation, the national flag flown at any federal installation or facility in that state, territory, or possession to be flown at half-staff consistent with that proclamation.</summary>
</bill>
