<bill session="111" type="h" number="4737" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HUD Demonstration Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize assistance for capacity building for community development and affordable housing under section 4 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2010-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2010--Introduced.
HUD Demonstration Improvement Act of 2010 - Amends the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 with respect to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) community development and affordable housing programs. Adds the National Urban League and the Housing Partnership Network to the list of entities eligible for HUD assistance to develop the capacity and ability of community development corporations and community housing development organizations to undertake community development and affordable housing projects and programs. Allows the use of such assistance in urban and rural areas. Directs the HUD Secretary, by notice, to require an entity, as a condition of eligibility for such assistance for a fiscal year, to submit a plan describing the manner in which the entity will use such assistance, including descriptions meeting specified requirements. (Thus replaces the requirement that the HUD Secretary establish necessary requirements to carry out the Act.)</summary>
</bill>
