<bill session="113" type="h" number="3217" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Pay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the pay and allowances of members of the Armed Forces in the event that the debt limit is reached or during a funding gap, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6064"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2013--Introduced.
Military Pay Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, in the event that U.S. debt reaches the statutory limit, to make available the following: (1) such amounts as the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard) determines to be necessary to continue to provide pay and allowances without interruption to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components, as well as civilian employees of the Department of Defense (DOD) (and the Department of Homeland Security [DHS] in the case of the Coast Guard) and designated contractors; and (2) such amounts as the President certifies to Congress as are necessary to carry out vital national security priorities. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, during any funding gap, to make emergency appropriations: (1) to continue to provide pay and allowances without interruption to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components, as well as civilian employees of DOD (and DHS in the case of the Coast Guard) and designated contractors; and (2) for such amounts as the President certifies to Congress as are necessary to carry out vital national security priorities.</summary>
</bill>
