<bill session="109" type="s" number="1804" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agricultural Assistance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide emergency assistance to agricultural producers who have suffered losses as a result of drought, Hurricane Katrina, and other natural disasters occurring during 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2005-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3702"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3702"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Seeds"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2005--Introduced.
Agricultural Assistance Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make payments to producers on a farm eligible for 2005 direct payments for a covered commodity if: (1) the farm is located in a disaster county; or (2) the producers on the farm have incurred qualifying 2005 crop losses due to damaging weather or related conditions. Requires as a condition for such assistance that producers of: (1) a covered commodity and other insurable commodities for each of the next two crop years obtain at least federal crop catastrophic risk protection, and in the event of contract violation repay any assistance received; and (2) eligible noninsurable commodities for each of the next two crop or calendar years file the required paperwork, and pay the administrative fee by the state filing deadline, and in the event of contract violation repay any assistance received. Directs the Secretary to: (1) make emergency financial assistance to producers (crop, timber, fisheries, and livestock producers) who have incurred losses in a disaster-designated county; (2) use Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) funds to carry out the 2002 Livestock Compensation Program for livestock producers in a disaster county, and for catfish producers; (3) transfer CCC funds for emergency surplus removal of agricultural commodities; (4) use CCC funds for assistance to fruit and vegetable producers, and for producers and first handlers of the 2005 cottonseed crop; and (5) make CCC commodity or payment assistance to certain loan-eligible first processors in a disaster-designated state to partially compensate producers and first processors for crop and other losses related to such natural disaster.</summary>
</bill>
