<bill session="112" type="h" number="3124" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Advisory Committee Act to increase the transparency of Federal advisory committees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400074"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2011-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1144"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2011--Introduced.
Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 2011 - Amends the Federal Advisory Committee Act (FACA) to require appointments to federal agency advisory committees to be made without regard to political affiliation or activity, unless otherwise required by federal statute. Directs the head of an agency, prior to appointing members to an advisory committee, to give interested persons an opportunity to suggest potential committee members. Requires an individual appointed to an advisory committee who is not a full-time or permanent part-time officer or employee of the federal government to be designated as: (1) a special government employee if the individual is providing advice based on the individual's expertise or experience, or (2) a representative if the individual is representing the views of an entity outside of the federal government. Prohibits an agency from designating committee members as representatives to avoid subjecting them to federal ethics rules and requirements. Requires each agency head to ensure that advice and recommendations of an advisory committee that reports to the agency are the result of the advisory committee's judgment, independent from the agency. Provides that an individual who is not an officer or employee of the federal government shall be regarded as a member of an advisory committee if the individual regularly attends and participates in committee meetings as if the individual were a member, even if the individual does not have the right to vote or veto the advice or recommendations of the committee. Requires each agency head to make available on the agency's Internet site specified information about each of the agency's advisory committees and their activities and to designate an Advisory Committee Management Officer to be responsible for the establishment, management, and supervision of the agency's advisory committees. Requires the Comptroller General to review compliance by agencies with FACA.</summary>
</bill>
