<bill session="112" type="h" number="2894" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Firefighters Special Operation Task Force Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration to provide assistance to firefighting task forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2011--Introduced.
Firefighters Special Operation Task Force Act - Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration to award up to 100 grants for task forces (two or more fire services that collectively consist of at least 50 firefighting personnel, operating under a cooperative agreement to coordinate incident response) each fiscal year for: (1) salary and benefits to hire firefighting personnel, (2) training, (3) equipment or support systems, (4) communications between task force members and a local police department or hospital or with any other appropriate governmental or private sector entity, and (5) compatibility and interoperability of training and equipment.Requires the Administrator to give priority to task forces serving geographic areas that have a high population density or that are located within 50 miles of: (1) a nuclear power facility; (2) a large facility that produces, treats, or refines chemicals or petroleum products; (3) a business district of national significance; or (4) a location with one or more critical infrastructures.Requires grantees to obtain non-federal matching funds of at least 55% of the amount awarded by the Administrator for each fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
