<bill session="109" type="h" number="3302" updated="2013-07-19T19:33:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Media Ownership Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prevent excessive concentration of ownership of the nation's media outlets, to restore fairness in broadcasting, and to foster and promote localism, diversity, and competition in the media.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2005-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate divestiture"/>
    <term name="Deregulation"/>
    <term name="Direct broadcast satellites"/>
    <term name="Economic concentration"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Fairness doctrine"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Public interest"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television industry"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2005--Introduced.
Media Ownership Reform Act of 2005 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a broadcast licensee to afford reasonable opportunity for the discussion of conflicting views on issues of public importance, consistent with the rules and policies of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) in effect on January 1, 1987. Prohibits the FCC from permitting any license for a commercial television broadcast station to be granted, transferred, or assigned to any party if such action would result in that party owning, operating, or controlling, or having a cognizable interest in: (1) stations which have an aggregate national audience reach exceeding 25 percent; or (2) such station and a cable television system whose service area overlaps with such commercial station's predicted Grade B contour. Requires any party currently having a license in excess of such limits to divest as necessary to comply with such limits within one year. Reduces from eight to three years the duration of a broadcast station operating license. Directs the FCC to modify its regulations concerning ownership of national and local radio broadcast stations to place limitations on such ownership (such limitations varying depending on the number of stations in the local market area). Declares invalid and without legal effect the final rules adopted by the FCC pursuant to its media ownership proceeding, and announced on June 2, 2003 (such rules providing specified media ownership deregulation). Reinstates the rules in effect prior to such rules. Requires the FCC to: (1) conduct, every three years, a review process concerning media ownership; and (2) prescribe rules to prevent persons controlling the distribution of video programming over network distribution systems from acquiring unreasonable proportions of such programming from subsidiaries or affiliates. Requires each broadcast licensee, at least every two years, to submit to the FCC, and publish, a report on how the station is meeting the requirement to serve the public interest. Requires each licensee to hold at least two community public hearings per year to determine local needs and interests.</summary>
</bill>
