<bill session="112" type="sr" number="388" updated="2013-07-20T02:13:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-01">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commemorating the 200th anniversary of the War of 1812 and "The Star Spangled Banner", and recognizing the historical significance, heroic human endeavor, and sacrifice of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Revenue Marine Service, and State militias, during the War of 1812.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2012-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-03-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1369" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1369" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1208-1209" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Honors the memory of the people of the United States who came together during the War of 1812, particularly those who gave their lives during the "Second War of Independence." Commends the men and women of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, and Coast Guard, and the state National Guards, who preserve the ideals of freedom, democracy, and the pursuit of happiness that were guaranteed by the victories of the War of 1812. Congratulates the U.S. Armed Forces, the National Parks Service, the Maryland War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission, and all other organizations and individuals involved in preserving and promoting the history of this great country, and supports their commemoration of the War of 1812 and "The Star Spangled Banner." Calls on the people of the United States to join in the commemoration of the bicentennial of the War of 1812 and "The Star Spangled Banner," and to celebrate that at the end of the war, as Francis Scott Key wrote, "our flag was still there."</summary>
</bill>
