<bill session="113" type="h" number="446" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Criminal Justice Commission Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Criminal Justice Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2013--Introduced.
National Criminal Justice Commission Act of 2013 - Establishes the National Criminal Justice Commission. Directs the Commission to: (1) review all areas of the criminal justice system, including federal, state, local, and tribal governments' criminal justice costs, practices, and policies; (2) make findings regarding such review and recommendations for changes to prevent, deter, and reduce crime and violence, reduce recidivism, improve cost-effectiveness, and ensure the interests of justice at every step of the criminal justice system; (3) consult with government and nongovernment leaders, including the United States Sentencing Commission; and (4) submit a final report on its findings, conclusions, and recommendations to Congress, the President, and state, local, and tribal governments and make such report available to the public. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Commission should work toward unanimously supported findings and recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
