<bill session="111" type="s" number="1576" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Forest Carbon Incentives Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a carbon incentives program to achieve supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions on private forest land of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8771-8772"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8772-8773" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/2009--Introduced.
Forest Carbon Incentives Program Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a carbon incentives program to achieve supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions on private forest land of the United States. Directs the Secretary (subject to specified requirements) to provide to owners of eligible land financial incentive payments for: (1) eligible practices that measurably increase carbon sequestration and storage over a designated period, as specified through a climate mitigation contract; and (2) permanent avoided deforestation agreements (i.e., permanent conservation easements that cover eligible land that will not be converted for development). Directs the Secretary to: (1) specify requirements to address intentional or unintentional reversal of carbon sequestration during the contract period; (2) issue regulations that specify eligible practices and related compensation rates, standards, and guidelines; (3) establish and implement protocols that provide monitoring and verification of compliance with such contracts; (4) report on progress toward reaching specified levels of carbon sequestration and storage through such contracts; and (5) adjust (at least every two years) eligible practices and compensation rates for future contracts based on the results.</summary>
</bill>
