<bill session="111" type="s" number="2877" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carbon Limits and Energy for America's Renewal (CLEAR) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program to regulate the entry of fossil carbon into commerce in the United States to promote clean energy jobs and economic growth and avoid dangerous interference with the climate of the Earth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13036"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2009--Introduced.
Carbon Limits and Energy for America's Renewal (CLEAR) Act - Requires the President to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions relative to 2005 levels by 20% by 2020, 30% by 2025, 42% by 2030, and 83% by 2050 through this Act. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program to reduce the emission of GHGs by: (1) placing a gradually declining limitation on the quantity of fossil carbon (carbon) permitted to be sold; and (2) requiring each first seller to surrender periodically to the Secretary a number of carbon shares equal to the quantity of covered carbon it produces or imports or be subject to a penalty. Defines a "first seller" as an entity in the business of producing or importing fossil carbon or production process carbon. Requires the President to establish a maximum aggregate quantity of carbon, and a corresponding number of carbon shares, permitted to be introduced into commerce for 2012. Requires that number of shares: (1) for 2012, 2013, and 2014 to be equal to the approximate level of carbon likely to be required by the economy during 2012; and (2) for each subsequent year to be reduced from the quantity of the previous year by 0.25%. Sets forth provisions concerning auctioning, purchasing, and selling shares. Restricts participation in such auctions to first sellers. Prohibits first sellers from directly or indirectly creating, purchasing, selling, or trading carbon share derivatives. Requires the Secretary to: (1) impose fees for the production process of carbon associated with commodities imported for sale; and (2) transfer collected fees and penalties to the Clean Energy Reinvestment Trust Fund established by this Act; and (3) distribute amounts from such Fund to individuals and entities that are unable to compete due to unfair market prices arising from disparate carbon limits or fees among countries. Requires the Secretary to: (1) promulgate regulations for the establishment, operation, and oversight of markets for carbon share derivatives; (2) provide carbon shares in excess of the aggregate quantity for carbon that is sequestered, injected, or embedded; (3) reduce the aggregate quantity of carbon shares for reductions of carbon emissions attributable solely to voluntary carbon reduction purchases; (4) establish a program that enables individuals to borrow against any future energy security dividends in order to make investments in energy efficiency or clean energy technologies and services; and (5) establish an Office of Consumer Advocacy for energy consumers. Establishes the Carbon Refund Trust Fund to be funded from auction proceeds and to distribute tax-free energy security dividends to U.S. residents.</summary>
</bill>
