<bill session="112" type="h" number="6360" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oversight and Accountability in Wartime Contracting Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase accountability in contracts for overseas contingency operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Oversight and Government Reform, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-07">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-07">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/2012--Introduced.
Oversight and Accountability in Wartime Contracting Act of 2012 - Directs the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) to: (1) limit contracts entered into in connection with an overseas contingency operation (OCO) to three years for competitively bid contracts and one year for non-competitively bid contracts and competitively bid contracts for which only one offer was received; (2) limit any contract for services in connection with an OCO to a single tier of subcontractors; and (3) require contractors, subcontractors, and related entities to consent to personal jurisdiction in covered civil actions (e.g., civil actions alleging rape or serious bodily injury, wrongful death, or breach of contract) involving overseas contracts valued at not less than $1 million. Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to develop a strategy for ensuring that timely, accurate, and complete information on contractor performance is included in past performance databases used by executive agencies for making source selection decisions. Requires the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and State, and the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to certify to specified congressional committees that a country for which funds have been appropriated for a capital project with an estimated value in excess of $1 million has the capability (in both financial and human resources) to effectively maintain and utilize the project. Establishes offices to oversee contingency contracting in DOD, the Department of State, and USAID. Requires the Inspectors General of DOD, the Department of State, and USAID to review and evaluate noncompetitive contracts and one-offer contracts and to submit annual reports on such contracts to specified committees of Congress. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) exclude from the gross income of DOD civilian employees compensation for active service in a combat zone, and (2) allow such employees a reduced estate tax rate and an exemption from the excise tax on local and toll telephone service. Directs the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with certain federal officials, to submit to specified congressional committees a report on the success of the U.S. mission in Afghanistan. Extends through FY2013 the annual reporting requirement of the Secretary of Defense on the plan for sustaining Afghanistan security forces.</summary>
</bill>
