<bill session="111" type="s" number="3535" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Next Generation Energy Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">New Alternative Transportation to Give Americans Solutions Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Nuclear Energy Expansion Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the energy security of the United States by promoting the production of natural gas, nuclear energy, and renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2010-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2010--Introduced.
Next Generation Energy Security Act of 2010 - Amends provisions of the Internal Revenue Code relating to natural gas and alternative fuels, nuclear energy, and renewable energy. New Alternative Transportation to Give Americans Solutions Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend through December 31, 2019, the alternative fuel excise tax credit for fuels and fuel mixtures involving compressed or liquefied natural gas, the alternative motor vehicle income tax credit for vehicles powered by compressed or liquefied natural gas, the tax credit for alternative fuel refueling property for property relating to electricity, and the energy tax credit and the tax credit for the production of electricity from renewable resources; (2) allow an offset against the regular and alternative minimum tax (AMT) for alternative motor vehicle and refueling property tax credit amounts and provide for the transferability of credit amounts; (3) allow through December 31, 2019, the issuance of tax-exempt natural gas vehicle bonds to finance natural gas vehicle projects; (4) increase the alternative motor vehicle tax credit for the purchase of vehicles fueled by compressed natural gas or liquefied natural gas; (5) modify the definition of a new qualified alternative fuel motor vehicle to include a vehicle that is capable of operating on compressed or liquefied natural gas and gasoline or diesel fuel; (6) allow expensing of the cost of manufacturing facility property used to produce vehicles fueled by compressed natural gas or liquefied natural gas; (7) increase and extend through December 31, 2019, the tax credit for alternative fuel vehicle refueling properties for vehicles using compressed or liquefied natural gas; (8) allow accelerated depreciation of advanced nuclear power facilities; (9) allow new tax credits for investment in nuclear power facility construction and for costs related to such construction; (10) make nuclear power facilities eligible for the qualifying advanced energy project tax credit; (11) increase and extend through 2030 the tax credit for production of electricity from advanced nuclear power facilities; (12) allow a new tax credit for the creation of jobs in the commercial nuclear power industry; and (13) increase the number of plug-in electric vehicles eligible for a tax credit. Requires federal agencies to purchase dedicated alternative fuel vehicles when complying with mandatory federal fleet alternative fuel vehicle purchase requirements, unless such agencies can show that alternative fuel is unavailable or purchasing such vehicles would be impractical. Directs the Secretary of Energy to make grants to manufacturers of light duty and heavy duty natural gas vehicles for the development of energy-efficient engines. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) should streamline the process for certification of natural gas vehicle retrofit kits. Nuclear Energy Expansion Act of 2010 - Expresses the sense of the Senate that Congress should adopt an energy policy that encourages the construction of new nuclear power plants beginning in 2010 through at least 2030. Requires the use of grant funds for five-year periods beginning on January 1, 2012, to increase the number and amounts of nuclear science talent expansion and competitiveness grants, support science primary and secondary education, and expand workforce training in the nuclear energy industry. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to establish and implement an expedited procedure for issuing combined construction and operating licenses for qualified new nuclear reactors. Increases funding for the Department of Energy (DOE) Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to expand the authority of the Secretary of Energy to cover the cost of delays in the full power operation of nuclear power plants. Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to extend the suspension of duties on watertube boilers, reactor vessel heads, and pressurizers for use in nuclear reactors. Amends the Atomic Energy Act to authorize the Secretary of Energy to: (1) purchase, lease, or access facilities for nuclear fuel management purposes, including for storage, processing, or fuel fabrication involving materials containing plutonium; and (2) enter into agreements with local governments for locating used fuel storage facilities. Declares it the policy of the United States to recycle used nuclear fuel to advance energy independence, maximize the energy potential of nuclear fuel in a poliferation-resistant manner, and reduce the volume and toxicity of high-level radioactive waste. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into partnerships with private industry for nuclear fuel recycling. Directs the Secretary to: (1) designate commercial used nuclear fuel treatment and recycling centers; and (2) establish a Next Generation Reactor System demonstration project. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to require the Secretary to: (1) analyze and assess the recharging infrastructure for plug-in electric drive vehicles; and (2) establish a program to support the deployment and integration of plug-in electric drive vehicles in multiple regions of the United States. Provides for the transfer of unobligated amounts under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to cover revenue losses resulting from the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
