<bill session="109" type="h" number="5096" updated="2013-07-19T19:49:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patents Depend on Quality Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PDQ Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 35, United States Code, to modify certain procedures relating to patents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2006-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E524-525"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2006--Introduced.
Patents Depend on Quality Act of 2006 or PDQ Act - Allows a person to request that the grant or reissue of a patent be reconsidered by the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) by filing an opposition seeking to invalidate one or more claims in the patent. Requires the Director of USPTO to issue and publish a certificate, in accordance with the final decision by the panel of three administrative patent judges, canceling any claim of the patent determined to be unpatentable and incorporating into the patent any new or amended claims determined to be patentable. Allows a third party to submit for consideration, and for inclusion in the record, prior art to determine whether the invention was known, used, in public use, or on sale or would have been obvious. Provides that a third party requester whose request for a reexamination results in an order is not estopped from asserting a claim which the third party requester could have raised during such reexamination proceedings. Allows treble damages only upon a finding of willful infringement of a patent. (Current law allows treble damages for any patent infringement.) Sets forth the grounds for a finding of willful infringement. Permits transfers of venue. Requires a court to stay an injunction pending appeal upon an affirmative showing that: (1) the stay would not result in irreparable harm to the owner of the patent; and (2) the balance of hardships from the stay does not favor the owner of the patent.</summary>
</bill>
