<bill session="111" type="s" number="994" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Breast Cancer Education and Awareness Requires Learning Young Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EARLY Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to increase awareness of the risks of breast cancer in young women and provide support for young women diagnosed with breast cancer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2009--Introduced.
Breast Cancer Education and Awareness Requires Learning Young Act of 2009 or EARLY Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to conduct a national evidence-based education campaign: (1) to increase public awareness regarding the threats posed by breast cancer to young women, including the particular risks faced by certain racial, ethnic and cultural groups; and (2) focusing on awareness of risk factors and achieving early detection through community-centered informational forums, public service advertisements, and media campaigns. Directs the Secretary to award grants to entities to establish national multimedia campaigns that: (1) will encourage young women to be aware of their personal risk factors, strategies and methods for increasing early detection and self awareness, genetic counseling and testing, imaging-based screening methods, evidence based preventative lifestyle changes, and other appropriate breast cancer early detection and risk reduction strategies; (2) will encourage young women of specific higher-risk populations to talk to their medical practitioners about those risks and methods for appropriate screening and surveillance; and (3) may include advertising through specified media. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to: (1) establish an advisory committee to assist in creating and conducting the public education campaign; (2) conduct an education campaign to increase awareness among health care professionals; and (3) conduct prevention research. Directs the Secretary to award grants to organizations and institutions to provide to young women diagnosed with breast cancer substantive assistance and health information from credible sources on: (1) education and counseling regarding fertility preservation; (2) social, emotional, psychosocial, financial, lifestyle, and caregiver support; (3) familial risk factors; and (4) risk reduction strategies to reduce recurrence or metastasis.</summary>
</bill>
