<bill session="111" type="s" number="3916" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission to study and report on the impact on consumers of permitting an increase in the amount of ethanol blended with gasoline for use in gasoline-powered engines used in vehicles operated in interstate commerce, on public streets and roads, or offroad, appliances such as lawn mowers and other nonvehicular devices, and marine engines, and to require the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to study and report on any safety or reliability impact of such an increase on motor vehicle engines and fuel systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7811"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to study and report to specified congressional committees on the potential impact on consumers of increasing the amount of ethanol blended with gasoline or other petroleum products for use as fuel for internal combustion engines. Directs the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) to study and report to specified congressional committees on whether the use of ethanol-gasoline blends of more than 10% by volume ethanol in motor vehicles will have an adverse impact on tailpipe emissions, exhaust temperatures, catalytic converters, and motor vehicle engine performance and durability. Declares the sense of Congress that federal departments and agencies should withhold from approving any increase in the use of ethanol or ethanol-gasoline blends as fuel for internal combustion engines until 30 days after both such reports have been submitted.</summary>
</bill>
