<bill session="112" type="h" number="2484" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia Research and Control Amendments Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act of 1998 to include a comprehensive and integrated strategy to address harmful algal blooms and hypoxia, to provide for the development and implementation of a comprehensive research plan and action strategy to reduce harmful algal blooms and hypoxia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2011-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 15.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16T15:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 112-333, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16T16:01:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Natural Resources Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 9, 2012.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T12:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-02-09T12:49:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="271">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 271.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1701"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2011--Introduced.
Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia Research and Control Amendments Act of 2011 - Amends the Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act of 1998 to require the President, through the Committee on Environment and Natural Resources of the National Science and Technology Council, to establish an Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia (Task Force). Directs the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, through the Task Force, to: (1) establish and maintain a National Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Program to develop a national strategy to address marine and freshwater harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events; (2) promote activities and an action strategy to implement such Program; (3) oversee the development and review of regional research and action plans for addressing marine and freshwater harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events; (4) maintain a focus on technology research and development for each of the categories of marine harmful algal blooms, freshwater harmful algal blooms, and hypoxia in monitoring, predicting, preventing, controling, mitigating, and responding to events; (5) expand the existing electronic clearinghouse to provide information about such harmful algal blooms and hypoxia; and (6) develop a mechanism to provide a reliable and cost-effective supply of toxin standards for comparative research. Establishes the duties of the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) under such Program. Directs the Administrator, through the Mississippi River/Gulf of Mexico Watershed Nutrient Task Force, to submit an updated assessment and a revised action plan prior to the implementation of any plan developed under such Act. Directs the Task Force to complete and submit to Congress and the President a plan for reducing, mitigating, and controlling hypoxia in the Chesapeake Bay.</summary>
</bill>
