<bill session="112" type="s" number="2019" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Los Angeles Residential Helicopter Noise Relief Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to prescribe regulations to reduce helicopter noise pollution in certain residential areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8738-8739"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8739" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2677"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2011--Introduced.
Los Angeles Residential Helicopter Noise Relief Act of 2011 - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to prescribe regulations for helicopter operations in Los Angeles County, California, that include requirements for helicopter flight paths and altitudes to reduce helicopter noise pollution in residential areas, increase safety, and minimize commercial aircraft delays. Requires the Administrator to exempt from such requirements helicopter operations related to emergency, law enforcement, or military activities. Directs the Administrator to make reasonable efforts to consult with local communities and local helicopter operators to develop regulations that meet the needs of local communities, helicopter operators, and the FAA.</summary>
</bill>
