<bill session="111" type="h" number="2631" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Affordable Gas Price Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the price of gasoline by allowing for offshore drilling, eliminating Federal obstacles to constructing refineries and providing incentives for investment in refineries, suspending Federal fuel taxes when gasoline prices reach a benchmark amount, and promoting free trade.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1247"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Affordable Gas Price Act - Declares without force or effect all provisions of existing federal law that prohibit spending appropriated funds to conduct oil or natural gas leasing and preleasing activities for any area of the Outer Continental Shelf. Revokes all existing withdrawals by the President under the authority of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to repeal: (1) the withdrawal of public lands within the Coastal Plain from entry or appropriation under federal mining or mineral leasing laws; and (2) the prohibition against the production, leasing, and development of oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR). Amends the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to shield from judicial review mandatory statements by certain federal officials regarding the environmental impact of federal actions upon the quality of the human environment. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) set forth additional incentives for investment in oil refineries; (2) suspend the tax on highway motor fuels when retail gasoline exceeds a certain benchmark; and (3) increase mileage reimbursement rates. Authorizes the President to extend normal trade relations treatment to the products of the Russian Federation and Kazakhstan.</summary>
</bill>
