<bill session="110" type="h" number="7327" updated="2013-07-19T21:33:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker, Retiree, and Employer Recovery Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Worker, Retiree, and Employer Recovery Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Worker, Retiree, and Employer Recovery Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Worker, Retiree, and Employer Recovery Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections related to the Pension Protection Act of 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and Labor discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Pomeroy asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10935-10943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-12-10T20:51:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10935-10943" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-12-11" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10914-10915" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2008-12-11">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2008-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-12-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-12-23">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-12-23" type="public" number="110-458">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-458.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3361"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6382"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/23/2008--Public Law.
Worker, Retiree, and Employer Recovery Act of 2008 - Title I: Technical Corrections Related to the Pension Protection Act of 2006 - Subtitle A: Technical Corrections Related to the Pension Protection Act of 2006 - (Sec. 101) Makes technical corrections to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to conform to the Pension Protection Act of 2006 regarding various specified items, including: (1) the target normal cost of benefits; (2) specified implementation and effective dates for certain requirements; (3) one-participant retirement plans; (4) special age-related rules in accrued benefit requirements for applicable defined benefit plans; (5) inapplicability in certain cases of the limitation on income deductions (for tax purposes) for employer contributions to one or more defined contribution plans; and (6) adjustments to averaging in the determination of the value of the assets of single-employer defined benefit pension plans for minimum funding purposes.(Sec. 110) Makes technical corrections to the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 with respect to railroad retirement payments to persons not entitled to an annuity.Subtitle B: Other Provisions - (Sec. 121) Requires that the value of assets for any ERISA plan under the averaging method be adjusted for expected earnings (in addition to contributions and distributions, as under current law).(Sec. 122) Modifies the interest rate assumption required with respect to certain small employer plans.(Sec. 123) Makes technical corrections to the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to require treatment of a rate of return or a method of crediting interest as a market rate of return and a permissible method of crediting interest in special age-related rules for governmental defined benefit plans.(Sec. 124) Prescribes a special rule for exclusion from gross income of certain reimbursements from governmental plans for health care expenses of a deceased accident or health care plan participant's beneficiary.(Sec. 125) Requires treatment as a qualified rollover contribution of any airline payment amount received by a qualified airline employee in an airline carrier bankruptcy which is transferred to a Roth IRA within 180 days of receipt.(Sec. 126) Revises asset valuation rules for certain commercial airline benefit plans.(Sec. 127) Increases by $4 the penalties for failure to file partnership returns and S corporation returns.Title II: Pension Provisions Relating to Economic Crisis - (Sec. 201) Provides a waiver of minimum distribution requirements for certain retirement plans and accounts for 2009.(Sec. 202) Revises requirements for determining the shortfall amortization base for a single-employer defined benefit pension plan the value of whose plan assets exceeds the plan funding target for any plan year beginning after 2007 and before 2011.(Sec. 203) Modifies for FY2009 application of the limitation on benefit accruals for single-employer plans with severe funding shortfalls. Requires substituting the plan's adjusted funding target attainment percentage for the preceding plan year for the adjusted funding target attainment percentage for the new plan year, but only if the percentage for the preceding plan year is greater.(Sec. 204) Provides for delay of the designation of multiemployer benefit plans as endangered or critical during FY2009.(Sec. 205) Extends the funding improvement and rehabilitation periods for multiemployer benefit plans in endangered or critical status for FY2008 or FY2009.</summary>
</bill>
