<bill session="111" type="s" number="3027" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">P2P Cyber Protection and Informed User Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent the inadvertent disclosure of information on a computer through certain "peer-to-peer" file sharing programs without first providing notice and obtaining consent from an owner or authorized user of the computer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1319"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2010--Introduced.
P2P Cyber Protection and Informed User Act - Makes it unlawful for any commercial entity that developed a file sharing program or distributed such a program (if the distributor is owned by the developing entity) to install, make available for installation, or download a file sharing program without: (1) immediately before program installation or downloading, providing conspicuous notice that the program allows files to be searched and copied by one or more other computers and obtaining informed consent to the installation; and (2) immediately before initial activation of a file sharing function of the program, providing conspicuous notice of which files will be made available and obtaining informed consent. Exempts: (1) modifications or upgrades of a program that was originally installed in compliance with this Act, provided certain requirements are met; and (2) pre-installed software. Makes it unlawful for such an entity to prevent the reasonable efforts of an owner or authorized user to block the installation of such a program or to prevent such a user from having a reasonable way to disable or remove the program. Makes this Act non-applicable to lawfully authorized investigative, protective, and intelligence activities of U.S. intelligence agencies or of U.S. and state law enforcement agencies. Treats a violation of this Act as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Prohibits construing this Act to limit or supersede any other federal or state law.</summary>
</bill>
