<bill session="112" type="h" number="3367" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disabled Public Safety Officers Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide public safety officer disability benefits to officers disabled before the enactment of the Federal public safety officer disability benefits law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2011-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2011--Introduced.
Disabled Public Safety Officers Fairness Act of 2011 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide for payment of disability benefits to public safety officers who became permanently and totally disabled prior to the enactment of such Act. Allows a public safety officer seeking a benefit on the basis of having been permanently and totally disabled as the direct result of a catastrophic injury sustained in the line of duty before the date of enactment of such Act to file a claim during the same period that would be applicable to an officer disabled after the date of enactment, except that in lieu of such a period beginning on the date of the injury it shall begin on the date of the enactment of this Act. Applies this Act to any public safety officer alive on or after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
