<bill session="109" type="h" number="3568" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Angie Fatino Save Our Children from Meth Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to provide for the transfer of ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, and phenylpropanolamine to schedule V of the schedules of controlled substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6494"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Angie Fatino Save Our Children from Meth Act of 2005 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to direct the Attorney General to transfer to schedule V ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, and phenylpropanolamine. Makes this provision inapplicable with respect to pseudoephedrine when contained in a product that is in a liquid, liquid capsule, or liquid-filled gel capsule, that does not contain more than 360 milligrams of pseudoephedrine, and that is approved under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (pseudoephedrine contained in such product shall then be considered a list I chemical). Revises the definition of "regulated transaction" to exclude specified transactions involving drugs or products that the Attorney General determines are being diverted for illicit purposes. Places restrictions on the sale of list I and schedule V pseudoephedrine products. Requires a registrant of list I products to: (1) place the products where the customers do not have direct access to them; (2) maintain a sales logbook that identifies the products, purchasers, dates, and times of sales; and (3) not sell such a product to persons under age 18. Prohibits a registrant of schedule V products that do not require prescriptions from dispensing such a product to a prospective purchaser under age 18. Sets penalties for violations. Prohibits any person from knowingly or intentionally purchasing at retail: (1) more than one list I pseudoephedrine product during a 24-hour period without a prescription; (2) more than 7,500 milligrams of pseudoephedrine in list I or schedule V products during a 30-day period without a prescription; or (3) such a list I product without legibly signing the appropriate logbook.</summary>
</bill>
