<bill session="109" type="h" number="5713" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United Nations Budget Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To pursue a policy of weighted voting with respect to the budgets of the United Nations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
United Nations Budget Reform Act of 2006 - States that it shall be U.S. policy to use its influence at the United Nations to pursue: (1) General Assembly adoption of formal procedures for the use of weighted voting in the General Assembly with respect to the adoption of regularly assessed budgets for biennial periods (the proportionate value of a member's vote to be equal to such member's assessed budget contribution); and (2) U.N. adoption of formal procedures that prohibit passage of a regularly assessed budget for a biennial period without first obtaining the unanimous consent of all members. Provides that if the United Nations adopts such a budget without unanimous consent the United States shall appropriate, but withhold from expenditure, 25% of its budget contributions which shall be available for release to the United Nations until the earlier of five years or until the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the United Nations is in compliance with this Act (such funds to revert to the United States if there is no certification).</summary>
</bill>
