<bill session="109" type="hr" number="861" updated="2013-07-19T19:01:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-16T11:17:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-16T11:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Declaring that the United States will prevail in the Global War on Terror, the struggle to protect freedom from the terrorist adversary.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 868 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 861 with 10 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. During consideration of H. Res. 861, pursuant to H. Res. 868, and notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the resolution to a time designated by the Speaker.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 868 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 868.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4024-4123" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4024" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 861 with 10 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. During consideration of H. Res. 861, pursuant to H. Res. 868, and notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the resolution to a time designated by the Speaker.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten hours of debate on H. Res. 861.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 861.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15T22:44:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 868, the Speaker announced that further consideration of H. Res. 861 would be resumed on Friday, June 16, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4139-4174" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16T09:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with the remaining 61 minutes of debate on H. Res. 861.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4173" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-06-16T11:17:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="288" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 256 - 153, 5 Present (Roll no. 288).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16T11:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="868"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2006--Passed House without amendment.
Honors: (1) all Americans who have taken an active part in the Global War on Terror, whether as first responders protecting the homeland, as servicemembers overseas, as diplomats and intelligence officers, or in other roles; and (2) the sacrifices of the U.S. Armed Forces and the Coalition partners, the Iraqis and Afghans who fight alongside them, their families, and others who risk their lives to help defend freedom. Declares that: (1) it is not in the U.S. national interest to set an arbitrary withdrawal or redeployment date for U.S. Armed Forces from Iraq; and (2) the United States is committed to completion of the mission to create a sovereign, free, and united Iraq. Congratulates Prime Minister Nuri Al-Maliki and the Iraqi people on the courage they have shown by participating, in increasing millions, in the 2005 elections and on the formation of the first government under Iraq's new constitution. Calls upon the nations of the world to promote global peace and security by standing with the United States and other Coalition partners to support the efforts of the Iraqi and Afghan people to live in freedom. Declares that the United States will prevail in the Global War on Terror.</summary>
</bill>
