<bill session="109" type="s" number="616" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indecent and Gratuitous and Excessively Violent Programming Control Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to inform the American public and to protect children from increasing depictions of indecent and gratuitous and excessive violent material on television, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2005-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2649-2650"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2650-2652" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio programs"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Violence in mass media"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2005--Introduced.
Indecent and Gratuitous and Excessively Violent Programming Control Act of 2005 - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to assess the: (1) technological and practical effectiveness of measures that require television broadcast station licensees (licensees) and multichannel video programming distributors (MVPDs) to rate and encode programming that could be blocked by parents; (2) prevalence of violent programming on television; and (3) effectiveness of the current system for rating and encoding violent programming. Requires the FCC, if it determines that current rating and encoding measures are not effective in protecting children from violent or indecent video programming, to initiate and conclude a rulemaking proceeding to: (1) prohibit licensees from broadcasting such programming during children's viewing hours; or (2) adopt measures that adequately protect children from such programming. Provides exemptions, including premium and pay-for-view services. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to provide forfeiture penalties for licensees or license applicants determined to have broadcast obscene, indecent, or profane language or images. Outlines factors to be considered in determining penalty amounts, including: (1) whether the material was live or recorded, scripted or unscripted; (2) whether a time delay blocking mechanism was implemented; (3) the size of the audience and market; and (4) whether the violation occurred during children's viewing hours. Requires public hearings with respect to violations of indecency prohibitions. Requires licensees or permittees that receive programming from an unaffiliated network to be given reasonable opportunity to review all recorded or scripted programming in advance, and to preempt any violating programming. Requires each licensee, MVPD, and other programming service to provide a warning of the specific content of each recorded or scripted program it broadcasts. Directs the FCC to: (1) assess the effectiveness of voluntary programming rating standards; and (2) require each licensee to broadcast daily at least six hours of educational and informational programming. Expresses the sense of Congress that each licensee, MVPD, and other programming service should reinstitute or adopt provisions set forth in the "Television Code of the National Association of Broadcasters," as adopted on December 6, 1951.</summary>
</bill>
