<bill session="111" type="s" number="3972" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Blue Alert Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage, enhance, and integrate Blue Alert plans throughout the United States in order to disseminate information when a law enforcement officer is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8064"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6235"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
National Blue Alert Act of 2010 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish a national Blue Alert communications network within the Department of Justice (DOJ) to disseminate information when a law enforcement officer is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty; and (2) assign a DOJ officer to act as the national coordinator of the Blue Alert communications network. Sets forth the duties of the national coordinator, including encouraging states and local governments to develop additional Blue Alert plans, establishing voluntary guidelines for states and local governments to use in developing such plans, developing protocols for efforts to apprehend suspects, and establishing an advisory group to assist states, local governments, law enforcement agencies, and other entities in initiating, facilitating, and promoting Blue Alert plans. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act to require the use of public safety and community policing grants to assist states in developing and enhancing a Blue Alert plan and communications network.</summary>
</bill>
