<bill session="113" type="h" number="2496" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the deployment of United States Armed Forces in support of a United Nations or mutual security treaty military operation absent express prior statutory authorization from Congress for such deployment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Introduced.
States that it is U.S. policy that: (1) the constitutional authority of Congress and the system of self-government and popular control established by the framers of the Constitution shall be protected, and (2) any vote of the United Nations (U.N.) Security Council or any party to a mutual security treaty shall only be advisory and does not constitute authority to deploy U.S. Armed Forces. Prohibits: (1) any unit or individual of the U.S. Armed Forces from being deployed in support of a U.N. or a mutual security treaty military operation absent prior statutory authorization from Congress; and (2) funds from being appropriated or otherwise made available to any U.S. executive agency in order to carry out any U.N. or mutual security treaty military operation unless the President obtains prior authorization by Congress, as required under article I, section 8 of the Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
