<bill session="110" type="h" number="6290" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lewis and Clark Mount Hood Wilderness Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain land in the State of Oregon as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1267-1268"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="647"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Skiing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2008--Introduced.
Lewis and Clark Mount Hood Wilderness Act of 2008 - Designates specified wilderness additions in Oregon as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Designates certain federal land as the "Richard L. Kohnstamm Memorial Area." Designates the Roaring River Wilderness as a potential wilderness area. Requires the inclusion of certain federal land in the Mount Hood Wilderness and the Salmon-Huckleberry Wilderness. Designates specified segments of creeks and rivers in Mount Hood National Forest as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system.Amends the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area Act to permanently protect the Hood River, Oregon. Establishes the Mount Hood National Recreation Area (Area) within the Mount Hood National Forest. Requires, upon completion of the Cooper Spur-Government Camp land exchange, the establishment of a Crystal Springs Watershed Special Resources Management Unit (Unit). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to manage the federal lands known as Upper Big Bottom and Cultus Creek in a manner that preserves the natural and primitive character of such lands for recreational, scenic, and scientific use. Provides for land exchanges in Clackasmas County, Oregon and in the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area. Requires the Secretary to impose conditions on land conveyances to require that applicable construction activities and alterations be conducted according to: (1) nationally recognized building and property maintenance codes; and (2) nationally recognized codes for development in the wildland-urban interface and wildfire hazard mitigation. Directs the Secretary participate in the development of a transportation plan developed by the Oregon Department of Transportation for the Mount Hood Region to promote economic development, preserve the landscape of the Mount Hood Region, and enhance public safety. Directs the Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes with treaty-reserved gathering rights on land encompassed by Mount Hood National Forest, to develop and implement a management plan that meets the cultural foods obligations of the United States under applicable treaties.Authorizes the construction of a trail in Mount Hood National Forest suitable for use by persons with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
