<bill session="109" type="h" number="1041" updated="2013-07-19T19:13:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security KidSave Accounts Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act to provide each American child with a KidSave Account, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400429"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2005-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grandparents"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Inheritance tax"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2005--Introduced.
Social Security KidSave Accounts Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to create a new part B (KidSave Accounts). Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to establish in the name of each individual born on or after January 1, 2006, an individual retirement account in the Thrift Savings Fund known as a KidSave Account. Requires such Account to be treated in the same manner as an account maintained by a Federal employee under the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) (into which contributions by or on behalf of the individual are deposited into one or more designated investment funds). Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund to each account holder's KidSave Account: (1) $2,000, on the date such individual's KidSave Account is established; plus (2) other, including rollover, contributions, by or on behalf of the individual, the aggregate amount of which in the case of any individual below age 19 is capped at $500 for any taxable year. Provides for the treatment of distributions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income any rollovers into a KidSave Account.</summary>
</bill>
