<bill session="111" type="h" number="2587" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Neighborhood Stabilization Program Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the reinvestment by States and localities of profits under the Neighborhood Stabilization Program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Neighborhood Stabilization Program Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008, as amended by the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, to revise requirements for the use by state and local governments of emergency assistance provided to them for the redevelopment of abandoned and foreclosed homes and residential properties. Requires any revenue generated, during a specified two-year reinvestment period, from the sale, rental, redevelopment, rehabilitation, or any other eligible use in excess of the cost to acquire and redevelop or rehabilitate an abandoned or foreclosed home or residential property, to be provided to and used by the state or local government in accordance with, and in furtherance of, the intent and provisions of this Act. Requires transfer of the revenue so generated in excess of such cost to the special account established in the U.S. Treasury into which money received as gifts and proceeds from the sale or redemption of gifts shall be deposited. Requires such revenues to be used for public debt reduction only.</summary>
</bill>
