<bill session="113" type="sr" number="268" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:23-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-06">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning the September 2013 terrorist attack at the Westgate Mall in Nairobi, Kenya, and reaffirming United States support for the people and Government of Kenya, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7414" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="234">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 234.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-11-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="hr" number="394"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kenya"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2013--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Condemns the atrocities and terrorist attack that occurred at the Westgate Mall in Nairobi, Kenya, from September 21 through 24, 2013. Offers condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of those who were killed in the attack and expresses hope for the recovery of the wounded, including U.S. citizens. Recognizes the many heroic acts by Kenyan citizens, first responders, and the Kenya Red Cross to rescue those caught in the Westgate Mall attack. Reaffirms U.S. support for the efforts of the government and people of Kenya to combat terrorism, promote tolerance, and bring the perpetrators of the Westgate Mall attack to justice. Commends Kenya's continued participation in the African Union Mission in Somalia. Recognizes Kenya as an important U.S. ally and partner.</summary>
</bill>
