<bill session="109" type="h" number="298" updated="2013-07-19T19:06:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Interior to provide public access to Farallon National Wildlife Refuge, Navassa National Wildlife Refuge, and Desecheo National Wildlife Refuge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2005-01-25" withdrawn="2005-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1183"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1183"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2005--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, to provide public access to, use of, and recreational opportunities at the Farallon National Wildlife Refuge, Navassa National Wildlife Refuge, and Desecheo National Wildlife Refuge pursuant to special use permits issued under the Refuge Recreation Act, the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, and regulations issued under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to limit access to such refuges to specified time periods but requires access to each refuge during at least one period each year. Directs the Secretary, in issuing special use permits under this Act, to give priority to permit applications that do not negatively impact opportunities for wildlife-dependent recreation. Authorizes the Secretary to include in any permit issued under this Act conditions that the Secretary determines necessary to protect fish and wildlife populations or habitat, or public health and safety.</summary>
</bill>
