<bill session="111" type="h" number="2702" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Suspend Brazil GSP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To suspend the application of Generalized System of Preferences for Brazil until such time as Brazil complies with its obligations toward the United States under the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Brazil"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2009--Introduced.
Suspend Brazil GSP Act - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to: (1) attain the immediate return of Sean Goldman and all children of the United States who are being held wrongfully in Brazil in contravention of the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction (Hague Convention); and (2) impress upon Brazil the importance of abiding by their obligations under the Hague Convention with respect to international child abduction cases involving children from the United States. Directs the President to: (1) notify World Trade Organization (WTO) member countries, not later than seven days after enactment of this Act, that the United States is suspending the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP) for Brazil; and (2) suspend, not later than 30 days after enactment of this Act, GSP and duty-free treatment for Brazil. Authorizes the President to reinstate GSP and duty-free treatment for Brazil if he certifies to Congress that Brazil is complying with the Hague Convention.</summary>
</bill>
