<bill session="110" type="h" number="3782" updated="2013-07-19T21:37:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reiterate the exclusivity of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 as the sole authority to permit the conduct of electronic surveillance, to modernize surveillance authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-10-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/2007--Introduced.
Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Improvement and Enhancement Act of 2007 - Prescribes the federal law provisions governing domestic electronic surveillance. Directs the President to brief each member of the congressional intelligence committees on: (1) the Terrorist Surveillance Program of the National Security Agency (NSA); and (2) any program which involves the electronic surveillance of U.S. persons in the United States for foreign intelligence purposes which is conducted by any federal department or entity without fully complying with the prescribed federal law provisions. Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) concerning electronic surveillance to: (1) extend the period for the application for orders for emergency electronic surveillance; (2) increase the number of judges with jurisdiction to hear applications for and grant orders approving electronic surveillance within the United States; and (3) provide for the acquisition of foreign communications between or among non-U.S. persons. Provides for the implementation of a document management system for, and authorizes additional personnel for the preparation and consideration of, electronic surveillance applications. Expands electronic surveillance authority under specified conditions, including when Congress is unable to convene because of an attack upon the United States. Repeals the Protect America Act. States that on December 31, 2009: (1) this Act shall cease to have effect; and (2) the provisions of law amended by this Act are amended to read as they read before this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
