<bill session="111" type="sr" number="64" updated="2013-07-20T00:16:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the need for the Environmental Protection Agency to end decades of delay and utilize existing authority under the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act to comprehensively regulate coal combustion waste and the need for the Tennessee Valley Authority to be a national leader in technological innovation, low-cost power, and environmental stewardship.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2775" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2009--Introduced.
Recognizes the need for the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) immediately conduct reviews of all coal combustion waste impoundments and landfills to ensure the safety of people and the environment located in any area that may be threatened by a spill or release; (2) report to the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on the earliest date the Agency can regulate coal combustion waste using its authority under the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA); and (3) issue rules as quickly as possible on regulating coal combustion waste under RCRA. Recognizes the need for the Tennessee Valley Authority to meet Congress's intentions and be a national leader in technological innovation, low-cost power, and environmental stewardship.</summary>
</bill>
