<bill session="109" type="s" number="3526" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Land Consolidation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Indian Land Consolidation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Indian Land Consolidation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Indian Land Consolidation Act to modify certain requirements under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5963-5964"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5964" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator McCain without amendment. With written report No. 109-294.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="536">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 536.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/29/2006 S10803-10804" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-09-30" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/29/2006 S10803-10804" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-09T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-09T15:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Probate law and practice"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5119"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/30/2006--Passed Senate amended.
Indian Land Consolidation Act Amendments of 2006 - Amends the Indian Land Consolidation Act (ILCA) to revise the meaning of land and improvements to specify that the term "permament improvement" to land subject to probate means only a decedent's interest in any improvement permanently affixed to a parcel of trust or restricted lands that was owned in whole or in part by the decedent immediately before his or her death. Revises requirements for the purchase option at probate. Requires the Secretary, in the case of multiple requests to purchase an interest in a decedent's land, to sell the interest to the eligible purchaser selected by the applicable heir, devisee, or surviving spouse. Repeals the requirement for sale of such an interest by public auction or sealed bid.Applies only to wills executed after July 20, 2007, the presumption of joint tenancy in the devise of trust or restricted interests in the same parcel of land to more than one person.Provides that the threshold for an involuntary purchase at probate (5% of the entire undivided ownership of a parcel of land) refers to the interest of the decedent in the parcel at the time of death, rather than the interest passing to the heir. States that the only eligible purchasers of an interest in an involuntary sale at probate are: (1) the Secretary under the fractional interest acquisition program; or (2) the Indian tribe, where the interest would otherwise be inherited by a nonmember. Applies these new requirements only to interests in the estates of decedents who die after July 20, 2007. Authorizes the Secretary to postpone such application date for an additional year.</summary>
</bill>
