<bill session="110" type="s" number="2026" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agent Orange Equitable Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, chapter 11, to clarify that an award of benefits based on a regulatory presumption established pursuant to 28 U.S.C. section 1116 after September 30, 2002, cannot be made effective earlier than the date the regulatory presumption was established; and to clarify that the presumption of herbicide exposure provided by 38 U.S.C. section 1116(f) applies only to veterans who served in Vietnam on land or on Vietnam's inland waterways and not to those who served only in waters offshore or in airspace above.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Herbicides"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/6/2007--Introduced.
Agent Orange Equitable Compensation Act - States that awards of veterans' disability compensation based on a presumption of service-connection due to exposure to certain herbicide agents during service in Vietnam (Agent Orange compensation) shall not be effective earlier than the effective date of the regulation establishing such presumption. States that, for purposes of such presumption, a veteran will be considered to have served in Vietnam only if the veteran was physically present on land in Vietnam or on its inland waterways, and not if the veteran served only on the waters offshore or in airspace above.</summary>
</bill>
