<bill session="110" type="s" number="1024" updated="2013-07-19T22:29:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safer DATA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safer Drug Assessment Technology Advancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the underlying science of drug safety decisionmaking and strengthen the ability of the Food and Drug Administration to assess, manage, and communicate drug safety information to patients and providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2007-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug interactions"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2007--Introduced.
Safer Drug Assessment Technology Advancement Act or the Safer DATA Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish: (1) minimum standards for collection and transmission of postmarketing data elements from electronic health data systems; and (2) a validated and integrated postmarket risk identification and analysis system to integrate and analyze safety data from multiple sources.Directs the Secretary to establish and maintain an active surveillance infrastructure to collect and report data for pharmaceutical postmarket risk identification and analysis.Requires the Secretary to establish and implement procedures under which the Secretary may routinely collaborate with a qualified entity to: (1) clean, classify, or aggregate data collected and data that is publicly available or that is provided by the Secretary; (2) perform advanced research on identified drug safety risks; (3) identify safety questions that require further clinical study; and (4) convene an expert advisory committee to oversee the establishment of standards for the ethical and scientific uses for, and communication of, postmarketing data collected.Requires the Secretary to improve the transparency of pharmaceutical data and allow patients and health care providers better access to pharmaceutical data by developing and maintaining an Internet site that: (1) provides comprehensive drug safety information for prescription drugs; and (2) improves communication of drug safety information to patients and providers.</summary>
</bill>
