<bill session="113" type="h" number="2510" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Veterans Exposed to Toxic Chemicals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish within the Department of Defense centers of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to open burn pits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412558" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412562" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Helping Veterans Exposed to Toxic Chemicals Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish within the Department of Defense (DOD) three centers of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to open burn pits and other environmental exposures. Requires the Secretary to select for such centers entities that: (1) are equipped with the specialized equipment needed to study, diagnose, and treat health conditions relating to such exposure; (2) have a publication track record of post-deployment health exposures among veterans from Iraq and Afghanistan; (3) have collaborated with a geosciences department that has a medical geology division; (4) have developed animal models and in vitro models of dust immunology and lung injury from Iraq and Afghanistan; and (5) have expertise in allergy and immunology, pulmonary diseases, and industrial and management engineering. Directs the Secretary to ensure that the centers collaborate with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), institutions of higher education, and other appropriate public and private entities to carry out specified responsibilities, including to: (1) implement the comprehensive plan and strategy for DOD for the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to such exposure; and (2) provide for dissemination within DOD of best practices for the treatment of such conditions and the training of health professionals. Requires the center to have access to and make use of the data accumulated by the burn pits registry established under the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2012.</summary>
</bill>
