<bill session="111" type="hr" number="553" updated="2013-07-19T23:00:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System should protect and enhance consumer and business access to credit by utilizing the provisions of the Federal Reserve Act and the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, and reserving access to liquidity programs for those financial institutions that have maintained or increased lending activities since the height of our economic crisis in October 2008.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2009-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System should: (1) protect and enhance American consumers' and businesses' access to credit; (2) encourage credit card issuers, banks, and other creditors to recognize long-standing customers who are in good standing by not cutting their credit lines or raising their interest rates; and (3) reserve access to programs under the Federal Reserve Act and the Emergency Response Stabilization Act for those institutions that are working to increase consumer and business access to credit.</summary>
</bill>
