<bill session="111" type="h" number="86" updated="2013-07-19T23:12:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-09T20:36:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-09T20:36:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate an unused lighthouse reservation, provide management consistency by bringing the rocks and small islands along the coast of Orange County, California, and meet the original Congressional intent of preserving Orange County's rocks and small islands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To eliminate an unused lighthouse reservation, provide management consistency by incorporating the rocks and small islands along the coast of Orange County, California, into the California Coastal National Monument managed by the Bureau of Land Management, and meet the original Congressional intent of preserving Orange County's rocks and small islands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2009-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16T15:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-334.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-11-16T15:07:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="192">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 192.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13534-13535" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 86.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09T20:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14417-14418" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-12-09T20:36:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="946" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 397 - 4 (Roll no. 946).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/07/2009 H13534" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09T20:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09T20:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 111-269.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="539">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 539.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Removes the temporary reservation for park, scenic, or other public purposes of certain rocks, pinnacles, reefs, and islands in the Pacific Ocean within a mile of the coast of Orange County, California. Makes such rocks, pinnacles, reefs, and islands part of the California Coastal National Monument and requires that they be administered as part of the Monument. Repeals the lighthouse reservation with respect to the San Juan and San Mateo Rocks and the two rocks in the vicinity of Laguna Beach, off the coast of Orange County.</summary>
</bill>
