<bill session="112" type="s" number="1081" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Project Delivery Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, to streamline the environmental review process for highway projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Project Delivery Improvement Act of 2011 - Authorizes a state to select without competitive bidding or the approval of the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) one or more proprietary, patented, or experimental products for use in a federal-aid highway project. Declares that state use of such products shall not affect the eligibility of the state or highway project to receive federal funding. Repeals certain parkland preservation requirements prohibiting the Secretary from approving a transportation program or project requiring the use of public park lands unless there is no feasible alternative to the use of such land. Makes the lead agency responsible for determining the purpose of and need for a project. Decreases from 180 days to 90 days after publication in the Federal Register of a notice that a permit, license, or approval for a highway or public transportation capital project is final the deadline for filing a claim seeking judicial review of the permit, license, or approval. Places the burden of proof of the claim on the claimant. Authorizes a state to designate a highway project as a categorical exclusion (that does not involve significant environmental impact). Revises U.S. policy on public lands and wildlife and waterfowl refuges to exclude historic sites. Authorizes the Secretary to approve a transportation program or project (other than a park road or parkway project) requiring the use of a park, recreation area, or wildlife and waterfowl refuge only if the Governor of the state (or mayor or chief executive of the city, county, or borough with management responsibility for or ownership of the area) agrees that such project is the preferred alternative.</summary>
</bill>
