<bill session="110" type="s" number="1455" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Health Information Technology and Privacy Advancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of a health information technology and privacy system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6945-6946"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2007--Introduced.
National Health Information Technology and Privacy Advancement Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) provide federal governmental assistance to the planning and development of, and provide for the implementation of, a national program for the establishment and operation of a national health information technology and privacy system; (2) ensure that timely arrangements are made under which there can be national participation in the establishment and use of the system; and (3) provide for incentives for physicians to engage in electronic patient-provider interactions.Establishes the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology.Authorizes the establishment of a nonprofit national health information technology and privacy corporation to: (1) plan, initiate, construct, own, manage, and operate a national health information technology and privacy system; (2) furnish access to individuals and to authorized providers and payers of health care services; and (3) specify rules for allowing access to non-identifiable health care data for public health and research purposes.</summary>
</bill>
