<bill session="112" type="s" number="2218" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the United States Fire Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2012-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. With written report No. 112-180.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="447">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 447.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6229"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2012 - Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to: (1) revise references to the U.S. Fire Administration (USFA) to provide for its establishment within the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) (rather than within the Department of Commerce) and to change references to the head of FEMA as the Administrator (rather than the Director), (2) authorize the USFA Administrator to appoint a Deputy Administrator (current law requires the Deputy Administrator to be appointed by the President), (3) authorize the USFA Administrator to take such steps as the Administrator considers appropriate to educate the public and overcome public indifference as to individual preparedness (as well as to fire and fire prevention), and (4) authorize appropriations to carry out such Act through FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
