<bill session="111" type="h" number="2665" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Centers of Excellence for Regional Smart Growth Planning Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish national centers of excellence for regional smart growth planning, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2009--Introduced.
National Centers of Excellence for Regional Smart Growth Planning Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) designate not fewer than three national centers of excellence for regional smart growth planning, selected from metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs) that have demonstrated regional planning excellence; (2) develop guidelines for the designation and operation of the Centers; and (3) allocate specified funds to each Center to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Administrator to make grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities for: (1) improving the collection of data and the development of models for smart growth planning; (2) implementing comprehensive regional smart growth planning programs; (3) applying planning outcomes in regional transportation plans; and (4) working with local governments to coordinate land use, transportation, and air quality planning. Directs the Centers to: (1) collect and distribute to MPOs information and best practices about regional smart growth planning; (2) make research and development recommendations to EPA and other entities to improve the quality and ease of smart growth analysis; (3) work with institutions of higher education and state and federal agencies to improve smart growth analysis; and (4) provide technical assistance to grant recipients.</summary>
</bill>
