<bill session="109" type="s" number="3882" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Terrorism Prevention Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Classified Information Procedures Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to support the war on terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="602">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 602.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="3848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Antiaircraft missiles"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Depositions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virus diseases"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2006--Introduced.
Terrorism Prevention Act of 2006 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose criminal penalties for providing material support or resources to a perpetrator of international terrorism, or to a family member of or other person associated with such perpetrator, with the intent to facilitate, reward, or encourage international terrorism. Increases criminal penalties for providing material support or resources to terrorists and foreign terrorist organizations and for receiving military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization. Denies federal benefits to individuals convicted of a federal crime of terrorism. Classified Information Procedures Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the Classified Information Procedures Act (CIPA) to: (1) allow interlocutory appeals from any order for access to classified information (currently, appeals lie only from orders entered under CIPA); (2) require courts to grant certain ex parte government requests for CIPA protective orders; and (3) restrict access to classified information obtained from nondocumentary sources. Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) prohibit hoaxes relating to terrorist offenses; (2) increase penalties for hoaxes about the death, injury, or capture of a member of the Armed Forces (U.S.); (3) include threats against a corporation or governmental entity in the crime of mailing threatening communications; (4) modify provisions relating to terrorist murders, kidnappings, and assaults; (5) impose criminal penalties for terrorist offenses resulting in death; (6) authorize the death penalty for certain terrorist crimes; and (7) increase penalties for false statements or obstruction of justice involving international or domestic terrorism. Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to make certain notification requirements under such Act inapplicable to individuals seeking immigration benefits.</summary>
</bill>
