<bill session="111" type="s" number="3120" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FIND Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fugitive Information Networked Database Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage the entry of felony warrants into the National Crime Information Center database by States and provide additional resources for extradition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2010-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1620-1621"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1621-1623" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="970"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2010--Introduced.
Fugitive Information Networked Database Act of 2010 or the FIND Act - Directs the Attorney General to make one-year grants to states or Indian tribes to develop and implement or upgrade secure electronic warrant management systems for the preparation, submission, and validation of felony warrants that are compatible and interoperable with the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) database. Provides for set asides of grant funds to hire additional personnel to validate warrants entered into the NCIC database and for Indian tribes. Requires states that submit a grant renewal application to file with the Attorney General and appropriate county clerk's offices an annual report specifying: (1) the number of defendants, including indigent defendants, assessed or interviewed for pretrial release; (2) the number of failures to appear for a scheduled court appearance; and (3) the number and type of infractions committed by defendants while on pretrial release. Directs the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to provide state, local, and tribal government agencies the technology to make state and local warrant databases compatible and interoperative with the NCIC database. Directs the Comptroller General to report to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees on felony warrants issued by state, local, and tribal governments and entered into the NCIC database and on the apprehension and extradition of persons with active felony warrants. Directs the Attorney General to make grants to states and Indian tribes to extradite fugitives for prosecution. Requires states and Indian tribes applying for grants to report to the Attorney General on the number of active felony warrants they have issued.</summary>
</bill>
