<bill session="113" type="h" number="2850" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EPA Hydraulic Fracturing Study Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">EPA Hydraulic Fracturing Study Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain procedures in the conduct by the Environmental Protection Agency of its study of the potential impacts of hydraulic fracturing on drinking water resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-08-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 113-252.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-23T17:12:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="179">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 179.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Reported to House amended.
EPA Hydraulic Fracturing Study Improvement Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in conducting the study of the potential impacts of hydraulic fracturing on drinking water resources, with respect to which a request for information was issued in November 2012, to: prior to issuance and dissemination of any final or interim report summarizing EPA research on such relationship, consider such reports to be Highly Influential Scientific Assessments requiring peer review in accordance with specified EPA and Office of Management and Budget (OMB) policy documents; require the reports to meet the standards and procedures for the dissemination of influential scientific, financial, or statistical information set forth in the EPA's Guidelines for Ensuring and Maximizing the Quality, Objectivity, Utility, and Integrity of Information Disseminated by the Environmental Protection Agency, developed in response to guidelines issued by OMB under the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act for Fiscal Year 2001; and ensure that identification of the possible impacts included in such reports be accompanied by objective estimates of the probability, uncertainty, and consequence of each identified impact, taking into account the risk management practices of states and industry, and that estimates or descriptions of probability, uncertainty, and consequence are as quantitative as possible given the validity, accuracy, precision, and other quality attributes of the underlying data and analyses, but no more quantitative than the data and analyses can support. Requires public release of the final report by September 30, 2016.</summary>
</bill>
