<bill session="110" type="h" number="2338" updated="2013-07-19T21:24:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Warming Wildlife Survival Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the policy of the Federal Government to use all practicable means and measures to assist wildlife populations in adapting to and surviving the effects of global warming, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400109"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1063-1064"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2204"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Freshwater resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2007--Introduced.
Global Warming Wildlife Survival Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate a national strategy for mitigating the impacts of global warming on wildlife populations and to revise it within five years after its promulgation and not later than every ten years thereafter to reflect new information.Requires the Secretary to establish a science advisory board to: (1) provide scientific and technical advice and recommendations on the impacts of global warming on wildlife and its habitat, areas of habitat of particular importance, and strategies and mechanisms to mitigate such impacts in the management of federal lands and in other federal wildlife conservation programs; (2) advise the National Global Warming and Wildlife Science Center and review the quality of the Center's research programs; and (3) advise the Secretary regarding the best science available.Requires the Secretary to establish the National Global Warming and Wildlife Science Center within the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to: (1) conduct scientific research on national issues related to the impacts of global warming on wildlife and its habitat and mechanisms for adaptation or mitigation of such impacts; and (2) provide scientific support to federal land management agencies and federal wildlife agencies regarding such issues.Authorizes the establishment of a State and Tribal Wildlife Grants Program, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, to provide wildlife conservation grants for the planning, development, and implementation of programs for the benefit of wildlife and their habitat, including species that are not hunted or fished.</summary>
</bill>
