<bill session="111" type="s" number="2974" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Return of Talent Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Return of Talent Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Return of Talent Program to allow aliens who are legally present in the United States to return temporarily to the country of citizenship of the alien if that country is engaged in post-conflict or natural disaster reconstruction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="338">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 338.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Return of Talent Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish the Return of Talent Program to permit a lawful permanent resident (and certain family members) to return to his or her country of citizenship or nationality for up to one year (with a six-month extension) in order to contribute to such country's postconflict or natural disaster reconstruction activities or to provide medical services. Permits such a resident to be considered to be physically present and residing in the United States for naturalization purposes under specified conditions, including that: (1) such absence was solely to engage in postconflict or natural disaster reconstruction or to provide medical services in the resident's country of citizenship or nationality and the Secretary determines that the resident is a citizen or national of certain countries in which there was a conflict or disaster; or (2) the resident is a physician or other health care worker and such temporary absence was solely for the purpose of providing medical services in the resident's country of citizenship or nationality in which certain conflicts or disasters occurred; and (3) prior to, and after, such temporary absence the resident establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that his or her U.S. absence was solely for the purpose of performing such activities or services. Authorizes up to 1,000 aliens in any fiscal year to obtain such preservation of residence and physical presence. Authorizes the spouse and any minor, dependent unmarried son or daughter who resides in the same household as the Program participant to return to such alien's country of citizenship or nationality or to reenter the United States. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to report to Congress regarding participating Program countries and reconstruction efforts and medical services provided. (Sec. 4) Authorizes FY2011 appropriations for United States Citizenship and Immigration Services to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
