<bill session="113" type="h" number="1842" updated="2013-11-02T06:34:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Family Home Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to improve the protections for servicemembers, surviving spouses, and disabled veterans against mortgage foreclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2013--Introduced.
Military Family Home Protection Act - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (the Act) to allow a court, in an action to enforce an obligation on real or personal property secured by a mortgage against a servicemember who is, or was, eligible for hostile fire or imminent danger pay during a period of military service, a servicemember placed on convalescent status, a veteran who was medically discharged and retired, or the surviving spouse of a member who died during military service, to stay such proceedings, upon request of a covered individual, for a specified period (generally, one year after the event occurred for which the individual became covered). Prohibits the sale, foreclosure, or seizure of the subject property during such period, except upon a court order or pursuant to an agreement authorized under the Act. Requires the individual so covered to notify the mortgagee, trustee, or other creditor of such coverage. Provides a criminal penalty for violations of the sale or foreclosure prohibitions, and increases current civil penalties for mortgage violations under the Act. Prohibits an individual from being denied or refused credit solely by reason of eligibility for relief under this Act. Requires a servicemember-mortgagor who does not reside in the mortgage-secured residence due to military relocation and who inquires about, or applies for, a refinancing to be considered to occupy such residence during the period of the relocation. Requires each lending institution acting as a creditor to such servicemember, veteran, or surviving spouse to designate an employee responsible for ensuring the institution's compliance with the requirements of this Act. Requires any such institution that had prior annual assets of $10 billion or more to maintain on its primary website a toll-free number for information concerning such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
