<bill session="110" type="h" number="1494" updated="2013-07-19T21:16:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the process for the development of needed pediatric medical devices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2007-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="830"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2007--Introduced.
Pediatric Medical Device Safety and Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require an application for the approval of a medical device or a product development protocol to include: (1) a description of any pediatric subpopulations that suffer from the disease or condition that the device is intended to treat, diagnose, or cure; and (2) the number of affected pediatric patients. Excludes a medical device distributed pursuant to the humanitarian device exemption from the prohibition that no device be sold for an amount that exceeds the cost of the device if: (1) the device is intended for the treatment or diagnosis of a disease or condition that occurs in pediatric patients; and (2) other specified requirements are met. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to designate a contact point to help innovators and physicians access funding for pediatric medical device development. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for demonstration projects to promote pediatric device development. Includes as a duty of the Office of Pediatric Therapeutics increasing pediatric access to medical devices. Allows the Secretary to require: (1) postmarket surveillance on certain devices that are expected to have significant use in pediatric populations; and (2) a prospective surveillance period of more than 36 months for such devices, as necessary. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to establish a publicly accessible database of all studies and surveillance of medical devices.</summary>
</bill>
