<bill session="112" type="h" number="2975" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Castle Clinton National Monument and Battery Castle Clinton National Monument and Battery Conservancy Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Battery Conservancy to construct and operate a performance facility at Castle Clinton National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2011--Introduced.
Castle Clinton National Monument and Battery Castle Clinton National Monument and Battery Conservancy Partnership Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the National Park Service (NPS), to enter into one or more agreements with the Battery Conservancy of New York City, New York, (or a successor not-for-profit organization) to design, construct, maintain, and operate the performance facility and associated structures and fixtures proposed for the Castle Clinton National Monument in New York City. Authorizes the Secretary to retain and use any funds that are received from the Conservancy in accordance with this Act for the operation, maintenance, enhancement, or interpretation of the Monument. Allows the Secretary to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Conservancy for interpretive and educational programming related to the Monument. Provides for the facility to be under U.S. ownership. Prohibits the Conservancy at any time from having any ownership interest, leasehold interest, or other right or interest in such facility. Requires the facility to be administered by NPS as part of the Monument.</summary>
</bill>
