<bill session="112" type="h" number="3068" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Sunset and Review Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the periodic review and automatic termination of Federal regulations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412447" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2012-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2011-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Affairs, Stimulus Oversight and Government Spending     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO28" subcommittee="Regulatory Affairs, Stimulus Oversight and Government Spending" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2011--Introduced.
Regulatory Sunset and Review Act of 2011 - Requires federal agencies to review their covered rules and modify, consolidate, or terminate such rules on a periodic basis. Defines "covered rule" to include a significant rule that is likely to result in an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more or any other rule designated by an agency for sunset review. Allows a person adversely affected by a rule that is not a significant rule to submit a petition for sunset review of such rule. Provides for sunset review of a rule upon the request of a congressional committee or a majority of the members of such committee. Requires the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) conduct an inventory of existing rules and deadlines for their sunset review; (2) prioritize rules for sunset review based on specified criteria, including the cost of the rule and the burden of reviewing it; (3) group related rules for simultaneous review; (4) provide guidance to agencies for conducting sunset reviews; and (5) provide feedback to agencies on sunset reviews and results. Requires a new significant rule to be reviewed: (1) within three years after taking effect, or (2) within seven years after taking effect if the rule is issued pursuant to negotiated rulemaking procedures or if compliance with the rule requires substantial capital investment. Requires each federal agency to designate a Regulatory Review Officer with responsibility for implementation of this Act. Provides for judicial review of a denial or delay in granting or denying a petition for sunset review of a rule.</summary>
</bill>
