<bill session="112" type="s" number="311" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Foods Equity Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the coverage of medically necessary food under Federal health programs and private health insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S633-634"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1311"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2011--Introduced.
Medical Foods Equity Act of 2011 - Amends titles XVIII (Medicare), XIX (Medicaid), and XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to include coverage of: (1) medically necessary food and food modified to be low protein that is formulated to be consumed or administered under the supervision of a physician and the medical equipment and supplies necessary to administer such food; and (2) pharmacological doses of vitamins and amino acids used for the treatment of inborn errors of metabolism. Applies such coverage requirements to the TRICARE program (military health care). Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA), the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to require health plans to provide coverage of such food, vitamins, and amino acids. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to determine the minimum yearly coverage for all health insurance plans based upon the expanded coverage provided by this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to establish age-specific minimum levels of coverage. Declares that the minimum yearly coverage determined by the Secretary shall not preempt any state standards that require a higher minimum yearly coverage level for the same services and benefits.</summary>
</bill>
