<bill session="109" type="s" number="1090" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Liquefied Natural Gas Import Terminal Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide certain requirements for the siting, construction, expansion, and operation of liquefied natural gas import terminals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Liquefied natural gas"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Pipeline siting"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2005--Introduced.
Liquefied Natural Gas Import Terminal Authorization Act - Amends the Natural Gas Act to prohibit siting, constructing, expanding, or operating a liquefied natural gas import terminal within a state unless: (1) an application to do so is submitted to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) and to the agency with siting authority in the state in which the liquefied natural gas import terminal is located; and (2) FERC and the state agency issue an order approving the application. Sets forth terms and conditions for application approval. Amends federal transportation law to permit a state to adopt additional or more stringent safety standards for liquefied natural gas pipeline facilities if those standards are compatible with the minimum standards prescribed under federal pipeline safety law. Prohibits a state authority from adopting or continuing in force safety standards for interstate pipeline facilities or transportation, except in the case of liquefied natural gas pipeline facilities.</summary>
</bill>
