<bill session="110" type="h" number="97" updated="2013-07-19T21:04:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accountability and Transparency in Ethics Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to reform the ethics process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, Rules, and Standards of Official Conduct, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="895"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="1018"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1754"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Accountability and Transparency in Ethics Act - Establishes an independent Investigations Commission within the legislative branch. Requires annual ethics training for Members and employees of the House of Representatives and for registered lobbyists. Amends Rule XXV (Limitations on Outside Earned Income and Acceptance of Gifts) of the Rules of the House to require advance authorization by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of any privately-funded trip by any Member, officer, or employee of the House. Amends such Rule and Rule XXXV (Gifts) of the Standing Rules of the Senate with respect to: (1) the market value of a flight on an airplane not licensed by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to operate for compensation or hire; (2) a ban on gifts worth less than $50; and (3) disbursements for a national party convention event in honor of a Member, officer, or employee. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (LDA) to: (1) transfer certain functions of the Clerk of the House to the Committee with respect to registration of lobbyists; (2) revise certain registration and disclosure requirements; and (3) prescribe civil fines for lobbyists offering certain gifts to Members, officers, or employees. Amends the federal criminal code to revise the one-year ban on lobbying contacts by former Members, officers, or employees of either chamber of Congress. Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit conversion of leadership PAC funds to personal use. Prohibits payment of campaign funds, except nominal reimbursements, to immediate family members of candidates. Prohibits involvement of a registered lobbyist in administration of certain campaign committees unless a candidate for federal office. Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House and Rule XXXVII (Conflict of Interest) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require a Member of Congress or Senator to prohibit all of his or her staff from having any official contact with the Member's or Senator's spouse or immediate family member if such individual is a registered lobbyist or is employed or retained by one to influence legislation. Expresses the sense of Congress that the use of a family relationship by a lobbyist who is an immediate family member of a Member of Congress to gain special advantages over other lobbyists is inappropriate.</summary>
</bill>
