<bill session="113" type="h" number="1688" updated="2013-11-02T06:33:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Never Contract With the Enemy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit contracting with the enemy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="675"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2013--Introduced.
Never Contract With the Enemy Act - States that it shall be the policy of the United States that executive agencies shall not contract with the enemy or with any person or entity that provides funds received under a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement to an enemy of the United States or that otherwise supports those actively opposing the United States or coalition forces in a contingency operation. Authorizes the termination or nullification of contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements valued in excess of $20,000 (currently, $100,000) with persons or entities identified as enemies of the United States. Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) and each senior procurement executive to use available intelligence to identify persons and entities who receive U.S. funds through contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements and who are: (1) providing such funds to an enemy or to a person or entity who is actively supporting an enemy of the United States, or (2) otherwise supporting those who are actively opposing U.S. or coalition forces in a contingency operation. Requires the Secretary and the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to jointly carry out a program for providing information to senior procurement executives and commanders of the geographic combatant commands relating to persons or entities who may be providing funding under contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements to enemies of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
