<bill session="111" type="s" number="3750" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Water Intensive Monitoring Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SWIM Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to include certain inland lakes within a coastal water monitoring and grant program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Safe Water Intensive Monitoring Act or the SWIM Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop water quality monitoring and notification criteria for, and provide grants to states and local governments to develop and implement water quality monitoring and notification programs for, such inland lakes that are designated by states for swimming and that have public beaches as the Administrator deems appropriate, considering: (1) the size of the lakes; (2) the annual number of visitors to the lakes; (3) identified harmful algal blooms or other known pathogens in the lakes; and (4) the potential health and economic impacts of poor water quality of the lakes with respect to affected communities, individuals, fish, and wildlife.</summary>
</bill>
