<bill session="109" type="h" number="2516" updated="2013-07-19T19:26:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Professional Athletes Drug Testing bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Professional Sports Integrity Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish standards for the testing of prohibited substances and methods for certain professional baseball, basketball, football, and hockey players.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2565"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1114"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Basketball"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hockey"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
    <term name="Urinalysis"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2005--Introduced.
Professional Sports Integrity Act of 2005 - Prohibits Major League Baseball, the National Basketball Association, the National Football League, or the National Hockey League from organizing or producing, or any person from competing in, a professional baseball, basketball, football, or hockey game without meeting the testing requirements established by this Act. Requires each such league to implement testing for the use of prohibited substances by professional athletes who compete in that league, including: (1) testing each athlete at least four times a year, twice during both the season and the off-season; (2) additional testing with reasonable cause; and (3) testing for all substances prohibited by the World Anti-Doping Agency. Requires for each athlete who tests positive: (1) a suspension for a minimum of two years for the first positive test result; (2) a permanent ban for any subsequent positive test result; (3) public disclosure of both the athlete's name and the prohibited substance; and (4) an opportunity to appeal. Deems a violation of this Act to be an unfair or deceptive act or practice. Authorizes the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce this Act. Requires biennial reports for each league. Expresses the sense of Congress that other professional sports leagues should adopt policies and procedures for the testing of steroids and other illicit substances that are substantially similar to those required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
