<bill session="109" type="s" number="2762" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Long-Term Care Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure appropriate payment for the cost of long-term care provided to veterans in State homes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2006-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2006-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4158-4159"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4159-4160" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2006--Introduced.
Veterans Long-Term Care Security Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to the congressional veterans' committees a detailed justification of any proposal to implement a reduction in per diem payments to state nursing homes for care provided to veterans. Directs the Secretary to pay for nursing home care furnished in a non-Department of Veterans Affairs nursing home where such care is provided to any veteran: (1) in need of such care for a service-connected disability; or (2) with a service-connected disability rated at 70 percent or more and in need of such care. Directs the Secretary to furnish such drugs and medicines as ordered by a duly licensed physician for any veteran: (1) in need of such drugs and medicines for a service-connected disability; or (2) with a service-connected disability rated at 50 percent or more in need of such drugs and medicines while being provided nursing home care payable through the Department. Authorizes the Secretary to treat certain health facilities as state homes for purposes of eligibility for payments for care provided to veterans.</summary>
</bill>
