<bill session="113" type="h" number="2246" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IDEA MOE Adjustment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act in order to limit the penalties to a State that does not meet its maintenance of effort level of funding to a one-time penalty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412558" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1095"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2013--Introduced.
IDEA MOE Adjustment Act - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to limit the penalty imposed on a state that reduces its level of funding for special education from one fiscal year to the next to a reduction of federal special education funds for one fiscal year. (Currently, that penalty may be imposed on a state for any fiscal year after the fiscal year the state reduces its special education funding.) Redistributes the federal special education funding that is denied to a penalized state to states that have not reduced their level of special education funding. Prohibits the Secretary of Education from considering those penalties or redistributions when calculating a state's share of federal special education funds for subsequent fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
