<bill session="109" type="h" number="6279" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Understanding Off-shoring and Outsourcing Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the collection of labor data by Federal agencies to better measure and evaluate the outsourcing and off-shoring of public and private sector business operations and services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Understanding Off-shoring and Outsourcing Act of 2006 - Requires the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce to revise its requirements for mandatory industry reporting of international services transactions to lower by 50% the per-company monetary thresholds above which companies must report import and export services transactions. Requires the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor to make specified revisions to the procedures and methodologies related to its collection and disaggregation of data relating to mass layoffs, relocations, and employment. Requires the Bureaus to study and report jointly to Congress on whether linking or coordinating their independent data relating to mass layoffs and import and export services transactions would improve the quality of information available about outsourcing and off-shoring of private sector business operations and services.</summary>
</bill>
