<bill session="109" type="h" number="2778" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense in Voter Registration Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to permit a voting registrar to remove an individual from the official list of registered voters for elections for Federal office on the ground that the individual no longer resides in the registrar's jurisdiction if the individual fails to vote in any election held during 2 consecutive Federal election cycles, the registrar sends a notice to the individual at the end of the second cycle, and the individual fails to respond to the notice within 60 days.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2005--Introduced.
Common Sense in Voter Registration Act of 2005 - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to permit a voting registrar to remove an individual from the official list of registered voters for Federal elections on the ground that the individual no longer resides in the registrar's jurisdiction, if the individual fails to vote in any election held during two consecutive Federal election cycles, the registrar sends a notice to the individual at the end of the second cycle, and the individual fails to respond to the notice within 60 days.</summary>
</bill>
