<bill session="112" type="h" number="3789" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulation of Mortgage Servicing Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish clear regulatory standards for mortgage servicers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3595"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="967"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/18/2012--Introduced.
Regulation of Mortgage Servicing Act of 2012 - Requires a mortgage servicer to assign one case manager to each borrower that seeks a mortgage loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Requires the case manager to: (1) manage the communication between the servicer and the borrower, and (2) make decisions about the borrower's eligibility for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Prohibits a servicer from initiating a covered foreclosure action against a borrower unless the servicer has performed specified tasks related to offering the borrower, if eligible, a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Requires a servicer to suspend a covered foreclosure action initiated before the enactment of this Act until such tasks have been performed. Prohibits a servicer, during the suspension period, from: (1) sending the borrower a notice of foreclosure, (2) conducting or scheduling a sale of the real property securing the mortgage, or (3) causing final judgment to be entered against the borrower. Prescribes requirements a servicer must meet in order to be deemed to have made a reasonable effort to obtain necessary information to determine a borrower's eligibility for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure. Requires a servicer, before notifying a borrower of his or her ineligibility for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure, to obtain the services of an independent reviewer to review the borrower's file and determine whether or not the borrower is eligible. Makes a violation of this Act a bar to a covered foreclosure action. Allows a servicer in compliance with this Act, however, to bring or proceed with a foreclosure action, regardless of any prior violation. Makes any servicer that fails to comply with any requirement of this Act liable to a borrower in the same manner that a creditor who fails to comply with any requirement is liable to a person.</summary>
</bill>
