<bill session="110" type="s" number="280" updated="2013-07-19T22:22:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Global Warming bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Climate Stewardship and Innovation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a program to accelerate the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions in the United States by establishing a market-driven system of greenhouse gas tradeable allowances, to support the deployment of new climate change-related technologies, and to ensure benefits to consumers from the trading in such allowances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S511-514"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6390-6391"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Private Sector and Consumer Solutions to Global Warming and Wildlife Protection. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-1113.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEV13" subcommittee="Private Sector and Consumer Solutions to Global Warming and Wildlife Protection" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="620"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="620"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="4226"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air travel"/>
    <term name="Aircraft engines"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Aquifers"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Automobile engines"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobile tires"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental economics"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrocarbons"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Ozone layer depletion"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Sulphur dioxide"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2007--Introduced.
Climate Stewardship and Innovation Act of 2007 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish and maintain the National Greenhouse Gas Database to collect, verify, and analyze information on greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Establishes a program for market-driven reduction of GHGs through the use of tradeable allowances. Requires certain covered entities that own or control a source of GHG emissions in the electric power, industrial, and commercial sectors of the U.S. economy to submit to the Administrator, beginning in 2012, one tradeable allowance for every metric ton of GHGs emitted. Requires the Administrator to establish a declining cap on tradeable allowances to reduce GHG emissions over time. Allows tradeable allowances to be sold, exchanged, purchased, retired, borrowed, offset, or otherwise used as permitted by this Act. Requires the Administrator to establish a program to allow covered entities to earn tradable allowances from developing countries' activities that result in certified emission reductions. Establishes the Climate Change Credit Corporation to manage tradeable allowances. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a Climate Technology Financing Board; (2) study technology transfer barriers, best practices, and technology transfer activities at federal laboratories related to the licensing and commercialization of technologies that result in reduced GHG emissions, increased ability to adapt to climate change impacts, or increased sequestration of GHGs; (3) analyze business opportunities available for climate change technologies; (4) establish a nonprofit government sponsored enterprise for providing investment in private sector technologies that show promise for climate change adaptation and mitigation applications; (5) create a program of public-private partnerships for climate innovation; (6) establish a national program to ensure that lessons learned and best practices concerning energy efficiency and GHG emission reductions are available to the public; (7) carry out a program of scientific research on potential abrupt climate change; (8) carry out a Climate Technology Challenge Program to award funding to stimulate innovation in technologies for reducing GHG emissions; (9) establish a program to reduce GHG emissions through deployment of energy efficiency measures by large commercial customers by providing for energy audits; (10) establish, operate, and report on a research and development program focused on advanced once-through fuel cycles, a Nuclear System Modeling project to evaluate the cost, safety, waste management, and proliferation avoidance and resistance of fuel cycles, and an Advanced Diversified Waste-Disposal Research Program; (11) establish a demonstration program to reduce the first-time regulatory costs of the current Nuclear Regulatory Commission licensing process incurred by the first applicant using an advanced reactor design; (12) establish a program to demonstrate the effectiveness of retooling an existing vehicle or component manufacturing facility to reduce vehicle GHG emissions and of increasing competitiveness of advanced technology vehicle production facilities; (13) establish guidelines for setting project baselines for reductions of GHG emissions and GHG storage in geological formations; (14) submit a climate change adaptation plan for the United States; and (15) conduct research on the impact of climate change on low-income populations everywhere in the world. Requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) to: (1) implement a plan to increase and establish priorities for funding research in the adaptation to and mitigation of climate change; and (2) establish a climate change science and technology enhancement program for math and science teachers. Establishes a National Medal of Climate Stewardship Innovation. Requires the Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) to determine the extent to which changes to the patent system are necessary to increase the flow of climate change-related technologies. Requires the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to establish a research program on global climate change standards and processes to provide knowledge on the reduction of GHGs. Provides for establishment of a joint competitive, merit-based research program to fund low- or zero-emissions transportation proposals. Requires the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to: (1) establish an interagency panel to establish standards for measurement of sequestered carbon; (2) establish a program on adaptation technologies and assess the climate change technological needs of various regions of the country; (3) perform one national and six regional infrastructure cost assessments to provide estimates of the range of costs anticipated for adaptation to the impacts of climate change.</summary>
</bill>
