<bill session="112" type="s" number="2299" updated="2013-07-20T02:36:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Servicemembers Rights Enforcement Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act and title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of civil relief to members of the uniformed services and to improve the enforcement of employment and reemployment rights of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2500-2501"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2501-2502" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6293"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2012--Introduced.
Servicemembers Rights Enforcement Improvement Act of 2012 - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (the Act) concerning the protection of servicemembers against default judgments to require a plaintiff, before filing an affidavit, to conduct a diligent and reasonable investigation to determine whether or not the defendant is in military service, including a search of available records of the Department of Defense (DOD) and any other available information. Makes a private right of action for a violation of the Act retroactive to December 19, 2003. Allows a veteran on whose behalf a complaint of a violation of employment or reemployment rights is made by the Attorney General (AG) to intervene in such action, and to obtain appropriate relief. Requires the AG, within 60 days after receiving a referral of an unsuccessful attempt to resolve a complaint relating to a state or private employer, to notify the person on whose behalf the complaint is submitted of either the decision to commence such an action or of when such decision is expected to be made. Requires, in the latter case, such decision to be made within an additional 30 days. Requires the AG to commence such an action when there is reasonable cause to believe that a state or private employer is engaged in a pattern or practice of resistance to the full enjoyment of such employment and reemployment rights and benefits, and that the pattern or practice is intended to deny the full exercise of such rights and benefits. Provides the Special Counsel with subpoena power to require the attendance and testimony of, and production of documents from, federal employees, to be enforced through the Merit Systems Protection Board. Authorizes the AG to issue and serve a civil investigative demand for the production of documentary material relevant to an investigation under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
