<bill session="111" type="h" number="4776" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution from charging a fee for admission to any exhibit which is part of the permanent collection of any museum or facility which is part of any bureau established in or under the Smithsonian Institution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E301, E309, E314-315"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2010--Introduced.
Prohibits the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution from charging a fee for admission to an exhibit that is part of the permanent collection of any museum or facility that is part of any bureau established in or under the Smithsonian Institution, including the National Gallery of Art. Allows the charging of a fee for admission to an exhibit if: (1) charging a fee is necessary and unavoidable; (2) the Secretary submits a statement explaining the determination to Congress; and (3) the charging of such fee does not become effective until after the expiration of a 45-day period beginning on the date the statement is submitted. Makes such prohibition non-applicable to a specified exhibition at the National Museum of Natural History. Requires the Secretary to submit a plan for eliminating the admission fee for such exhibition which shall include steps to cover the expenses incurred in carrying out the exhibition.</summary>
</bill>
