<bill session="109" type="s" number="2588" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the certification of programs to provide uninsured employees of small businesses access to health coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2006-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4883-4884"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2006 - Amends the Social Security Act to create a new title XXII to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants for the startup and operation of 50 eligible three-share pilot programs for a five-year period. Characterizes a three-share program as three-way health insurance premium sharing among employer, employee, and the grant funds. Authorizes the use of grants to establish three-share programs, provide for contributions to premiums, and establish risk pools. Requires grant applicants to: (1) be either nonprofits or local governmental entities; (2) define the program's service region; (3) have the capacity to carry out administrative functions associated with managing health plans; and (4) have demonstrated community involvement. Requires programs to pay for the costs of services through monthly premiums, divided among employee, employer, and grant funds according to specified percentages. Sets forth minimal coverage requirements for three-share program eligibility. Requires the Administrator to develop a formula to determine which businesses qualify as distressed businesses for purposes of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
