<bill session="111" type="h" number="6467" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Middle Class Tax Relief Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide middle class tax relief, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4853"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2010--Introduced.
Middle Class Tax Relief Act of 2010 - Makes the general terminating date of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2010 (EGTRRA) (i.e., December 31, 2010) inapplicable to provisions of that Act relating to individual income tax rate reductions, tax benefits related to children and adoption, marriage penalty relief, and education. Repeals the terminating date of the Jobs Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003 that applies to reductions in the tax rate for capital gains and dividend income, subject to the income thresholds set forth by this Act.. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish permanent reductions in income tax rates for individual taxpayers whose adjusted gross income is $200,000 or less ($250,000 for married couples filing joint tax returns); (2) allow a permanent exemption from limitations on itemized tax deductions and personal exemptions for individual taxpayers whose adjusted gross income is $200,000 or less ($250,000 for married couples filing joint tax returns); (3) allow a 15% tax rate on capital gains and dividend income for individual taxpayers whose adjusted gross income is $200,000 or less ($250,000 for married couples filing joint tax returns); (4) allow a permanent increase in the refundable portion of the child tax credit; (5) make permanent the increased earned income tax credit and the modifications to such credit enacted by EGTRRA; (6) make permanent the increased ($125,000) expensing allowance for depreciable business and investment property; and (7) extend through 2011 the increased alternative minimum tax (AMT) exemption amounts and the offset against the AMT for certain nonrefundable personal tax credits. Provides for compliance of the budgetary effects of this Act with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
