<bill session="110" type="s" number="3324" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education for the 21st Century Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide leadership regarding science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7287"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7287-7289" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2008--Introduced.
Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education for the 21st Century Act of 2008 - Establishes the National Council for Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education (STEM Council) as a federally chartered corporation composed of stakeholders in effective STEM education. Directs the STEM Council to: (1) identify critical deficiencies in STEM education systems and propose collaborative strategies that will allow Council members to address such deficiencies; (2) serve as an informational resource for the Department of Education (Department) and, through it, state and local educational agencies on effective STEM education practices; (3) promote STEM fields and the value of a STEM education to the public; and (4) maintain a public database on federal STEM scholarship and fellowship opportunities and other STEM and relevant non-STEM programs. Establishes, within the Council, a standing committee on science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education (STEM Committee) composed of representatives from all federal departments and agencies involved in STEM education. Requires the STEM Committee to coordinate all federally funded or administered STEM education efforts and harmonize them with state and local efforts through the STEM Council. Directs the Secretary of Education to conduct a comprehensive evaluation of the Department's STEM education programs.</summary>
</bill>
