<bill session="109" type="s" number="1563" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ABCs for Children's Health Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advancing Better Coverage and Care for Children's Health Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to protect and strengthen the safety net of children's public health coverage by extending the enhanced Federal matching rate under the State children's health insurance program to children covered by medicaid at State option and by encouraging innovations in children's enrollment and retention, to advance quality and performance in children's public health insurance programs, to provide payments for children's hospitals to reward quality and performance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9477-9478"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9478-9480" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Advancing Better Coverage and Care for Children's Health Act of 2005 - or the ABCs for Children's Health Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for the phased-in application of an enhanced federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for children whose eligibility is optional under Medicaid. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to pay to each state with an approved plan 90% of the sums expended during a quarter attributable to the design, development, implementation, and evaluation of enrollment systems (including "express lane enrollment) determined likely to provide more efficient and effective administration of the plan's enrollment and retention of eligible children. Prohibits the Secretary from imposing or approving an elimination or modification of the amount, duration, or scope of certain services relating to early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services, or specified requirements for arranging for corrective treatment. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Center for Medicaid and State Operations of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, to enter into agreements with the National Quality Forum to facilitate the development of consensus-based pediatric quality and performance measures. Directs the Secretary to award grants to eligible entities for development and evaluation of such measures. Requires the Secretary to establish demonstration projects in each of three specified categories to advance quality and performance in the delivery of medical assistance to children under Medicaid. Makes appropriations for such projects Directs the Secretary to implement a four-year program to develop, implement, and evaluate a pay-for-performance program for eligible children's hospitals providing critical access to children eligible for Medicaid. Makes apppropriations for such four year program. Amends the Public Health Services Act to include children's hospitals as covered entities which manufacturers of covered drugs, under an agreement with the Secretary, charge no more than the average manufacturer drug price.</summary>
</bill>
