<bill session="112" type="h" number="1008" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Benton MacKaye Cherokee National Forest Land Consolidation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the conveyance of a small parcel of National Forest System land in the Cherokee National Forest and to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to use the proceeds from that conveyance to acquire a parcel of land for inclusion in that national forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2011--Introduced.
Benton MacKaye Cherokee National Forest Land Consolidation Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to convey and quitclaim to the Towee Falls Baptist Church a parcel of National Forest System land in Cherokee National Forest, Tennessee, which surrounds the Church. Requires Towee Falls Baptist Church to pay to the Secretary an amount of cash that is equal to the fair market value of such parcel based on an appraisal approved by the Secretary. Requires deposit of the consideration received by the Secretary into a specified account in the Treasury and makes the monies so deposited available for the acquisition of lands and interests in the Cherokee National Forest. Authorizes the Secretary to use such monies to acquire from the Monroe County Tennessee Board of Education a tract of land known as the Doc Rogers tract if the Secretary and the Board reach an agreement on the terms of a federal acquisition.</summary>
</bill>
