<bill session="113" type="s" number="948" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Quality Complex Rehabilitation Technology Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage and payment for complex rehabilitation technology items under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2013--Introduced.
Ensuring Access to Quality Complex Rehabilitation Technology Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to cover, as medical and other health services, complex rehabilitation technology items designed and configured for a specific qualified individual to meet that individual's unique: (1) medical, physical, and functional needs related to a medical condition; and (2) capacities for basic activities of daily living (ADLs) and instrumental ADLs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) designate complex rehabilitation technology items (excluding adaptive equipment to operate motor vehicles or certain prosthetic devices and orthotics), and (2) establish eligibility criteria for them. Prescribes requirements for payments for CRT items. Directs the Secretary to establish standards for clinical conditions for CRT item payment as well as quality standards for suppliers of such items. Directs the Secretary to establish a Healthcare Procedure Coding System (HCPCS) coding subset that uses specified HCPCS codes for CRT items. Requires payment for replacement of a CRT item (or any part of one), without regard to certain continuous use or useful lifetime restrictions established for items of durable medical equipment (DME), if a qualified ordering practitioner determines that a replacement item (or part) is necessary.</summary>
</bill>
