<bill session="112" type="h" number="6365" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13T17:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-13T17:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Security and Job Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Security and Job Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to replace the sequester established by the Budget Control Act of 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2012-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 778.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5956-5969" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 117 and H.R. 6365, under a closed rule for both measures. Each are debatable for one hour. In both cases all points of order against provisions in the measure are waived, and in each case, one motion to recommit, with or without instructions is made in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 6365.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5956-5969" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Van Hollen moved to recommit with instructions to The Budget.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5967-5969" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5967" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Hollen motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to strike sections 3 and 4 in the bill and replace with a new section outlining conditional elimination of sequestration and requirements of deficet reduction legislation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5968" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 170 - 247 (Roll no. 576).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-09-13T17:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="577" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 223 - 196 (Roll no. 577).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5957" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="778"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Passed House without amendment.
National Security and Job Protection Act - Makes the effective date of this Act contingent upon enactment of: (1) the reconciliation Act with certain spending reductions for a specified deficit reduction contemplated by H.Con.Res. 112, as passed by the House of Representatives on March 16, 2012; or (2) similar legislation that achieves outlay reductions within five years after enactment that equal or exceed specified outlay reductions flowing from the budget authority reductions required by the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act), as in force immediately before enactment of this Act, as it applies to direct spending in the defense function for FY2013 combined with the outlay reductions flowing from the across-the-board decrease in discretionary spending made by this Act. Amends the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act to abolish the distinction between security and nonsecurity categories of discretionary spending for new budget authority in FY2013. Combines the dollar amounts of the current categories ($686 billion for the security category and $361 billion for the nonsecurity category) into a single amount of $1.047 trillion in new budget authority. Revises sequestration requirements for FY2013 to require a $19.104 billion across-the-board decrease in the discretionary spending category as of January 2, 2013. Directs the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue a supplemental sequestration report for FY2013 to eliminate any discretionary spending breach of the $1.047 trillion spending limit, as adjusted by the $19.104 billion across-the-board reduction requirement of this Act. Directs the President to issue an order to eliminate the breach, if any, identified in such report. Nullifies any sequestration order the President may issue under the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act to carry out reductions to direct spending for the FY2013 defense function (050). Provides that, if the legislation referred to above is enacted and achieves the outlay reductions specified, and those reductions exceed the outlay reductions flowing from the spending budget authority reductions required by the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act, the direct spending reductions for the nonsecurity category for FY2013 (otherwise required to be reduced) shall be reduced by the difference. Requires the President by October 15, 2012, to transmit to Congress a legislative proposal that meets such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
