<bill session="112" type="s" number="1653" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Tourism Facilitation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make minor modifications to the procedures relating to the issuance of visas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2011-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Brazil"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2011--Introduced.
International Tourism Facilitation Act - Amends the Department of State and Related Agency Appropriations Act, 2005 to authorize the Secretary of State to charge consular services fees which may be deposited in the appropriate Department of State account to the extent that the amount of such fees collected during a fiscal year is greater than the amount of consular service fees deposited in the Treasury during FY2011. Amends the Department of State Authorities Act of 2006 to repeal the Secretary's authority to amend consular service surcharges in support of enhanced border security that are in addition to passport and immigrant visa fees in effect on January 1, 2004. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Secretary to waive nonimmigrant visa interviews for up to three additional years (four years total) for individuals who previously held a U.S. visa. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress regarding nonimmigrant visa projections and plans to service such projections through 2020 in the high-growth markets of Brazil, China, and India.</summary>
</bill>
