<bill session="110" type="h" number="6258" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carbon Capture and Storage Early Deployment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To accelerate the development and early deployment of systems for the capture and storage of carbon dioxide emissions from fossil fuel electric generation facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1224"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2008--Introduced.
Carbon Capture and Storage Early Deployment Act - Authorizes qualified industry organizations to conduct a referendum among the owners or operators of distribution utilities delivering fossil fuel-based electricity for the creation of a Carbon Storage Research Corporation. Requires the Corporation to be established as a division or affiliate of the Electric Power Research Institute upon approval of those persons representing two-thirds of the total quantity of fossil fuel-based electricity delivered to retail consumers. Requires the Corporation, annually, to collect an assessment on such distribution utilities that shall reflect the relative carbon dioxide emission rates of different fossil fuel-based electricity. Sets initial rates of assessment for coal, natural gas, and oil. Authorizes the Corporation to adjust the assessments to reflect changes in the expected quantities of such electricity from different fuel types such that the assessments generate between $1.0 billion and $1.1 billion annually. Authorizes the Corporation to collect assessments and conduct operations for 10 years. Dissolves the Corporation after 15 years. Provides for the Corporation to use funds derived from assessments to: (1) issue grants and contracts to private, academic, and governmental entities to accelerate the commercial demonstration or availability of carbon dioxide capture and storage technologies and methods; and (2) purchase carbon dioxide through reverse auctions or other acquisition methods when needed to conduct tests of carbon dioxide store sites in the case of established projects that are storing carbon dioxide emissions. Requires: (1) the Corporation to support large-scale demonstrations of carbon capture and storage (CCS) technologies capable of advancing the technologies to commercial readiness; and (2) the Corporation's Board to establish policies regarding the ownership of intellectual property developed as a result of Corporation support that encourage individual ingenuity and invention. Authorizes Corporation grants or contracts for programs or projects of the Department of Energy (DOE) or its affiliated national laboratories and other fossil energy research entities and of academic organizations or consortia to accelerate the commercial development and demonstration of CCS or carbon capture and conversion technologies. Provides for recovery of a distribution facility's costs of complying with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
