<bill session="113" type="h" number="3273" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-08T19:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-08T19:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth Working Group Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth Working Group Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a bicameral working group on deficit reduction and economic growth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412416" joined="2013-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 373.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389-6397" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 373, the House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on H.R. 3273.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6395" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Brownley (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to Rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6395" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6395" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Brownley motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J.Res. 59, Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sessions raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Sessions stated that the proposed amendment contained in the motion to recommit with instructions was not germane. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Brownley (CA) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sessions moved to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6396" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 194 (Roll no. 533).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6396" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="534" datetime="2013-10-08T19:41:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 197 (Roll no. 534).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 373, and upon the adoption of H.J. Res. 89, the text of H.R. 3273, as passed by the House, is appended as new matter at the end of H.J. Res. 89 and the Clerk is directed to make conforming modifications in the engrossment of H.J. Res. 89.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 373, H.R. 3273 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="373"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="373"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="89"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth Working Group Act of 2013 - Establishes the Bicameral Working Group on Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth, comprised of 20 Members of Congress, to recommend to the House of Representatives and Senate overall levels of discretionary spending, including for FY2014, changes in the statutory limit on the public debt, and reforms in direct spending programs. Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Majority Leader of the Senate to each appoint 10 members of their respective chamber to serve on the Working Group. Designates a co-chair in each chamber and allows the Minority Leaders of the House and Senate to each recommend the appointment of 4 of the 10 members in each chamber. Requires the Working Group to report its recommendations, including any required legislative language, to the House and Senate within three days after their adoption. Prohibits the Working Group from reporting any recommendation that does not receive the support of a majority of its members. Requires the termination of the Working Group immediately after the transmission of its recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
