<bill session="112" type="h" number="909" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Roadmap for America's Energy Future</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand domestic fossil fuel production, develop more nuclear power, and expand renewable electricity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412481" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412441" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412447" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2011-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2011-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412398" joined="2011-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412430" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2011-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-31">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO30" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1023"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2011--Introduced.
A Roadmap for America's Energy Future - Deems the Draft Proposed Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2010-2015 to have been approved by the Secretary of the Interior as a final oil and gas leasing program in full compliance with specified environmental law. Directs such Secretary to conduct a lease sale every 270 days in each outer Continental Shelf (OCS) planning region for which there is a commercial interest in purchasing federal oil and gas leases for OCS production. Requires the federal share of proceeds of lease sales from newly open areas to be deposited in the American-Made Energy Trust Fund (established by this Act). Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to: (1) modify the OCS leasing program; and (2) direct the Secretary to include, in each 5-Year Program, lease sales proposals offering for oil and gas leasing at least 75% of the available unleased acreage within each OCS Planning Area. Prescribes requirements for coordination with adjacent states regarding pipeline construction for crude oil, petroleum products, and natural gas. Prohibits, on either federal OCS or state waters, uses that are incompatible with: (1) oil and gas leasing, or (2) full oil or natural gas exploration and production on geologically prospective tracts. Requires the Secretary to accept, in satisfaction of mitigation requirements, proposals for mitigation measures on a site away from the area impacted by exploration and production activities. Directs the Secretary to establish a leasing program for oil, gas and oil shale within the Alaska Coastal Plain (ANWR). Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 (ANILCA) to repeal the prohibition against production of oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR). Allocates to the state of Alaska 50% of federal revenues derived from federal oil and gas leasing operations. Establishes in the Treasury the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund. Requires the Secretary to hold a lease sale offering an additional 10 parcels for lease for oil shale development. Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to develop, construct, and operate a coal-to-liquid facility. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal the limitation on federal contracting for procurement and acquisition of alternative fuels with respect to associated lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions. States it is the policy of the United States to facilitate the continued development and growth of a safe and clean nuclear energy industry through reductions in financial, regulatory, and technical barriers to construction and operation. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to: (1) issue operating permits for 200 new commercial nuclear reactors, and (2) establish a process for licensing facilities for the recycling of spent nuclear fuel. Amends of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to eliminate the Office Of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. Requires the federal government to site and permit at least one radiological material geologic repository for the disposal of radiological material. Retains the repository site at Yucca Mountain (Nevada) as such a site unless the NRC determines that it is unsuitable. Directs the NRC to: (1) continue to review the pending Department of Energy (DOE) license application to construct the nuclear waste repository at Yucca Mountain until a determination is made on the merits, and (2) make a determination within 90 days after enactment of this Act on the suitability of Yucca Mountain for the repository site. Removes all current statutory limitations upon the amount of radiological material that can be placed in Yucca Mountain. Requires the NRC to replace them with new limits based on scientific and technical analysis of the full capacity of Yucca Mountain for the storage of radiological material. Directs the Secretary of Energy to apply for an alternative geologic repository providing at least 120,000 tons of storage capacity if the NRC determines Yucca Mountain is not a suitable location. Requires DOE to report to Congress on the feasibility of establishing an independent radiological material management program. Authorizes DOE to: (1) award a contract to an eligible entity to manage the nation's activities regarding radiological material repositories; and (2) transfer to that entity control and ownership of all NRC-issued licenses, allowances, and responsibilities for the operation of the nuclear materials repository at Yucca Mountain. Prohibits the President from blocking or hindering spent nuclear fuel recycling activities. Directs DOE to: (1) inventory all materials it owns that could be used to power commercial nuclear reactors, (2) establish a nuclear fuel supply reserve, and (3) transmit to Congress a long-term plan for introducing nuclear fuel supplies from the reserve into the market. Directs the NRC to implement an expedited procedure for issuing a Combined Construction and Operating License. Instructs the NRC Chairman to report recommendations to Congress regarding development of technology-neutral plant design specifications. Directs the DOE Secretary to establish a National Nuclear Energy Council. Directs the DOE Secretary and the NRC Chairman to reevaluate and accelerate the Next Generation Nuclear Power Plant schedule. Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from using the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to prevent uranium mining on federal lands unless the Secretary makes findings explaining the reason for such prevention. Instructs the Chairman of the NRC to make recommendations to Congress regarding streamlined licensing of small and modular nuclear reactors. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the American-Made Energy Trust Fund to receive certain revenues from oil, gas, and oil shale leases. Instructs the DOE Secretary to: (1) establish a reverse auction program to award funds from the American-Made Energy Trust Fund to eligible entities to generate an amount of electric energy, and (2) establish within DOE a Reverse Auction Authority to conduct such auctions. Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) redefine greenhouse gas, and (2) prohibit regulation of a greenhouse gas for climate change purposes. Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to prohibit consideration of the climate change-related impact of a greenhouse gas upon any species of fish, wildlife, or plant.</summary>
</bill>
