<bill session="113" type="s" number="1001" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Export Embargo Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to the Government of Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412573" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3661-3662" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2013--Introduced.
Iran Export Embargo Act - Amends the Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation Act of 2012 to direct the President to prohibit all transactions in property and property interests of a person (as defined in this Act) if such property and property interests are in the United States or within the possession or control of a U.S. individual. Directs the President to prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that has knowingly conducted or facilitated a significant transaction with respect to the importation, sale, or transfer of goods or services from Iran on behalf of a described person. Directs the President to impose sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act with respect to an individual that knowingly: (1) imports, purchases, or transfers goods or services from a described person; and (2) provides underwriting services or insurance or reinsurance to a described person. Describes a "person" as: (1) the state and the government of Iran, or any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of such government, including the Central Bank of Iran; (2) any person owned or controlled by, or acting for or on behalf of, such government; or (3) any other person determined by the President to be described in clauses (1) or (2).</summary>
</bill>
