<bill session="112" type="s" number="1878" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coordination of Pro Bono Medically Recommended Dental Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to assist low-income individuals in obtaining recommended dental care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4091"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2011--Introduced.
Coordination of Pro Bono Medically Recommended Dental Care Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award competitive grants to, or enter into contracts with, eligible entities to fund the employment costs of professionals who will use grant or contract funds to: (1) coordinate the provision of medically recommended dental care to eligible low-income individuals by volunteer dentists in a manner consistent with state licensing laws; and (2) verify the medical, dental, and financial needs of individuals who may be eligible for free dental services. Requires an eligible: (1) entity to be tax exempt and provide for the participation of eligible individuals in a free dental services program on a national basis; and (2) individual to be entitled to benefits or be enrolled under Medicare, Medicaid, or a state plan or waiver under the State Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP).</summary>
</bill>
