<bill session="111" type="h" number="6162" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coin Modernization, Oversight, and Continuity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Coin Modernization, Oversight, and Continuity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Coin Modernization, Oversight, and Continuity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Coin Modernization, Oversight, and Continuity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide research and development authority for alternative coinage materials to the Secretary of the Treasury, increase congressional oversight over coin production, and ensure the continuity of certain numismatic items.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400424"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Watt asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Financial Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7312-7313" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7312" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-09-29T19:50:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30">
      <text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8292" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-11-30" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2010-11-30">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-12-14" type="public" number="111-302">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-302.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h782"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/14/2010--Public Law.
Coin Modernization, Oversight, and Continuity Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report biennially to specified congressional committees on production costs for each circulating coin, cost trends, and possible new metallic materials or technologies for the production of circulating coins. Requires detailed recommendations in such reports for: (1) changes to the metallic content of circulating coins; (2) changes in coin production methodology that would further reduce the costs of production; and (3) legislative changes necessary to achieve such goals. Prohibits the Secretary from including any recommendation for specifications: (1) for producing a circulating coin that would require significant change to coin-accepting and coin-handling equipment to accommodate changes to all circulating coins simultaneously; or (2) that would facilitate or allow the use of a coin with a lesser value produced, minted, or issued by another country, or the use of any token or other easily or regularly produced metal device of minimal value, in the place of a circulating coin produced by the Secretary. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to complete the first biennial report and to develop and evaluate the use of new metallic materials for circulating coin production, to: (1) conduct any appropriate testing of appropriate coinage metallic materials; and (2) work with federal and nonfederal entities, including independent research facilities or suppliers of the metallic material used in volume production of circulating coins.</summary>
</bill>
