<bill session="111" type="s" number="3011" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Black Clergy for the Elimination of HIV/AIDS Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to address HIV/AIDS in the African-American community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1964"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2010--Introduced.
National Black Clergy for the Elimination of HIV/AIDS Act of 2009 [sic] - Authorizes the Director of the Office of Minority Health of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to public health agencies and faith-based organizations to conduct HIV/AIDS prevention, testing, and related outreach activities to reduce HIV/AIDS in the African-American community. Authorizes the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to: (1) make grants to public health agencies and faith-based organizations to conduct HIV/AIDS and sexually transmitted disease outreach, prevention, and testing activities targeted to the African-American community; and (2) provide family reunification services, mental health counseling, HIV/AIDS, sexually transmitted disease, and substance abuse testing and treatment to runaway or homeless youth or youth who are HIV positive or at risk for HIV/AIDS. Authorizes the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) make grants to faith-based organizations for public health intervention and prevention activities in the African-American community to reduce HIV/AIDS, sexually transmitted diseases, tuberculosis, and viral hepatitis; (2) expand and intensify HIV/AIDS activities in that community; (3) expand funding to build the capacity of African-American communities to respond to HIV/AIDS; and (4) implement a national media outreach campaign to urge sexually active individuals to be tested for and know their HIV/AIDS status. Authorizes the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to research strategies to reduce the transmission of HIV/AIDS in the African-American community. Authorizes the Director of the National Center on Minority Health and Health Disparities to make grants for the study of biological and behavioral factors that lead to increased HIV/AIDS prevalence in the African-American community. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration to award grants to health care professionals to treat individuals with HIV/AIDS. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) submit an annual report to Congress and the President on the impact of HIV/AIDS in the African-American community; and (2) study and report on the status of the HIV/AIDS epidemic among African-Americans. Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to: (1) National Black Clergy HIV/AIDS Awareness Sunday; (2) prevention of, testing for, and treatment of HIV/AIDS by all federal agencies; and (3) HIV testing of federal inmates by the Bureau of Prisons.</summary>
</bill>
