<bill session="113" type="h" number="2909" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Call Center Worker and Consumer Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Labor to maintain a publicly available list of all employers that relocate a call center overseas, to make such companies ineligible for Federal grants or guaranteed loans, and to require disclosure of the physical location of business agents engaging in customer service communications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412580" joined="2013-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Oversight and Government Reform, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1565"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
United States Call Center Worker and Consumer Protection Act of 2013 - Requires a business enterprise that employs 50 or more employees, excluding part-time employees, or 50 or more employees who in the aggregate work at least 1,500 hours per week, exclusive of overtime, in a call center to notify the Secretary of Labor at least 120 days before relocating such center outside of the United States. Subjects violators to a civil penalty of up to $10,000 a day. Directs the Secretary to establish, maintain, and make publicly available a list of all such employers that relocate a call center. Authorizes the Secretary to remove from the list an employer that has relocated the call center from a location outside the United States to a location inside the United States. Requires such an employer to remain on the list for up to three years after each relocation. Makes such an employer ineligible for federal grants or federal guaranteed loans for five years after being added to the list, except where the employer demonstrates that a lack of such loan or grant would threaten national security, result in substantial job loss in the United States, or harm the environment. Requires the head of federal or state executive agency or military department, when awarding a civilian or defense-related contract, to give preference to a U.S. employer that does not appear on the list. Requires a business entity that initiates or receives a customer service communication to require each of its employees or agents participating in the communication to disclose their physical location at the beginning of each such communication unless all involved employees or agents are located in the United States. Exempts any communication: (1) initiated by a consumer if the consumer knows or reasonably should know that the employee or agent is located outside the United States, or (2) related to the provision of emergency services. Requires such a business entity, upon request, to transfer a customer to a customer service agent who is physically located in the United States. Authorizes the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to exclude certain classes or types of business entities or customer services communications from the requirements of this Act under exceptionally compelling circumstances. Sets forth enforcement provisions.</summary>
</bill>
