<bill session="111" type="h" number="3933" updated="2013-07-19T23:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent the avoidance of tax on income from assets held abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2009-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4213"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1934"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2009--Introduced.
Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise and add reporting and other requirements relating to income from assets held abroad, including by: (1) requiring foreign financial and nonfinancial institutions to withhold 30% of payments made to such institutions by U.S. individuals unless such institutions agree to disclose the identity of such individuals and report on their bank transactions; (2) denying a tax deduction for interest on non-registered bonds issued outside the United States; (3) requiring any individual who holds more than $50,000 in a depository or custodial account maintained by a foreign financial institution to report on such accounts; (4) imposing an enhanced tax penalty for underpayments attributable to undisclosed foreign financial assets; (5) extending the limitation period for assessment of underpayments with respect to assets held outside the United States; (6) requiring certain tax advisors who assist U.S. individuals in acquiring a direct or indirect interest in a foreign entity to file an information return disclosing the identity of the foreign entity and the individual investors; (7) requiring shareholders of a passive foreign investment company to file informational returns; (8) enhancing tax rules and penalties relating to foreign trusts with U.S. beneficiaries; and (9) requiring withholding of tax on dividend equivalent payments received by foreign individuals.</summary>
</bill>
