<bill session="112" type="s" number="3661" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Space Exploration Sustainability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reaffirm and amend the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2012--Introduced.
Space Exploration Sustainability Act - Amends the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 to make it: (1) a long-term goal for the National Aeronautics Space Administration (NASA) to sustainably expand permanent human presence beyond low-Earth orbit and to expand economic activity in space, and (2) a key objective of the United States to expand throughout cis-lunar space (the region of space from the Earth out to and including the region around the surface of the Moon) and beyond. Requires the Administrator of NASA to submit to Congress a strategy for achieving the long-term goal of sustainably expanding a human presence beyond low-Earth orbit through robust use of cis-lunar space. Instructs NASA to proceed with the utilization of the International Space Station, technology development, and follow-on transportation systems, including the space launch system and the multi-purpose crew vehicle.</summary>
</bill>
