<bill session="110" type="s" number="977" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Furthering the Independence of Federal Prosecutors Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 11 of title 18, United States Code, to ensure United States attorneys are able to act impartially, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Special prosecutors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/2007--Introduced.
Furthering the Independence of Federal Prosecutors Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to one year for intentionally coercing, pressuring, or attempting to influence the decision of a U.S. attorney to conduct a criminal investigation or pursue a prosecution of any person based upon that person's race, sex, national origin, political activities, or political beliefs. Requires the appointment of a special prosecutor for enforcement of this Act. Prohibits a federal government attorney, in determining whether to prosecute or take other action against an individual in a criminal matter, from considering: (1) the race, religion, sex, national origin, or political association, activities or beliefs of such individual; (2) the personal feelings of such attorney concerning such individual, the associates of such individual, or the victim; or (3) the possible effect of a decision on the professional or personal circumstances of such attorney.</summary>
</bill>
