<bill session="111" type="h" number="5059" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Central Rockies Land Exchange and National Park System Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for certain land exchanges in Gunnison County, Colorado, and Uintah County, Utah.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3537"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2010--Introduced.
Central Rockies Land Exchange and National Park System Enhancement Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), if the Bear Ranch, LLC, offers to convey all interest in specified non-federal parcels of land within the Curecanti National Recreation Area in Gunnison County, Colorado, and Dinosaur National Monument in Uintah County, Utah, for inclusion in the National Park System, to accept the offer and the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to convey to the Ranch all interest of the United States in specified federal land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or the United States Forest Service. Requires the USDA Secretary, if the Darien Ranch offers to convey all interest in certain non-federal land in Gunnison County, to accept the offer, and upon receipt of such land, to convey to the Ranch a permanent right-of-way of no more than 200 feet in width for a water intake on Rapid Creek and water pipeline (and access to such intake and pipeline) running along an existing irrigation ditch from the Creek to private land. Requires the values of the federal and non-federal lands in each separate land exchange to be equal and to be determined by appraisals performed in accordance with this Act. Requires lands acquired by the Secretary and the USDA Secretary, respectively, to become part of: (1) the Curecanti National Recreation Area or Dinosaur National Monument; and (2) the unit of the National Forest System in which the land is located. Requires implementation of a travel management plan for the design, construction, improvement, replacement, or other siting of roads, trails, and trailheads in the Anthracite-Spring Creek Travel Planning Area.</summary>
</bill>
