<bill session="112" type="h" number="3880" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the imposition of sanctions on foreign financial institutions that are members of an entity that provides services relating to secure communications, electronic funds transfers, or cable transfers to the Central Bank of Iran or sanctioned financial institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2012-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2012-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA20" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 to impose sanctions on a foreign financial institution that employs a member of the board of directors of an entity that provides, or facilitates access to, services relating to secure communications, electronic funds transfers, or cable transfers to the Central Bank of Iran or a sanctioned financial institution. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from prohibiting or conditioning the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution for employing a member of the board of directors of such an entity if the services relate to petroleum-related transactions from Iran that occur before the date on which specified sanctions apply.</summary>
</bill>
