<bill session="111" type="h" number="3750" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Transfer Facilitation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize certain transfers of water in the Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2009-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2467-2468, E2491-2492"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1759"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2009--Introduced.
Water Transfer Facilitation Act of 2009 - Considers the following voluntary water transfers to meet specified conditions for authorized transfers of Central Valley Project (CVP) water under the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992: (1) a transfer of irrigation water among CVP contractors from the Friant, San Felipe, West San Joaquin, and Delta divisions; and (2) a transfer of water among current or prior temporary or long-term water service, repayment, water rights settlement, or exchange contractors within a division of the CVP. Conditions any such transfer on not interfering with the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act and the Settlement. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the Commissioner of Reclamation, to initiate and complete on an expedited basis the programmatic development of environmental documentation to facilitate voluntary water transfers within the CVP. Requires such documentation to include all applicable environmental reviews, permitting, and consultations, including the environmental documentation needed to address concerns regarding the Giant Garter Snake. Directs the Commissioner, by January 10, 2010, to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that: (1) describes the status of efforts to help facilitate and improve the water transfers under this Act, including transfers originating from the Sacramento Valley; and (2) provides recommendations on ways to facilitate and improve the process for water transfers within the CVP and water transfers between the CVP and state water projects. Requires the Commissioner to update the report by July 15, 2010, and every 180 days thereafter until no further federal action is warranted or authorized regarding the transfers under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
