<bill session="109" type="h" number="3182" updated="2013-07-19T19:32:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Water Supply Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Water Desalination Act of 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Supercomputers"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Water purification"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
National Water Supply Enhancement Act - Reauthorizes the Water Desalination Act of 1996. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish an advanced water supply enhancement program and fund research, development, and demonstration projects for the development and commercialization of advanced water supply technologies and processes, including desalination. Requires the Secretary to coordinate with a California federal research facility with experience working with state and local water authorities to carry out water treatment and water quality technology development: (1) focusing on efficient desalination and technologies for selective extraction of contaminants; (2) using resident advanced supercomputer modeling to optimize technology design; and (3) emphasizing unique new technologies, membranes, and materials, excluding incremental development of conventional technologies. Directs the Secretary and the California facility to work with local water agencies and city governments in carrying out the program to find solutions for local water needs. Requires the Secretary to: (1) submit a report to Congress that identifies federal research facilities around the United States that could serve as regional centers for water supply enhancement; and (2) conduct a study of the management and disposal of concentrates produced in the production of desalinated waters from coastal water and brackish water and evaluate possible solutions to the management and disposal of concentrates.</summary>
</bill>
