<bill session="111" type="h" number="5853" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fiscal Responsibility and Retirement Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XXXII of the Public Health Service Act to require review and approval by law prior to collection of premiums under the CLASS program, to require notice to individuals prior to enrollment, and to require termination of the program in the event of actuarial unsoundness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400038" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412277" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2010--Introduced.
Fiscal Responsibility and Retirement Security Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to require congressional approval of the designation by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) of a benefit plan as the CLASS Independence Benefit Plan under the CLASS program (a national, voluntary insurance program for purchasing community living assistance services and supports). Sets forth procedures for such congressional approval by joint resolution. Prohibits an employer from enrolling an employee in the CLASS program without providing specified notice to the employee, which includes: (1) the significant risk of failure of such a program; (2) information on deficits that the program is expected to run; (3) a statement that there is no separate pool of money set aside to pay the CLASS program benefits; and (4) an explanation of the immediate termination of the program if it is reported to be actuarially unsound. Prohibits premiums from being collected before the Secretary has promulgated the required regulations in final form. Terminates such program if the report by the Board of Trustees of the CLASS Independence Fund indicates that the Fund is projected to be actuarially unsound over the 75-year period beginning with the fiscal year in which such report is submitted. Establishes a refund process.</summary>
</bill>
