<bill session="109" type="s" number="846" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide fair wages for America's workers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3902-3903" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-04-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="80">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 80.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to deny any force or effect to any portion of a rule promulgated on April 23, 2004, that has the effect of exempting from FLSA overtime compensation requirements (which limit maximum hours at regular compensation) any employee who would not otherwise be exempted if regulations in effect on March 31, 2003, remained in effect. Reinstates that portion of such regulations that would prevent such an employee from being exempt. Directs the Secretary of Labor to increase, in a specified manner, the minimum salary level for the exemption for executive, administrative, and managerial occupations from FLSA overtime compensation requirements. Amends the FLSA to increase the Federal minimum wage to: (1) $5.85 an hour, beginning on the 60th day after enactment of this Act; (2) $6.55 an hour, beginning 12 months after that 60th day; and (3) $7.25 an hour, beginning 24 months after that 60th day. Expresses the sense of the Senate regarding multiemployer pension plans.</summary>
</bill>
