<bill session="109" type="s" number="2803" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Coal Mine Safety bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mine Improvement and New Emergency Response Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MINER Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Mine Improvement and New Emergency Response Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">MINER Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Mine Improvement and New Emergency Response Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">MINER Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Mine Improvement and New Emergency Response Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">MINER Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to improve the safety of mines and mining.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2006-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2006-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2006-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4619"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/17/2006 S4707-4710" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Frist for Senator Enzi with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="439">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 439.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-05-24" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5045-5050" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5045-5048" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3449-3458" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2803.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3480" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-06-07T19:14:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="234" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 381 - 37 (Roll no. 234).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3449-3452" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07T19:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-06-15" type="public" number="109-236">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-236.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="2006-12-06">
      <text>By Senator Enzi from Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions filed written report. Report No. 109-365.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5432"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5481"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Government and the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2006--Public Law.
Mine Improvement and New Emergency Response Act of 2006 or the MINER Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to require underground coal mine operators to: (1) carry out continuously a program to improve accident preparedness and response at each mine; and (2) adopt and update accident response plan for evacuations and for maintenance of individuals trapped underground. Requires such a plan to provide for: (1) redundant means and local coordination of communication; (2) post-accident location of underground personnel; (3) emergency air supplies; (4) self-rescuer caches, maintenance, and replacement; (5) escapeways and flame-resistant directional lifelines; (6) emergency training; and (7) within three years, post accident wireless communication between underground and the surface and electronic tracking of trapped persons. (Sec. 3) Declares that no one may bring an action against covered individuals or their regular employers for property damage or injury (or deaths) resulting from mine accident rescue operations, unless the damage or injury was the result of gross negligence, reckless conduct, or illegal conduct or where the regular employer is the operator of the mine where the rescue activity takes place. Defines "regular employer" to mean the entity that is the covered employee's legal or statutory employer pursuant to applicable state law. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Labor to require: (1) Mine Safety and Health Administration (MSHA) to establish and update criteria to certify the qualifications of mine rescue teams; and (2) mine operators to have one employee knowledgeable in emergency response on each shift and two certified mine rescue teams available at each mine within one hour. (Sec. 5) Requires notification of a mine accident to be provided to the Secretary by the operator within 15 minutes of knowledge of a death or potentially fatal injury. Imposes a civil penalty upon operators who do not provide such notification. (Sec. 6) Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to establish within the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) an Office of Mine Safety and Health to enhance the development of new mine safety technology and applications and to expedite the commercial availability and implementation of such technology. Authorizes the NIOSH Director to: (1) award competitive grants to institutions and private entities to encourage the development and manufacture of mine safety equipment; (2) award contracts to educational institutions or private laboratories for the performance of product testing or related work with respect to new mine technology and equipment; and (3) establish an interagency working group to share technology, research, and developments concerning mine safety and accident response. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to require: (1) the temporary assignment of a departmental official as a liaison with the families of victims of mine tragedies involving multiple deaths; and (2) MSHA to be as responsive as possible to family requests for information and to serve as the primary communicator. (Sec. 8) Prescribes penalties for operator violations of health or safety standards or orders, including withdrawal orders. (Sec. 9) Authorizes the Secretary to institute a civil action for relief when an operator violates orders or decisions issued under this Act. (Sec. 10) Requires the Secretary to finalize mandatory health and safety standards relating to the sealing of abandoned areas in coal mines which shall increase the current 20 psi standard. (Sec. 11) Establishes a Technical Study Panel to provide independent scientific review and recommendations regarding the use of belt air and the composition and fire retardant properties of belt materials in mines. (Sec. 12) Requires the Secretary of Education to establish a program to provide scholarships to individuals to increase the skilled workforce for mine operators, mine safety inspectors, and other MSHA personnel. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 13) Requires NIOSH to provide for research on various refuge alternatives in an underground coal mines. (Sec. 14) Requires the Secretary of Labor to award Brookwood-Sago Mine Safety Grants for education and training programs to better identify and prevent unsafe working conditions in and around mines. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
