<bill session="113" type="h" number="2107" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No More Ghost Money Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit monetary payments by the Federal Government to employees, officers, and elected officials of foreign countries for purposes of bribery, coercion, or any activity that is illegal or undermines the rule of law or corrupts a public officer or the office such officer represents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
No More Ghost Money Act - Prohibits any federal department, agency, or federal government contractor from making a monetary payment to any official of a foreign country for the purposes of bribery, coercion, or any illegal activity that undermines the rule of law or corrupts a public official. Requires the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) to report to Congress on all monetary payments made by the CIA to officials of the Government of Afghanistan on or after September 11, 2001. Authorizes the President to waive the requirements of this Act if compliance would harm U.S. national security or members of the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
