<bill session="111" type="s" number="3411" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Help HAITI Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Help Haitian Adoptees Immediately to Integrate Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the adjustment of status for certain Haitian orphans paroled into the United States after the earthquake of January 12, 2010.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2010-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2010-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5283"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Introduced.
Help Haitian Adoptees Immediately to Integrate Act of 2010 or the Help HAITI Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to adjust to permanent resident status an alien who was granted parole admission into the United States pursuant to the humanitarian parole policy for certain Haitian orphans announced on January 18, 2010, and suspended as to new applications on April 15, 2010, if such alien: (1) applies for adjustment; (2) is physically present in the United States when the adjustment application is filed; and (3) is admissible as an immigrant. Deems such an alien to satisfy the requirements applicable to adopted children if, before the alien is 18 years of age, he or she adjusts to permanent resident status and is adopted by a U.S. citizen (which may occur before, on, or after status adjustment). Permits a parent or legal guardian to apply on behalf of a minor. Prohibits any derivative immigration benefits for the birth parent of an alien adjusted under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
