<bill session="111" type="h" number="2441" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">First Responders Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide adequate benefits for public safety officers injured or killed in the line of duty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400635"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4338"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1037"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2885"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
First Responders Support Act of 2009 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) increase death and disability benefits for public safety officers; and (2) expand educational benefits for dependents of public safety officers killed or disabled in the line of duty. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for up to $7,500 of the medical expenses paid or incurred by a public safety officer or a family member for injuries sustained while such officer was performing an official duty. Authorizes the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to award grants for mental health services or counseling to public safety officers seriously injured in the line of duty and the family members of such officers who are killed or seriously injured in the line of duty.</summary>
</bill>
