<bill session="111" type="s" number="3184" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Protection Compact Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Child Protection Compact Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide United States assistance for the purpose of eradicating severe forms of trafficking in children in eligible countries through the implementation of Child Protection Compacts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2010-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2010-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment. With written report No. 111-337.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="624">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 624.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2737"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Child Protection Compact Act of 2010 - (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary of State, through the Ambassador-at-Large of the Department of State's Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, to provide assistance (grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts with eligible entities) for an eligible country with a significant prevalence of trafficking in children that enters into a Child Protection Compact with the United States to support policies and programs to eradicate the trafficking of children. Specifies an eligible entity to be: (1) the national government of an eligible country; (2) regional or local governmental units of the country; or (3) a nongovernmental organization or a private entity with expertise in the protection of vulnerable children, the investigation and prosecution of those who engage in or benefit from child trafficking, or rescue of child victims of trafficking. (Sec. 5) Sets forth the following initial criteria for Compact eligibility: (1) the country is eligible for assistance from the International Development Association and has a per capita income that is equal to or less than the Association's historical ceiling; (2) the country is not ineligible for certain U.S. economic assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961; and (3) the country is a Tier II country or Tier II Watch List country designated as not meeting minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking. States that a country should be selected for a Compact based upon: (1) a documented high prevalence of trafficking of children within the country; and (2) a demonstrated government commitment to address severe forms of trafficking of children, including enforcement of laws criminalizing such trafficking, cooperation with appropriate local and international non-governmental organizations, and treatment of child trafficking victims in accordance the Protocol to Prevent, Suppress and Punish Trafficking in Persons, Especially Women and Children, Supplementing the United Nations Convention Against Transnational Organized Crime. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide assistance under this Act only if a country enters into a Child Protection Compact with the United States that establishes a three-year plan for achieving shared objectives; and (2) enter into contracts or make grants to facilitate Compact development and implementation. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary to suspend or terminate assistance if a country or entity: (1) is engaged in activities which are contrary to U.S. national security interests; (2) has engaged in a pattern of actions inconsistent with eligibility criteria; or (3) has failed to adhere to its Compact responsibilities. (Sec. 8) Sets forth congressional notification and reporting provisions. (Sec. 9) Expresses the sense of Congress that, of the total amounts to be appropriated for FY2011-FY2013 for the Department of State and foreign operations, up to $30 million should be used to carry out the purposes of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
