<bill session="112" type="hr" number="597" updated="2013-07-20T01:08:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-28T14:39:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-28T14:39:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 112) establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2013 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2014 through 2022, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-423, by Mr. Woodall.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The first reading of the concurrent resolution shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution are waived. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Each amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, and shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. All points of order against such amendments are waived except that the adoption of an amendment in the nature of a substitute shall constitute the conclusion of consideration of the concurrent resolution for amendment. It shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of March 29, 2012, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules, as though under clause 1 of rule XV, relating to a measure extending expiring surface transportation authority.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-27T18:47:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="122">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1654-1662, H1663-1664" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 597.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 183 (Roll no. 139).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1662" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-03-28T14:39:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="140" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 184 (Roll no. 140).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1654" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="hc" number="112"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2012--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 112) establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2013 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2014 through 2022, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</summary>
</bill>
