<bill session="112" type="hr" number="199" updated="2013-07-20T01:04:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the 29 coal miners who perished in the explosion at the Upper Big Branch Mine in Montcoal, West Virginia, on April 5, 2010, and remembering all those who have lost their lives while mining for the resources on which the United States relies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sr" number="129"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2011--Introduced.
Honors the coal miners who lost their lives in the explosion at the Upper Big Branch Mine in Montcoal, West Virginia, on April 5, 2010. Extends the continued heartfelt condolences of the House of Representatives to the families of the deceased, who are still looking for answers to the tragedy. Recognizes the hardships faced by survivors of the tragedy and fellow miners who worked side-by-side with the deceased. Acknowledges the risks faced by all miners, as well as the important and often overlooked contributions that miners make to the United States. Expresses the appreciation of the House for the volunteers, first responders, and mine rescue teams who fearlessly risk their lives to save miners after tragedies. Reaffirms the commitment of the House to keep miners safe and healthy on the job.</summary>
</bill>
