<bill session="112" type="s" number="1135" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy and Revenue Enrichment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the reenrichment of certain depleted uranium owned by the Department of Energy, and for the sale or barter of the resulting reenriched uranium, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3448" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2054"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Energy and Revenue Enrichment Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to contract with a qualified operator for a 24-month pilot program for the reenrichment at an enrichment plant of certain depleted uranium, beginning no later than June 1, 2012. Authorizes the Secretary to sell the reenriched uranium generated under the contract and allocate the proceeds according to a certain scheme. Directs the Secretary to assume title to, and responsibility for, the disposition of depleted uranium so generated. Prohibits the Secretary from selling, each year during the pilot program and the subsequent 24 months after program completion, an amount of uranium exceeding 15% of the U.S. domestic uranium supply. Prohibits the sale of more than 10% of the U.S. domestic uranium supply during any year after such 48-month period, unless such sales will have no significant effect on uranium markets.</summary>
</bill>
