<bill session="111" type="sr" number="63" updated="2013-07-20T00:16:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to amend the Standing Rules of the Senate to ensure that all congressionally directed spending items in appropriations and authorization legislation fall under the oversight and transparency provisions of S. 1, the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2773-2774"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2773" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2009--Introduced.
Amends Rule XLIV (Congressionally Directed Spending and Related Items) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require all congressionally directed spending items to be included in the text of an appropriations or authorization bill and its conference report. Requires a Senator's request for such an item, together with specified information, to be posted on the Senator's website within 48 hours of the request. Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate legislation that contains a congressionally directed spending item for a private for-profit or non profit entity. Authorizes a Senator to raise a point of order against one or more provisions of a conference report if they constitute a congressionally directed spending item that was not included in the measure originally committed to the conferees by either chamber. Makes it out of order to vote on the adoption of a conference report unless it is available in a searchable format on a publicly accessible congressional website at least 48 hours before such vote. Requires an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Members of the Senate to waive application of such points of order. Requires each committee of jurisdiction to make required statements and certifications under the Rule about each congressionally directed spending item available for public inspection on the Internet within 48 hours after receipt of a request.</summary>
</bill>
