<bill session="112" type="h" number="2819" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Subsidizing Hollywood Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, and any other officer or employee of the Federal Government from providing information about the mission to kill Osama bin Laden to any person outside the Federal Government until the Inspectors General of the Department of Defense and the Central Intelligence Agency carry out an investigation and provide a briefing to Congress on the matter, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412284"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/12/2011--Introduced.
Stop Subsidizing Hollywood Act - Prohibits the Secretary of Defense, Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, and any other federal officer or employee from providing any information about the mission to kill Osama bin Laden to any person outside the federal government until the completion of an investigation and classified briefing to Congress by the Inspectors General of the Department of Defense (DOD) and Central Intelligence Agency (CIA). Requires such investigation and briefing to consider, at a minimum, all the questions set forth in the letter of August 9, 2011, from the Chairman of the House Committee on Homeland Security to such Inspectors General. Directs the Secretary to: (1) determine the full costs of operations for providing assistance to entertainment media by the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Public Affairs, and (2) require that fees charged to persons receiving such assistance be adequate to cover such full costs.</summary>
</bill>
