<bill session="109" type="s" number="961" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to reauthorize and reform the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-256.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1600"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mine water"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Reform Act of 2005 - Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to repeal the authorization for use of certain moneys in the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund: (1) by the Secretary of Agriculture for reclamation of rural lands; and (2) by the Department of the Interior for certain studies, research, and demonstration projects. Extends the authority to collect reclamation fees to 2019. Revises Fund allocation requirements with respect to such fees. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer specified sums to: (1) the United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund; (2) the United Mine Workers of America 1992 Benefit Plan; and (3) a certain multiemployer health benefit plan established after July 20, 1992, by the parties that are the settlors of the 1992 Plan. Repeals Fund objectives concerning: (1) protection , construction, or enhancement of public facilities such as utilities, roads, recreation and conservation facilities adversely affected by coal mining practices; and (2) the development of publicly owned land adversely affected by coal mining practices, including land acquired as provided for recreation and historic purposes, conservation, and reclamation purposes and open space benefits. States that no lien shall be filed against any person who neither consented to, nor participated in, nor exercised control over the mining operation which necessitated reclamation. Repeals the limitation of such prohibition to persons who owned the surface before May 2, 1977. Modifies guidelines for certification of completion of coal reclamation.</summary>
</bill>
