<bill session="111" type="h" number="2056" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Money, Clean Elections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the financing of House elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications, Technology, and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission (FEC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Introduced.
Clean Money, Clean Elections Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) with respect to: (1) eligibility and qualifying contribution requirements, seed money limits, and benefits of clean election financing of House election campaigns; (2) establishment of a House Clean Elections Fund; (3) eligibility for Fund allocations as well as such allocations; (4) a seed money contribution requirement; (5) contribution and expenditure requirements; (6) certification of whether or not a federal election candidate is a clean money candidate; (7) benefits for participating candidates; (8) payment of fair fight funds; (9) administration of the House Clean Elections System; (10) reporting requirements for nonparticipating candidates; (11) modification of electioneering communication reporting requirements; (12) limitation on coordinated expenditures by political party committees with participating candidates; and (13) treatment of coordinated expenditures as contributions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a tax credit for voluntary donations to the House Clean Elections Fund. Establishes the Clean Elections Review Commission. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to entitle clean money candidates to receive specified free broadcast time and reduced broadcast rates in certain circumstances. Amends federal postal law to prohibit franked mass mailings by Members of Congress (except public meeting notices) during the 90 days before primary and general election periods, unless they are not candidates for re-election to any other federal office. Amends FECA to: (1) empower the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to petition the U.S. Supreme Court for a proceeding on certiorari; and (2) reduce from 48 to 24 hours the deadline for electronic filing with the FEC of reports by each political committee of contributions received within 90 days before an election.</summary>
</bill>
