<bill session="113" type="s" number="559" updated="2013-11-02T06:56:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Former American Hostages in Iran Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Justice for Former American Hostages in Iran Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a fund to make payments to the Americans held hostage in Iran, and to members of their families, who are identified as members of the proposed class in case number 1:08-CV-00487 (EGS) of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 113-104.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="183">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 183.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3200"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Justice for Former American Hostages in Iran Act of 2013 - Establishes in the Treasury the American Hostages in Iran Compensation Fund for the purpose of making payments to the 52 Americans held hostage in the U.S. embassy in Tehran, Iran, from November 3, 1979-January 20, 1981. Imposes a surcharge, to be deposited into the Fund, of 30% on the amount of: (1) any fine or monetary penalty assessed on a person for violation of a law or regulation penalizing any economic activity relating to Iran that is administered by the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Justice (DOJ), or the Department of Commerce; or (2) the monetary amount of a settlement entered into by a person regarding a suspected violation of such a law or regulation. Requires Fund payments of $150,000 plus $5,000 for each day of captivity first to each living former hostage and then to the estate of each deceased former hostage. Requires a payment recipient to waive and forever release all existing claims against Iran and the United States arising out of the hostage events. Directs the Secretary to notify each individual qualified to receive a payment of the individual's claim status. States that: (1) if a claim is denied or approved for less than the full amount, the individual shall be entitled to submit additional information; (2) the Secretary may affirm, modify, or revise the former action; and (3) the Secretary's actions in identifying claimants and in disbursing Fund amounts shall be final on all questions of law and fact, and shall not be subject to review by any other U.S. official, agency, or court. Directs the Secretary to report annually to Congress on the status of the Fund until the date: (1) on which all amounts have been made to all recipients, or (2) five years after the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
