<bill session="110" type="h" number="3850" updated="2013-07-19T21:37:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible and Effective Solutions for Children Using and Entering Online Services Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the collection and use of data related to crimes of child exploitation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2007--Introduced.
Responsible and Effective Solutions for Children Using and Entering Online Services Act of 2007 - Amends the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 to: (1) specify the types of information that providers of electronic communication or remote computing services (providers) should include, if available, in reports of apparent child pornography violations; (2) authorize the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC) to forward provider reports to appropriate state, local, and foreign law enforcement agencies; (3) grant immunity from criminal prosecution (in addition to civil immunity) to providers who comply in good faith with child pornography reporting requirements; (4) authorize NCMEC to provide images of child pornography to providers to assist them in stopping the further transmission of child pornography images and in developing technologies and best practices to prevent and detect child pornography; and (5) preempt state laws that impose notification and liability provisions pertaining to child pornography on the Internet.</summary>
</bill>
