<bill session="113" type="h" number="2206" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Tolerance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide enhanced protections for prospective members and new members of the Armed Forces during entry-level processing and training.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
No Tolerance Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to establish and maintain a policy to uniformly define and prescribe what constitutes an inappropriate and prohibited relationship, communication, conduct, or contact, including when such an action is consensual, between: (1) a member of the Armed Forces (member) who is superior in rank to, exercises control over, or supervises a person during entry-level process or training; and (2) a prospective member or member undergoing such processing and training. Makes violators subject to prosecution under the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ). Directs such Secretaries to require the processing for administrative separation of any member in response to the first substantiated violation of such policy, if the member is not otherwise punitively discharged or dismissed for such violation. Requires the DOD Secretary to submit to the congressional defense committees a proposed UCMJ punitive article regarding such violations.</summary>
</bill>
