<bill session="111" type="s" number="247" updated="2013-07-20T00:25:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accelerated Retirement of Inefficient Vehicles Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to accelerate motor fuel savings nationwide and provide incentives to registered owners of high fuel consumption automobiles to replace such automobiles with fuel efficient automobiles or public transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S394-395"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S396-397" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1550"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1606"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2640"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2751"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1135"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1200"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1248"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2009--Introduced.
Accelerated Retirement of Inefficient Vehicles Act of 2009 - Establishes in the Department of Energy the Accelerated Retirement of Inefficient Vehicles Program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) authorize the issuance of a redeemable voucher, with limitations, to the registered owner of an eligible high fuel consumption automobile for the purchase of a new or used fuel efficient automobile upon transfer of the eligible automobile title to a participating dealer, dismantler, or scrap recycling facility; (2) allow a dealer, dismantler, or scrap recycling facility to participate in the program if they agree to scrap the eligible high fuel consumption automobile, issue a voucher to its owner, and meet all applicable requirements; (3) require dealers to accept such vouchers as partial payment for the purchase of a new or used fuel efficient automobile; and (4) make payments to dealers who accepted vouchers between January 1, 2009, and December 31, 2014. Authorizes the use of vouchers to acquire single-passenger transit fare credits. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations that allow operators of bus and rail public transit systems to redeem properly issued vouchers to offset the purchase price of annual transit passes or any other form of individual transit fare credit designated by the transit system operator. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
