<bill session="110" type="s" number="2709" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Crossing Deterrence Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase the criminal penalties for illegally reentering the United States and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-03-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="594">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 594.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2008--Introduced.
Border Crossing Deterrence Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to expand Operation Streamline (the zero-tolerance prosecution policy for illegal entry and reentry) to all 20 border sectors. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) revise and increase criminal penalties, including establishing mandatory minimum penalties, for an alien's entry into the United States at an improper time or place; and (2) revise criminal penalty and related provisions, and establish mandatory minimum sentences, respecting the reentry of an alien who has been removed from the United States. Amends the federal criminal code to establish a mandatory minimum criminal penalty of five years for an alien's destruction of U.S. government-installed border barriers or infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
