<bill session="110" type="s" number="2350" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Glaucoma Screening Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program to provide screenings for glaucoma to individuals determined to be at a high risk for glaucoma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3005"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2007--Introduced.
Glaucoma Screening Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to expand coverage of screening for glaucoma to include individuals who are both older than 49 years of age and Hispanic.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program to award a grant to an eligible entity to provide glaucoma screenings to individuals determined to be at high risk. Requires such an entity to: (1) utilize mobile screening units to test for glaucoma and other eye diseases; (2) target screening activities to populations primarily consisting of high-risk individuals; (3) form partnerships with federally-qualified health centers to increase awareness of the need for glaucoma screenings and to provide screenings for high-risk individuals; and (4) provide grants to approved medical residency training programs to permit participating students to conduct such screenings.</summary>
</bill>
