<bill session="113" type="s" number="1035" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Targeted Strike Oversight Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require an independent alternative analysis of the consideration of the use of targeted lethal force against a particular, known United States person knowingly engaged in acts of international terrorism against the United States and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412545"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Targeted Strike Oversight Reform Act of 2013 - Requires the head of an element of the intelligence community to notify the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) upon determining that a U.S. person is engaged in acts of international terrorism against the United States such that the government is considering the legality or use of targeted lethal force against that person. Requires the DNI: (1) within 15 days thereafter, to complete an independent alternative analysis of the information relied on to support such determination; (2) to notify the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community (IG) and the congressional intelligence committees of the receipt of such notification; and (3) to notify such committees of the person's identity and the results of the independent analysis. Directs the IG to annually review, and report to the DNI and such committees on, any notifications received and the compliance of each element of the intelligence community with all appropriate policies and procedures related to the use of targeted lethal force against a U.S. person.</summary>
</bill>
