<bill session="109" type="hr" number="602" updated="2013-07-19T18:59:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15T13:11:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-15T13:11:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2830) to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the pension funding rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T22:51:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-346, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T22:51:00-05:00">
      <text>In lieu of the amendments recommended by the Committees on Education and the Workforce and Ways and Means now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. During consideration of H.R. 2830 pursuant to this resolution, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the bill to a time designated by the Speaker.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-12-14T22:51:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="131">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 131.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T10:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11660-11670" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T10:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 602.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T11:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11669" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T11:28:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 602 the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T12:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11678" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-12-15T13:11:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="633" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 199 (Roll no. 633).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11660" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T13:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="109" type="h" number="2830"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2830 (Pension Protection Act of 2005).</summary>
</bill>
