<bill session="112" type="h" number="6686" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mercury Use Reduction Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act relating to certain mercury compounds, products, and processes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="3697"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2012--Introduced.
Mercury Use Reduction Act of 2012 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) to redefine &#8220;mercury&#8221; as: (1) elemental mercury, (2) a mercury compound, and (3) a mixture that contains elemental mercury or a mercury compound that is mixed with any other material. Prohibits, beginning on January 1, 2014, the: (1) production of mercury from the extraction, beneficiation, and processing of mercury-containing ores and minerals (specifies that such prohibition does not prohibit the production of mercury from mining of other ores if the mercury is produced incidentally from the beneficiation or processing of that ore or related pollution control activities); (2) production of vinyl chloride monomer using a mercury-added feedstock or catalyst; (3) manufacturing, processing, or distribution in commerce of certain mercury-added measuring devices, a mercury-added pesticide, a mercury-added thermostat, or a mercury-added relay or mercury-added switch; and (4) export of certain mercury compounds or such mercury-added products. Prohibits, beginning on January 1, 2015, the: (1) manufacturing, processing, or distribution in commerce of a mercury-added battery, individually or as a component of a product; and (2) exporting of such mercury-added batteries. Sets forth exemptions to such prohibitions. Amends the Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act to repeal provisions concerning phasing out the use of batteries that contain mercury. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) report on the use of mercury to produce polyurethane products; (2) publish an inventory of mercury supply, use, and trade by April 1, 2014, and every three years thereafter; and (3) publish a list of such compounds the export of which is prohibited. Establishes reporting requirements for manufactures of mercury or mercury-added products and manufacturers that intentionally use mercury in a manufacturing process. Authorizes elemental mercury to be stored on a long-term basis at a facility for which a permit has been issued for that purpose under the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Exempts such long-term storage from prohibitions on hazardous waste disposal under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
