<bill session="111" type="h" number="2973" updated="2013-07-19T23:38:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Interior to notify units of local government when a Native American group files a petition to become a federally recognized Indian tribe and before the decision on the petition is made, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2009--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, to notify certain local governments: (1) within 60 days after a petition is filed requesting that a tribe be recognized, acknowledged, or reacknowledged as a federally recognized Indian tribe; (2) within 30 days after enactment of this Act regarding pending petitions; and (3) 90 days before a decision on a petition is announced. Describes a local government to be notified as a local city, parish, or county government located within a 25-mile radius of land that would be taken into trust for or transferred to, or for which jurisdiction would be given to, a tribe pursuant to such a petition. Prohibits Secretary from taking land into trust for the benefit of an Indian tribe or member thereof unless an Act enacted after this Act specifically instructs the Secretary to do so. Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to make the Act inapplicable to an Indian tribe or to Indian lands of an Indian tribe until that tribe has been a federally recognized Indian tribe for at least 25 continuous years, except for tribes that were federally recognized before enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
