<bill session="113" type="h" number="74" updated="2013-11-02T06:19:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Traffic Stops Along the Border Statistics Study Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the collection of data on traffic stops, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
Traffic Stops Along the Border Statistics Study Act of 2013 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) conduct a nationwide study of stops for traffic violations by law enforcement officers; (2) perform an initial analysis of existing data, including complaints alleging and information concerning traffic stops motivated by race and other bias; and (3) gather specified data from a nationwide sample of jurisdictions, including the traffic infraction alleged to have been committed that led to the stop, identifying characteristics of the driver stopped, whether immigration status was questioned, and whether any warning or citation was issued as a result of the stop. Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to law enforcement agencies to collect and submit data collected under this Act to the appropriate agency as designated by the Attorney General. Prohibits information released from revealing the identity of any individual who is stopped or any officer involved.</summary>
</bill>
