<bill session="111" type="h" number="1343" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">First Responders Fighting Terrorism Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide immunity from civil liability to first responders engaged in lawful efforts to prevent acts of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2010-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2009--Introduced.
First Responders Fighting Terrorism Protection Act of 2009 - Grants qualified immunity from civil liability for a first responder who: (1) takes reasonable action to prevent an act of terrorism; or (2) observes or receives a report of, and takes reasonable action to respond to, any suspicious transaction, activity, or occurrence that indicates that an individual may be engaging, or preparing to engage, in a violation of law relating to a terrorist act. Makes a first responder not entitled to assert the defense of qualified immunity nevertheless immune from civil liability under federal, state, and local law if such responder acted in good faith and on objectively reasonable suspicion. Entitles a first responder found to be immune from liability under this Act to recover from the plaintiff all reasonable costs and attorney fees.</summary>
</bill>
