<bill session="112" type="h" number="2273" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-14T14:13:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-14T14:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to facilitate recovery and beneficial use, and provide for the proper management and disposal, of materials generated by the combustion of coal and other fossil fuels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412414" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2011-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-26T12:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-226.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-26T12:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="147">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 147.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 431 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2273 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce shall be considered as an original bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 431 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 431.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6934-6959" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2273 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce shall be considered as an original bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T10:49:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 431 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T10:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Kevin Yoder to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T10:49:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2273.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T11:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shimkus amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment No 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rush amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rush amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rush demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the adoption of amendments which had previously been debated and on which further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T13:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2273.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T13:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6956" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6943-6945" label="text  of committee amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cicilline moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6956-6958" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6956" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cicilline motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to implement a warning system in the event of a catastrophic failure at a coal ash disposal site. Under this amendment, the EPA Administrator must require the owner or operator of a surface coal ash disposal site, such as a disposal pile or lagoon, to equip such site with a sufficient system to monitor for, and notify the public of a potentially hazardous condition that could lead to failure of the site's ability to contain coal ash.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6957" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T14:06:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 172 - 238 (Roll no. 799).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-10-14T14:13:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="800" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 267 - 144 (Roll no. 800).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="202">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 202.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="431"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3409"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1751"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1971"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3512"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h837"/>
    <amendment number="h838"/>
    <amendment number="h839"/>
    <amendment number="h840"/>
    <amendment number="h841"/>
    <amendment number="h842"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/14/2011--Passed House amended.
Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize states to adopt and implement coal combustion residuals permit programs. Requires each state governor to notify the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) within six months about whether such state will implement such a program. Requires states that decide to implement such a program to: (1) submit to the Administrator within 36 months a certification that such program meets the specifications of this Act; and (2) maintain either an approved municipal solid waste program for the control of hazardous disposal or an authorized state hazardous waste program. Establishes minimum requirements for coal combustion residuals permit programs. Requires: (1) the revised criteria established by this Act to apply to such programs; (2) landfills, surface impoundments, or other land-based units that may receive coal combustion residuals (structures) to be designed, constructed, and maintained to provide for containment of the maximum volumes of coal combustion residuals appropriate for the structure; (3) such programs to apply such revised criteria to surface impoundments; and (4) new structures that first receive coal combustion residuals after this Act's enactment to be constructed with a base located a minimum of two feet above the upper limit of the natural water table. Authorizes: (1) state agency heads to require action to correct structural integrity deficiencies according to a schedule for structures that are classified as posing a high hazard potential pursuant to the guidelines published by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) entitled "Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety: Hazard Potential Classification System for Dams"; (2) state agency heads to require that such a structure close if such deficiency is not corrected according to such schedule; (3) states to inspect structures and implement and enforce such permit program; and (4) states to address wind dispersal of dust from coal combustion residuals by requiring dust control measures. Sets forth revised criteria for such programs with respect to: (1) design, groundwater monitoring, corrective action, and closure and post-closure for structures; (2) location restrictions for new structures in floodplains, wetlands, fault areas, seismic impact zones, and unstable areas; (3) criteria for air quality, financial assurance, surface water, and record keeping; (4) criteria for run-on and run-off control systems for landfills and other land-based units, other than surface impoundments that receive coal combustion residuals; and (5) run-off control systems for surface impoundments. Authorizes states to determine that such criteria is not needed for the management of their coal combustion residuals permit program. Authorizes the Administrator to treat such state determination as a deficiency if it does not accurately reflect the needs for the management of coal combustion residuals in the state. Requires the Administrator to provide a state with notice of, and an opportunity to remedy, deficiencies. Requires the Administrator to implement such a program for a state only if: (1) the governor of such state notifies the Administrator that such state will not implement a program, (2) the state is notified of, but fails to remedy, program deficiencies, or (3) the state notifies the Administrator that it will no longer implement such a program. Sets forth provisions concerning resumption of implementation by states. Requires the time period and method for a structure's closure to be set forth in a schedule in a closure plan that takes into account the site-specific characteristics of such structure. Directs the closure plan for a surface impoundment to require the removal of liquid and the stabilization of remaining waste as necessary to support the final cover. Prohibits the Administrator from applying such programs to the utilization, placement, and storage of coal combustion residuals at surface mining and reclamation operations. (Sec. 3) Prohibits this Act from being construed to alter the EPA's regulatory determination, entitled "Notice of Regulatory Determination on Wastes from the Combustion of Fossil Fuels," that the fossil fuel combustion wastes addressed in that determination do not warrant regulation under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
