<bill session="109" type="s" number="3483" updated="2013-07-19T20:43:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Innovation Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">College Pathway Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Teacher Professional Development Institutes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve national competitiveness through enhanced education initiatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5662-5663"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5663-5669" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Learning"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Magnet schools"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2006--Introduced.
National Innovation Education Act - College Pathway Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states to establish preschool through postsecondary (P-16) education stewardship commissions or systems consisting of such commissions and P-16 education data systems. Tasks each commission with reaching a consensus among statewide education stakeholders on the skills, knowledge, and patterns of coursework needed to successfully transition to and complete postsecondary education. Requires that state-level longitudinal P-16 data systems track the academic performance of each student so that the factors which correlate with such success may be identified and publicized. Authorizes the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award competitive grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for the development or improvement of magnet school programs which focus on science, mathematics, and technology education. Directs the NSF to award grants to LEAs to enable implementation of innovation-based experiential learning. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education for integrated courses in mathematics, science, or engineering and teacher education, that lead to undergraduate degrees in such fields with concurrent teacher certification. Requires grantees to work with LEAs to support new teachers. Teachers Professional Development Institutes Act - Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to partnerships, or joint ventures between institutions of higher education and LEAs serving a significant low-income population, for the conduct of collaborative seminars designed to enhance the subject matter and pedagogical resources of seminar participants. Requires the NSF to: (1) expand the Graduate Research Fellowship Program and the Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship Program; (2) establish a clearinghouse for sharing program elements used in successful professional science master's degree programs; (3) award grants for pilot programs to four-year institutions of higher education to facilitate the creation or improvement of such programs; (4) submit a multiyear plan that describes how the funds authorized by this Act for doubling research funding shall be used; and (5) study how the federal government should support the new discipline of service science. Authorizes appropriations for the NSF Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology Talent Expansion Program.</summary>
</bill>
