<bill session="112" type="h" number="6535" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Save America's National Economy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to repeal the sequestration added by the Budget Control Act of 2011, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1124"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Save America's National Economy Act - Repeals provisions of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, as added by the Budget Control Act of 2011, that require automatic reductions in discretionary spending (sequestration) between FY2013 and FY2021. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase individual income tax rates for taxpayers whose taxable income exceeds $1 million, and (2) provide for an adjustment in the capital gains tax of taxpayers whose taxable income is subject to the 45% tax bracket. Establishes caps on funding levels for overseas contingency operations and related activities for FY2013-FY2021.</summary>
</bill>
