<bill session="112" type="s" number="790" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for mandatory training for Federal Government supervisors and the assessment of management competencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2391-2392"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2392-2393" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1492"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2011--Introduced.
Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2011 - Expands requirements relating to specific training programs for federal agency supervisors by requiring the head of each federal agency to establish: (1) a program to train supervisors in carrying out their duties, including mentoring and motivating employees, fostering a employee-friendly work environment, and effectively managing employees with unacceptable performance ratings; (2) a program to train supervisors on prohibited personnel practices. employee collective bargaining and union participation rights, and the procedures and processes used to enforce employee rights; and (3) a program under which experienced supervisors mentor new supervisors. Requires: (1) the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to issue guidance to federal agencies on competencies supervisors are expected to meet in order to effectively manage, and be accountable for managing, the performance of employees; and (2) each agency to assess the performance of its supervisors and the overall capacity of its supervisors, based on such guidance.</summary>
</bill>
