<bill session="112" type="s" number="1085" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to define next generation biofuel, and to allow States the option of not participating in the corn ethanol portions of the renewable fuel standard due to conflicts with agricultural, economic, energy, and environmental goals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3430-3431"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2009"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to revise the renewable fuel program by: (1) requiring the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)&#160;to ensure that transportation fuel sold or introduced into commerce in the United States, on an annual average basis, contains at least the applicable volume of "next generation biofuel" (currently "cellulosic biofuel"); and (2) replacing the term "cellulosic biofuel" with "next generation biofuel." Defines "next generation biofuel" to mean: (1) renewable fuel that is derived from any cellulose, hemicellulose, lignin, or algae that is derived from renewable biomass; or (2) nonethanol renewable fuel that is derived from renewable biomass. Directs the Administrator to allow states that enact a law that elects to not participate in the applicable volume of renewable to not so participate, other than the applicable volumes of renewable fuel required for advanced biofuel, next generation biofuel, and biomass-based diesel.</summary>
</bill>
