<bill session="109" type="h" number="6329" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Recidivism Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure prompt access to supplemental security income, social security disability, and Medicaid benefits for persons released from certain public institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2006-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2006--Introduced.
Recidivism Reduction Act - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income for Aged, Blind, and Disabled) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to require the reinstatement upon release of an otherwise eligible disabled inmate for SSI benefits which were terminated owing to the inmate's incarceration in a jail, prison, penal institution, or correctional facility for a period of 12 or more consecutive months. Requires the inmate to apply for reinstatement and resumption of such benefits within 36 months after release. Allows application for reinstatement even before release. Permits provisional benefits to such an individual until the application is acted upon. Requires the reinstatement of SSI benefit eligibility for such an individual's spouse if the spouse was previously an SSI-eligible spouse. Amends SSA title II (Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Benefits) (OASDI) to direct the Commissioner of Social Security to develop a system for prerelease application for resumption of suspended OASDI disability insurance benefits, or other benefits based on disability. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide training and technical assistance to states regarding procedures to suspend, rather than terminate, medical assistance under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) for individuals during the period they are inmates of public institutions. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on state actions to suspend Medicaid benefits. Increases from 90% to 95% the federal matching rate for any state implementing a Medicaid suspension system, under which medical assistance for an incarcerated individual is placed in an inactive instead of a terminated status.</summary>
</bill>
