<bill session="113" type="h" number="1022" updated="2013-11-02T06:27:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Energy Critical Elements and American Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To develop an energy critical elements program, to amend the National Materials and Minerals Policy, Research and Development Act of 1980, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412514"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2013--Introduced.
Securing Energy Critical Elements and American Jobs Act of 2013 - Establishes in the Department of Energy (DOE) a research, development, and commercial application program to assure the long-term, secure, and sustainable supply of energy critical elements to satisfy the national security, economic well-being, and industrial production needs of the United States. Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) support new or significantly improved processes and technologies (as compared to those currently in use in the energy critical elements industry; (2) encourage multidisciplinary collaborations and opportunities for students at institutions of higher education; (3) collaborate with the relevant agencies of foreign countries with interests relating to energy critical elements; (4) establish a Research and Development Information Center to catalogue, disseminate, and archive information on energy critical elements; and (5) submit an implementation plan to Congress. Directs the President, acting through the Office of Science and Technology Policy, to coordinate the actions of federal agencies to: (1) promote an adequate and stable supply of energy critical elements, (2) identify energy critical elements and establish early warning systems for supply problems, (3) establish a mechanism for the coordination and evaluation of federal programs with energy critical element needs, and (4) encourage private enterprise in the development of an economically sound and stable domestic energy critical elements supply chain. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to authorize the Secretary to make loan guarantee commitments for the commercial application of new or significantly improved technologies for specified rare earth materials projects. Amends the National Materials and Minerals Policy, Research and Development Act of 1980 to: (1) instruct the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to coordinate federal materials research and development through the National Science and Technology Council (instead of, as currently required, the Federal Coordinating Council for Science, Engineering, and Technology, which is now defunct), (2) modify the duties of the Secretary of Commerce regarding critical needs assessment, and (3) repeal specified duties of the Secretaries of Defense and of the Interior. Repeals the National Critical Materials Act of 1984.</summary>
</bill>
