<bill session="112" type="h" number="1939" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing CPSC Authority and Discretion Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide the Consumer Product Safety Commission with greater authority and discretion in enforcing the consumer product safety laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2011-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2011--Introduced.
Enhancing CPSC Authority and Discretion Act of 2011 - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008&#160;to revise the limit on lead content in children's products by: (1) delaying by one year the step-down of the lead limit, (2) limiting application of the most stringent lead limit to children's products that are designed or intended primarily for use by a child six years old or younger and that can be placed in a child's mouth, and (3) applying lead limits only to products manufactured after the effective date of such limits.Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to grant an exception from lead limits for a specific product, material, or component part under specified circumstances. Applies an alternative lead limit to certain metal component parts in children's products. Exempts from lead limits: (1) battery terminals in children's products intended primarily for outdoor recreational use, and (2) certain used children's products. Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to prohibit the CPSC from requiring third party testing of children's products until the CPSC meets specified conditions, including making a determination that the benefits of testing justify the costs. Establishes an exemption from crib safety standards for child care facilities using certain fixed-side cribs. Applies limits on phthalates in children's toys or child care articles only to any accessible, plasticized component part of a children's toy or child care article. Authorizes the CPSC to exempt toys or articles from such limit if compliance is not necessary to protect children's health. Terminates interim phthalates limits unless the CPSC meets certain rulemaking deadlines. Authorizes the CPSC to: (1) exclude a product or class of products from requirements that manufacturers of children's products place identifying marks on their products if it is not practicable for such products to bear such marks, and (2) establish alternative requirements for identification of such products. Revises provisions concerning the publicly available consumer product safety information database, including by limiting who can submit reports for inclusion in the database.</summary>
</bill>
