<bill session="113" type="s" number="924" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Building Code Incentive Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to enhance existing programs providing mitigation assistance by encouraging States to adopt and actively enforce State building codes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1878"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="905"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Safe Building Code Incentive Act of 2013 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to increase the maximum total of contributions for a major disaster by an amount equal to 4% of the estimated aggregate amount of grants to be made under the Act, if at the time of a declaration of a major disaster the affected state has in effect and is actively enforcing an approved state building code. Requires a state, to be eligible for the increased federal share, to submit its state building code to the President for approval.Directs the President to approve a state building code submitted upon determining that it: (1) is consistent with the most recent version of a nationally recognized model building code, (2) has been adopted by the state within six years of the most recent version of the nationally recognized code, and (3) uses the nationally recognized code as a minimum standard.Requires the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to set appropriate standards for the periodic update, resubmittal, and approval of state building codes, consistent with similar mitigation planning requirements under the Stafford Act.Authorizes the use by states and local governments of technical and financial assistance to implement predisaster hazard mitigation measures to establish and operate a building department and carry out enforcement activities to implement an approved state building code.Directs the President, in determining whether to provide technical and financial assistance to a state or local government, to take into account the extent to which that government is carrying out activities to implement an approved state building code.</summary>
</bill>
