<bill session="112" type="s" number="3174" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vocational and Technical Entrepreneurship Development Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a vocational and technical entrepreneurship development program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3131"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2012--Introduced.
Vocational and Technical Entrepreneurship Development Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a program to make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, state small business development centers to provide, on a statewide basis, technical assistance to secondary schools, post-secondary vocational or technical schools, or nonprofit organizations that serve youth and young adults for the development and implementation of curricula designed to promote vocational and technical entrepreneurship. Prohibits the Administrator from requiring matching funds as a grant condition. Requires: (1) grant recipients to report to the Administrator on their use of funds, and (2) the Administrator to submit to Congress a program evaluation. Directs the association of small business development centers to act as an information clearinghouse regarding vocational and technical entrepreneurship education programs.</summary>
</bill>
