<bill session="109" type="h" number="1810" updated="2013-07-19T19:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand Alaska Native contracting of Federal land management functions and activities and to promote hiring of Alaska Natives by the Federal Government within the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2005--Introduced.
Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct an Alaska Federal Lands Management Demonstration Project. Requires the Secretary to select no fewer than six eligible, geographically representative tribes or tribal organizations per year (up to a maximum of 12) to perform administrative and management functions, construction, maintenance, data collection, biological research, and harvest monitoring on conservation system units in Alaska. Requires selected tribes to complete a planning phase before negotiating and contracting with the Secretary. Excludes revenue-producing visitor services unless agreed to by the Alaska Native corporations most directly affected. Excludes the Denali National Park. Provides for planning grants. Directs the Secretary to establish a demonstration project with the Koyukuk River Basin Moose Co-Management Team, Inc., for the provision of services at the Koyukuk and Kanuti National Wildlife Refuges. Authorizes the use of intergovernmental personnel actions to assign Federal employees to the contractor while retaining their Federal employment status.</summary>
</bill>
