<bill session="113" type="h" number="2037" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a demonstration grant program to recruit, train, deploy, and professionally support psychiatric physicians in Indian health programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-10-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2013--Introduced.
Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award a five-year grant to one department of psychiatry in, or one non-profit entity affiliated with, an accredited medical school in this country to carry out a demonstration program to recruit, train, deploy, and professionally support psychiatric physicians who agree to provide primary and specialty health care services in Indian health programs for at least two years. Requires the grantee to: (1) create a nationally-replicable workforce model that identifies and incorporates best practices for carrying out such activities, and (2) provide participating psychiatric physicians with up to one year of supplemental clinical and cultural competency training that enables them to provide primary and specialty health care services in Indian health programs. Requires participating psychiatric physicians to: (1) be licensed or eligible for licensure to practice in the state to which they will be deployed; and (2) demonstrate a commitment, beyond the one year of training and two years of deployment, to a career as a specialty care or primary care physician providing mental health services in Indian health programs. Gives a preference to psychiatric physicians who are American Indians or Alaska Natives. Directs the Secretary to make a repayment, under the Indian Health Service Loan Repayment Program, of the educational loans of participating psychiatric physicians for each year of their deployment to an Indian health program.</summary>
</bill>
