<bill session="109" type="s" number="245" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abrupt Climate Change Research Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the development and coordination of a comprehensive and integrated United States research program that assists the people of the United States and the world to understand, assess, and predict human-induced and natural processes of abrupt climate change.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S750-751"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Geophysical prediction"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2005--Introduced.
Abrupt Climate Change Research Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish within the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and carry out a scientific research program on abrupt climate change. Lists as purposes of the program: (1) to develop a global array of terrestrial and oceanographic indicators of paleoclimate in order to sufficiently identify and describe past instances of abrupt climate change; (2) to improve understanding of thresholds and nonlinearities in geophysical systems related to the mechanisms of abrupt climate change; (3) to incorporate such mechanisms into advanced geophysical models of climate change; and (4) to test the output of such models against an improved global array of records of past abrupt climate changes.</summary>
</bill>
