<bill session="110" type="h" number="3621" updated="2013-07-19T21:35:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safety, Accountability, and Funding Efficiency for Transportation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require government agencies carrying out surface transportation projects to conduct a cost-benefit analysis before procuring architectural, engineering, and related services from a private contractor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2007--Introduced.
Safety, Accountability, and Funding Efficiency for Transportation Act of 2007 - Requires government agencies to prepare cost benefit analyses before entering any private contract of $100,000 or more to procure private sector architectural, engineering, and related services for a surface transportation project. Provides for public disclosure of the results of such cost-benefit analysis if the government agency determines it is in the public interest to enter into the contract. Authorizes the waiver of such requirements if it is determined that the government agency cannot perform the work to be conducted under the contract with existing or additional government employees because such work is of an emergency, specialty, or intermittent nature.</summary>
</bill>
