<bill session="110" type="h" number="5153" updated="2013-07-19T21:49:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Conforming Loan Limit Temporary Adjustment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase temporarily the conforming loan limits of the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation in certain areas, enhance mortgage market liquidity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2008--Introduced.
Conforming Loan Limit Temporary Adjustment Act of 2008 - Increases the maximum original principal obligation of certain mortgages originated between July 1, 2007, and December 31, 2008, that may be purchased by the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Association (Freddie Mac). Allows a loan whose principal amount is 125% of the area median price for a residence of applicable size, up to 175% of the regular loan limitation. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) securitization of mortgages by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac plays an important role in providing liquidity to the U.S. housing markets; and (2) Congress, therefore, encourages Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to securitize mortgages acquired under the increased conforming loan limits established in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
