<bill session="112" type="h" number="3171" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Juvenile Justice Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 with respect to juveniles who have committed offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
Juvenile Justice Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to: (1) revise and add definitions under such Act relating to the treatment of juveniles held in custody while awaiting trial for criminal offenses; (2) require state plans under such Act to separate juveniles from the adult prison population, monitor for and eliminate the use of dangerous practices, unnecessary isolation, unnecessary room time, and unreasonable restraint for holding juveniles in custody, and provide training of prison staff on techniques for effective behavior management of juvenile offenders; (3) provide incentive grants to states to adopt programs for the mental health treatment needs of juveniles in custody and for the placement of such juveniles in the least restrictive detention or correctional settings; and (4) prohibit the placement of juveniles who have not been charged with adult criminal offenses in secure detention or correctional facilities.</summary>
</bill>
