<bill session="112" type="h" number="4295" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consolidate Heavy-handed and Outdated Programs Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Department of Energy and the Environment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2012-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Appropriations, Science, Space, and Technology, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="892"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="892"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2012--Introduced.
Consolidate Heavy-handed and Outdated Programs Act of 2012 - Consolidates the Department of Energy (DOE) and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish the Department of Energy and the Environment (DEE), with the primary mission of ensuring U.S. security and prosperity by: (1) protecting human health; (2) safeguarding the natural environment; and (3) addressing U.S. energy, environmental, and nuclear challenges through transformative science and technology solutions. Transfers to the DEE Secretary all of the functions of the EPA Administrator and the Secretary of Energy. Establishes within the Department: (1) an Energy and Environmental Information Administration, (2) an Office of Science, (3) an Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, (4) an Office of Indian Energy Policy and Programs, and (5) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission as an independent regulatory commission. Transfers to the Commission specified functions of the Federal Power Commission (FPC). Preserves the Southeastern Power Administration, the Southwestern Power Administration, and the Bonneville Power Administration as distinct organizational entities within DEE, each headed by an Administrator. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish policy for the National Nuclear Security Administration, (2) assess annually the vulnerability of Department's facilities to terrorist attack, and (3) establish an enterprise-wide strategic sourcing program to improve efficiencies and economies in EPA's acquisition programs. Requires the President to: (1) submit a proposed National Energy Policy Plan to Congress by April 1, 2013, and biennially thereafter; and (2) issue an executive order that provides for administrative cost savings across the federal government. Repeals provisions providing for the weatherization assistance program, the Energy Efficiency and Conservation Block Grant Program, sustainable energy resources for consumers grants, the low income community energy efficiency pilot program, the Ultra-Deepwater and Unconventional Natural Gas and Other Petroleum Resources Research and Development Program, the fossil energy research and development program, state energy conservation plans, diesel emissions reduction grants, and grants to states for radon programs. Rescinds specified unobligated balances of the amounts made available for energy efficiency and renewable energy. Terminates the state water pollution control revolving funds program, grants for water pollution control programs, nonpoint source management programs, the state drinking water revolving loan funds program, public water system supervision programs, the state underground injection control program, and the diesel emissions reduction grant program. Terminates EPA's grant program for coastal recreation water quality monitoring and notification, Clean Automotive Technology program, targeted watershed grants program, performance partnership grants program, U.S. Mexico border water infrastructure program, tribal assistance grants programs, Chemical Risk Management Fibers program, Environmental Education program, and program to automatically transfer funds from its Hazardous Substance Superfund account to other federal agencies. Limits appropriations available: (1) for activities within DOE's fossil energy research and development account for FY2013, (2) to carry out the Second Line of Defense radiation detection equipment installation activities, and (3) to carry out EPA's Superfund remedial program. Prohibits funds from being made available for the construction of the Chemistry and Metallurgy Research Replacement facility in FY2013-FY2017. Prohibits the Secretary from providing in FY2013-FY2017: (1) grants to communities to develop plans and implement projects that reduce greenhouse gas emissions; (2) targeted airshed grants to California; and (3) grants for the construction of drinking water, wastewater, or storm water infrastructure or for water quality protection. Limits the amount that the Secretary may transfer to the Great Lakes Initiative.</summary>
</bill>
