<bill session="111" type="s" number="1703" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Act of June 18, 1934, to reaffirm the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to take land into trust for Indian tribes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300037"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2010-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9842"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan with amendments. With written report No. 111-247.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="515">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 515.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3697"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3742"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Amends the Act commonly known as the Indian Reorganization Act to apply the Act to all federally recognized Indian tribes, regardless of when any tribe became recognized. (This effectively overrules the Supreme Court's decision in Carcieri v. Salazar, which held that the Secretary of the Interior could not take land into trust for a specified tribe because that tribe had not been under federal jurisdiction when the Act was enacted.) Makes such amendments retroactive as if included in the Indian Reorganization Act as of the date of its enactment on June 18, 1934. Provides that this Act does not affect any law other than the Indian Reorganization Act or limit the Secretary of the Interior's authority under any federal law or regulation other than the Indian Reorganization Act. Requires the Secretary to conduct and submit to Congress a study that: (1) describes the Carcieri decision's effect on Indian tribes and tribal land; and (2) includes a list of each affected Indian tribe and parcel of tribal land.</summary>
</bill>
