<bill session="111" type="s" number="858" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Oceans Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Ernest "Fritz" Hollings National Ocean Policy and Leadership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect the oceans and Great Lakes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Introduced.
National Oceans Protection Act of 2009 - Declares that the purpose of this Act is to secure the full range of benefits of healthy ocean and Great Lakes ecosystems. Establishes a national ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes policy and related principles. Requires each federal agency, as possible and in accordance with other laws, to interpret and administer policies, regulations, and laws in accordance with such policy. Ernest "Fritz" Hollings National Ocean Policy and Leadership Act - Formally establishes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) as a civilian agency and transfers to NOAA's administrator any NOAA-related authority previously vested in the Secretary of Commerce. Establishes: (1) a National Ocean Advisor and a Council on Ocean Stewardship in the Executive Office of the President; and (2) a Presidential Panel of Advisers on Oceans and Climate. Designates nine ocean regions to promote coordinated regional efforts to implement the national ocean policy. Requires the NOAA Administrator to establish or designate a Regional Ocean Partnership for each region and requires each Partnership to prepare a Regional Ocean Strategic Plan. Establishes: (1) the Committee on Ocean Science, Education, and Operations; (2) a marine biodiversity research program; (3) a network of regional Ocean Ecosystem Resource Information Systems; (4) a national interagency ocean and coastal public education program; (5) the National Ocean Science and Technology Scholarship Program; (6) the NOAA Office of Education; and (7) an educational partnership with minority-serving institutions. Requires a national mass media campaign to increase public awareness of oceans.Establishes the Ocean and Great Lakes Conservation Trust Fund.Requires payments to coastal states for Regional Ocean Strategic Plan activities. Authoirzes the United States Postal Service (USPS) to consider printing a special postage stamp to enable the public to help protect, maintain, and restore marine ecosystems.</summary>
</bill>
