<bill session="112" type="sr" number="379" updated="2013-07-20T02:13:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-17">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original resolution condemning violence by the Government of Syria against the Syrian people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Kerry with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="325">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 325.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S858-859" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-02-17" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1020, S1020-1021" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1020-1021" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Condemns the government of Syria's use of force against civilians and its violations of the fundamental human rights and dignity of the Syrian people. Expresses solidarity with the people of Syria, who have exhibited courage and determination to rid themselves of a brutal dictatorship. Expresses disappointment with the governments of the Russian Federation and China for their veto of the U.N. Security Council resolution condemning Bashar al-Assad and the violence in Syria and urges them to reconsider their votes. Encourages Security Council members to pursue a resolution supporting a political solution to the Syrian crisis. Commends the League of Arab States' efforts to bring about a peaceful resolution in Syria. Regrets that the League's observer mission was not able to monitor the full implementation of the League of Arab States' Action Plan of November 2, 2011, due to the escalating violence in Syria. Urges the international community to review legal processes available to hold Syrian government officials accountable for crimes against humanity and violations of human rights.</summary>
</bill>
