<bill session="111" type="h" number="3198" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wildlife Without Borders Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide international wildlife management and conservation programs through the Wildlife Without Borders Program in the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1755-1756"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2009--Introduced.
Wildlife Without Borders Authorization Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a Wildlife Without Borders Program within the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to provide international wildlife conservation assistance through the initiation, facilitation, and promotion of locally adapted wildlife management and conservation programs in coordination with non-governmental organizations, governments, private businesses, and community leaders. Specifies the species, regional, and global program components that shall be included in the Wildlife Without Borders Program. Permits the Secretary, in the administration of the Wildlife Without Borders Program, to accept donated funds and to use them for capacity building, grants, and other on-the-ground uses carried out under the regional and global program components authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
