<bill session="112" type="sc" number="25" updated="2013-07-20T02:16:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution welcoming the independence of the Republic of South Sudan, congratulating the people of South Sudan for freely and peacefully expressing their will through an internationally accepted referendum, and calling on the Governments and people of Sudan and South Sudan to peacefully resolve outstanding issues including the final status of Abyei.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2011-07-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4644-4645" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4644-4645" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4643-4644" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-19T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="hc" number="65"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Norway"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Welcomes the independence of the Republic of South Sudan and recognizes South Sudan as the newest member of the international community. Congratulates the people of South Sudan for expressing their desire for independence through an internationally accepted referendum and notes the government of Sudan's recognition of the referendum and South Sudan's independence. Calls on the governments of Sudan and South Sudan to resolve outstanding matters (including the final status of Abyei and disputed border areas) in order to ensure a smooth transition to two states and to mitigate points of conflict. Welcomes the deployment of Ethiopian peacekeepers to Abyei and the new United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS). Calls on the government of Sudan to allow for continued United Nations (U.N.) peacekeeping operations in Southern Kordofan and Blue Nile states. Calls on the U.S. government and the international community, in coordination with the governments of Sudan and South Sudan, to support peace, rule of law, and good governance in Sudan and South Sudan. Urges that the Darfur peace process remain a priority in U.S.-Sudan relations. Welcomes the anticipated nomination of a United States ambassador to the Republic of South Sudan.</summary>
</bill>
