<bill session="111" type="h" number="3833" updated="2013-07-19T23:46:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapters 81, 83, and 84 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for enhanced benefits for survivors of Federal public safety officers killed in the line of duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412222"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/2009--Introduced.
Provides that the pay used to compute monthly compensation based on the death of a federal employee who died from personal injury sustained in the line of duty as a public safety officer, or any survivor annuity under such circumstances, shall be determined based on the pay grade or level which is one grade higher than would otherwise apply. Entitles anyone who is eligible for such monthly compensation or annuity as the survivor of a public safety officer who died on or after January 1, 1974, to: (1) have such compensation or annuity recomputed upon application submitted within 12 months after enactment of this Act; and (2) a lump-sum payment for the period between January 1, 1974, and the date as of which regular monthly compensation or survivor annuity payments are adjusted to reflect the recomputation.</summary>
</bill>
