<bill session="110" type="s" number="2660" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Protection and Cost Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to ensure that the mission and functions of Regional Transmission Organizations and Independent System Operators include keeping energy costs as low as reasonably possible for consumers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1125-1126"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1126" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="5547"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2008--Introduced.
Consumer Protection and Cost Accountability Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to consider whether a rate or charge made, demanded, or received by a Transmission Organization (TO) would enable the TO to provide or facilitate reliable service to consumers at the lowest reasonable cost.Instructs FERC, in determining whether a TO filing to establish or change a rate or charge is consistent with specified requirements, to consider whether the rate or charge would: (1) provide consumer benefits that outweigh any anticipated costs to consumers as demonstrated by a cost-benefit analysis submitted by the TO; or (2) have only a de minimis impact upon the total delivered costs to the consumer.Directs FERC to ensure that each TO is subject to biennial, independent audits.</summary>
</bill>
