<bill session="111" type="s" number="2909" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">WORK Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker Ownership, Readiness and Knowledge Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide State programs to encourage employee ownership and participation in business decisionmaking throughout the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/2009--Introduced.
Worker Ownership, Readiness and Knowledge Act or the WORK Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish within the Department of Labor an Office of Employee Ownership and Participation to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking. Requires the Office Director, with federal grants and acting as an information clearinghouse, to: (1) support existing programs in the states designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking; and (2) promote the formation of new such programs. Directs the Secretary to establish a program, administered by the Director, which is designed to foster employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking throughout the United States.</summary>
</bill>
