<bill session="111" type="s" number="3563" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rebuilding Local Business Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to temporarily designate as a HUBZone counties that are most affected by a recession.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2010-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6251"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2010--Introduced.
Rebuilding Local Business Act of 2010 - Amends the Small Business Act to designate as a HUBZone (historically underutilized business zone), for purposes of assistance under such Act: (1) an initial period rebuilding county; and (2) an extension period rebuilding county. Defines an initial period rebuilding county as a county, parish, or similar political subdivision: (1) for which the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) determines that the one-year unemployment rate is at least 120% of the one-year average unadjusted unemployment rate for the United States; (2) that is not a HUBZone or will cease to qualify as a HUBZone two years after such unemployment determination; and (3) during the three-year period beginning on the date of such unemployment determination. Defines an extension rebuilding county as a county, parish, or political subdivision: (1) in which the Administrator has made the above unemployment determination; (2) for which the above three-year period has ended; (3) for which the Administrator determines that the unemployment rate as of a specified date is at least 140% of the average unadjusted unemployment rate; and (4) for which such designation extends for an additional specified period after the three-year period.</summary>
</bill>
