<bill session="112" type="h" number="3706" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01T20:43:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-08-01T20:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create the Office of Chief Financial Officer of the Government of the Virgin Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-17T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-600.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-17T17:41:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="435">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 435.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lamborn moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5435-5437" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3706.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Lamborn objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5618" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-08-01T20:43:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/31/2012 H5435" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Passed House amended.
Requires the Governor of the Virgin Islands to appoint a Chief Financial Officer, with the advice and consent of the Legislature of the Virgin Islands, from a list required by this Act. States that if: (1) the Legislature has not confirmed a nominee within 90 days of receiving such list the Governor shall appoint a Chief Financial Officer on an acting basis until the Legislature consents to a Chief Financial Officer, (2) a Chief Financial Officer has not been appointed within 180 days after enactment of this Act the Virgin Islands Chief Financial Officer Search Commission shall appoint from such list an Acting Chief Financial Officer until a Chief Financial Officer is appointed, and (3) the Acting Chief Financial Officer serving in an acting capacity for 180 consecutive days shall become the Chief Financial Officer. Sets forth the Chief Financial Officer's duties. Directs the Board of Elections of the Virgin Islands, as part of the closest regularly scheduled, islands-wide election in the Virgin Islands to the expiration of the fourth year of the five-year term of the Chief Financial Officer, to hold a referendum to determine whether the position of Chief Financial Officer shall be made a permanent part of the executive branch of the government of the Virgin Islands. Establishes the Virgin Islands Chief Financial Officer Search Commission to recommend at least three candidates for the Chief Financial Officer position. Terminates the Commission upon the nomination and confirmation of the Chief Financial Officer.</summary>
</bill>
