<bill session="113" type="hr" number="186" updated="2013-11-02T06:17:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Congratulating the people of Kenya on their commitment to peaceful elections, as demonstrated on March 4, 2013, and calling on Kenyans to come together to continue to implement political, institutional, and accountability reforms envisioned in the Kenyan constitution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412404"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sr" number="90"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Kenya"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2013--Introduced.
Congratulates the people of Kenya on their commitment to peaceful elections, as demonstrated on March 4, 2013. Calls on the people of Kenya to continue to reject intimidation and violence, and encourages the peaceful and credible resolution of electoral disputes in the courts. Urges: (1) restraint on all sides, while recognizing the right of the people of Kenya to peacefully exercise their constitutional rights to freedom of expression, assembly, and demonstration; and (2) accountability for anyone found to be complicit in promoting violence or manipulating electoral processes or results. Affirms that accountability for the 2007-2008 post-election violence is a critical element to ensure Kenya's democracy and long-term stability. Calls on the government of Kenya to seek justice for the victims of political violence, including by honoring its obligations to cooperate with the International Criminal Court. Encourages the people and government of Kenya to support implementation of constitutional reforms, rule of law, and efforts to strengthen governing, security, and judicial institutions. Reaffirms that the people of the United States will stand with the people of Kenya in support of democracy, partnership, and peace.</summary>
</bill>
