<bill session="111" type="s" number="3382" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, through the Coastal Program of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to work with willing partners and provide support to efforts to assess, protect, restore, and enhance important coastal areas that provide fish and wildlife habitat on which Federal trust species depend.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5344"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2010--Introduced.
Coastal Habitat Conservation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to carry out within the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service a Coastal Program to: (1) identify the most important natural resource problems and solutions in priority coastal ecosystems in partnership with federal, state, local, and tribal governments, nongovernmental institutions, nonprofit organizations, and private individuals or corporate entities; (2) provide technical and financial support through partnerships with such governments, institutions, organizations, and private individuals for voluntary habitat assessment, protection, planning, restoration, and enhancement projects on public or private land; (3) assist in the development and implementation of monitoring protocols and adaptive management procedures so as to ensure the success of coastal ecosystem conservation and restoration measures; and (4) collaborate with partners and the public regarding methods and models for the conservation, restoration, and enhancement of coastal ecosystems. Requires the Secretary to employ youth volunteers and organizations that provide service opportunities for youths to carry out nonhazardous habitat restoration and enhancement activities.</summary>
</bill>
