<bill session="109" type="h" number="1395" updated="2013-07-19T19:16:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection of Children from Methamphetamine Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to provide a minimum mandatory prison sentence for manufacturing methamphetamine on properties where children reside, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2005-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2005--Introduced.
Protection of Children from Methamphetamine Act of 2005 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to provide for a 20-year mandatory minimum term of imprisonment for the manufacture of methamphetamine on premises in which an individual under age 18 resides. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study to determine: (1) the extent to which food, water, air, soil, equipment, or other matter becomes contaminated with methamphetamine or other harmful substances as a result of proximity to the methamphetamine manufacturing process; and (2) whether any adverse health conditions result from children's exposure to such process or to contaminated matter. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible States (i.e., those which had more than 200 methamphetamine lab seizures in 2004) to carry out programs to provide a comprehensive response to the health and mental health problems of children that are associated with living in a home in which methamphetamine is unlawfully manufactured, administered, or distributed. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the procedures and services of programs carried out with such grants include: (1) coordination among law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, child protective services, and health professionals; (2) removal of children from toxic or drug-endangering environments; and (3) medical and dental health evaluation and services, drug and toxic chemical exposure screening, and mental health evaluation and services.</summary>
</bill>
