<bill session="110" type="h" number="179" updated="2013-07-19T21:05:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Access in Fire Emergencies Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To confirm the jurisdiction of the Consumer Product Safety Commission with respect to releasing systems on residential window bars and to establish a consumer product safety standard ensuring that all such bars include a quick-release mechanism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Safe Access in Fire Emergencies Act of 2007 - Requires the Consumer Products Safety Commission to establish a consumer product safety standard for window bars that: (1) requires all window bars manufactured or installed in the United States to incorporate releasing systems that meet minimum standards; and (2) addresses such systems for interior and exterior based bars. Provides that the minimum standards shall require that such systems provide for: (1) egress when actuated; and (2) manual activation from inside a residence allowing escape through a protected opening. Requires compliance enforcement under the Consumer Products Safety Act. Directs the Commission to require each manufacturer to include in the packaging a statement explaining window bar installation and releasing system operation. Expresses the sense of the Congress that public housing, low-income housing, manufactured housing units, and homes purchased using any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under the National Housing Act should meet a minimal standard that requires window bars to incorporate an emergency releasing system. Requires the Commission to establish and maintain a National Electronic Injury Surveillance System code and system for collection of information and statistics on casualties associated with window bars.</summary>
</bill>
