<bill session="111" type="h" number="6048" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to ensure that certain tenants are able to return to affordable housing after a major disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to provide assistance to a person who owns or operates a rental dwelling unit damaged or destroyed by a major disaster for that unit's repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement if: (1) before the disaster the unit was made available for occupancy only by low- or moderate-income tenants; (2) the person will continue, for a specified minimum period, to make available rental dwelling units for occupancy only by such tenants; and (3) the person has applied for a disaster loan under the Small Business Act and either has been determined to be ineligible for such a loan or has obtained such a loan in the maximum amount for which the Small Business Administration (SBA) determines the person is eligible.</summary>
</bill>
