<bill session="113" type="h" number="3152" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Veterans and Seniors First Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Members of Congress, the President, the Vice President, and the head of any Executive department from receiving pay for any period in which there is a Government shutdown and to provide for payments to seniors, military and veterans during a Government shutdown.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412430" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2013-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, House Administration, Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2013--Introduced.
Pay Our Veterans and Seniors First Act - Prohibits a Member of Congress, the President, the Vice President, and the head of any executive department from receiving: (1) basic pay for any period in which there is more than a 24-hour lapse in appropriations for any executive agency as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution, or (2) retroactive pay for such period. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, during any lapse in FY2014 appropriations when interim or full-year appropriations for the affected accounts have not been enacted, to transfer to the appropriate Secretary from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated such amounts as are necessary to provide the following: pay and allowances to members of the Armed Forces, including reserve component members, who perform active service; benefits under the TRICARE for Life program, Medicare, and title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act; and veterans' benefits and programs.</summary>
</bill>
