<bill session="111" type="s" number="3269" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Teen and Novice Driver Uniform Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STANDUP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide driver safety grants to States with graduated driver licensing laws that meet certain minimum requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2010-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1895"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
Safe Teen and Novice Driver Uniform Protection Act of 2010 or the STANDUP Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to award incentive grants to states with graduated driver licensing laws that require novice drivers younger than age 21 to comply with a two-stage licensing process before receiving an unrestricted driver's license. Requires such laws, at a minimum, to include: (1) a learner's permit stage that commences at age 16 or older, lasts at least six months, prohibits driver use of a cellular phone or other communications device in nonemergency situations, prohibits nighttime driving, and remains in effect until commencement of the intermediate stage or the driver attains age 18; (2) an intermediate stage in effect until the driver attains age 18 that commences immediately after expiration of the learner's permit stage, lasts at least six months, prohibits driver use of a cellular phone or other communications device in nonemergency situations, prohibits nighttime driving, prohibits more than one non-familial passenger under age 21 unless there is a licensed driver at least age 21 present in the vehicle; and (3) any other requirement that the Secretary may require. Directs the Secretary to withhold a certain percentage of federal-aid highway funds from states that do not comply with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
