<bill session="113" type="h" number="862" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-17T19:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-17T19:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the conveyance of two small parcels of land within the boundaries of the Coconino National Forest containing private improvements that were developed based upon the reliance of the landowners in an erroneous survey conducted in May 1960.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412286"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-75.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-17T15:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="51">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 51.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bishop (UT) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3664-3665" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 862.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3668-3669" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="247" datetime="2013-06-17T19:12:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 395 - 1 (Roll no. 247).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3664" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2013--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to convey all interest of the United States in two parcels of land within the boundaries of the Coconino National Forest, Arizona, that contain private improvements that landowners developed based upon an erroneous survey conducted in May 1960, to the person or legal entity representing the majority of those landowners. Requires the person or legal entity that represents such landowners to pay $20,000.00 to the Secretary as consideration for the conveyance of the parcels. Requires the Secretary to deposit the consideration received under this Act into a special account in the fund established under the Sisk Act and to make such deposited funds available for the acquisition of land in the National Forest System. Revokes public orders withdrawing any of the federal land from appropriation or disposal under the public land laws, to the extent necessary to permit the conveyance of all of the federal land. Withdraws the federal land authorized for conveyance under this Act from entry and appropriation under the public land laws, location, entry, and patent under the mining laws, and operation of the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws until the completion of the conveyance. Makes the conveyance authorized by this Act subject only to such surveys and clearances as are needed to protect U.S. interests. Terminates the authority provided under this Act three years after this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
