<bill session="109" type="h" number="4698" updated="2013-07-19T19:45:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Relief Volunteer Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide liability protection for individuals who volunteer to assist victims of national disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 9.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Good samaritan laws"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2006--Introduced.
Disaster Relief Volunteer Protection Act of 2006 - Provides liability protection for individuals who volunteer to assist victims of national disasters for any injury (including personal injury, property damage or loss, and death) caused by an act or omission in connection with disaster relief services provided or facilitated by the volunteer, if: (1) the injury was not caused by willful, wanton, or reckless misconduct; and (2) the injury was not caused by the volunteer's operating a motor vehicle, vessel, aircraft, or other vehicle for which the state requires the operator or the owner to possess an operator's license or maintain insurance. Extends such liability protection to: (1) the volunteer's employer, host, or enabling person, entity, or organization; (2) nonprofit organizations providing or facilitating disaster relief services; or (3) governmental or intergovernmental entity that donates disaster relief goods to a U.S. agency or instrumentality for any injury caused by such donated goods. Prohibits the award of punitive damages in any civil action against a disaster relief volunteer or governmental or intergovernmental entity, unless willful, wanton, or reckless misconduct is established by clear and convincing evidence. Provides for proportionate liability for noneconomic damages.</summary>
</bill>
