<bill session="109" type="s" number="2752" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles II and XVIII of the Social Security Act to limit the service of a member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, or the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund serving as a member of the public to one four-year term and to require the President to consult with the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Finance of the Senate prior to nominating an individual to serve as such a member.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2006-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2006--Introduced.
Amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to limit to one four-year term the service of the public member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, or the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund. Requires the President to consult with the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Finance of the Senate before nominating an individual to serve as a public member.</summary>
</bill>
