<bill session="111" type="s" number="2962" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Blind Persons Return to Work Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to apply an earnings test in determining the amount of monthly insurance benefits for individuals entitled to disability insurance benefits based on blindness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S343"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="886"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2010--Introduced.
Blind Persons Return to Work Act of 2010 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to: (1) apply a specified earnings test in the determination of the amount of monthly insurance benefits for blind beneficiaries; (2) limit to once a year any review of a determination of disability based on blindness; and (3) reduce any excess earnings of blind beneficiaries by the amount of impairment related work expenses. Directs the Commissioner of Social Security, with respect to the mandatory annual report of earnings by an individual entitled to a monthly insurance benefit, to develop procedures to avoid paying less than the correct amount of benefits to any such individual as a result, during the year, of a termination of employment or a significant reduction in hours of work.</summary>
</bill>
