<bill session="112" type="hr" number="327" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the trial and subsequent convictions of Mikhail Khodorkovsky and Platon Lebedev by the Government of the Russian Federation constitute a politically motivated case of selective arrest and prosecution which put in serious doubt the rule of law and the independence of Russia's judicial system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe and Eurasia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA14" subcommittee="Europe and Eurasia" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) Mikhail Khodorkovsky and Platon Lebedev are prisoners who have been denied basic due process rights under international law and the laws of the Russian Federation for political reasons; (2) the Russian Federation's standing as a nation supporting democracy, freedom of expression, an independent judiciary, human rights, and the rule of law would be validated by overturning the convictions of Mikhail Khodorkovsky and Platon Lebedev and securing their immediate release; and (3) the Russian Federation is encouraged to take these actions in furtherance of a new and more positive relationship between the United States and Russia.</summary>
</bill>
