<bill session="110" type="s" number="2684" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Section 8 Voucher Reform Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reform the housing choice voucher program under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1469-1470, S1480-1482"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1470-1480" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Senate Subcommittee on Housing, Transportation and Community Development. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSBK09" subcommittee="Housing, Transportation, and Community Development" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1851"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2008--Introduced.
Section 8 Voucher Reform Act of 2008 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to revise requirements for public housing agency (PHA) inspections of each dwelling unit for which a housing assistance payment contract is established. Requires an initial inspection before any assistance payment is made. Allows such payments if failure to meet standards is a result only of non-life threatening conditions.Permits a PHA, in the case of projects receiving certain federal housing subsidies, to authorize occupancy before completion of an initial inspection.Requires biennial inspections (currently annual inspections) to determine compliance. Provides, upon a family's request, for interim inspections.Prescribes requirements for reviews and calculation of family income.Prescribes eligibility criteria for assistance based upon assets and income.Revises requirements governing: (1) assistance to low-income working families; (2) tenant-based contract renewals; (3) administrative fees; and (4) the home ownership downpayment grant program.Authorizes a PHA to report to certain consumer reporting agencies information regarding the past rent payment history of a family receiving housing choice vouchers.Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish standards and procedures for assessing PHA performance in carrying out the programs for tenant-based rental assistance and for homeownership assistance, including biennial assessments.Revises the rent calculation for housing assistance payment contracts.Directs the Secretary to endeavor to define market areas.Limits a PHA's elective applicant screening.Revises requirements for enhanced voucher assistance.Authorizes the Secretary to provide preservation project-based voucher assistance in lieu of enhanced voucher assistance upon request of the owner of the multifamily housing project. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with the Social Security Administration and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to permit HUD participation in certain state demonstration programs providing for persons with significant disabilities to be employed and to continue to receive certain federal and state benefits.Requires the Comptroller General to identify and report to Congress on obstacles to using vouchers in federally subsidized housing projects.Requires state agencies to furnish to the Secretary certain data on tenants in low-income housing projects receiving tax credits under the Internal Revenue Code.Authorizes a PHA to use subsidy payments otherwise due the owner to pay for continued utility service to avoid hardship to program participants.Requires the Secretary to provide access to HUD programs for persons with limited English proficiency.</summary>
</bill>
