<bill session="112" type="s" number="646" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Natural Hazards Risk Reduction Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Windstorm Impact Reduction Act Reauthorization of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Natural Hazards Risk Reduction Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">National Windstorm Impact Reduction Act Reauthorization of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize Federal natural hazards reduction programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2011-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-150.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-02-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="329">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 329.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1379"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3479"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3479"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Natural Hazards Risk Reduction Act of 2011 - Title I: Earthquakes - National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2011 - Amends the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 to revise and reauthorize the National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program through FY2015. (Sec. 103) Repeals provisions establishing the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Earthquake Hazards Reduction and an associated advisory committee. (Sec. 104) Revises responsibilities of Program agencies, including by making: (1) the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) responsible for research and development to improve building standards and practices; (2) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), consistent with its all hazards approach, responsible for facilitating the adoption of model building codes; (3) the United States Geological Survey (USGS) responsible for providing real-time earthquake information; and (4) the National Science Foundation (NSF) responsible for funding basic research. (Sec. 105) Makes NIST (currently, USGS) responsible for organizing investigations under the post-earthquake investigations program. Title II: Wind - National Windstorm Impact Reduction Reauthorization Act of 2011 - Amends the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Act of 2004 to revise and reauthorize the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program through FY2015. (Sec. 203) Repeals provisions requiring the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to establish an Interagency Working Group responsible for the planning, management, and coordination of the Program. (Sec. 204) Designates NIST as the lead agency and sets forth revised responsibilities of NIST and the other Program agencies: FEMA, NSF, and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Title III: Interagency Coordinating Committee on Natural Hazards Risk Reduction - (Sec. 301) Establishes an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Natural Hazards Risk Reduction, chaired by the Director of NIST, to oversee the planning and coordination of the National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program, the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program, and other federal research for natural hazard mitigation that the Committee considers appropriate. Requires: (1) the Committee to develop strategic plans and coordinated budgets for such Programs; and (2) the Director to establish an Advisory Committee on Earthquake Hazards Reduction and such other advisory committees as necessary to advise NIST on research, development, and technology transfer activities to mitigate the impact of natural disasters. Title IV: National Construction Safety Team Act Amendments - (Sec. 401) Amends the National Construction Safety Team Act to authorize safety teams to be established for deployment after events causing the failure of infrastructure, as well as buildings, leading to a substantial loss of life. Title V: Fire Research Program - (Sec. 501)Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to include among the types of fires subject to the Fire Research Center's research program fires at the wildland-urban interface.</summary>
</bill>
