<bill session="109" type="s" number="3898" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Reportable Conditions Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act to provide for the health of Americans by implementing a system that detects and identifies in a timely manner diseases, conditions, and events that represent a threat to humans, animals, food production and the water supply.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6086"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2006--Introduced.
National Reportable Conditions Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Commission on National Reportable Conditions to review state and local regulations to determine the existence of conditions that represent a serious threat to the health of individuals in the United States, compile a list of national reportable conditions to be recommended for certifications, and advise the Secretary. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, based upon the Commission's recommendations, to: (1) annually certify a list of national reportable conditions (i.e., diseases, conditions, and events that when identified by health practitioners, veterinarians, animal and food production specialists, state and local health professionals, environmental and public utility workers, and laboratory workers must be reported to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS)); (2) establish an electronic National Reportable Conditions System, a data repository of records processed by the System, a process to enable commercial entities to transmit reports to a single government entity, and a process for the identification of obstacles or challenges to the achievement of the purposes of this Act (including a research program to identify or create solutions); and (3) award grants to state and local entities to enable them to conduct surveillance and timely reporting activities regarding the submission of reports. Requires the Secretary to establish a process that permits the simultaneous submission of reports to a state or local jurisdiction to achieve compliance with a state or local law.</summary>
</bill>
