<bill session="111" type="s" number="682" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mental Health on Campus Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve mental and behavioral health services on college campuses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3672-3673"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3673-3675" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1704"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2009--Introduced.
Mental Health on Campus Improvement Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award grants to eligible institutions of higher education to improve mental and behavioral health services and outreach on college and university campuses. Directs the Secretary to give special consideration to programs that: (1) demonstrate the greatest need; (2) propose effective approaches for initiating or expanding campus services; (3) target underserved and at-risk populations; (4) coordinate with a community mental health center or other community mental health resources; (5) identify how the college or university will address psychiatric emergencies; and (6) demonstrate the greatest potential for replication and dissemination. Allows the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to convene an interagency, public-private sector working group to plan, establish, and begin coordinating and evaluating a targeted public education campaign that is designed to focus on mental and behavioral health on college campuses. Requires the Secretary to establish the College Campus Task Force to discuss mental and behavioral health concerns on college and university campuses.</summary>
</bill>
