<bill session="112" type="s" number="82" updated="2013-07-20T02:17:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Adoption Tax Relief Guarantee Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to repeal the sunset of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 with respect to the expansion of the adoption credit and adoption assistance programs, to repeal the sunset of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act with respect to increased dollar limitations for such credit and programs, and to allow the adoption credit to be claimed in the year expenses are incurred, regardless of when the adoption becomes final.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2012-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Adoption Tax Relief Guarantee Act - Exempts provisions expanding the adoption tax credit and adoption assistance programs enacted by the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 from the general terminating (sunset) provisions of that Act. Eliminates the terminating date in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act applicable to increases in the adoption tax credit and employer-provided adoption benefits. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the tax credit for adoption expenses in the taxable year in which such expenses are paid or incurred.</summary>
</bill>
