<bill session="110" type="s" number="3616" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Internet Skill Game Licensing and Control Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to provide for the licensing of Internet skill game facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
Internet Skill Game Licensing and Control Act of 2008 - Prescribes license requirements for the operation of an Internet skill game facility in interstate or foreign commerce. Shields persons from liability for engaging in investment banking, payments processing, or financial activities with a licensee if such activities comply with specified law. Sets forth prohibitions and limitations of licenses in states and upon Indian lands where permitted bets or wagers are prohibited. Cites conditions under which a state or Indian tribe may establish requirements governing an Internet skill game facility.Prohibits a licensee, as a condition of its license, from facilitating a bet or wager in connection with a sporting event or contest of a sporting league. Subjects violations of this Act to specified criminal penalties.</summary>
</bill>
