<bill session="111" type="s" number="3202" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haitian-American Enterprise Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the strengthening of the Haitian private sector.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2010-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2010--Introduced.
Haitian-American Enterprise Fund Act - Authorizes the President, after congressional consultation, to designate one private, nonprofit organization as the Haitian-American Enterprise Fund to receive funds and support under this Act to promote the Haitian private and agricultural sectors and joint U.S.-Haitian ventures through loans, grants, equity investments, technical assistance, training, and insurance. States that: (1) a grant agreement between the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and the Fund shall require the Fund to liquidate its assets and dissolve not later than December 31, 2020, unless USAID determines that the Fund should be extended; and (2) all Fund assets remaining at such time shall be used to organize a follow-on U.S.-Haiti legacy foundation. Applies the enterprise fund provisions of the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 to the Fund in the same manner as such provisions apply to other similar U.S.-established enterprise funds. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
