<bill session="111" type="h" number="1046" updated="2013-07-19T23:21:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Product Safety Enhancement and Clarification Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the effective implementation of children's product safety standards under the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400328"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2009--Introduced.
Children's Product Safety Enhancement and Clarification Act of 2009 - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008 to exempt a children's product made solely out of fabric from provisions limiting the amount of lead in children's products. Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), in implementing those lead limits with regard to a small business, a person who sells used goods, or a charity to: (1) work cooperatively with the entity; (2) take into account economic, administrative, or other limits on the entity's compliance ability; and (3) construe those provisions favorably to the entity. Exempts a children's product made solely out of fabric from provisions requiring a manufacturer to certify, based on third party testing, that the product complies with an applicable children's product safety rule before importing, warehousing, or distributing the product.</summary>
</bill>
