<bill session="111" type="s" number="1489" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Contracting Programs Parity Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to create parity among small business contracting programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="S7792-7793"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Contracting Programs Parity Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Act with respect to the HUBZone (historically underutilized business zone) program to authorize (current law requires) a contracting opportunity to be awarded under the program on the basis of competition restricted to qualified HUBZone small businesses if the contracting officer expects that not less than two qualified HUBZone small businesses will submit offers and that the award can be made at a fair market price. Includes within HUBZone federal procurement small business contract participation goals small business subcontracting participation goals. Authorizes the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish mentor-protege programs for small businesses owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans and women, and HUBZone small businesses, modeled on the SBA mentor-protege program for small businesses participating in the 8(a) general small business development program.</summary>
</bill>
