<bill session="112" type="s" number="1516" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sustainable States Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a program under which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall provide grants to eligible State consortia to establish and carry out municipal sustainability certification programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3424"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2011--Introduced.
Sustainable States Act of 2011 - Establishes a program under which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) shall provide no more than 20 grants to sustainable state consortia (partnerships consisting of local governments, states, public universities, and other municipal organizations, businesses, or nonprofit organizations) to establish and carry out municipal sustainability certification programs. Requires each grant to have a three year term. Defines "municipal sustainability certification program" as a program that: (1) determines a set of state-specific benchmarks for use in evaluating sustainability, and (2) certifies a municipality as sustainable based on documented achievement of those benchmarks. Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish flexible guidelines that reflect regional differences for use by such consortia in establishing such programs; (2) annually compile data from such consortia and report to Congress on municipal actions undertaken to obtain municipal sustainability certification; (3) encourage such consortia to establish certification standards beyond the guidelines established by the Administrator, adapt the administration of the program to meet regional or local needs, and plan for public-private partnership agreements that will sustain the operation of the certification program of a state beyond the term of the grant; and (4) establish a website that permits interactive dialogue and collaboration among community leaders and citizens engaged in municipal sustainability certification. Establishes a program under which the Administrator shall award no more than 20 project grants to municipalities certified by sustainable state consortia to extend the leadership of the municipalities in meeting sustainability challenges.</summary>
</bill>
