<bill session="109" type="sr" number="42" updated="2013-07-19T20:07:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on promoting initiatives to develop an HIV vaccine.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1063-1064"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1063" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-292.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="hr" number="286"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2005--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that the President should: (1) mobilize necessary economic and scientific support for the Global HIV Vaccine Enterprise (an alliance of the world's leading scientists and independent organizations committed to accelerating the development of an HIV vaccine by enhancing coordination, information sharing, and collaboration globally); and (2) urge members of the Group of Eight (Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Russia, the United Kingdom, and the United States) to garner support from their own communities for the development of an HIV vaccine. Calls for such countries to: (1) take further measures to explore and implement Enterprise initiatives; (2) leverage financial contributions from the international philanthropic community to provide funding to promote the development of an HIV vaccine; (3) include the scientific and political leadership of the countries most affected by the pandemic of HIV and AIDS; and (4) develop a plan for furthering such efforts prior to their June 2005 meeting. Urges the President to generate global support for the Global HIV Vaccine Enterprise by carrying out an initiative that: (1) coordinates and partners with member countries, the private sector, and other countries; (2) encourages Group of Eight countries to act swiftly to mobilize resources; (3) includes a strategic plan to prioritize challenges to the development of an HIV vaccine, to coordinate research and product development, and to encourage greater use of information-sharing networks and technologies; (4) encourages the establishment of coordinated global HIV vaccine development centers; and (5) increases cooperation and communication among regulatory agencies on issues related to AIDS and HIV.</summary>
</bill>
