<bill session="109" type="h" number="1084" updated="2013-07-19T19:13:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-27T15:34:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-27T15:34:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the establishment at Antietam National Battlefield of a memorial to the officers and enlisted men of the Fifth, Sixth, and Ninth New Hampshire Volunteer Infantry Regiments and the First New Hampshire Light Artillery Battery who fought in the Battle of Antietam on September 17, 1862, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="2005-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-111.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-08T19:05:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="63">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5202" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1084.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-06-27T15:34:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5202" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-355.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="748"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Infantry"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="Volunteer forces"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2005--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to authorize the establishment, at a suitable location approved by the Secretary within the boundaries of Antietam National Battlefield, Maryland, of a memorial to the officers and enlisted men of the Fifth, Sixth, and Ninth New Hampshire Volunteer Infantry Regiments and the First New Hampshire Light Artillery Battery who fought in the Battle of Antietam on September 17, 1862. Requires the Secretary to select the persons who will be permitted to establish the memorial. Makes the size, design, and inscriptions of the memorial subject to the approval of the Secretary. Prohibits the expenditure of any federal funds to design, acquire, prepare the site selected for, or install, the memorial. Requires the selected persons, until the memorial is installed, to submit to the Secretary annual reports of the operations related to fundraising efforts for the memorial and progress on the establishment of such memorial. Requires the Secretary to assume responsibility for the maintenance of the memorial upon installation. Allows the Secretary to accept contributions for maintaining the memorial from the selected persons and from other persons. Requires that accepted amounts be merged with other funds available to the Secretary for the maintenance of the memorial and credited to a separate account with the National Park Service.</summary>
</bill>
