<bill session="110" type="s" number="3732" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Small House Nursing Homes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to assist in creating substantive culture change in long-term residential care by establishing a small house nursing home loan program to provide for the establishment, renovation, and construction of small house nursing homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-12-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10947-10948"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10948-10949" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2008--Introduced.
Promoting Small House Nursing Homes Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a small house nursing home loan program under which the Secretary makes grants for the establishment, renovation, and construction of small house nursing homes that meet the requirements of this Act. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) a Small House Advisory Panel to evaluate applications for loans under the program in conjunction with lenders; and (2) an evaluation tool and evaluation criteria with which to prioritize borrowers.Sets forth eligibility criteria for a loan under this Act, including that that home: (1) is designed to establish substantive culture change; (2) has been approved to operate a skilled nursing facility or a nursing facility; and (3) ensures that at least 30% of the residents of the facility are Medicaid-funded individuals.Requires the Secretary to develop model small house nursing home guidelines. Sets forth requirements for a small house nursing home that obtains proceeds from a direct loan under this Act, including that the home provides specified training to all staff. Gives priority in awarding loans to nursing homes that have a certain residential structure, such as private bedrooms, and to homes with a legally binding collective bargaining agreement.Terminates this program 25 years after the date on which amounts are initially appropriated.</summary>
</bill>
