<bill session="112" type="s" number="3576" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-22">FAIL:ORIGINATING:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide limitations on United States assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="530">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 530.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2012 S6679-6684" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:SENATE" datetime="2012-09-22" how="roll" result="fail" roll="196" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Under the order of 9/21/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, failed of passage in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 10 - 81. Record Vote Number: 196.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-22">
      <text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 530.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6452"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2849"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Introduced.
Prohibits amounts from being obligated or expended for any direct U.S. assistance, loan guarantee, or debt relief to Libya, Egypt, Pakistan, or a host country of a U.S. diplomatic facility that was attacked, trespassed upon, breached, or attempted to be attacked, trespassed upon, or breached, on or after September 1, 2012. Authorizes the President to request that the prohibition be suspended with respect to a country if the President certifies to Congress that: (1) such country is cooperating with investigations into an attack, has arrested or extradited persons associated with the attack, and is improving local security; and (2) all persons associated with the attack have been identified by U.S. law enforcement and are in U.S. custody. Prohibits any request with respect to Pakistan until: (1) Dr. Shakil Afridi has been released alive from prison; (2) all charges brought against Dr. Afridi have been dropped; and (3) if necessary to ensure his freedom, Dr. Afridi has been allowed to leave Pakistan alive. Requires the President to report to Congress regarding the extent to which advanced weaponry remaining unsecured after the fall of Moammar Qaddafi was used by the individuals responsible for the September 11, 2012, attack on the U.S. consulate in Benghazi, Libya. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as an authorization for the use of military force.</summary>
</bill>
