<bill session="111" type="h" number="1832" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Prescription Drug Affordability Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to limit the increase in premium costs for beneficiaries under the Medicare prescription drug program to no more than the Social Security cost-of-living adjustment, and to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to negotiate lower prescription drug prices on behalf of Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400430"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4752"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Prescription Drug Affordability Act of 2009 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) limit Medicare part D prescription drug plan (PDP) cost increases to the Social Security cost-of-living increase; and (2) direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to negotiate with pharmaceutical manufacturers the prices that may be charged to PDP sponsors and MedicareAdvantage (MA) organizations for covered part D drugs for part D eligible individuals who are enrolled under a PDP or under an MA-Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plan.</summary>
</bill>
