<bill session="111" type="h" number="4601" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Nurse Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of the National Nurse.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2010-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2010--Introduced.
National Nurse Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Public Health Service an Office of the National Nurse, headed by a registered nurse appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS). Directs the Secretary to: (1) initially appoint the individual serving as the Chief Nurse Officer of the Public Health Service as of this Act's enactment as the first National Nurse; and (2) thereafter appoint the National Nurse in accordance with Commissioned Corps Instruction CC23.4.6 (relating to Chief Professional Officer Nominations), as in effect on February 13, 2008. Grants the National Nurse the same rank and grade as the Deputy Surgeon General.Lists duties of the National Nurse, including to provide leadership and coordination of Public Health Service nursing professional affairs for the Office of the Surgeon General and other agencies of the Service, to conduct media campaigns, and to provide guidance and leadership for activities that will increase public safety and emergency preparedness. Requires the National Nurse to: (1) identify annual health priorities; (2) encourage volunteerism and strengthen the relationship between government agencies and health-related national organizations; and (3) encourage community-based, nonprofit organizations to seek grants for the purpose of education and interventions to address the annual priorities (including evaluating the activities encouraged by the National Nurse and conducted by such organizations, and disseminating information to governmental agencies, schools, and organizations interested in health promotion and improving public health through community action).</summary>
</bill>
