<bill session="111" type="h" number="5669" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-28T21:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-28T21:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain Federally owned land located in Story County, Iowa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cardoza moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6260-6261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T21:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5669.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-28T21:07:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6260-6261" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T21:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3613"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2010--Passed House amended.
Requires conveyance of approximately 44 acres of federally owned land administered by the Agricultural Research Service which comprises part of the National Animal Disease Center (the property) in the city of Ames, Iowa, to the city of Ames and its assigns. Requires the city: (1) to pay to the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) the market value of the property, to be determined by an appraisal; and (2) at closing, to pay or reimburse the reasonable transaction and administrative costs associated with the conveyance incurred by the Secretary. Requires the city and the Secretary to bear their own attorneys fees. Requires the Secretary to meet disclosure requirements for hazardous substances, but to otherwise not be required to remediate or abate such substances or any other hazardous pollutants, contaminants, or waste that might be present on the property at the time of closing. Bars requiring the Secretary to mitigate or abate any lead-based paint or asbestos-containing building materials present on the property at the time of closing. Sets forth the procedure the Secretary shall follow if the property has such paint or building materials present on it at that time. Requires the deposit of funds received from the conveyance into the Treasury to be credited to the Agricultural Research Service and to be: (1) used for the acquisition of land and interests and other related purposes of the National Animal Disease Center; and (2) considered to authorize the acquisition of land as may be necessary for the USDA to carry out its work.</summary>
</bill>
