<bill session="112" type="s" number="2024" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sandia Pueblo Settlement Technical Amendment Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Sandia Pueblo Settlement Technical Amendment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make technical amendment to the T'uf Shur Bien Preservation Trust Area Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-11">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Akaka with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="561">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 561.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3734"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Sandia Pueblo Settlement Technical Amendment Act - Amends the T'uf Shur Bien Preservation Trust Area Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture, upon the receipt of certain consideration and at the request of the Sandia Pueblo of New Mexico and the Secretary of the Interior, to transfer certain national forest land to the Secretary of the Interior to be held in trust for the Pueblo, provided a land exchange with the Pueblo required by that Act is not completed within 90 days of this Act's enactment. Requires that national forest land to be preserved as open space in its natural state. Requires the Pueblo to transfer to the Secretary, in exchange for such land, the Pueblo's La Luz tract and an amount equal to the difference between the value of: (1) the national forest land as open space in its natural state, and (2) the La Luz tract and the compensation owed to the Pueblo by the Secretary for the right-of-way and conservation easement on its Piedra Lisa tract.</summary>
</bill>
