<bill session="113" type="h" number="2469" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E942"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Amends the District of Columbia Code to direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia, in coordination with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, to establish a program that allows the Mayor to provide educational assistance to members of the District of Columbia National Guard who have satisfactorily completed their initial active duty service and agree to serve for at least six years. Requires such assistance to be used by members for expenses incurred in pursuing their first undergraduate, master's, vocational, or technical degree or certification at an approved institution of higher education. Prohibits members who are receiving a Reserve Officer Training Corps scholarship from receiving this Act's assistance.</summary>
</bill>
