<bill session="110" type="s" number="3222" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Transition Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Clean-Coal-Derived Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the energy security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6412"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3669"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Natural gas reserves"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2008--Introduced.
Energy Transition Act of 2008 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to modify requirements governing publication and uses of projected state lines on the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS). Authorizes a state governor to petition the Secretary of Energy to make available for oil and gas leasing any moratorium area within the offshore administrative boundaries beyond the submerged land of a state that is located greater than 50 miles from the state coastline (new producing areas). Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (ANILCA) to repeal the prohibition against producing oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR). Sets forth an oil and gas leasing program for the Alaskan Coastal Plain, including the Refuge. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, to: (1) designate specified acreage of the Coastal Plain as special areas; (2) exclude from leasing or surface occupancy any such special area; and (3) permit the use of horizontal drilling technology into such areas from the outside. Requires the state of Alaska to establish the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund. Prohibits exportation of oil or gas produced from leases granted under this Act. Allocates revenues among the Energy Independence Fund (established by this Act), the state of Alaska, and the Secretary of the Treasury. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), upon request, to enter into a permitting agreement with a state or Indian tribe under a streamlined approval process for refinery construction and operation. Amends the Clean Air Act with respect to renewable biomass. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal EPA authority to waive specified prohibitions against certain fuels or fuel additives. Clean-Coal-Derived Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2008 - Directs the President to promulgate regulations to ensure that aviation fuel, motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel sold or introduced into commerce in the United States contains the applicable volume of clean coal-derived fuel. Exempts small refineries from compliance with such regulations until 2018, unless the President extends such exemption if compliance would impose a disproportionate economic hardship. Amends the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008 to repeal the prohibition against final regulations for the commercial leasing program for oil shale resources on public land. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to require the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey to increase activities relating to the Energy Resources Program and other resource assessment activities related to domestic oil and natural gas reserves. Establishes the Energy Independence Fund. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to develop and report to Congress a strategic and comprehensive plan to eliminate all foreign imports of oil from countries outside of North America by 2028.</summary>
</bill>
