<bill session="110" type="s" number="2614" updated="2013-07-19T22:43:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GEAR Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Greenhouse Gas Emission Atmospheric Removal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to facilitate the development, demonstration, and implementation of technology for the use in removing carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S818-819"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2008--Introduced.
Greenhouse Gas Emission Atmospheric Removal Act or the GEAR Act - Declares that it is the policy of the United States to provide incentives to encourage the development and implementation of technology to permanently remove greenhouse gases (GHGs) from the atmosphere on a significant scale.Establishes within the Department of Energy (DOE) the Greenhouse Gas Emission Atmospheric Removal Commission.Requires the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Commission, to provide financial awards on a competitive basis to entities for the achievement of milestones in developing and applying technology that could significantly slow or reverse the accumulation of GHGs in the atmosphere by permanently capturing or sequestrating those gases without significant countervailing harmful effects.Requires the Commission to: (1) develop specific requirements for the competition, performance, monitoring and verification, and the scale of awards; (2) establish minimum levels for the capture or net sequestration of GHGs required to qualify for a financial award; (3) offer awards to entities that demonstrate achievement of specified technological goals; and (4) establish standards for required peer review of proposals seeking such awards.Vests title to intellectual property arising from such awards in U.S. entities. Bars title transfer to an entity not incorporated in the United States until the first obtained patent expires. Authorizes the United States to reserve a license to have such property practiced on its behalf.</summary>
</bill>
