<bill session="110" type="s" number="3495" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect Pregnant Women and Children from Dangerous Lead Exposures Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect pregnant women and children from dangerous lead exposures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2008--Introduced.
Protect Pregnant Women and Children from Dangerous Lead Exposures Act of 2008 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), no later than April 30, 2009, to use the best available science to: (1) promulgate a final rule revising EPA's lead-based paint hazard standard promulgated under the Toxic Substances Control Act to a more protective level that safeguards the health of pregnant women and children; and (2) require the use of a lead dust cleaning clearance methodology that ensures lead dust levels meet such revised standard. Requires the Administrator to ensure that EPA's Clean Air Science Advisory Committee peer reviews the analyses that the Administrator uses to revise such standard and to require the use of such methodology.Requires the Administrator, no later than April 22, 2010, to integrate into EPA's revised rules on renovation and remolding activities that create lead-based paint hazards such revised standard and methodology. Requires the Administrator to review and reevaluate the health protectiveness of the rule revising EPA's lead-based paint hazard standard to determine whether to increase protections for the health of pregnant women and children: (1) every five years; or (2) more frequently if significant scientific findings indicate that the standard should be so revised.Declares that this Act does not modify or affect any effective date described in the final rule of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled "Lead: Renovation, Repair, and Repainting Program" published on April 22, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
