<bill session="112" type="s" number="1076" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify the roving wiretap authority of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="990"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1050"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1070"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1074"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to impose limits on roving electronic surveillance by revising specifications and adding directions required to be included in the order of a designated judge approving such surveillance, including, in cases where the facility or place at which the electronic surveillance will be directed is unknown at the time the order is issued, that the electronic surveillance be conducted only for such time as reasonable to presume that the target of the surveillance is or was reasonably proximate to the particular facility or place. Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to make the following FISA provisions, subject to exceptions, read as they read on October 25, 2001 (prior to enactment of the USA PATRIOT Act on October 26, 2001): (1) effective December 31, 2013, provisions specifying the directions to be contained in orders approving electronic surveillance of a foreign power or agent of a foreign power; and (2) effective May 27, 2011, provisions authorizing the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to apply for orders requiring production of business records and other tangible things in investigations related to foreign intelligence and international terrorism and directing the Attorney General (DOJ) to annually inform Congress of such requests.</summary>
</bill>
