<bill session="112" type="sr" number="77" updated="2013-07-20T02:11:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that domestic oil and gas resources are critical to our Nation's security and economy and the Secretary of the Interior should take immediate action to streamline the shallow and deepwater permitting process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S977-978" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="hr" number="140"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2011--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the nation's economy and security depend upon full and immediate restoration of shallow and deepwater drilling operations in the Gulf of Mexico, and (2) the long-term economic health of Alaska depends upon the responsible development of the oil and natural gas reserves of the Beaufort and Chukchi Seas. Urges the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) streamline the review and approval of applications for both shallow and deepwater drilling permits in the Outer Continental Shelf, (2) take immediate action to provide the shallow and deepwater industry with a completed sample application meeting all new safety and environmental regulations, (3) supply written guidance and clarification to applicants regarding new safety requirements, and (4) give permit applicants timely and detailed explanations on any areas of a permit which do not satisfy new requirements.</summary>
</bill>
