<bill session="110" type="s" number="3586" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Green Hospitals, Healthy Hospitals Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide loans to hospitals and nonprofit health care institutions to implement green building technologies, waste management techniques, and other environmentally sustainable practices to improve employee performance, reduce healthcare costs, and improve patient outcomes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical wastes"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
Green Hospitals, Healthy Hospitals Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting in conjunction with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to provide nonprofit hospitals and health care institutions with 30-year no interest loans to enable such institutions to comply with the guidelines of the Green Guide for Health Care or successor regulations of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) on green building technologies.Directs the Secretary to enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine for a report on the use of green building technologies, waste management techniques, and other environmentally sustainable practices to improve employee performance, reduce health care costs, and improve patient outcomes. Requires the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to include in its annual report on health care quality a summary of the most recent research on green health care and the ways in which environmentally sustainable practices can improve employee performance, reduce health care costs, and improve patient outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
