<bill session="109" type="sr" number="365" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Reform Earmarks Process resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to provide a 60 vote point of order against out-of-scope material in conference reports and open the process of earmarks in the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S515"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S514-515" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2006--Introduced.
Makes it out of order to consider a conference report that includes any matter not committed to the conferees by either chamber. Requires a point of order to be made and voted on separately for each item in violation of this Resolution. Sets forth procedures for consideration of the point of order. Allows waiver or suspension of this Resolution in the Senate only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Members. Requires the same three-fifths affirmative vote to sustain an appeal of the ruling of the Chair on a point of order raised under this Resolution. Amends rule XVI (Committee Procedure) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to make it out of order to consider any bill or amendment between the chambers or conference report on such a measure unless a list is made available to all Members and the general public for at least 24 hours before its consideration of all earmarks in it, the identity of the Member who proposed each earmark, and an explanation of the essential governmental purpose for it. Requires any Member who requests an earmark in the bill, before its consideration in the Senate, to file a copy of the request with the Secretary of the Senate. Requires the request to be printed in the Congressional Record. Amends rule XXVIII (Conference Committees, Reports, Open Meetings) to make it out of order to consider a conference report if it is not available to all Members and made available to the general public on the Internet for at least 24 hours before its consideration.</summary>
</bill>
