<bill session="111" type="h" number="6255" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require mail-order pharmacies to notify customers when generic drugs become available and to prevent mail-order pharmacies from substituting drugs without the express authorization of the prescriber.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412219"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Requires a mail-order pharmacy to inform a customer to whom it dispenses a prescription brand name drug when a generic drug that is the pharmaceutical equivalent becomes available. Permits a mail-order pharmacy to substitute a generic drug for a brand name drug or a brand name drug for a generic drug if the mail order pharmacy: (1) notifies the customer that the pharmacy will request that the prescriber provide an authorization to make such a substitution; and (2) after providing such notification, obtains the express written authorization of the prescriber of the drug to make such a substitution. Requires the prescriber to provide notice to the customer of an authorization. Permits the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to assess civil penalties against a mail-order pharmacy for violations of this Act. Declares that this Act preempts state laws to the extent any are inconsistent with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
