<bill session="111" type="h" number="5470" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To exclude an external power supply for certain security or life safety alarms and surveillance system components from the application of certain energy efficiency standards under the Energy Policy and Conservation Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8104-8105" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5470.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-12-08T11:22:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8104-8105" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-12-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10933" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-01-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-01-04" type="public" number="111-360">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-360.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2011--Public Law.
Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA) to exempt from the applicability of No-Load Mode energy efficiency standards an external power supply manufactured before July 1, 2017, that: (1) is an AC-to-AC external power supply; (2) has a nameplate output of 20 watts or more; (3) is certified by the Secretary of Energy (DOE) as being designed to be connected to a security or life safety alarm or surveillance system component; and (4) is permanently marked with a distinguishing mark established within the External Power Supply International Efficiency Marking Protocol for Single Voltage External AC-DC and AC-AC Power Supplies. Defines a "security or life safety alarm or surveillance system" as equipment designed and marketed to, on a continuous basis: (1) monitor, detect, record, or provide notification of intrusion or access to real property or physical assets or notification of threats to life safety; (2) deter or control access to real property or physical assets or to prevent the unauthorized removal of physical assets; or (3) monitor, detect, record, or provide notification of fire, gas, smoke, flooding, or other physical threats to real property, physical assets, or life safety. Directs the Secretary to: (1) require, with appropriate safeguard for the protection of confidential business information, the submission of unit shipment data on an annual basis; and (2) restrict the eligibility of external power supplies for the exemption provided on a finding that a substantial number of external power supplies are being marketed to or installed in applications other than security or life safety alarm or surveillance systems.</summary>
</bill>
