<bill session="112" type="s" number="3489" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Good Neighbor Social Security Office and Community Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect senior citizens, disabled persons, veterans, and other beneficiaries and customers of the Social Security Administration by performing the process for closure of field offices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412384"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Good Neighbor Social Security Office and Community Protection Act of 2012 - Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to develop and publish: (1) financial guidelines that may be used to identify Social Security Administration field offices for possible closure, and (2) standardized closure procedures that meet certain requirements. Requires such guidelines and procedures to provide that identification of an Administration field office for possible closure shall not require the Commissioner to begin closure procedures for it. Requires the Commissioner to: (1) develop an office closure and service continuity proposal for any office so identified which the Commissioner decides to close that contains, among other specified items, the estimated cost of the closure; (2) notify state and local chief executive offices and the public before closure; (3) require the Commissioner to hold at least one hearing to take public comments before making a final decision to close a field office; (5) issue a final closure decision only after review of such comments and evaluation of any alternatives to closing the office; and (6) continue to operate an office proposed for closure in good faith and with the assumption of continued service until the notice of the Commisioner's final closure decision is made.</summary>
</bill>
