<bill session="109" type="s" number="3363" updated="2013-07-19T20:42:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for accelerated payment of survivors' and dependents' educational assistance for certain programs of education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-715.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2416"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2006--Introduced.
Permits accelerated payments of educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill to an individual enrolled in program with tuition in excess of 200% of the monthly rate of educational assistance otherwise payable when the program is an approved program of education that either: (1) leads to employment in a high technology occupation in a high technology industry; or (2) lasts less than two years and leads to employment in a sector of the economy that is projected to experience a substantial increase in the number of jobs, positively affect the growth of another sector of the economy, or consists of existing or emerging businesses that are being transformed by technology and innovation and require new skills for workers. Includes as an authorized program for purposes of such assistance a program of education pursued at a tribally controlled college or university as defined under the Tribally Controlled College or University Assistance Act of 1978.</summary>
</bill>
