<bill session="111" type="h" number="4851" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Continuing Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Continuing Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Continuing Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Continuing Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a temporary extension of certain programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2010-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, Education and Labor, Energy and Commerce, Financial Services, the Judiciary, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McDermott moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1548-1553" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4851.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-03-17T15:32:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1548-1549" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="323">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 323.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2099" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the bill presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2099" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2099" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-12">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2191-2202" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-12">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the bill invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 60 - 34. Record Vote Number: 109.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2200" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2200" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2226" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2226" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2226-2235" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2265-2269, S2275-2289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Cloture motion on the bill presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2288" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2288" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2341-2357, S2363-2367" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Cloture motion on the bill withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2365" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-04-15" how="roll" result="pass" roll="117" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay. 59 - 38. Record Vote Number: 117.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2365-2366" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Levin asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time to take from the Speaker's table H.R. 4851, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House, without intervention of any point of order or question of consideration, a motion offered by the chair of the Committee on Ways and Means or his designee that the House agree to the Senate amendment; that the Senate amendment be considered as read; the motion be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Ways and Means; and that the previous question be considered as ordered on the motion to final adoption without intervening motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to a previous special order the House moved to agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2615-2620" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 4851.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-04-15T20:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="211" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by recorded vote: 289 - 112 (Roll no. 211).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2615-2616" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15T20:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-04-15" type="public" number="111-157">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-157.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3404"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3548"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3756"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4183"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4213"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4691"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4691"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4707"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5453"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5618"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5647"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6419"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1647"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1699"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2831"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3153"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3153"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3173"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3420"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3551"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3706"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3981"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3990"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3720"/>
    <amendment number="s3721"/>
    <amendment number="s3723"/>
    <amendment number="s3724"/>
    <amendment number="s3725"/>
    <amendment number="s3726"/>
    <amendment number="s3727"/>
    <amendment number="s3728"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/15/2010--Public Law.
Continuing Extension Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 with respect to the state-established individual emergency unemployment compensation account (EUCA). Extends the final date for entering a federal-state agreement under the Emergency Unemployment Compensation (EUC) program through June 2, 2010. Postpones the termination of the program until November 6, 2010. Amends the Assistance for Unemployed Workers and Struggling Families Act to extend until June 2, 2010: (1) federal-state agreements increasing regular unemployment compensation payments to individuals; and (2) requirements that federal payments to states cover 100% of EUC. Amends the Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008 to exempt weeks of unemployment between enactment of this Act and November 6, 2010, from the prohibition in the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 against federal matching payments to a state for the first week in an individual's eligibility period for which extended compensation or sharable regular compensation is paid if the state law provides for payment of regular compensation to an individual for his or her first week of otherwise compensable unemployment. (Thus allows temporary federal matching for the first week of extended benefits for states with no waiting period.) (Sec. 3) Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA) to extend through May 31, 2010, premium assistance for COBRA benefits (health insurance continuation benefits under the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985). Prescribes a special rule for an individual who experiences a qualifying event related to a termination of employment on or after April 1, 2010, and before the enactment of this Act. Applies to all COBRA continuation coverage, including state continuation coverage programs, with respect to such individual rules similar to those in the ARRA: (1) extending the election period for, and the effect on, COBRA continuation coverage; and (2) requiring a notice of such action by the administrator of a group health plan. (Sec. 4) Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to extend through May 31, 2010, the 0% update to the conversion factor in the Medicare physician payment computation. (Sec. 5) Amends SSA titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) with respect to the prohibition against incentive payments to hospital-based eligible professionals for use of certified electronic health record (EHR) technology. Redefines "hospital-based eligible professional" to repeal its application to outpatient settings, thereby permitting incentive payments to an eligible professional who furnishes services in an outpatient clinic. (Sec. 6) Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2010 to extend the use of 2009 poverty guidelines through May 31, 2010. Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from publishing updated poverty guidelines for 2010 until after such date. (Sec. 7) Amends the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2010 to extend through May 31, 2010, the national flood insurance program. (Sec. 8) Requires federal employees furloughed as a result of the lapse in expenditure authority from the Highway Trust Fund after 11:59 p.m. on February 28, 2010, through March 2, 2010, to be compensated for such lapse at their standard rates of compensation. Ratifies and approves all actions taken by federal employees, contractors, and grantees to maintain the essential level of government operations, services, and activities to protect life and property and to bring about orderly termination of government functions during such lapse, if otherwise in accord with the provisions of the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2010. Requires funds used by the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to compensate such employees to be: (1) derived from funds previously authorized out of the Highway Trust Fund and made available or limited to DOT by the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010; and (2) subject to the obligation limitations established in such Act. (Sec. 9) Extends through May 31, 2010, the adjustment of royalty fees for the secondary transmission of the primary analog transmissions of network stations and superstations. Extends through such date the moratorium on copyright liability for certain subscribers not receiving a signal of Grade A intensity of a local network television broadcast station and receiving signals of network stations affiliated with the same network, if such subscribers had satellite service of such network signal terminated between July 11, 1998, and October 31, 1999. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to extend through May 31, 2010, the exemption of a subscriber from the originating station consent requirement for retransmission of broadcasting station signals if the subscriber receives the retransmitted signals directly to a home satellite antenna, is located outside the station's local market, and resides in an unserved household. Extends through June 1, 2010, the requirement that certain Federal Communications Commission (FCC) regulations prohibit: (1) a television broadcast station that provides retransmission consent from engaging in exclusive contracts for carriage or failing to negotiate in good faith; and (2) a multichannel video programming distributor from failing to negotiate in good faith for retransmission consent. (Sec. 10) Amends the ARRA to extend through May 31, 2010, the small business loan guarantee program. Makes appropriations for the program as well as for the cost of certain loan guarantee fee reductions and eliminations. (Sec. 11) Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the Value Added Tax (VAT) is a massive tax increase that will cripple families on fixed income and only further push back America's economic recovery; and (2) it opposes a VAT. (Sec. 12) Designates this Act, except Sec. 4, as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
