<bill session="109" type="s" number="559" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection of Vulnerable Populations During Humanitarian Emergencies Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Protection of Vulnerable Populations During Humanitarian Emergencies Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make the protection of vulnerable populations, especially women and children, who are affected by a humanitarian emergency a priority of the United States Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2006-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2006-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2259-2260"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2260-2262" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Lugar with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="453">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 453.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Children's rights"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex-oriented businesses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Reported to Senate amended.
Protection of Vulnerable Populations During Humanitarian Emergencies Act of 2005 -Title I: Program and Policy Coordination - (Sec. 101) Directs the Secretary of State to develop a comprehensive strategy for the protection of vulnerable populations, especially women and children, who are affected by a humanitarian emergency. (Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary to designate an individual within the Department of State or the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) as the Coordinator for such efforts. Title II: Prevention and Preparedness - (Sec. 201) Directs the Coordinator to develop related reporting and monitoring systems. (Sec. 202) Authorizes USAID to establish a fellowship program to increase USAID expertise in carrying out protective activities of vulnerable populations, especially women and children, affected by a humanitarian emergency. Title III: Protection of Refugees and Internally Displaced Persons - (Sec. 301) Prohibits certain Department or USAID funds for refugees or internally displaced persons from being provided to a primary grantee or contractor unless the grantee or contractor has adopted a code of conduct that is consistent with the six core principles recommended by the United Nations Inter-Agency Standing Committee. (Sec. 302) Directs the Coordinator to seek to provide health services to vulnerable populations, including: (1) responding to the consequences of sexual violence; (2) providing testing and treatment for HIV/AIDS and sexually transmitted diseases; (3) providing essential obstetric and prenatal care; and (4) developing a plan to integrate essential women's health services into the primary health care services provided during a humanitarian emergency. (Sec. 303) Amends the Microenterprise for Self-Reliance Act of 2000 and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to seek to extend microcredit program availability to vulnerable populations, including women and displaced persons. (Sec. 304) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to permit the President to furnish military education and training to military and related civilian personnel of foreign countries if it would improve the protection of civilians, especially women and children, including refugees or displaced persons. (Sec. 305) Expresses the sense of Congress that the United Nations (U.N.) should strengthen the ability of its Department of Peacekeeping Operations to protect civilians, especially women and children, from sexual exploitation by peacekeeping personnel. Title IV: Protection of Vulnerable Populations Affected by a Humanitarian Emergency - (Sec. 401) States that the U.S. Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank) should take steps to ensure that disarmament, demobilization, and reintegration programs provide benefits to former combatants that are comparable to the benefits provided by such programs to other individuals. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees on all Department or USAID programs to assist foreign countries with the enforcement of laws to protect women and children and improve accountability for sexual exploitation and abuse. (Sec. 402) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act authorize the President to use the authorities under such Act to provide assistance for programs to protect vulnerable populations during humanitarian emergencies.</summary>
</bill>
