<bill session="111" type="hr" number="406" updated="2013-07-19T22:59:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07T11:53:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-07T11:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 1728) to amend the Truth in Lending Act to reform consumer mortgage practices and provide accountability for such practices, to provide certain minimum standards for consumer mortgage loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-98, by Mr. Cardoza.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. The resolution waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute except for clause 10 of rule XXI. This waiver does not affect the point of order available under clause 9 of rule XXI (regarding earmark disclosure).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-06T16:52:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="51">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 51.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5313-5324" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 406. During the course of debate, Mr. Cardoza asked unanimous consent to modify the description of the Frank amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 111-98 in the form provided to the desk. Agreed to without objection. Subsequently, the House resumed debate on H.Res. 406.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5323" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-07T11:53:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="237" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 247 - 174 (Roll no. 237).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5313" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T11:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1728"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2009--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for further consideration of H.R. 1728 (Mortgage Reform and Anti-Predatory Lending Act).</summary>
</bill>
