<bill session="110" type="h" number="3862" updated="2013-07-19T21:37:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preparing America's Seniors for the Digital Transition Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve public awareness in the United States among older individuals and their families and caregivers about the impending Digital Television Transition through the establishment of a Federal interagency taskforce between the Federal Communications Commission, the Administration on Aging, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, and the outside advice of appropriate members of the aging network and industry groups.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2007-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2125"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Electronics industry"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2007--Introduced.
Preparing America's Seniors for the Digital Transition Act of 2007 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), commencing not later than January 1, 2008, or 60 days after enactment, to enter into a partnership with the Administration on Aging and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to create a comprehensive nationwide public education campaign that provides information and assistance to older individuals to ensure that such individuals receive uninterrupted television service during the transition from analog to digital television that is to occur on February 17, 2009, and to mitigate the likelihood of success of fraudulent schemes relating to such transition that may target such older individuals. Provides for an advisory board which shall include representatives from minorities, the disabled, non-native English speakers, tribal groups, and other vulnerable populations. Sets forth: (1) public notification (and labeling and advertising, as appropriate) requirements for full power commercial television broadcast licensees, noncommercial broadcasters, multichannel video programming distributors, electronic retailers, and manufacturers; and (2) penalties for noncompliance. Provides for grants for provide public education outreach and installation assistance to older individuals and other vulnerable populations. Amends the Digital Television Transition and Public Safety Act of 2005 to revise the program specifications of the digital-to-analog converter box program, including requiring a standard application to receive a coupon.</summary>
</bill>
