<bill session="111" type="h" number="1295" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness in Housing Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To mitigate mortgage foreclosures, facilitate and include fairness in housing recovery, and combat mortgage fraud, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2009-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412010" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2009--Introduced.
Fairness in Housing Recovery Act of 2009 - Shields a servicer from liability for entering into a loan modification or loss mitigation plan for certain mortgages pursuant to guidelines issued by the Secretary of the Treasury under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA), if such servicer acts consistent with the fiduciary duty of servicers of pooled residential mortgages required by the Truth in Lending Act. Amends the National Housing Act to replace the Hope for Homeowners Program with a program for insurance of home ownership retention mortgages. Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act to establish the Office of Housing Counseling Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to provide financial assistance to governmental entities and nonprofit organizations providing home ownership or rental counseling. Requires the Secretary to study and report to Congress on the root causes of default and foreclosure of home loans. Amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to direct the Secretary periodically to prepare a consumer education booklet on real estate settlement practices for federally related mortgage loan applicants. Amends the National Housing Act to prescribe limitations upon participation in origination and mortgagee approval. Establishes Commission on the Foreclosure and Mortgage Lending Crisis to study and report to Congress on the current legal and regulatory framework governing the housing mortgage lending markets and how it contributed to the increased foreclosure rate. Authorizes appropriations to the Attorney General to combat mortgage fraud. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) and the Federal Credit Union Act (FCUA) to increase the maximum deposit insurance and borrowing authorities of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) and the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA). Amends the FDIA with respect to systemic risk special assessments. Amends the FCUA to direct the NCUA Board to establish a National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund restoration plan in specified circumstances. Amends the EESA to prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from making any purchase for which the Secretary receives control-diluting stock. Declares that for a taxpayer who holds an interest in a subsidized residence: (1) the exclusion of gain from sale of principal residence under the Internal Revenue Code shall not apply to any gain from the sale or exchange of such interest, and (2) a specified rate of tax on specified gain shall be twice the rate which would otherwise apply. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a refundable general home buyer credit for residences purchased during 2009 or 2010. Prescribes general conditions for mortgage relief.</summary>
</bill>
