<bill session="112" type="s" number="1689" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Sexual Assault Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require a comprehensive policy on reporting and tracking sexual assault incidents and other safety incidents that occur at medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1627"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2074"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
Veterans Sexual Assault Prevention Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop and implement, by February 1, 2012, a centralized and comprehensive policy on reporting and tracking sexual assaults and other safety incidents at each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), including: (1) risk-assessment tools; (2) mandatory security training; (3) physical security precautions (surveillance camera systems and panic alarm systems); (4) criteria and guidance for employees communicating and reporting incidents to specified supervisory personnel, VA law enforcement officials, and the Office of Inspector General; (4) an oversight system within the Veterans Health Administration; (5) procedures for VA law enforcement officials investigating, tracking, and closing reported incidents; and (6) clinical guidance for treating sexual assaults reported over 72 hours after assault. Requires the Secretary to: (1) submit an annual report to Congress on such incidents and policy implementation, and (2) prescribe applicable regulations. Repeals required annual reports concerning registered nurse staffing at VA health care facilities.</summary>
</bill>
