<bill session="112" type="h" number="1517" updated="2013-07-20T01:23:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Holley Lynn James Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 10 and 28, United States Code, to provide for military sexual assault and domestic violence accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2012-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2011--Introduced.
Holley Lynn James Act - Directs the Deputy Inspector General for Policy and Oversight of the Department of Defense (DOD) to: (1) develop a DOD-wide sexual assault prevention and response policy and domestic violence policy, and (2) provide oversight within DOD with respect to such policies. Requires the Deputy Inspector General to: (1) provide guidance and technical assistance to the heads of the military departments in addressing matters concerning sexual assault and domestic violence prevention and response, (2) maintain sexual assault and domestic violence data collected from each military department, and (3) collaborate with appropriate federal and state agencies that address such issues. Directs the Deputy Inspector General for Policy and Oversight to determine the feasibility of establishing a Military Sexual Predator Database. Outlines criteria for the disposition of rape, sexual assault, sexual harassment, and domestic violence cases. Specifies the rights of a victim in such a case. Allows a claim to be brought against the United States for damages or other appropriate relief for any act or omission related to or arising out of assaultive conduct, or failure to prevent or properly investigate or prosecute such conduct. Defines assaultive conduct as sexual assault or harassment, domestic violence, assault and battery, intentional infliction of emotional distress, false imprisonment, or discrimination or negligent hiring, supervision, promotion, or retention.</summary>
</bill>
