<bill session="109" type="sr" number="76" updated="2013-07-19T20:07:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-09">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the anniversary of the deadly terrorist attacks launched against the people of Spain on March 11, 2004.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2005-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2005-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-03-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2304" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2304" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2400" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Spain"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
    <term name="Summit diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses solidarity with the people of Spain as they commemorate the victims of the March 2004 Madrid terrorist attacks, and condemns such attacks and all other terrorist acts against innocent civilians. Welcomes: (1) the European Union (EU) decision to mark the anniversary of the worst terrorist attack on European soil with a Day of Civic and Democratic Dialogue; and (2) the Club of Madrid initiative to bring together leaders and experts to develop an agenda for fighting terrorism and strengthening democracy. Calls upon the United States and all nations to continue to work together to identify and prosecute the perpetrators of the Madrid attacks. Looks forward to receiving the recommendations of the International Summit on Democracy, Terrorism, and Security for strengthening international cooperation against terrorism through democratic means.</summary>
</bill>
