<bill session="113" type="h" number="49" updated="2013-11-02T06:19:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy Independence and Price Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will result in an environmentally sound program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Coastal Plain of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
American Energy Independence and Price Reduction Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to implement a competitive leasing program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources on the Coastal Plain of Alaska. Permits lease sales to be conducted through an Internet leasing program if such a system will result in savings to the taxpayer, an increase in the number of bidders participating, and higher returns than oral bidding or a sealed bidding system. Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 to repeal the prohibition against leasing or other development leading to production of oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR). Deems any oil and gas leasing programs and activities authorized by this Act to be in compliance with ANWR purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to designate up to 45,000 acres of the Coastal Plain as a Special Area, after consultation with the state of Alaska, the city of Kaktovik, and the North Slope Borough. Permits directional drilling in the Special Area. Prescribes procedures governing Coastal Plain lease sales, as well as terms and conditions, including: (1) environmental protection; (2) federal and state distribution of revenues; and (3) rights-of-way. Sets forth: (1) a "no significant adverse effect" standard to govern Coastal Plain activities; and (2) guidelines for expedited judicial review of complaints. Establishes the ANWR Alternative Energy Trust Fund, into which shall be deposited 50% of the amount of bonus, rental, and royalty revenues from Federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
