<bill session="112" type="hr" number="625" updated="2013-07-20T01:08:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the members of the United States Armed Forces who served in Vietnam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400130"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2012--Introduced.
Recognizes and remembers the valiant sacrifices of members of the U.S. Armed Forces killed in action, missing in action, or prisoners of war. Encourages the Philadelphia Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Medical Center to establish an advisory committee to consider whether the name of the hospital should be changed to recognize the efforts of an individual or group of veterans in the service of the United States. Supports the inclusion in the advisory committee of diverse stakeholders, including veteran service organizations, community organizations, patients served by the hospital, and other stakeholders. Believes the actions and commendations of specific individuals, including Corporal Michael Joseph Crescenz, should be appropriately considered by the advisory committee. Seeks any recommendations that the advisory committee may develop in order to inform congressional deliberations about changing the name of the Philadelphia Medical Center or otherwise recognizing the service of Philadelphia area veterans.</summary>
</bill>
