<bill session="111" type="h" number="3748" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Efficiency via Carbon Harvesting and Restoration (WECHAR) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish loan guarantee programs to develop biochar technology using excess plant biomass, to establish biochar demonstration projects on public land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2009-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1713"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2009--Introduced.
Water Efficiency via Carbon Harvesting and Restoration (WECHAR) Act of 2009 - Requires the Director of the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to conduct resources assessments that collect and synthesize interagency and state data to quantify: (1) invasive plant species and excess biomass (plant matter targeted for removal from public land to promote ecosystem health) in the form of dangerous fuel loads on public land that can be used for feedstock (plant matter or materials that serve as the raw material for the production of biochar and bioenergy); (2) estimated carbon content in that feedstock; (3) estimated potential biochar (charcoal or black carbon derived from organic matter through pyrolysis) and bioenergy (hydrocarbons derived from organic matter through pyrolysis) producible from that feedstock; and (4) potential water savings resulting from removal of invasive plant species and excess biomass on public land, by watershed. Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to each: (1) establish a program to provide guarantees of loans by private institutions to develop and optimize commercially and technologically viable biochar production units, to produce, respectively, four and two units for deployment to remote landscapes, and for the construction or acquisition of biochar production facilities, provided the loan applicants will be dedicated primarily to contract restoration work with the Bureau of Land Management, National Park Service, or Forest Service using pinyon pine and juniper feedstock in the Great Basin, tamarisk feedstock in the Mojave Desert, or excess biomass feedstock, such as trees killed by bark beetle infestations in the Intermountain West; and (2) initiate three-year programs to employ such biochar production units in pilot applications in various U.S. climates and ecosystems. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide competitive grants to conduct research and analysis: (1) to identify attributes and composition profiles of biochar and bioenergy for various uses; (2) to identify potential uses and markets for biochar and bioenergy; (3) relating to environmental benefits and impacts of biochar and bioenergy use; and (4) regarding potential uses of biochar in landscape restoration.</summary>
</bill>
