<bill session="111" type="s" number="3110" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Broadband Service Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve consumer protection for purchasers of broadband services by requiring consistent use of broadband service terminology by providers, requiring clear and conspicuous disclosure to consumers about the actual broadband speed that may reasonably be expected, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2010--Introduced.
Broadband Service Consumer Protection Act - Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to start a rulemaking to assist consumers: (1) in making realistic assumptions, before they purchase broadband service, about the actual speeds that may reasonably be expected and how those assumptions may be affected by the consumer's hardware, peak service periods, and other factors; and (2) in determining, after they purchase broadband service, whether they are getting the level of broadband service for which they are paying. Requires the FCC, in those regulations, to establish, and revise as needed, technical standards for quantifying broadband service measures of performance and other features.</summary>
</bill>
