<bill session="112" type="h" number="6552" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To continue an advisory committee considering the optimal security, reliability, and interoperability of communications systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400392"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to continue the advisory committee known as the FCC's Communications Security, Reliability, and Interoperability Council. Requires the Council to submit to the FCC and Congress recommendations on how to: (1) promote reliable 9-1-1 services, E9-1-1 services, and Next Generation 9-1-1 services and extend next generation capabilities to other services using abbreviated dialing codes; (2) make broadband networks, Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) systems, and other communications networks more secure, resilient, and defendable against Internet-based attacks; (3) leverage advanced technologies and the Internet to distribute emergency alerts and warnings to the public; and (4) improve priority services programs related to national security and emergency preparedness, including Government Emergency Telecommunications Service, Telecommunications Service Priority, and Wireless Priority Service. Directs the Council to include with such recommendations a summary of the greatest and growing threats to the security of communications networks and an itemization of any statutory or regulatory obstacles. Prohibits this Act from being construed as a grant of authority to the FCC to adopt rules or regulations imposing binding obligations on businesses or consumers.</summary>
</bill>
