<bill session="110" type="s" number="1700" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Nuclear Fuel for Peace and Nonproliferation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support the establishment of an international regime for the assured supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means and to authorize voluntary contributions to the International Atomic Energy Agency to support the establishment of an international nuclear fuel bank.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300021"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="885"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Netherlands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reactor fuel reprocessing"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2007--Introduced.
International Nuclear Fuel for Peace and Nonproliferation Act of 2007 - States that it is U.S. policy to support the establishment of an international regime for the assured supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means under multilateral authority, such as the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA). Authorizes the President to make grant basis contributions to the IAEA for an international nuclear fuel bank to maintain a low-enriched uranium reserve of reactor fuel for eligible countries. Requires the President, prior to making such contributions, to certify to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations that: (1) the IAEA has received specified monetary pledges for the international nuclear fuel bank; (2) the bank will be established in a non-nuclear weapon state under IAEA oversight; and (3) the bank will provide nuclear reactor fuel only to a country that is in full compliance with IAEA and other safeguards, agrees to use the nuclear reactor fuel in accordance with IAEA safeguards, does not operate uranium enrichment or spent-fuel reprocessing facilities, and is not a state sponsor of terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
