<bill session="110" type="h" number="1578" updated="2013-07-19T21:17:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wounded Warriors Joint Health Care Performance Metrics and Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish and monitor medical holdover performance standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2007-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1577"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1579"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2007--Introduced.
Wounded Warriors Joint Health Care Performance Metrics and Transparency Act - Assigns the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs responsibility for establishing performance standards for each step of the medical holdover patient process. Defines "medical holdover patient" as a member of the Armed Forces, including a member of the National Guard or other reserve component, who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, or who is otherwise in medical hold or holdover status, for an injury, illness, or disease incurred or aggravated while on active duty.Directs the Secretary of Defense to require each military medical installation to perform a quarterly inspection based on the performance standards established by this Act. Requires the Assistant Secretary to provide reports on such inspections to the Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, and other military officials. Requires the Assistant Secretary to develop and enforce standards for: (1) security and medical personnel to perform daily rounds of each medical inpatient and outpatient facility, including a requirement for 24-hour access for patients with medical emergencies or needs; (2) responding to patient questions and scheduling medical appointments; and (3) in-processing and out-processing, counseling, and information for patients and family members. Requires the Assistant Secretary to: (1) submit monthly reports to the Secretary and the Inspector General on military service performance in all categories of medical holdover patient care; and (2) meet semi-annually with the Secretaries of the military departments to address medical holdover program execution issues.Requires the Inspector General to audit and review the medical holdover system and the performance standards developed by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
