<bill session="113" type="h" number="1625" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Tar Sealants Reduction Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit the manufacture, processing, distribution in commerce, and use of coal tar sealants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2013-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2013--Introduced.
Coal Tar Sealants Reduction Act of 2013 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) to prohibit any person from: (1) manufacturing any coal tar sealant beginning one year after this Act's enactment, (2) processing or distributing in commerce any such sealant beginning one and one-half years after such enactment, or (3) using any such sealant beginning two and one-half years after such enactment. Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate rules to prescribe methods for the transportation, storage, and disposal of such sealants. Defines "coal tar sealant" to mean any product intended for use on a paved surface that contains any substance identified by the Chemical Abstracts Service number 65996-93-2, including ingredients listed as coal tar, refined coal tar, refined tar, or refined coal tar pitch.</summary>
</bill>
