<bill session="109" type="s" number="1984" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intellectual Property Rights Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to safeguard the national security and economic health of the United States by improving the management, coordination, and effectiveness of domestic and international intellectual property rights enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300006"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2005-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2005--Introduced.
Intellectual Property Rights Enforcement Act - Establishes the Intellectual Property Enforcement Network, consisting of specified representatives of various government agencies, to: (1) establish policies, objectives, and priorities concerning international intellectual property protection and law enforcement; (2) protect U.S. intellectual property rights overseas, including by creating an international task force; and (3) coordinate and oversee implementation of such policies, objectives, and priorities by relevant agencies. Requires the Deputy Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) to: (1) provide information to members and employees of the Network with appropriate security clearance; and (2) assign CIA employees to work on achieving suchpolicies, objectives, and priorities. Requires the agencies in the Network to: (1) share the information they collect; (2) coordinate civil and criminal actions related to intellectual property rights; (3) establish formal processes for working with state and local government agencies and consulting with companies, labor unions, writers, artists, and other interested persons and groups; and (4) consult with the Register of Copyrights on law enforcement matters. Urges the President and relevant agency officers, when meeting with certain foreign countries, to stress the importance of establishing and participating in the international task force. Calls for other government intellectual property initiatives to be consolidated into the work of the Network to prevent duplication. Amends the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2000 to repeal provisions establishing the National Intellectual Property Law Enforcement Coordination Council.</summary>
</bill>
