<bill session="113" type="s" number="491" updated="2013-11-02T06:56:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brownfields Utilization, Investment, and Local Development Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to modify provisions relating to grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2896"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2896"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2013--Introduced.
Brownfields Utilization, Investment, and Local Development Act of 2013 or the BUILD Act - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to include among entities eligible for brownfields revitalization funding: (1) a tax-exempt charitable organization, (2) a limited liability corporation in which all managing members are tax-exempt charitable organizations or limited liability corporations whose sole members are such organizations, (3) a limited partnership in which all general partners are tax-exempt charitable organizations or limited liability corporations whose sole members are such organizations, or (4) a qualified community development entity. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program to provide multipurpose grants to carry out inventory, characterization, assessment, planning, or remediation activities at brownfield sites in a proposed area. Revises the brownfield site characterization and assessment grant program to authorize an eligible entity that is a governmental entity to receive a grant for property acquired by such governmental entity prior to January 11, 2002, even if the governmental entity does not qualify as a bona fide prospective purchaser as defined under such Act. Increases the maximum amount the President may give in grants and loans to eligible entities for brownfield remediation. Repeals prohibitions on giving grants and loans for brownfields revitalization for administrative costs and the cost of complying with federal law. Excludes from the meaning of "administrative costs" costs for investigating and identifying the extent of the contamination, designing and performing a response action, or monitoring a natural resource. Requires the Administrator to give priority to small communities, Indian tribes, rural areas, or low-income areas with a population of not more than 15,000 in providing assistance to facilitate the inventory of brownfield sites, site assessments, remediation of brownfield sites, community involvement, or site preparation. Requires the Administrator, in giving grants for brownfields revitalization, to give consideration to waterfront brownfield sites. Requires the Administrator to establish a program to provide grants to: (1) carry out inventory, characterization, assessment, planning, feasibility analysis, design, or remediation activities to locate a clean energy project at brownfield sites; and (2) capitalize a revolving loan fund for such purposes. Authorizes the Administrator to provide grants for state response programs. Extends the authorizations of appropriations for brownfields revitalization funding and state response programs.</summary>
</bill>
