<bill session="110" type="s" number="3185" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevent Unfair Manipulation of Prices Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for regulation of certain transactions involving energy commodities, to strengthen the enforcement authorities of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under the Natural Gas Act and the Federal Power Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6330"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Propane"/>
    <term name="Swaps (Finance)"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2008--Introduced.
Prevent Unfair Manipulation of Prices Act of 2008 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act (CEA) to extend the regulatory authority of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to certain transactions in derivatives involving specified energy commodities ("included energy transactions"), including those on foreign boards of trade.Defines "included energy transaction" as a contract, agreement, or transaction in an energy commodity for future delivery that: (1) provides for a delivery point in the United States; or (2) is transacted on a computer terminal located in the United States.Prohibits the CFTC from exempting from regulation any "included energy transaction" unless certain notice to Congress and public comment requirements are met. Declares null and void any CFTC "no-action letter" exemptions from CEA requirements for "included energy transactions."Requires the CFTC to establish uniform limits on the aggregate number of positions with respect to "included energy transactions" which may be held by any person for the prompt month, for each month, and for all months in all markets subject to CFTC jurisdiction.Excludes swaps involving "included energy transactions" from any CEA exemption for bona fide hedging transactions.Defines "bilateral included energy transaction" as an included energy transaction executed or traded other than on or through a trading facility. Exempts such transactions from the requirement that transactions be made on or through a designated contract market. Applies to "bilateral included energy transactions" certain reporting and recordkeeping requirements.Instructs the CFTC to publish monthly on its website: (1) the aggregate number and value of long and short positions held by a person in any portfolio constructed to match or track the components of an index of all commodities; and (2) the portion of the positions that are net long positions in "included energy transactions."Amends the Natural Gas Act and the Federal Power Act to set forth enforcement powers of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), including cease-and-desist proceedings, temporary orders, and general implementation authority.</summary>
</bill>
