<bill session="109" type="s" number="1928" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SMART Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spending Money Accountably to Rebuild After Tragedy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce mandatory and discretionary spending in order to offset the cost of rebuilding the Gulf Region in the wake of Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bikeways"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Magnetic levitation vehicles"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terminals (Transportation)"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Walking"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2005--Introduced.
Spending Money Accountably to Rebuild After Tragedy Act or SMART Act - Provides a 5% rescission in the: (1) budget authority provided (or obligation limitation imposed) for FY2006 for each discretionary account in each FY2006 appropriations Act (except any FY2005 supplemental appropriation Act, the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006, and the Department of Defense Appropriations Act); (2) budget authority provided in any advance appropriation for FY2006 for such account in any prior fiscal year appropriations Act; and (3) contract authority provided in FY2006 for any program subject to a limitation contained in this joint resolution. Permits the President to except certain programs, projects and accounts, in whole or in part, from such rescission; provided however, that such exceptions do not, in the aggregate, exceed 1% of the overall amount rescinded. Prohibits the FY2006 cost of living adjustments in the statutory pay system of federal employees. Allows such adjustment for federal law enforcement officers. Provides for a two-year: (1) delay of implementation of the Medicare part D prescription drug benefit under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA); and (2) extension of the Medicare prescription drug discount card and the transitional assistance program. Increases the transitional assistance for such period. Amends SSA to accelerate the income-related reduction in Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance Benefits for Aged and Disabled) premium subsidy. Repeals the authorization for funding for high priority projects programs provided in the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU). Rescinds any such unobligated balances as well as other unobligated balances of funds authorized by SAFETEA-LU for specified programs. Reduces the obligation ceiling for: (1) federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs, with specified exceptions; and (2) contract authority for certain transportation research programs. Rescinds any unused obligation limitation for certain high priority projects. Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies Act - Establishes the Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies to: (1) evaluate executive agencies and their programs; and (2) submit to Congress a plan recommending any realignments or eliminations.</summary>
</bill>
