<bill session="112" type="s" number="2373" updated="2013-07-20T02:37:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SEC Regulatory Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the consideration by the Securities and Exchange Commission of the costs and benefits of its regulations and orders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2308"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4078"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2012--Introduced.
SEC Regulatory Accountability Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), before promulgating a regulation or issuing any order, to: (1) identify the nature and significance of the problem that the proposed regulation is designed to address in order to assess whether any new regulation is warranted; (2) use the Office of the Chief Economist to assess the costs and benefits of the intended regulation and adopt it only on a determination that its benefits justify the costs; (3) ensure that any regulation is accessible, consistent, written in plain language, and easy to understand; and (4) measure and seek to improve the actual results of regulatory requirements. Directs the SEC to review its regulations and orders periodically to determine their efficacy and whether to modify or repeal them.</summary>
</bill>
