<bill session="113" type="s" number="979" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drunk Driving Repeat Offender Prevention Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code, to condition the receipt of certain highway funding by States on the enactment and enforcement by States of certain laws to prevent repeat intoxicated driving.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1665"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2013--Introduced.
Drunk Driving Repeat Offender Prevention Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to withhold specified graduated percentages of a state's apportionment of certain federal-aid highway funds for FY2015-FY2017 if the state has not enacted and is not enforcing a law requiring the installation of an ignition interlock device for a minimum of 180 days on each motor vehicle operated by an individual convicted of driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence. Defines "driving while intoxicated" and "driving under the influence" as driving or being in actual physical control of a motor vehicle while having a blood alcohol concentration greater than or equal to the lesser of: (1) the blood alcohol concentration limit of the state in which the individual is driving; or (2) 0.08%. Requires an ignition interlock device to: (1) require a driver to provide a breath sample before the motor vehicle starts, and (2) prevent a motor vehicle from starting if the alcohol concentration of the driver is above the legal limit.</summary>
</bill>
