<bill session="111" type="h" number="2550" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Municipal Advisers Regulation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require the registration of municipal financial advisers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Municipal Advisers Regulation Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to make it unlawful for a person not associated with a municipal financial adviser to make use of the mails or means of interstate commerce to act as a municipal financial adviser unless such person is registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) as a municipal financial adviser in accordance with this Act. Defines "municipal financial adviser" as a person who, for compensation, engages in the business of: (1) providing advice to a municipal securities issuer with respect to issuance of securities, investment of proceeds from such securities, the hedging of risks associated with such securities, or preparation of disclosure documents; (2) assisting a municipal securities issuer in selecting or negotiating guaranteed investment contracts or other investment products; or (3) assisting a municipal securities issuer in the primary offering of securities not involving a public offering. Provides requirements concerning sanctions (including revocation of registration), fair practices, compliance with standards of operational capability, and the fiduciary duty of such an adviser.</summary>
</bill>
