<bill session="112" type="s" number="1197" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a feasibility study before carrying out any Federal action relating to the Chicago Area Water System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402675"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Chief of Engineers, prior to any major federal action to prevent the introduction or establishment of a population of aquatic nuisance species between the Great Lakes and the Mississippi River Basins that would impact the flow of commerce or commercial activity within the Chicago Area Water [sic] System, to prepare an economic impact statement regarding: (1) the impact on commerce and commercial activity and on jobs and job opportunities; (2) any adverse economic effects that could not be avoided; (3) alternatives to the proposed action; (4) the relationship between any local short-term impacts on commerce or commercial activity and maintenance and enhancement of long-term productivity and environmental values; and (5) any adverse impacts to public or private property, including damage relating to flooding or new water drainage patterns. Allows such statement to be combined with a detailed statement of environmental impacts required to be prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
</bill>
