<bill session="113" type="h" number="278" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John Tanner Fairness and Independence in Redistricting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit States from carrying out more than one Congressional redistricting after a decennial census and apportionment, to require States to conduct such redistricting through independent commissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2013-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution And Civil Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="223"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="337"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2490"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2758"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2978"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political representation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2013--Introduced.
John Tanner Fairness and Independence in Redistricting Act - Prohibits a state that has been redistricted after an apportionment from being redistricted again until after the next apportionment of Representatives, unless the state is ordered by a court to conduct such a subsequent redistricting in order to: (1) comply with the U.S. Constitution, or (2) enforce the Voting Rights Act of 1965. Requires such redistricting to be conducted through a plan developed by the independent redistricting commission established in the state, or if such plan is not enacted into law, the redistricting plan selected by the state's highest court or developed by a U.S. district court. Prescribes requirements for: (1) establishment of a state independent redistricting commission (including provisions for holding each of its meetings in public and maintaining a public Internet site); (2) development of a redistricting plan (including soliciting and considering public comments) and its submission to the state legislature (with public notice of plans at least seven days prior to such submission); (3) selection of a plan, under specified conditions, by the state's highest court or the U.S. district court for the district in which the capital of the state is located; (4) special rules for redistricting conducted under a federal court order; and (5) Election Assistance Commission payments to states for carrying out redistricting.</summary>
</bill>
