<bill session="111" type="h" number="6124" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Control for Energy and Environment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend certain provisions of the Natural Gas Act relating to exportation or importation of natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2010--Introduced.
Local Control for Energy and Environment Act - Amends the Natural Gas Act and the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal federal regulatory oversight over: (1) companies engaged in the importation or exportation of natural gas in foreign commerce; and (2) the persons engaged in such importation or exportation. Repeals: (1) the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to approve or deny applications for the siting, construction, expansion, or operations of liquid natural gas (LNG) terminals; (2) the requirement that FERC enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Defense (DOD) ensuring FERC coordination with DOD regarding the siting, construction, expansion or operation of LNG facilities that may affect an active military installation; and (3) the oversight functions of both FERC and the states concerning state and local safety considerations over LNG terminal construction. Requires any agency agreements, collaborations, or activities entered into by FERC concerning the environmental impact, public safety, or security of an LNG facility to: (1) include input by and consultation with the state in which such facility is located; and (2) make available to the public in print and on an Internet website reports and documents generated from such agreements, collaborations, and activities.</summary>
</bill>
