<bill session="112" type="hj" number="48" updated="2013-07-20T02:08:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Additional Continuing Appropriations Amendments, 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Additional Continuing Appropriations Amendments, 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Additional Continuing Appropriations Amendments, 2011</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Additional Continuing Appropriations Amendments, 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2011, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-14T18:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 167 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 48 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 167 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 167.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1811-1825" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 48 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1823" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Critz moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1823-1824" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1823" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Critz motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to prohibit use of funds in the joint resolution to develop or implement a system that cuts Social Security benefits, or that privatizes Social Security, or to develop or implement a system that cuts Medicare benefits, eliminates guaranteed health coverage for seniors, or establishes a Medicare voucher plan that limits payments to beneficiaries in order to purchase health care in the private sector.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1824" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 190 - 239 (Roll no. 178).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-03-15T15:31:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="179" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 271 - 158 (Roll no. 179).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1811-1814" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-03-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="20">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 20.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1788-1800" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2011-03-17" how="roll" result="pass" roll="44" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 87 - 13. Record Vote Number: 44.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-03-18">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-03-18" type="public" number="112-6">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-6.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Corporation for Public Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Ireland"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Northern Ireland"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2011--Public Law.
Additional Continuing Appropriations Amendments, 2011 - Amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2011 (CAA of 2011) (P.L. 111-242) to extend through April 8, 2011, specified continuing appropriations for FY2011. Provides funding at a specified rate of operations for certain agricultural, conservation, and rural development programs. Eliminates specified funding for: (1) the Agricultural Research Service, (2) the Natural Resources Conservation Service, (3) the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, (4) the Federal Payment to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia, (5) the International Fund for Ireland, (6) the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Brownfields Redevelopment, and (7) the Federal Railroad Administration. Eliminates specified funds made available in the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010 for: (1) a certain grant to the National Center for Natural Products Research; (2) an agricultural pest facility in Hawaii; (3) the Congressional Hunger Fellows Program; (4) grants to the Wisconsin Department of Agriculture, Trade, and Consumer Protection, to the Vermont Agency of Agriculture, Foods, and Markets, and to the Wisconsin Department of Agriculture, Trade and Consumer Protection; (5) development of a prototype for a national carbon inventory and accounting system for forestry and agriculture; (6) the International Food Protection Training Institute; and (7) the Center for Foodborne Illness Research and Prevention. Provides funds at a specified rate of operations for: (1) the Departments of Commerce, of Justice (DOJ), of the Interior, of Agriculture, of Labor, of Health and Human Services (HHS); (2) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); (3) the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA); (4) the Corporation for Public Broadcasting; (5) the House of Representatives for salaries and expenses, including those for officers and employees; and (6) Library of Congress salaries and expenses. Prohibits the use of certain funding made available in the CAA of 2011 for operations of: (1) the Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission; or (2) the Durham Museum in Omaha, Nebraska. Rescinds specified funds made available for the Bureau of the Census. Rescinds specified unobligated balances available for the Emergency Steel, Oil, and Gas Guaranteed Loan Program Account. Provides funds at a specified rate for operations for the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund Program Account. Provides funds at a specified rate for operations for the Office of National Drug Control Policy. Provides funding at a specified rate for operations for the General Services Administration (GSA), and the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA). Eliminates funding for GSA construction and acquisition. Eliminates additional amounts made available in the CAA of 2010 for the Small Business Administration (SBA), salaries and expenses. Rescinds specified unobligated balances available for the U.S. Customs and Border Protection. Eliminates funding for any project under the Preserve America Program in the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009. Rescinds specified unobligated funds appropriated for the National Park Service. Bars the use of funds provided for EPA Geographic Programs. Eliminates certain funds for EPA competitive grants to communities to develop plans and demonstrate and implement projects which reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Rescinds specified unobligated balances available to the Forest Service for wildland fire management. Eliminates funding to the Department of the Navy for clean-up activities at the Treasure Island Naval Station, Hunters Point Annex. Rescinds specified funds appropriated to the Social Security Administration (SSA) for investment in information technology and telecommunications hardware and software infrastructure. Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibition against the use of funds appropriated by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
