<bill session="109" type="s" number="138" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SBA Microenterprise Improvements Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make improvements to the microenterprise programs administered by the Small Business Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S351-353"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S355-356" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
SBA Microenterprise Improvements Act - Amends the Small Business Act to revise the Small Business Administration's (SBA's) microloan program (a program under which SBA loans and grants are made to intermediaries, who then make loans to small businesses and provide to borrowers technical assistance, such as managerial and strategic advice) to: (1) revise eligibility requirements for microloan intermediaries; (2) increase from $7,500 to $10,000 the microloan small loan limit; (3) increase from 25 to 30 the percentage of a microloan grant that an intermediary may use to contract-out the provision of technical assistance by a third party; (4) remove the requirement that intermediaries make only short-term loans to small businesses; (5) require an annual report from the SBA to Congress on microloan amounts transferred to cover administrative expenses of technical assistance grants; (6) require the Administrator to develop a subsidy microloan program model that is more accurate than the current model; and (7) increase from 25 to 30 the percentage of technical assistance that an intermediary may provide to potential (rather than actual) borrowers. Amends the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 to revise the Program for Investment in Microentrepreneurs (PRIME), a program to provide SBA assistance for the benefit of disadvantaged entrepreneurs through grants to qualified organizations. Authorizes a qualified organization to use grants to provide training and technical assistance to disadvantaged Native American entrepreneurs and prospective entrepreneurs. Requires each organization receiving assistance under PRIME to: (1) submit an annual activities report to the SBA; and (2) collect data on individuals counseled or trained and related information. Extends through FY 2007 the authorization of appropriations for PRIME.</summary>
</bill>
