<bill session="109" type="s" number="3511" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to extend for 5 years the Mark-to-Market program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2006-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-1052.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5527"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2006--Introduced.
Mark-to-Market Extension Act of 2006 - Amends the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997 to reauthorize through FY2011: (1) the Federal Housing Administration (FHA)-insured MultifamilyHousing Mortgage and Housing Assistance Restructuring (Mark-to-Market) program; and (2) the Office of Multifamily Housing Assistance Restructuring. Permits the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to waive rent level limits for: (1) disaster-damaged eligible projects; and (2) up to 9% (currently 5%) of all units subject to restructured mortgages in any fiscal year, based on certain findings of special need. Redefines eligible multifamily housing project to include properties worthy of cost-effective preservation even though their rents fall below a level otherwise authorized that, on an average per unit or per room basis, exceeds the rent of comparable properties in the same market area. Requires each mortgage restructuring and rental assistance sufficiency plan to determine, for units assisted with project-based assistance in eligible multifamily housing projects, adjusted rent levels for disaster-damaged eligible projects equal to 100% of the fair market rents for the relevant market area. Revises requirements for an approved mortgage restructuring and rental assistance sufficiency plan with respect to modification or forgiveness of all or part of a second mortgage held by the Secretary (debt relief) if the project concerned is acquired by a tenant organization or tenant-endorsed community-based nonprofit or public agency. Sets forth requirements for alternative periods of eligibility for such nonprofit debt relief if the purchaser acquires the project subsequent to the date of recordation of the related affordability agreement.</summary>
</bill>
