<bill session="109" type="s" number="1854" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Price Gouging bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Treat Emergency Victims Fairly Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit price gouging for commodities and services sold during national emergency situations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/7/2005 S11237" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Introduced.
Treat Emergency Victims Fairly Act of 2005 - Declares it is unlawful for any seller of goods or services of any type (including food, transportation, housing, and energy supplies) to engage in price gouging, that is, the charging of an unreasonable and unconscionable price for such a good or service immediately before, during, or after a natural disaster or other emergency formally declared by federal or state authorities. Permits the federal government, through the Attorney General, or a state government acting through its attorney general, to bring an action in federal or state court to enforce this Act. Requires an action that is brought under this Act in federal court to receive expedited review. Permits the Attorney General of the United States and a state attorney general, respectively, to recover restitution or disgorgement of excess profits. States that this Act does not preempt or otherwise affect any state or local law.</summary>
</bill>
