<bill session="111" type="s" number="3291" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coltsville National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish Coltsville National Historical Park in the State of Connecticut, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2808"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5131"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2010--Introduced.
Coltsville National Historical Park Act - Establishes the Coltsville National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park Service (NPS) in Connecticut. Requires such Park to provide interpretation and viewing of specified sites, including the East Armory and Colt Park. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a written arrangement with the Connecticut State Library, Wadsworth Atheneum, and the Colt Trust, or other public entities, as appropriate, to gain access to Colt-related artifacts to have them on display in the East Armory or within the Park. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the owners of any properties within the Coltsville Historic District or any national significant properties within the Park under which the Secretary may identify, interpret, restore and provide technical assistance for the preservation of such properties. Requires any federal funds under such an agreement to be matched on a one-to-one basis by non-federal funds. Permits the acquisition of lands or interests owned by the state or any political subdivision of the state by donation only. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance and public interpretation of related historic and cultural resources within the Historic District. Requires the Secretary to complete a management plan for the Park, with the advice of the Coltsville National Historical Park Advisory Commission established by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
