<bill session="110" type="h" number="3156" updated="2013-07-19T21:31:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Violent Crime Control Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Controlled Substances Analogue Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Death Penalty Procedures Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Gang Deterrence and Community Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Proceeds of Crime Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To control violent crime.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412190" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1860"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2007--Introduced.
Violent Crime Control Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to increase or impose new criminal penalties for: (1) the use of firearms to commit a crime of violence or a drug trafficking crime; (2) interstate transportation in aid of racketeering; (3) using interstate facilities to commit murder-for-hire and other violent crimes; and (4) violent crimes and drug crimes committed by illegal aliens.Extends the limitation period for prosecuting violent crimes and crimes of terrorism. Death Penalty Procedures Improvement Act of 2007 - Revises death penalty hearing procedures and provisions for the implementation of the death sentence.Imposes a minimum mandatory prison term for possession of child pornography. Increases criminal penalties for sexual exploitation of children and child pornography.Proceeds of Crime Act of 2007 - Expands criminal forfeiture provisions to include certain crimes involving terrorism, fraud and computer crimes, alien smuggling, food stamp fraud, intellectual property theft, contraband cigarettes, and trafficking in persons. Expands prohibitions against money laundering activities. Revises civil forfeiture provisions.Controlled Substances Analogue Reform Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to redefine "controlled substance analogue" for purposes of criminal prohibitions against trafficking in certain substances whose chemical structures are substantially similar to substances in schedule I or II of such Act.Imposes mandatory restitution for victims of violent crime.Imposes or increases criminal penalties for certain crimes of terrorism, including providing material support to facilitate, reward, or encourage international acts of terrorism, attempts or conspiracies to obtain military-type training from a foreign terrorism organization, and terrorist offenses resulting in death. Authorizes the death penalty for certain terrorist offenses involving weapons of mass destruction.Gang Deterrence and Community Protection Act of 2007 - Revises criminal penalties for and definitions relating to crimes committed by criminal street gangs, including interstate travel in aid of racketeering, murder for hire, drug trafficking, use of firearms in committing violent crimes, and use of interstate commerce facilities to commit multiple murder.Amends: (1) the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act (RICO) to expand the definition of "racketeering activity" to include interstate murder; and (2) the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize the use of community-based justice grants to hire additional prosecutors to reduce case backlogs and to assist in the accurate identification and successful prosecution of young violent offenders.Authorizes the Attorney General to designate specific areas that are located within one or more states as high intensity interstate gang activity areas.</summary>
</bill>
