<bill session="113" type="h" number="2124" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping the Promise of IRCA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve worksite enforcement, prevent crime, and gain operational control of the borders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400628"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, Ways and Means, Armed Services, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Keeping the Promise of IRCA Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require an employer to attest, during the verification period and under penalty of perjury, that the employer has verified that an individual is not an unauthorized alien by: (1) obtaining and recording the individual's social security account number, and (2) examining specified documents that establish such individual's identity and employment authorization. Requires an individual to attest that he or she is a U.S. citizen or national, a lawful permanent resident, or an alien authorized to work in the United States. Subjects an individual who knowingly uses the social security number or other identification of another person to criminal penalties. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) (Secretary) to establish an employment eligibility verification system (EEVS), patterned after the E-Verify system. (Eliminates the current paper-based I-9 system.) Sets forth EEVS responsibilities of the Commissioner of Social Security (SSA) and the Secretary. Establishes a phased-in EEVS participation deadline (six months to two years) for different categories of employers. Directs the Secretary to work with the states to establish a common data set and data exchange protocol for electronic birth and death registration systems. Directs the Secretary to check against all available terrorist watch lists those alien smugglers and smuggled individuals who are interdicted at U.S. land, air, and sea borders. Revises alien smuggling and related criminal offense and penalty provisions. Provides extraterritorial jurisdiction over such offenses. Limits a defense of necessity for knowingly bringing an illegal alien into the United States from the high seas. Exempts from certain of such violations a bona fide nonprofit, religious organization in the United States that enables an alien who is present in the United States to serve as a volunteer minister or missionary for such organization in the United States. Prohibits a state or local government from receiving criminal alien assistance program (SCAAP) assistance if it is not in compliance with the prohibition of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 against any restriction by a government entity or official of communications by any other government entity or official with a federal immigration agency involving information about an individual's citizenship or immigration status. Grants specified arrest and weapons authority to Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) enforcement agents and deportation officers who have completed immigration enforcement training. Authorizes the Secretary to hire 2,500 ICE detention enforcement officers. Directs the Secretary to: (1) hire additional ICE deportation enforcement officers and support personnel; (2) assist state or local gang or drug task forces if requested; (3) assist federal, state, and county prisons or jails; (4) increase ICE detention capacity; (5) hire additional ICE prosecutors; and (6) establish a pilot program to allow deportation officers and immigration enforcement agents to electronically process and serve charging documents and place detainers while in the field. Requires immigration officers who encounter illegal aliens with specified criminal convictions, gang affiliations, or who pose a risk to public safety or national security to process such aliens and refer them for removal proceedings by issuing a Notice to Appear. Amends the the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) prohibit issuance of visas to citizens, subjects, nationals, or residents of a country listed in the most recent quarterly delayed repatriation report until the Secretary notifies the Secretary of State that the country is no longer listed, or each alien listed in the report with respect to such country has been removed from the United States; and (2) deny entrance to visa holders who are citizens, subjects, nationals, or residents, of such a country. Directs the Attorney General (DOJ) to create and fill 20 additional immigration judgeships. Establishes an ICE Advisory Council. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop the biometric automated entry and exit control system within two years; and (2) establish biometric exit pilot programs at a minimum of 10 land ports of entry, including at least two each in California, Arizona, New Mexico, and Texas, and at least two on the U.S.-Canada border. Requires DHS to assess the effectiveness of border enforcement strategies and tools by using the metric of operational control. (Defines operational control as the prevention of all unlawful U.S. entries, including entries by terrorists, other unlawful aliens, instruments of terrorism, narcotics, and other contraband.) Directs the Secretary to develop a national strategy to secure the borders that describes actions to be carried out to achieve operational control over all U.S. ports of entry and the U.S. international land and maritime borders by December 31, 2015. Provides for border technology improvement through equipment sharing with the Department of Defense (DOD). Requires that ICE and U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) personnel be provided with adequate equipment to ensure their safety.</summary>
</bill>
