<bill session="113" type="s" number="196" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assure equity in contracting between the Federal Government and small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2013--Introduced.
Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2013 - Increases from: (1) 23% to 25% the government-wide small business procurement contract goal, and (2) 5% to 10% the government-wide procurement goal for small disadvantaged businesses and women-owned businesses. Limits the number of categories for which a small business may qualify under such goals. Requires, for purposes of such goals, the total value of all prime contracts for a fiscal year to include the value of each contract awarded, regardless of whether it was awarded as the result of unrestricted competition or any determination by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) with respect to the potential for a small business to perform the contract or a subcontract. Directs the Administrator to consult with the heads of other federal agencies to develop and implement standards for procurement officers to take into consideration the past compliance of potential contractors with small business subcontracting goals when making contract awards.</summary>
</bill>
