<bill session="111" type="s" number="3906" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PREEMIE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prematurity Research Expansion and Education for Mothers who deliver Infants Early Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce preterm labor and delivery and the risk of pregnancy-related deaths and complications due to pregnancy, and to reduce infant mortality caused by prematurity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2010-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2010-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7809"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Prematurity Research Expansion and Education for Mothers who deliver Infants Early Act or the PREEMIE Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of NIH with respect to research on the causes&#160;and prevention of preterm labor and delivery and the care and treatment of preterm infants; (2) establish within NIH a multicenter clinical program and trans-disciplinary&#160;centers for prematurity research;&#160;(3) require the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to conduct research, activities, and studies on preterm birth; and (4) require the CDC to award grants for telemedicine demonstration projects for services for high risk pregnancies. Directs the Secretary to: (1)&#160;establish and implement a national science-based consumer education campaign on the prevention of preterm birth; and (2) conduct and report on research studies and demonstration projects for reducing the rate of preterm birth. Requires the Advisory Committee on Infant Mortality of HHS to report annually to the Secretary on a strategic plan for the conduct of preterm birth-related research.</summary>
</bill>
