<bill session="113" type="s" number="52" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Efficiency and Savings in Government Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the energy and water efficiency of Federal buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Promoting Efficiency and Savings in Government Act - Requires each energy manager of a building owned by the General Services Administration (GSA) to carry out an audit of that building that: (1) identifies any modification necessary to improve energy efficiency that, within 10 years of implementation, will result in energy cost savings equal to the total investment made; and (2) quantifies the estimated cost-savings associated with any identified efficiency improvements. Requires the Administrator of GSA to report on all efficiency improvements identified in the audit, the total estimated cost-savings associated with the efficiency improvements, and the status of implementation of the efficiency improvements. Requires each lease of a building or space entered into by a federal department or agency to include: (1) a maximum energy intensity standard; (2) a lighting efficiency requirement, accounting for appropriate task lighting; and (3) an incentive structure that allows a department or agency leasing the building or space and the building owner to share the financial savings of efficiency investments and efficient operating practices. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to require the Federal Director of the Office of Federal High-Performance Green Buildings to include in the report to Congress a summary of the energy and water use of federal buildings.</summary>
</bill>
