<bill session="111" type="s" number="3590" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carbon Capture and Sequestration Deployment Revenue Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide financial incentives to facilitate the development and early deployment of carbon capture and sequestration technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2010-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3589"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3591"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2010--Introduced.
Carbon Capture and Sequestration Deployment Revenue Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) expand the tax credit for carbon dioxide sequestration to include carbon dioxide that is converted to a stable form in which it is securely and permanently sequestered; (2) allow a 30% increase in the qualifying advanced coal project tax credit for the incremental cost of carbon capture and sequestration systems; (3) allow an increase in the carbon dioxide sequestration tax credit for the use of new or retrofit electric utility or industrial units to provide for carbon capture and sequestration in secure geologic storage; and (4) allow issuers of qualified carbon sequestration bonds income and excise tax credits for payments of interest with respect to such bonds. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to provide additional funding for loan guarantees for: (1) constructing or retrofitting new or existing commercial scale electric generation units or industrial facility units for carbon capture and sequestration; and (2) constructing carbon dioxide transmission pipelines to transport carbon dioxide to sequestration sites or to sites where carbon dioxide will be used for hydrocarbon recovery.</summary>
</bill>
