<bill session="110" type="s" number="3313" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Victims of Polygamy Assistance Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Federal Polygamy Task Force, to authorize assistance for victims of polygamy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7156" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Bigamy"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Introduced.
Victims of Polygamy Assistance Act of 2008 - Establishes within the Department of Justice a Federal Polygamy Task Force to strengthen federal law enforcement activities and provide state and local law enforcement officials the assistance they need to address the illegal activity of one or more polygamist organizations. Requires the Federal Polygamy Task Force to: (1) formulate effective responses to the unique set of crimes committed by polygamist organizations; (2) establish partnerships with state and local law enforcement agencies to share relevant information and strengthen state and federal efforts to combat crimes perpetrated by polygamist organizations; (3) assist states by providing strategies and support for the protection of witnesses; (4) track the criminal behavior of polygamist organizations that cross state and international borders; and (5) ensure that local officials charged with protecting the public are not corrupted because of financial, family, or membership ties to a polygamist organization. Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to authorize the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime to make grants to specified entities to develop, establish, and maintain programs for the enforcement of rights and provision of social services for an individual exploited or otherwise victimized by practitioners of polygamy. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide for discretionary grants by the Attorney General to states and local governments to investigate and prosecute polygamist organizations that violate federal, state, or local laws.</summary>
</bill>
