<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1215" updated="2013-07-19T21:01:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the Armed Forces from the Inland Empire in California and their families for their extraordinary sacrifices serving the United States in Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2008--Introduced.
Recognizes that Armed Forces members from the Inland Empire region of southern California, including San Bernardino and Riverside Counties, gave, and continue to give, to our nation. Commits to providing wounded warriors with the highest quality of medical care available, including for their families. Commends Inland Empire citizens and organizations who volunteer to support America's wounded warriors. Encourages Members and citizens to show support and appreciation for returning troops. Honors the sacrifices made by Armed Forces members from the Inland Empire and their families. Understands that the American people are forever grateful to Armed Forces members from the Inland Empire for their service to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
