<bill session="111" type="h" number="5963" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Students Using the Camp Community for Enrichment, Strength, and Success Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting SUCCESS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a grant program to fund pilot projects to explore how the camp experience promotes physical activity and healthy lifestyles among children and youth, reduces summer learning loss, and promotes academic achievement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Promoting Students Using the Camp Community for Enrichment, Strength, and Success Act or the Promoting SUCCESS Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to nonprofit organizations, for-profit organizations, and local educational agencies to carry out summertime learning pilot programs for students during their summers after grades five through nine. Requires such programs to provide students with camp activities geared toward: (1) reducing childhood obesity through increased physical activity and healthy lifestyle choices; (2) strengthening high school graduation rates by reducing summer learning loss and improving academic achievement; and (3) promoting positive youth development. Directs the Secretary to arrange for an independent evaluation of the pilot programs. Requires the Secretary to provide a grant or contract to one or more national nonprofit organizations to collect best practices from among this Act's grantees and provide grantees with training, technical assistance, and professional development.</summary>
</bill>
