<bill session="112" type="s" number="3476" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Access to Child Care for Homeless Families Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to ensure access to high-quality child care for homeless children and families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Introduced.
Improving Access to Child Care for Homeless Families Act of 2012 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) Congress has enacted successful policies to increase homeless children's access to and stability in public elementary and secondary schools and Head Start Programs; (2) in order to increase homeless families' access to and continuity in care, similar policies should be applied to federal child care programs; and (3) such policies will assist homeless parents in maintaining employment and regaining housing, and will provide critical interventions to support that vulnerable population of children. Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require the lead agency to coordinate the provision of services under such Act with social services programs that include: (1) Head Start and Early Head Start programs under the Head Start Act; (2) programs and services of partners that serve vulnerable populations; and (3) programs and services of entities receiving grants to provide homeless veterans with housing, employment-related services, or supportive services. Revises state plan requirements to require consideration of homeless children in the use of funds for child care services and activities. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out a pilot program of grants to states to identify and implement best practices for increasing access to and continuity of child care for homeless children.</summary>
</bill>
