<bill session="112" type="h" number="3566" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness in Foreclosures Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure uniformity and fairness in deficiency judgments arising from foreclosures on mortgages for single family homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2011-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2011--Introduced.
Fairness in Foreclosures Act of 2011 - Declares that no action for a deficiency judgment arising from an obligation under a residential mortgage may be brought except in accordance with this Act. Declares that no such deficiency judgment may be issued unless the court has determined that the foreclosure sale for the property securing repayment was conducted in accordance with specified requirements. Specifies a formula for determining the total amount a plaintiff may recover in such a deficiency judgment. Declares that no action for a deficiency judgment may be brought if the (nonrecourse) mortgage terms prohibit recovery after: (1) the residential property securing repayment of such obligation is sold at foreclosure sale, or (2) the mortgage is foreclosed in the manner provided under the law of the state in which the property is located. Declares that if the mortgagor is a member of a low-income family: (1) no action may be brought for a deficiency judgment; and (2) a deficiency in recovery, from a foreclosure sale, of the full amount of the mortgage obligation may not be reported to any consumer reporting agency or disclosed to any person other than the mortgagor or the mortgagor's personal representative, unless such disclosure is otherwise required by law.</summary>
</bill>
