<bill session="111" type="h" number="5708" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Urban Jobs Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to provide grants to the National Urban League for an Urban Jobs Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Urban Jobs Act of 2010 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to make grants to the National Urban League to operate, through local affiliates, an Urban Jobs Program to provide job training, education, and support services and activities for eligible young adults to prepare them for entry into the workforce. Defines "eligible young adults" as individuals ages 18 to 24 who: (1) are not enrolled in secondary or post-secondary school; or (2) are or have been subject to the criminal justice process. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Jobs Council Advisory Committee. Expresses the sense of Congress that National Urban League affiliates should establish local jobs council advisory committees to aid in establishing local community support for local implementation of the program.</summary>
</bill>
