<bill session="109" type="h" number="4363" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iris Scan Security Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to enable States to include iris scan information from certain convicted criminals in State criminal records systems, to provide for the use of the information by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, and to require Federal firearms dealers to obtain iris scan information from prospective firearms purchasers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2005--Introduced.
Iris Scan Security Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to enable states to: (1) include in state criminal records systems iris scan information obtained from individuals prohibited by federal or state law from possessing or receiving a firearm by reason of having been convicted in state court of a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding one year or a misdemeanor domestic violence crime; and (2) provide such information electronically to the national instant criminal background check (NICS) system. Requires a state grantee to: (1) provide to the NICS system such information from the database as the Attorney General may require; and (2) not disclose any information in the database except for a law enforcement purpose. Directs the Attorney General to prescribe regulations necessary to ensure that the system is equipped to receive iris scan information and to use the information in responding to requests from licensees for information about whether receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate federal or state law. Amends the code to prohibit the transfer of a firearm by a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer to an unlicensed individual unless the licensee performs an iris scan and provides the NICS system electronically with the information obtained from the scan.</summary>
</bill>
