<bill session="111" type="h" number="5060" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education, Achievement, and Opportunity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a refundable credit against income tax for tuition expenses incurred for each qualifying child of the taxpayer in attending public or private elementary or secondary school.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2010--Introduced.
Education, Achievement, and Opportunity Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a refundable tax credit for the qualified education expenses of children attending a public, private, parochial, or religious school providing elementary or secondary education. Defines "qualified education expenses" as amounts paid for tuition and fees, computers, educational software, computer support services, required books, academic tutoring, special needs services for children with disabilities, transportation fees, and academic testing services. Limits the annual amount of such credit to $2,500 for a child enrolled in an elementary school and $3,500 for a child enrolled in a secondary school, and reduces such credit for taxpayers whose modified adjusted gross income exceeds $75,000 ($150,000 in the case of a joint return).</summary>
</bill>
