<bill session="112" type="s" number="3291" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Telephone Billing Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit unauthorized third-party charges on wireline telephone bills, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2012--Introduced.
Fair Telephone Billing Act of 2012 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit local exchange carriers or providers of interconnected VoIP (Voice over Internet Protocol) service from placing a third-party charge that is not directly related to the provision of telephone services on the bill of a customer, unless the third-party charge is: (1) from a certified third-party vendor, (2) for a product or service that the carrier or provider markets or sells jointly with its own service, and (3) consented to and believed to be requested by the customer. Defines a "third-party charge" as a charge for a product or service not provided by a local exchange carrier or a provider of interconnected VoIP service that is included on a bill for the services the local exchange carrier or provider of interconnected VoIP service offers to its customers. Subjects violators to civil forfeiture and specified penalties. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promulgate rules to: (1) ensure that a provider of wireless services gives each customer the means to avoid receiving third-party charges on the wireless customer's wireless bill and discloses such an option clearly and conspicuously, (2) establish procedures for such a provider to ensure that third-party charges have been authorized by the wireless customer; and (3) enable a wireless customer to seek and receive reimbursement from the provider for any unauthorized third-party charges.</summary>
</bill>
