<bill session="109" type="s" number="1962" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to revise certain repayment contracts with the Bostwick Irrigation District in Nebraska, the Kansas Bostwick Irrigation District No. 2, the Frenchman-Cambridge Irrigation District, and the Webster Irrigation District No. 4, all a part of the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2005-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-460.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="4000"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2005--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to revise the repayment contracts with the Bostwick Irrigation District in Nebraska, the Kansas Bostwick Irrigation District No. 2, the Frenchman-Cambridge Irrigation District, and the Webster Irrigation District, by: (1) equalizing the annual total repayment obligation under the contracts for the distribution works construction charge and the water supply repayment obligation for the remaining years of the contracts, relying upon the annual water supply repayment obligation as of the date of this Act's enactment as the base for equalizing the annual total payments; and (2) extending the date for adjusting the annual deposits into the distribution works reserve fund and the district water supply reserve fund for an additional 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
