<bill session="109" type="h" number="4820" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">PORTS bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Port Operations Require Tough Scrutiny (PORTS) Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Defense Production Act of 1950 to strengthen the requirements relating to investigations under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2006-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E225-226"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, International Relations, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Corporate divestiture"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2006--Introduced.
Port Operations Require Tough Scrutiny (PORTS) Act of 2006 - Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 relating to investigations of proposed corporate mergers, acquisitions, or takeovers (transactions) in the United States by a foreign interest which could affect U.S. national security to: (1) extend from 30 to 60 days after notification of the proposed transaction the period in which such investigation must be commenced by the President, if it is determined that there should be an investigation; and (2) allow an extension of such deadline by up to ten additional days if determined appropriate. Requires the investigation of a transaction which could result in foreign control of a person engaged in interstate commerce in the United States that could affect U.S. critical infrastructure. States with respect to certain mandatory investigations that if the President determines that the transaction should be approved or does not otherwise object to the transaction and the President does not suspend or prohibit such transaction, then the President, within 30 days after such decision, shall notify Congress of the decision. Allows Congress 45 days after such notification to enact into law a joint resolution disapproving the decision of the President and requiring the President to prohibit the proposed transaction, or, if the transaction has been completed, directing the Attorney General to seek divestment. Requires annual reports from the President to the congressional homeland security and intelligence committees on actions taken with regard to such investigations. Directs the Commissioner of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) verify on-site the security measures of each individual and entity participating in the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism (C-TPAT) program and the Free And Secure Trade (FAST) program; and (2) establish policies for non-compliance with requirements of the C-TPAT program, including probation and expulsion.</summary>
</bill>
