<bill session="113" type="h" number="1409" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Export Promotion Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to further enhance the promotion of exports of United States goods and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2013--Introduced.
Export Promotion Reform Act - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to require the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC), in assessing the appropriate levels and allocation of resources among agencies in support of export promotion and export financing, to review the proposed annual budget of each agency before the agency submits it to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for inclusion in the budget the President submits to Congress. Requires the President to take necessary steps to grant the TPCC chairperson authority to ensure that the TPCC carries out each of its duties and develops and implements its governmentwide strategic plan for federal trade promotion efforts. Revises the authority of the Secretary of Commerce to establish foreign offices of the United States and Foreign Commercial Service. Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct every five years a global assessment of overseas markets to determine those with the greatest potential for increasing U.S. exports, and (2) deploy Commercial Service personnel and other resources on the basis of the global assessment. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to require the U.S. Foreign Service chief of mission to a foreign country, in promoting U.S. goods and services for export to that country, to do so through the development of a plan, drafted in consultation with the TPCC, for effective diplomacy to remove or reduce obstacles to exports of such goods and services. Requires the precepts for selection boards responsible for recommending promotions into and within the Senior Foreign Service, especially members with economic affairs responsibilities, to emphasize performance which demonstrates the effectiveness of efforts to promote the export of U.S. goods and services in accordance with a commercial diplomacy plan. Requires the inspections, investigations, and audits of the Inspector General of the Department of State to examine the effectiveness of commercial diplomacy relating to the promotion of exports of U.S. goods and services.</summary>
</bill>
