<bill session="112" type="s" number="3545" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Farmer Bankruptcy Tax Clarification Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 11 of the United States Code to clarify the rule allowing discharge as a nonpriority claim of governmental claims arising from the disposition of farm assets under chapter 12 bankruptcies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6342-6343"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6343" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Introduced.
Family Farmer Bankruptcy Tax Clarification Act of 2012 - Amends chapter 12 (Debt Adjustment of a Family Farmer or Fisherman with Regular Annual Income) of federal bankruptcy law to revise the exclusion from the requirement of full payment under a discharged debtor's plan of any claim owed to a governmental unit arising as a result of the sale, transfer, exchange, or other disposition of a farm asset used in the debtor's farming operation (in which case the claim is treated as unsecured and not entitled to priority payment). Requires the debtor's plan to provide for: (1) the treatment as a non-priority unsecured claim of any claim owed to a governmental unit by the debtor or the estate arising as a result of the sale, transfer, exchange, or other disposition of a farm asset; but also (2) the payment of that claim. Repeals the precondition that such treatment may be made only if the debtor receives a discharge in bankruptcy. Authorizes a governmental unit to file postpetition claims relating to the disposition of farm assets. Authorizes the trustee or the debtor, also, to file such postpetition claims (including a claim for a tax for which a return is due) if the governmental unit has not filed by a specified deadline. Authorizes modification of the bankruptcy plan after its confirmation in order to provide for the payment of a non-priority unsecured claim presented by a governmental unit that arose after the petition filing date.</summary>
</bill>
