<bill session="111" type="h" number="5635" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Onondaga Lake Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out activities for the restoration, conservation, and management of Onondaga Lake, New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412297"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6360"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2010--Introduced.
Onondaga Lake Restoration Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish the Onondaga Lake Watershed Council to: (1) develop and periodically revise an Adaptive Management Plan for the restoration, conservation, and management of Onondaga Lake; (2) establish and implement a program for the public's participation in the Plan's development and revision; and (3) establish and direct the Onondaga Lake Scientific Center to advise the Council on development and implementation of the Plan. Requires the Plan to: (1) identify measurable goals for the restoration, conservation, and management of Onondaga Lake and for compliance with all laws affecting the restoration and conservation of the Lake; and (2) incorporate and update the recommendations of the Onondaga Lake Management Plan to recommend strategies for management of the biological makeup of the Lake, the physical development of the Lake and its surroundings, and the use of the Lake for recreational and other purposes. Prohibits the Plan's recommendations from being carried out before it is approved by the Administrator and the governor of New York. Authorizes the Administrator to make funds available to members of the Council and the Center to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Administrator to make grants to specified governmental officials in New York and members of the Center: (1) to implement Plan strategies; (2) for research, surveys, administrative services, and studies; and (3) to gather data in support of litigation undertaken by New York or the Onondaga Nation to compel cleanup or obtain cleanup and damage costs from parties responsible for the pollution of Onondaga Lake. Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1999 to revoke provisions that require the Secretary of the Army to plan and construct projects that are consistent with the Onondaga Lake Management Plan and to provide financial assistance for the development and implementation of projects to restore, conserve, and manage the lake.</summary>
</bill>
