<bill session="111" type="h" number="2111" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Commission on Financial Accountability and Preparedness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Congressional Commission on Financial Accountability and Preparedness to examine and report upon the facts and causes relating to the breakdown in the financial and credit markets in 2008, and investigate and report to the Congress on its findings, conclusions, and recommendations for prosecution of criminal behavior.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2009-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="768"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2009--Introduced.
Congressional Commission on Financial Accountability and Preparedness Act of 2009 - Establishes the Congressional Commission on Financial Accountability and Preparedness to review and report to Congress on the actions leading up to the 2008 breakdown in the financial markets and failures in the regulatory system. Requires the Commission to submit special reports on: (1) any corporate abuse of taxpayer funds the Commission finds occurred; (2) the current state of the regulatory system and its effectiveness in overseeing the participants in the financial system and protecting consumers; and (3) any fiduciary negligence, fraudulent behavior, poor corporate governance, obstructionism, or media manipulation that the Commission determines was engaged in by relevant corporate officers and elected or appointed government officials.</summary>
</bill>
