<bill session="112" type="h" number="6344" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey lands of the former Fort Bayard Military Reservation in Grant County, New Mexico, to the village of Santa Clara, the city of Bayard, or the county of Grant in that State, in tracts of not less than 40 acres, and at market price at its present state of use as agricultural grazing lands as determined by the Secretary, for business and community development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to convey at current state of agricultural use market prices specified lands formerly part of the Fort Bayard Military Reservation, Grant County, New Mexico, to the Village of Santa Clara, the City of Bayard, and Grant County, New Mexico, in tracts of not less than 40 acres, for business and community development. Requires approval of all parties for any such conveyance. Provides that the Secretary shall be responsible for the costs and recovery of any historic or prehistoric cultural properties located on such lands.</summary>
</bill>
