<bill session="112" type="sr" number="454" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Department of Energy hosting the Third International Conference on Nuclear Power Plant Life Management.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2012-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3089" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2012--Introduced.
Commends the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and the Department of Energy (DOE) for hosting the Third International Conference on Nuclear Power Plant Life Management in the United States. Applauds the efforts of conference attendees to discuss and explore the increased role of nuclear power plant life management in support of license renewal and the safe, long-term operation of commercial nuclear reactors throughout the world. Thanks the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) for organizing the Third International Conference on Nuclear Power Plant Life Management in the United States for the first time, and encourages member states of the IAEA to take advantage of the latest available technology to further develop licensing programs, promote safety, and secure the long-term success of commercial nuclear power generation.</summary>
</bill>
