<bill session="112" type="s" number="2001" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rogue Wilderness Area Expansion Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand the Wild Rogue Wilderness Area in the State of Oregon, to make additional wild and scenic river designations in the Rogue River area, to provide additional protections for Rogue River tributaries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8682-8683"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8683-8684" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-642.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3436"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2011--Introduced.
Rogue Wilderness Area Expansion Act of 2011- Adds specified federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in the Wild Rogue Wilderness as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to add specified segments of creeks to the designation of the Rogue River in Oregon as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system. Prohibits: (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from licensing the construction of any dam, conduit, reservoir, powerhouse, transmission line, or other project works affecting specified stream segments; and (2) any federal department or agency from assisting in the construction of any water resources project affecting any such segment, except for maintaining or repairing existing projects.</summary>
</bill>
