<bill session="109" type="s" number="3546" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to serious adverse event reporting for dietary supplements and nonprescription drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2006-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6285-6287"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-05">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Enzi with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-324.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="586">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 586.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-12-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  S11376-11381" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR  S11377-11378" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07T10:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07T22:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Barton (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 H9243-9246" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3546.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:42:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T02:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 H9303-9304" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-12-09T03:06:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="543" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 203 - 98 (Roll no. 543).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 H9243-9245" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T03:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-12-09">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-12-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-12-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-12-22" type="public" number="109-462">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-462.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6168"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Nonprescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2006--Public Law.
Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require a manufacturer, packer, or distributor whose name appears on the label of a nonprescription drug or dietary supplement marketed in the United States to: (1) submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services within 15 business days any report of a serious adverse event associated with use of such drug or supplement in the United States; (2) submit within 15 business days any related medical information that is received within one year of the initial report; (3) maintain records related to each report for six years; and (4) permit inspection of such records. Allows a retailer whose name appears on the label as a distributor to authorize the manufacturer or packer to submit the required reports so long as the retailer directs all reported adverse events to such manufacturer or packer. Requires the Secretary to develop systems to ensure that duplicate reports of a serious adverse event are consolidated. Allows the Secretary to establish an exemption from such reporting that would have no adverse effect on public health. Considers a serious adverse event report to be: (1) a safety report that may be accompanied by a statement, which shall be included in any public disclosure of the report, that denies that the report or the records constitute an admission that the product involved caused or contributed to the adverse event; and (2) a record about an individual and a medical or similar file the disclosure of which violates the Freedom of Information Act unless all personally identifiable information is redacted. Provides that the submission of any adverse event report shall not be construed as an admission that the drug or supplement involved caused or contributed to the adverse event. Prohibits any state or local government from establishing or continuing any requirements related to a mandatory system for adverse event reports for nonprescription drugs or dietary supplements that are not identical to the requirements of this Act. Prohibits the responsible person from: (1) refusing to permit access to any required record; or (2) failing to establish or maintain any record, or make any report, required under this Act. Deems a nonprescription drug or dietary supplement that is marketed in the United States to be misbranded unless its label includes a domestic address or phone number for the reporting of a serious adverse event. (Sec. 4) Prohibits the falsification of a serious adverse event report. (Sec. 5) Prohibits the importation of a drug or supplement subject to this Act if the Secretary has credible information indicating that the responsible person has not complied with the requirements of this Act or has not allowed access to its records.</summary>
</bill>
