<bill session="111" type="s" number="3464" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Practical Energy and Climate Plan Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an energy and climate policy framework to reach measurable gains in reducing dependence on foreign oil, saving Americans money, improving energy security, and cutting greenhouse gas emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2010-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2010--Introduced.
Practical Energy and Climate Plan Act of 2010 - Revises the Corporate Average Fuel Economy (CAFE) standards by requiring at least a 4% annual increase in the average fuel economy level beginning in model year 2017, unless the standards are technologically unachievable, cannot be achieved without materially reducing the overall safety of automobiles, or are not cost effective. Requires the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to: (1) prescribe separate standards for passenger and non-passenger automobiles to achieve a combined fuel economy average of at least 34.1 miles per gallon for model year 2016 (currently 35 miles per gallon for model year 2020) for the total fleet of automobiles manufactured; and (2) determine the greatest achievable fuel efficiency improvement targets for rules pertaining to commercial medium- and heavy-duty vehicles and work trucks. Authorizes the Secretary to implement regulations for vehicle classes and components of such vehicles on an accelerated basis. Requires manufacturers to ensure that 50% of automobiles and light duty trucks manufactured in model years 2013-2014 are dual fueled (90% in 2015 and subsequent model years). Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA) to require an electric utility to obtain no less than 15% of the base quantity of electricity it sells to consumers from diverse energy for 2015-2019, 20% for 2020-2024, 25% for 2025-2029, 30% for 2030-2049, and 50% for 2050. Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish a federal diverse energy credit trading program. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish an incentive program to permanently retire conventional coal plants with the largest pollution-related liabilities. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) replace the incentive program for the production of cellulosic biofuels with one for the production of renewable fuels; and (2) require the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer funding to the Secretary of Energy for the cost of loan guarantees to promote the development of advanced nuclear energy facilities. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a refundable and transferable income tax credit for fuel savings amounts achieved by a new qualified fuel-efficient motor vehicle; and (2) impose an excise tax on the sale of a fuel guzzler motor. Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to require the Secretary of Energy to: (1) update national model building energy codes at least every three years; and (2) establish targets for overall energy savings in buildings and minimum building efficiency standards. Establishes in DOE a Homes and Buildings Energy Retrofits Program that has an annual target energy efficiency retrofit rate of 5% for homes and 2% for commercial buildings. Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to: (1) direct federal agencies to ensure that new federal buildings are designed to enhance energy efficiency; (2) revise requirements concerning agency procurement of energy efficient products; and (3) direct agency heads to implement best management practices for energy-efficient management of servers and data centers. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans to public power districts, public utility districts, or specified electric cooperatives that borrowed and repaid, prepaid, or are paying electric loan made or guaranteed by the Rural Utilities Service for making loans to consumers for implementing energy efficient measures. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to: (1) require the Secretary of Energy to carry out a grant program to pay the federal share of creating a revolving loan program for manufacturers to implement commercially available technologies or processes that significantly reduce system energy intensity and improve U.S. industrial competitiveness; (2) include computer monitors and displays as covered products under the energy conservation program for consumer products other than automobiles; and (3) require the Secretary to establish an energy conservation standard for each type or class of covered industrial equipment.</summary>
</bill>
