<bill session="113" type="s" number="1543" updated="2013-11-02T07:05:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Pay for Our Military Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to appropriate such funds as may be necessary to ensure that members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components thereof, and supporting civilian and contractor personnel continue to receive pay and allowances for active service performed when a funding gap caused by the failure to enact interim or full-year appropriations for the Armed Forces occurs, which results in the furlough of non-emergency personnel and the curtailment of Government activities and services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3187"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="171"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1541"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2013--Introduced.
Ensuring Pay for Our Military Act - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, during a funding gap impacting the Armed Forces, to make available to the Secretary of Defense (DOD), and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) in the case of the Coast Guard, out of any amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as necessary to continue to provide pay and allowances to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components, who perform active service during the funding gap. Allows for the provision of such pay and allowances, at the discretion of the DOD Secretary, to: (1) DOD civilian personnel providing support to such members, and (2) DOD contractor personnel providing direct support to such members. Defines "funding gap" as any period after the beginning of a fiscal year for which interim or full-year appropriations for the personnel accounts of the Armed Forces for that fiscal year have not been enacted.</summary>
</bill>
