<bill session="109" type="s" number="3322" updated="2013-07-19T20:42:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-26">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to build operational readiness in civilian agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2006-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2006-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5389-5390"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-05-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5394-5397" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5394-5397" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6104"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="209"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Volunteer forces"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) States that the purpose of this Act is to provide for the development, as a core mission of the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), of an expert civilian response capability to carry out stabilization and reconstruction activities in a country or region that is in, or is in transition from, conflict or civil strife. (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress respecting specified steps to improve stabilization and reconstruction activities. (Sec. 5) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to provide assistance in stabilizing and reconstructing a country or region that is at risk of, in, or is in transition from, conflict or civil strife. Authorizes: (1) an initial appropriation for such activities, and provides that an amount for FY2007 may be made available for the development, training, and operations of the Response Readiness Corps; and (2) appropriations for replenishment of such funds. (Sec. 6) Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish within the Department an Office of the Coordinator for Reconstruction and Stabilization, which shall be headed by a Coordinator. Sets forth Office functions, including: (1) monitoring political and economic instability; (2) assessing related potential crises and responses; (3) coordinating with relevant executive agencies; (4) identifying state, local, and private sector personnel available to participate in the Response Readiness Corps or the Response Readiness Reserve; (5) international coordination and information sharing; and (6) coordinating plans for joint military-civilian operations. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary: (1) in consultation with the Administrator of USAID, to establish a Response Readiness Corps to provide stabilization and reconstruction activities in foreign countries or regions that are in, or are in transition from, conflict or civil strife (up to 250 personnel to serve in the Corps, and such other personnel as the Secretary may designate from the Department of State and USAID); and (2) in consultation with relevant executive agencies, to establish a Response Readiness Reserve of federal and at least 500 non-federal personnel to augment the Corps. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate committees respecting efforts to establish the Response Readiness Corps. (Sec. 8) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Army, to establish a stabilization and reconstruction curriculum for use in programs of the Foreign Service Institute, the National Defense University, and the United States Army War College. Sets forth curriculum content. (Sec. 9) States that service in stabilization and reconstruction operations overseas, membership in the Response Readiness Corps, and education and training in the stabilization and reconstruction curriculum should be considered among the favorable factors for promotion of executive agency employees. States that the Secretary and the Administrator should take steps to ensure that, not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, at least 10% of Department and USAID employees in the United States are members of the Response Readiness Corps or are trained or identified for potential Response Readiness Corps deployment. Authorizes the creation of incentives and benefits to recognize and reward participants. (Sec. 10) Sets forth personnel provisions. (Sec. 11) Authorizes FY2007 appropriations for personnel, education and training, equipment, and travel costs.</summary>
</bill>
