<bill session="112" type="h" number="602" updated="2013-07-20T01:15:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TEAM-Education Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transition toward Excellence, Achievement and Mobility through Education Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to make improvements to the individualized education program under that Act and facilitate the transition of children with disabilities to adulthood, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412280"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2012-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2011--Introduced.
Transition toward Excellence, Achievement and Mobility through Education Act of 2011 or TEAM-Education Act of 2011 - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to allow states to use special education grant funds to contract with entities that have the experience to assist disabled children in accomplishing the transition objectives outlined in their Individualized Education Programs (IEPs). Conditions a state's eligibility for such grant funds on its having a plan to coordinate state efforts to transition disabled youth into adulthood. Requires local educational agencies (LEAs) to provide a disabled child and his or her parents, when the child's secondary education ends, with a comprehensive record of the child's work experiences and skills that would be relevant to prospective employers, post-secondary education programs, career placement services, and mentors. Requires IEPs, after a child attains age 14, to describe: (1) the transition services to be provided to assist the child in reaching postsecondary goals, and (2) the training the child will receive to empower the child to act on his or her own behalf. (Currently, IEPs are to address postsecondary goals and transition services when children turn 16.) Requires an IEP team: (1) to include a representative of the state intellectual and developmental disabilities agency after a disabled child attains age 14, if the child is expected to be eligible to receive certain adult services upon reaching adulthood; (2) to consider the transition services necessary to assist the child to attain postsecondary education, integrated employment, independent living, and community participation; (3) at the request of a 14 year old disabled child, to take certain steps to enable his or her parents to advocate at IEP team meetings on the child's behalf; and (4) after the child attains age 14, to evaluate the progress made in meeting, and discuss any additional services that may be needed to meet, the child's transition objectives. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to provide grants to states to assist LEAs in establishing transition service coordinators.</summary>
</bill>
