<bill session="112" type="s" number="3705" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect our Kids Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a commission to develop a national strategy and recommendations for reducing fatalities resulting from child abuse and neglect.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2012-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8364-8365"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="6655"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2012--Introduced.
Protect Our Kids Act of 2012 - Establishes the Commission to Eliminate Child Abuse and Neglect Fatalities to: (1) study the use of child protective services and child welfare services under titles IV and XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to reduce fatalities from child abuse and neglect; (2) develop recommendations to reduce such fatalities for federal, state, and local agencies, and private sector and nonprofit organizations, including recommendations to implement a comprehensive national strategy for such purpose; and (3) develop guidelines for the type of information that should be tracked to improve interventions to prevent such fatalities. Requires any federal agency affected by a recommendation to report to Congress its response and plans to address it. Amends SSA title IV part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) to make an adjustment to the Contingency Fund for State Welfare Programs with respect to deposits for FY2013-FY2014, reserving a specified amount for Commission activities.</summary>
</bill>
