<bill session="111" type="s" number="1379" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Efficiency in Housing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage energy efficiency and conservation and development of renewable energy sources for housing, commercial structures, and other buildings, and to create sustainable communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Housing, Transportation and Community Development. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSBK09" subcommittee="Housing, Transportation, and Community Development" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2336"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3402"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Energy Efficiency in Housing Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish: (1) annual energy efficiency participation incentives for HUD programs to achieve substantial improvements in energy efficiency; (2) budget-neutral incentives to encourage lenders to make energy-efficient and location-efficient mortgages; (3) incentives for increasing the energy efficiency of multifamily housing subject to mortgages insured under the National Housing Act; and (4) an energy efficiency demonstration program for multifamily housing projects assisted with project-based rental asistance. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to: (1) require the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) to assign an additional housing credit for compliance with Federal Mortgage Insurance Association (Fannie Mae) and Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) housing goals for energy efficient mortgages; and (2) require the HUD Secretary to establish a commission to develop and recommend model mortgage products and underwriting guidelines that provide market-based incentives to incorporate energy efficiency upgrades and location efficiencies in new mortgage loan transactions. Amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to require Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to develop loan products and flexible underwriting guidelines to facilitate a secondary market for energy-efficient and location-efficient mortgages for low and moderate income families and for second and junior mortgages made for purposes of energy efficiency or renewable energy. Amends the National Housing Act to require the Secretary, in applying underwriting standards for mortgages on single-family housing, to consider the impact on the income of borrowers under Federal Housing Administration (FHA) mortgage insurance programs and Native American and Native Hawaiian loan guarantee programs from savings on utility costs resulting from energy efficiency standards established by this Act. Amends the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 to require the collection of information on energy-efficient and location-efficient mortgages. Requires the Secretary to develop and implement a pilot program for the financing of capital improvements to improve the energy efficiency and conservation of assisted housing projects. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to prohibit the Secretary from making a site revitalization grant unless the applicant's proposed revitalization plan meets specified Green Developments requirements. Amends the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 to require real estate appraisals, in determining the value of a property, to consider any renewable energy sources or energy-conserving improvements or features of the property. Establishes in the Treasury the Alternative Energy Sources State Revolving Fund to provide loans to states and Indian tribes to carry out renewable energy and energy conservation activities. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to nonprofit organizations to increase low-income community development capacity. Authorizes the Secretary to make loan guarantees for the financing of renewable energy systems leased for residential use. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to establish green banking centers to provide energy efficiency information to consumers seeking a mortgage, home improvement loan, or home equity loan. Requires the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the impact of this Act on the availability of affordable mortgages. Requires the Secretary to obtain information from public housing agencies on the energy costs of their housing units and report such information to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
