<bill session="110" type="s" number="3336" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Clean Energy Tax Extenders Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce our dependence on foreign oil by investing in clean, renewable, and alternative energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300035"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2008--Introduced.
New Clean Energy Tax Extenders Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend various energy production and conservation provisions.Extends through 2012: (1) the tax credits for producing electricity from certain renewable resources (e.g., for wind, biomass, geothermal, and hydropower facilities), for residential energy efficient property, and for investment in clean renewable energy bonds; and (2) the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial buildings. Expands the tax credit for production of electricity from renewable resources to include marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy as a renewable resource. Extends through 2016 the energy tax credits for solar, fuel cell, and microturbine property and the tax credit for residential energy efficient property. Repeals the dollar per kilowatt limitation on the energy tax credit for fuel cell property.Extends through 2011 the tax credit for energy efficiency improvements to existing homes. Makes biomass fuel burning stoves eligible for such credit. Extends the tax credit for energy efficient household appliances produced after 2007.Denies major integrated oil companies a tax deduction for income attributable to the domestic production of oil, gas, or any primary product thereof. Revises the treatment of foreign oil and gas extraction income and foreign oil related income for purposes of the foreign tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
