<bill session="109" type="h" number="4180" updated="2013-07-19T19:41:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Identification and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require communications which consist of prerecorded telephone calls to meet the disclosure and disclaimer requirements applicable to general public campaign communications transmitted through radio, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400241" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2005-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require communications which consist of prerecorded telephone calls to meet the disclosure and disclaimer requirements applicable to general public campaign communications transmitted through radio. Requires the audio statement to: (1) be made at the beginning of the telephone call; and (2) clearly state the name and permanent street address of the person making the disbursement for the call (disbursing person). Requires the telephone number which will appear in the recipient's caller identificaton device to be the telephone number used in the disbursing person's regular course of business, without regard to whether or not the person placed the telephone call itself.</summary>
</bill>
