<bill session="112" type="h" number="175" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Smart Housing in Disasters Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to develop lifecycle plans and tracking procedures for housing units provided to individuals and households to respond to disaster-related housing needs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Smart Housing in Disasters Act of 2011 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Stafford Act) to cover as a major disaster any "catastrophic incident" as defined by the Homeland Security Act, namely any natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster that results in extraordinary levels of casualties or damage or disruption severely affecting the population (including mass evacuations), infrastructure, environment, economy, national morale, or government functions in an area. Amends the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to develop, as an annex to the National Disaster Housing Strategy, a lifecycle and tracking plan for housing units provided to individuals and households affected by an emergency or major disaster that establishes policies for procurement, delivery, installation, maintenance, deactivation, and disposal of the units. Requires the plan to: (1) emphasize the acquisition of housing units that can be recycled and reused for multiple emergencies or major disasters; and (2) include a process for the Administrator to track each housing unit from its date of acquisition through its date of disposal. Amends the Stafford Act to direct the President, upon determining that a temporary housing unit purchased under such Act for housing disaster victims is unsuitable for habitation, to alter such unit in a manner that will prevent it from being used for habitation before it is disposed through sale to a recycler or other purchaser.</summary>
</bill>
