<bill session="112" type="h" number="3555" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Genetically Engineered Technology Farmer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Genetically Engineered Crop and Animal Farmer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Genetically Engineered Organism Liability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide additional protections for farmers and ranchers that may be harmed economically by genetically engineered seeds, plants, or animals, to ensure fairness for farmers and ranchers in their dealings with biotech companies that sell genetically engineered seeds, plants, or animals, to assign liability for injury caused by genetically engineered organisms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412440" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2011--Introduced.
Genetically Engineered Technology Farmer Protection Act - Genetically Engineered Crop and Animal Farmer Protection Act - Requires a biotech company that sells any genetically engineered animal, plant, or seed that will be used in the United States to: (1) provide the purchaser with written notice of possible legal and environmental risks of such article's use (such disclosure shall neither relieve the company from liability nor be construed to create purchaser liability), and (2) disclose any technology fees to the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) and not charge fees that are higher than those outside the United States. Sets forth related contract prohibitions and limitations. Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify which plants are outcrossed pollinators and make such information available to affected sellers and purchasers, and (2) issue rules to require mitigation strategies for predominately outcrossed crops. Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) establish the best achievable resistance plan for plant-incorporated pesticides engineered to include toxins derived from the bacterium Bacillus thuringiensis (Bt), (2) revoke Bt registrations not in plan compliance, (3) reduce a pesticide's use if it is determined to be facilitating Bt-toxin resistance in pests, and (4) establish an advisory panel. Prohibits: (1) labeling seeds as non-genetically engineered if the Secretary determines such seeds contains genetically engineered material; (2) manufacture, sale, or planting of genetically engineered or chemically induced non-fertile seeds; and (3) loan discrimination against a producer who refuses to use genetically engineered plants or animals. Authorizes, with respect to violations under this Act: (1) the Secretary to assess civil penalties; and (2) citizen suits against the Secretary, a federal agency, or an individual. Genetically Engineered Organism Liability Act of 2011 - States that: (1) a biotech company shall be liable to any party injured by the release of a genetically engineered organism into the environment if the injury results from such genetic engineering, and (2) liability may not be waived or otherwise avoided by contract.</summary>
</bill>
