<bill session="109" type="h" number="3897" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Madera Water Supply and Groundwater Enhancement Project Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Madera Water Supply and Groundwater Enhancement Project Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Madera Water Supply Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Madera Irrigation District for purposes of supporting the Madera Water Supply and Groundwater Enhancement Project.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Madera Irrigation District for purposes of supporting the Madera Water Supply Enhancement Project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-01-31T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-368.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-01-31T16:46:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="197">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 197.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4922-4923" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3897.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4922" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2006--Passed House amended.
Madera Water Supply Enhancement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation, to study and report to Congress on the feasibility of constructing the Madera Water Supply and Enhancement Project. Limits the federal share of the cost of the study to 50%. Requires all planning, design, and construction of the Project to be undertaken in accordance with a cooperative agreement between the Secretary and the Madera Irrigation District, California. Authorizes the Secretary, upon determining that the Project is feasible, to enter into a cooperative agreement through the Bureau with the District for the support of the design and construction of the Project. Limits the federal share of the capital costs of the Project to 25%. Directs the Secretary, before obligating funds, to work cooperatively to use plans, designs, and engineering and environmental analyses that have already been prepared by the District for the Project. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
