<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1756" updated="2013-07-19T23:11:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-08T18:43:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-08T18:43:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 5281) to amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify and improve certain provisions relating to the removal of litigation against Federal officers or agencies to Federal courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-677, by Mr. Polis (CO).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-08T17:23:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="252">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 252.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T17:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8213-8220" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T17:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1756.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T17:33:00-05:00">
      <text>The rule provides for consideration of the Senate amendments to H.R. 5281. The resolution makes in order a motion by the Committee on the Judiciary that the House concur in the Senate amendments numbered 1 and 2; and that the House concur in the Senate amendment numbered 3 with an amendment printed in the report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T18:03:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8220" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T18:03:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the resolution until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T18:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8221-8222" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-12-08T18:43:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="623" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 211 - 208 (Roll no. 623).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8213" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T18:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="5281"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 5281) to amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify and improve certain provisions relating to the removal of litigation against Federal officers or agencies to Federal courts.</summary>
</bill>
