<bill session="109" type="h" number="5718" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 with respect to the trade adjustment assistance program, and for other purpose.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="2006-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Trade Adjustment Assistance Reform Act - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to repeal group eligibility requirements for trade adjustment assistance (TAA) that: (1) the country to which the workers' firm has shifted production of the articles be a party to a free trade agreement with the United States; or (2) such country be a beneficiary country under the Andean Trade Preference Act, African Growth and Opportunity Act, or the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act.Requires the Secretary of Labor, with respect to textile and apparel workers, to make group eligibility determinations without regard to the sales, imports, and production factors of the group eligibility requirements.Requires the Secretary of Labor to study and report to Congress on the feasibility of allowing states to use a greater portion of their TAA funds for administrative expenses.Increases the amount of payments for training of adversely affected workers under the Act.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the credit for health insurance costs of certain TAA and Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) pension recipients.Requires the Secretaries of the Treasury and of Labor each to carry out compatible and coordinated programs to simplify the TAA eligibility process.</summary>
</bill>
