<bill session="111" type="h" number="1667" updated="2013-07-19T23:26:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">War Profiteering Prevention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit profiteering and fraud relating to military action, relief, and reconstruction efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/2009--Introduced.
War Profiteering Prevention Act of 2009 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit profiteering and fraud involving a contract or the provision of goods or services in connection with a mission of the U.S. Government overseas. Imposes: (1) a fine of not more than $1 million and/or a prison term of up to 20 years for knowingly defrauding the United States or a provisional authority in connection with such a mission or for materially overvaluing any goods or services with the intent to defraud; (2) a fine of not more than $1 million and/or a prison term of up to 10 years for falsification or concealment, false statements, or false documents in connection with such contracts or goods or services. Grants extraterritorial federal jurisdiction over war profiteering and fraud offenses. Permits venue for the prosecution of such offenses in any district where any act in furtherance of an offense took place or where any party to a contract or provider of goods or services is located. Allows criminal forfeiture of property obtained from a war profiteering or fraud offense. Makes war profiteering and fraud a predicate offense for prosecuting money laundering and racketeering offenses.</summary>
</bill>
