<bill session="110" type="s" number="2915" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safeguarding Social Security Numbers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Commissioner of Social Security to issue uniform standards for the method for truncation of social security account numbers in order to protect such numbers from being used in the perpetration of fraud or identity theft and to provide for a prohibition on the display to the general public on the Internet of social security account numbers by State and local governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2008--Introduced.
Safeguarding Social Security Numbers Act of 2008 - Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to issue uniform standards for the method for truncation of Social Security account numbers in order to facilitate their protection from use in fraud or identity theft. Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the display of Social Security account numbers to the general public on the Internet by state and local governments, except in compliance with such truncation standards. Directs the Attorney General to award grants to state and local governments to come into compliance with such prohibition or the exception to it.</summary>
</bill>
