<bill session="111" type="sr" number="251" updated="2013-07-20T00:18:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-07">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the Government of Afghanistan, with the support of the international community, should fulfill its obligations to ensure that women fully participate as candidates and voters in the August 20, 2009, presidential and provincial council elections in Afghanistan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-08-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9091" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text as passed Senate CR S9091"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9090" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Congratulates the women and women-led organizations of Afghanistan on the launch of the Five Million Afghan Women Campaign. Urges the government of Afghanistan to ensure that sufficient staffing is in place in women's polling stations, including security staff and equipment and appropriate polling place personnel, and include women in committees charged with election security and related processes. Urges the government of Afghanistan, the religious, community, and cultural leaders to encourage women to participate in the August 2009 elections. Urges the government of Afghanistan and the Independent Electoral Commission to continue to consult with the Afghan Ministry of Women's Affairs, the Afghan Independent Human Rights Commission, and women-led nongovernmental organizations regarding women's participation in the elections. Encourages the Secretary of State to continue to mobilize U.S. resources for programs throughout Afghanistan to raise the awareness of women in Afghanistan regarding governance and their rights as citizens. Urges the new government of Afghanistan to meaningfully engage women in such new government.</summary>
</bill>
