<bill session="111" type="hr" number="653" updated="2013-07-19T23:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-17T11:00:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-17T11:00:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1018) to amend the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act to improve the management and long-term health of wild free-roaming horses and burros, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-212, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except for clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources shall be considered as adopted. The resolution waives all points of order against provisions of the bill, as amended. This waiver does not affect the point of order available under clause 9 of rule XXI. The amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules, if offered by Representative Rahall or his designee, shall be considered as read and separately debatable for 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent and shall not be subject to a demand for the division of the question. The amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part B of the report of the Committee on Rules, if offered by Representative Hastings (WA) or his designee shall be considered as read and separately debatable for 30 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-16T19:31:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="91">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8306-8313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 653.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17T10:09:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 653, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8315-8316" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 188 (Roll no. 574).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8312-8313, H8315-8316" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8312-8313" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-07-17T11:00:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="575" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 236 - 186 (Roll no. 575).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8306-8307" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-17T11:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="1018"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1018) to amend the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act to improve the management and long-term health of wild free-roaming horses and burros.</summary>
</bill>
