<bill session="109" type="h" number="5393" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Natural Disaster Housing Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Natural Disaster Housing Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the Department of Housing and Urban Development to coordinate Federal housing assistance efforts in the case of disasters resulting in long-term housing needs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2006-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 109-607, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 29, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T20:20:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 17, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-17T14:44:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Transportation Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Dec. 8, 2006.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2983"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Floodplains"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Public utility rates"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Reported to House without amendment, Part I.
Natural Disaster Housing Reform Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Makes the Department of Housing and Urban Development the primary federal agency responsible for coordinating and administering housing assistance in connection with any major disaster that will result in long-term housing needs. Prescribes guidelines for the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to implement such assistance. (Sec. 3) Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the President, upon state request, to provide such housing assistance if the relevant major disaster will displace individuals or households from their predisaster primary residences, or will render such residences uninhabitable, for a period of 30 days or more. Instructs the President, when making any cost effectiveness determination, to consider whether manufactured modular housing can be provided at a federal cost less than the same cost necessary to provide other readily fabricated dwellings. Authorizes the President to provide financial assistance for: (1) the repair, to a safe and sanitary living or functioning condition, of existing rental units that will be used as alternate housing accommodations; and (2) permanent and semi-permanent housing construction in remote locations of declared major disaster or emergency in connection with Hurricane Katrina of 2005 during the period between August 28, 2005, and December 31, 2007. Permits the location in a special flood hazard zone, under the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, of any permanent, semi-permanent, or temporary housing, including any readily fabricated dwelling, manufactured housing, or manufactured modular housing. Instructs the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to develop detailed and comprehensive mass evacuation plans for individuals or households receiving assistance for the 18-month period following a disaster declaration.</summary>
</bill>
