<bill session="113" type="h" number="284" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Accountability Pay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for rates of pay for Members of Congress to be adjusted as a function of changes in Government spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2013-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2013--Introduced.
Congressional Accountability Pay Act - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to revise the method of adjusting the annual rate of pay of Members of Congress. Requires a decrease in the rate of pay for each Member by a specified percentage if outlays for any fiscal year are greater than outlays for the preceding fiscal year. Amends the Federal Salary Act of 1967 to require that recommendations by the Citizens' Commission on Public Service and Compensation conform with this Act, except those for the salaries of the Chief Justice of the United States, judges of U.S. district courts, and judges of the U.S. Court of International Trade.</summary>
</bill>
