<bill session="111" type="s" number="2858" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brittany Wilkinson Mitochondrial Disease Research and Treatment Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish an Office of Mitochondrial Disease at the National Institutes of Health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2010-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12808-12809"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3502"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2009--Introduced.
Brittany Wilkinson Mitochondrial Disease Research and Treatment Enhancement Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of Mitochondrial Disease within the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Requires the Director of the Office to develop, make publicly available, and implement a written plan to facilitate and coordinate research into mitochondrial disease. Authorizes the Director to award grants for: (1) integrated, multi-project research programs related to mitochondrial disease and planning activities associated with such programs; and (2) the establishment of Mitochondrial Disease Centers of Excellence to promote interdisciplinary research and training related to mitochondrial disease. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish: (1) a national registry of medical information collected from patients with mitochondrial disease for research purposes; and (2) a national biodepository of tissues and DNA collected from patients with mitochondrial disease for research purposes.</summary>
</bill>
