<bill session="111" type="h" number="831" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Comptroller General to conduct a study of the legal requirements and policies followed by the Department of Transportation in deciding whether to approve international alliances between air carriers and foreign air carriers and grant exemptions from the antitrust laws in connection with such international alliances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E190-191"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Competition Policy" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Comptroller General to study legal requirements and policies followed by the Department of Transportation in deciding whether to: (1) approve cooperative agreements between an air carrier and a foreign air carrier (international alliances) to provide foreign air transportation; and (2) exempt such alliances from the U.S. antitrust laws. Requires: (1) the Comptroller General to report to the Secretary and Congress study results, including any recommendations for authority or policy changes with respect to approving such alliances and granting such exemptions; and (2) the Secretary to issue a determination, after public comment, whether such changes will be adopted.</summary>
</bill>
