<bill session="113" type="hj" number="75" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-04T18:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-04T18:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Nutrition assistance for low-income women and children bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400004"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T16:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 371.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6262-6272" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T16:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6270" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kirkpatrick moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6270" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6270" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceedings with 10 minutes of debate on the Kirkpatrick motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. The amendment would replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J. Res. 59, Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Aderholt stated that the amendment was not germane to the underlying bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kirkpatrick moved to appeal the ruling of the chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6271" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 185 (Roll no. 523).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6271" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="524" datetime="2013-10-04T18:10:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 164 (Roll no. 524).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6262-6263" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="209">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 209.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="371"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="74"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the Department of Agriculture (USDA) for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided in the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2013 (division A of P.L. 113-6), for continuing projects or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this joint resolution, that were conducted in FY2013, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by such Act under the heading "Department of Agriculture--Domestic Food Programs--Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)." Requires the rate of operations to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-6), and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2). Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities. Authorizes amounts made available for civilian personnel compensation and benefits to be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for FY2013, except that such authority shall not be used until after the agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Nutrition Assistance for Low-Income Women and Children Act.</summary>
</bill>
