<bill session="113" type="h" number="2676" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Information Technology to Enhance Community Health Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MITECH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to encourage the adoption and use of certified electronic health record technology by safety net providers and clinics under the Medicaid program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1286"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2013--Introduced.
Medicaid Information Technology to Enhance Community Health Act of 2013 or MITECH Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to extend payments to encourage the adoption and use of certified electronic health record (EHR) technology to qualified safety net clinics (QSNCs). Defines a QSNC as a clinic or network of clinics operated by a private non-profit or public entity at least 30% percent of whose patient volume is attributable to needy individuals. Defines a "QSNC-based" individual as one who furnishes substantially all of his or her professional services in a QSNC and through use of the clinic's facilities and equipment, including qualified EHRs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a procedure through which a QSNC may demonstrate meaningful use of certified EHR technology in order to receive incentive payments.</summary>
</bill>
