<bill session="113" type="s" number="1152" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building a Health Care Workforce for the Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to help build a stronger health care workforce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4409"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2013--Introduced.
Building a Health Care Workforce for the Future Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award matching grants to enable states to implement scholarship programs to ensure an adequate supply of health professionals. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to assist medical schools in developing and strengthening primary care mentorship programs and cultivating leaders in primary care among its students. Requires the Secretary to award grants to medical and other health professions schools to promote priority competencies that are selected annually by the Secretary, acting through the Advisory Committee on Training in Primary Care and Dentistry, in order to foster curricular innovations to improve the education and training of health care providers. Directs the Institute of Medicine to study the documentation requirements for cognitive services (evaluation and management services) required under Medicare and Medicaid and through private health insurers.</summary>
</bill>
