<bill session="110" type="s" number="3101" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to extend expiring provisions under the Medicare program, to improve beneficiary access to preventive and mental health services, to enhance low-income benefit programs, and to maintain access to care in rural areas, including pharmacy access, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time. Pursuant to the order of the Senate of June 6, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="772">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 772.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5431" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5431" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5467-5468"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5539-5564" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Cloture not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 54 - 39. Record Vote Number: 149.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5564" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reid to reconsider the vote by which cloture was not invoked on the motion to proceed to the measure [Record Vote Number 149] made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5564" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5564" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6212"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6331"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Anesthetics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Imaging systems in medicine"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Lung diseases"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medigap"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-help devices for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4980"/>
    <amendment number="s4981"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/6/2008--Introduced.
Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for coverage of additional preventive services.Provides for gradual elimination of copayment rates for Medicare psychiatric services.Places prohibitions and limitations on certain sales and marketing activities under Medicare Advantage (MA) plans and prescription drug plans.Requires offering of a range of Medicare supplemental policies.Extends the qualifying individual program. Provides for application of a full low-income subsidy assets test under the Medicare Savings Program.Eliminates Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) late enrollment penalties paid by subsidy-eligible individuals.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to states for state health insurance assistance programs, area agencies on aging, and aging and disability resource centers. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to states for increasing the delivery of mental health services or other health care services to meet the needs of veterans of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom living in rural areas. Permits rebasing for sole community hospitals.Directs the Secretary to establish a demonstration project for development and testing of new community health integration models in certain rural counties.Amends the Tax Relief and Health Care Act of 2006, as amended by the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Extension Act of 2007, to extend through FY2009 the reclassification of certain hospitals.Increases physicians' payments. Revises requirements for and extends the quality reporting system, including incentive payments.Directs the Secretary to establish a Physician Feedback Program. Provides for: (1) incentives for electronic prescribing of medicine; (2) expanded access to primary care services; (3) extension of the floor on Medicare work geographic adjustment under the Medicare physician fee schedule; and (4) an accreditation requirement for advanced diagnostic imaging services.Revises requirements for Medicare anesthesia teaching programs. Makes permanent the exception to the 60-day limit on Medicare reciprocal billing arrangements between two physicians over a longer continuous period during all of which one of them is ordered to active duty as a member of a reserve component of the armed forces.Provides for coverage of pulmonary and cardiac rehabilitation.Revises payment rules for power-driven wheelchairs.Extends increased Medicare payments for ground ambulance services. Amends the Public Health Services Act to direct the Secretary to establish pilot projects with respect to chronic kidney disease.Revises requirements for renal dialysis.Provides for phase-out of indirect costs of medical education from capitation rates.Revises requirements for MA private fee-for-service plans as well as MA plans for special needs individuals.Modifies requirements for quality improvement programs.Requires prompt payment of clean claims by prescription drug plans and MA-Prescription Drug plans under Medicare part D. Revises the definition of medically accepted indication for drugs.Directs the Secretary to: (1) contract with a consensus-based entity for certain activities relating to health care performance measurement; and (2) evaluate and report to Congress on approaches for the collection of data regarding health care disparities.Creates the Medicare Improvement Fund.Extends the transitional medical assistance (TMA), the abstinence education program, and allotments for disproportionate share hospitals (DSHs) under SSA title XIX (Medicaid).Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to extend supplemental grants under SSA title IV part D (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF).Amends the Public Health Service Act to extend special diabetes grant programs.</summary>
</bill>
