<bill session="109" type="h" number="3818" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Forest Service Partnership Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Forest Service Partnership Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into partnership agreements with entities and local communities to encourage greater cooperation in the administration of Forest Service activities on and near National Forest System lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2005-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T16:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-325, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2676"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2005--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Forest Service Partnership Enhancement Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, in connection with the administration of specified Forest Service activities on and near National Forest System (NFS) lands, to enter into agreements, including cost-share agreements, with cooperators for: (1) developing, producing, or selling education and interpretive materials and products; (2) developing, conducting, or selling education and interpretive programs and services; (3) constructing, maintaining, or improving facilities for the sale or distribution of educational and interpretive materials, products, programs, and services; (4) operating facilities; (5) selling health and safety convenience products; (6) collecting funds from the sale of such materials, products, programs, and services; (7) activities to restore and maintain the ecological integrity and biodiversity of NFS lands; (8) watershed restoration and enhancement activities on NFS lands, or on other lands that benefit resources on NFS land within the same watershed, for protecting, restoring, and enhancing resources, including fish and wildlife habitat, or reducing risk from natural disaster where public safety is threatened; and (9) such other cooperative activities as the Secretary considers to be appropriate. Directs the Secretary to require such terms and conditions in an agreement as are necessary to protect investments to be made by the United States, including terms related to the ownership of any facilities or improvements constructed or improved under such an agreement. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) cost-sharing, including providing for in-kind contributions; and (2) the treatment of funds received under an agreement. Repeals certain authorities relating to: (1) cooperative arrangements for the printing of educational materials and the continuation of the Challenge Cost Share Program; and (2) Watershed Restoration and Enhancement Agreements.</summary>
</bill>
