<bill session="109" type="s" number="2307" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Competitive and Fair Agricultural Markets Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance fair and open competition in the production and sale of agricultural commodities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2006-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2006-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1428-1429"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Competitive and Fair Agricultural Markets Act of 2006 - Amends the Agricultural Fair Practices Act of 1967 to define specified terms. Establishes within the Department of Agriculture the Office of Special Counsel for Competition Matters, which shall be headed by a Special Counsel for Competition Matters. States that the Office shall: (1) investigate and prosecute violations of this Act, the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, and any other Act that the Secretary of Agriculture determines appropriate; (2) serve as a liaison between the Department and the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) with respect to competition and trade practices in the food and agricultural sector; and (3) maintain a staff of attorneys and other appropriate professionals. Requires a dealer, handler, contractor, processor, or commission merchant with annual sales in excess of $100 million to file an annual corporate structure report with the Secretary. Prohibits unfair or deceptive acts or practices: (1) in agricultural commerce; (2) concerning producer associations; and (3) in agricultural contracts. Sets forth agricultural and production contract and enforcement provisions. Amends the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 to eliminate the "slaughter" requirement from the definitions of "poultry grower," "poultry growing arrangement," and "live poultry dealer." Extends: (1) administrative enforcement authority to live poultry dealers; and (2) temporary injunction or restraining order authority to instances of poultry care. States that: (1) it shall be an unlawful practice to engage in an unfair or discriminatory practice or device regardless of whether the practice or device causes a competitive injury or otherwise adversely effects competition; and (2) a person affected by specified unfair practices shall not be required to prove predatory intent, competitive injury, or likelihood of injury.</summary>
</bill>
