<bill session="110" type="h" number="7159" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Windstorm Impact Reduction Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3638"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
National Windstorm Impact Reduction Reauthorization Act of 2008 - Amends the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Act of 2004 to revise provisions governing the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program. Designates the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) as the lead agency for Program planning, management, and coordination. (Repeals provisions regarding the existing Interagency Working Group responsible for Program planning, management, and coordination.)Establishes the Interagency Working Group on Wind Impact Reduction (IWG) to coordinate activities and facilitate communication among Program agencies in reducing the impacts of windstorms. Requires the Director of NIST to: (1) establish a Program Office to ensure coordination and synergy across Program agencies; (2) prepare the Program's annual budget; (3) facilitate preparation of the IWG's biennial report to Congress and the National Science and Technology Council; (4) support research and development for building codes and standards; (5) promote implementation of research results; (6) support deployment of interagency teams to investigate major windstorm events and data collection and analysis; and (7) participate in, coordinate, or support other Program mitigation activities.Sets forth: (1) the duties of the Program Office and of the IWG (including preparation of an interim working plan for Program operations and a strategic plan for achieving Program objectives); and (2) supportive roles of the National Science Foundation (NSF), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), the Department of Transportation (DOT), the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), and the Army Corps of Engineers. Authorizes appropriations for the Program for FY2009-FY2013.</summary>
</bill>
