<bill session="112" type="s" number="3524" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enforcing Orders and Reducing Customs Evasion Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Enforcing Orders and Reducing Customs Evasion Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to deter the evasion of antidumping and countervailing duty orders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Baucus. With written report No. 112-209.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="500">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 500.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3057"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1133"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Enforcing Orders and Reducing Customs Evasion Act of 2012 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to require the Commissioner responsible for U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), upon the filing of an allegation or a referral from another federal agency, to investigate claims of evasion of antidumping or countervailing duties with respect to covered merchandise entered into the United States. Defines "evasion" to mean entering covered merchandise into U.S. customs territory by means (except in the case of clerical error) of any document or electronically transmitted data or information, written or oral statement, or act that is material and false, or any material omission, which results in reduction or non-application of any cash deposit or other security or any amount of applicable antidumping or countervailing duties. Requires the Commissioner, if after the initiation of an investigation and a finding of reasonable suspicion, as an interim measure to: (1) suspend liquidation of each unliquidated entry of covered merchandise, (2) extend the period for liquidating each unliquidated entry entered before the date of such investigation, and (3) take such additional measures to protect U.S. revenue. Requires the Commissioner, in the case of an affirmative determination based on substantial evidence, to: (1) suspend or continue to suspend liquidation of unliquidated entries of covered merchandise, (2) extend or continue to extend the period for liquidating such entries, (3) request the administering authority (Secretary of Commerce or other responsible U.S. officer) to identify the applicable antidumping or countervailing duties or cash deposit rate for such entries, (4) require the posting of cash deposits and assess duties, and (5) take appropriate additional enforcement measures. Applies the amendments made by this Act to goods from Canada and Mexico. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to report annually to Congress on efforts being taken to prevent and investigate the entry of covered merchandise into the U.S. customs territory through evasion.</summary>
</bill>
