<bill session="110" type="h" number="1972" updated="2013-07-19T21:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Environmental Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to prohibit discrimination regarding exposure to hazardous substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Carcinogens"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2007--Introduced.
Community Environmental Equity Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit any entity that handles, manages, treats, releases, discharges, disposes, stores, transports, removes, moves, or delivers any covered substance from disproportionately exposing any person or community to such substance on the ground of race, color, national origin, or economic status. Defines "covered substance" to include: (1) any contaminant identified under the Safe Drinking Water Act; (2) any pesticide chemical under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; (3) any chemical listed as a known or probable human carcinogen under the National Toxicology Program of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS); (4) any chemical substance or mixture regulated under the Toxic Substance Control Act; (5) any hazardous waste identified under the Solid Waste Disposal Act; (6) any pesticide registered under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act; and (7) any air pollutant regulated under the Clean Air Act.Requires such an entity to: (1) work in partnership with state and local government officials and the federal government to comply with this Act; and (2) address actual or potential disproportionate exposure to covered substances prior to pursuing authorization or approval to work with such substances.Authorizes enforcement: (1) by denial or termination of authorization to work with covered substances; (2) by any other means authorized by law; and (3) for an entity receiving federal financial assistance, through specified compliance provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Health Impact Profile Program to make grants to community-based organizations and community health centers to assist in the planning and development of community health impact profiles.</summary>
</bill>
