<bill session="112" type="s" number="386" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unemployment Insurance Solvency Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide assistance to certain employers and States in 2011 and 2012, to improve the long-term solvency of the Unemployment Compensation program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S885"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S885-887" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2011--Introduced.
Unemployment Insurance Solvency Act of 2011 - Amends title XII of the Social Security Act (Advances to State Unemployment Funds) to: (1) extend through December 31, 2012, the waiver granted to states for payment of interest on advances made from the federal unemployment account in the Unemployment Trust Fund; and (2) authorize the governor of any state that has outstanding repayable advances from the federal unemployment account to apply to the Secretary of Labor to enter into a voluntary principal abatement agreement. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend the 6.2% employment tax rate for employers through 2013 and impose a reduced 5.78% rate in 2014, (2) modify the rate applicable to the limit on the credit allowed to employers for the federal unemployment tax, and (3) increase the taxable wage base for the federal unemployment tax to $15,000 in 2014. Amends title IX of the Social Security Act (Miscellaneous Provisions Relating to Employment Security) to increase the rate of interest payable on unemployment compensation reserves and lower the rate of the employment tax for employers in states whose unemployment compensation fund remains solvent.</summary>
</bill>
