<bill session="111" type="h" number="5269" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To express the sense of Congress that Federal job training programs that target older adults should work with nonprofit organizations that have a record of success in developing and implementing research-based technology curriculum designed specifically for older adults.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400074"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2010--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Senior Community Service Employment Program (SCSEP), and any other federal program that provides job training and placement services for older adults, should: (1) work with nonprofit organizations that have a record of success in developing and implementing research-based technology curriculum designed specifically for older adults; and (2) partner with such organizations to provide training, student materials, and support for a broad range of workforce technology skills, including basic and intermediate computer skills, Internet, email, word processing, spreadsheets, presentations, and other appropriate key skills for assisting older workers to enter or reenter the workforce.</summary>
</bill>
