<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1688" updated="2013-07-19T23:10:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to supporting the goals and ideals of the seventh annual National Cybersecurity Awareness Month and supporting the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security to raise awareness of cyber threats and enhance cybersecurity in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="797"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Expresses support for: (1) the goals and ideals of National Cybersecurity Awareness Month; (2) the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to disseminate information to the public to raise awareness of cybersecurity threats and enhance cybersecurity in the United States; and (3) DHS's activities intended to improve the ability of the United States to prevent, protect against, detect, attribute, report, respond to, and recover from cyber attacks. Congratulates the National Cyber Security Alliance, the Multi-State Information Sharing and Analysis Center, DHS, and other organizations working to improve cybersecurity in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
