<bill session="109" type="s" number="2311" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Older Americans Sustainable Mobility Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a demonstration project to develop a national network of economically sustainable transportation providers and qualified transportation providers, to provide transportation services to older individuals, and individuals who are blind, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2006-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1431-1432"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxicabs"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the aged"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Older Americans Sustainable Mobility Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Aging, to establish a demonstration project to enable qualified persons (specified older, blind, or visually impaired individuals and qualified passengers) to obtain: (1) economically sustainable transportation services (demand-responsive transportation services by automobile by a combination of volunteer and paid drivers) from economically sustainable transportation providers (nonprofit transportation providers that receive funding to connect to, and provide economically sustainable services through, a national network of transportation providers); and (2) transportation services from qualified transportation providers (nonprofit, public, or licensed private transportation providers that connect to and provide transportation through such network). Allows an income tax credit for 30% of the value of transportation services allocated to a transportation account of a qualified individual in exchange for the transfer of a motor vehicle to an economically sustainable transportation provider. Directs the Secretary to make grants to such transportation providers to pay for the federal share of the costs of acquiring and using technology to connect to the national network and the costs of participating in, and providing economically sustainable transportation services through, the network.</summary>
</bill>
