<bill session="112" type="h" number="6286" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400129"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act of 2012 - Establishes the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in California to promote environmentally responsible high-quality motorized and non-motorized trail based recreation, including off-highway vehicle use, scenic touring, and access for hunting and gem collecting, while protecting landscape resources. Instructs the Secretary to use the 2005 Clear Creek Management Area Travel Management Plan as modified by this Act or by the Secretary to incorporate natural resource protection information unavailable in 2005 as the basis for an interim management plan to govern motorized recreation in the Recreation Area. Requires the Secretary to create a comprehensive management plan for the Recreation Area within two years of enactment of this Act. Requires landowners to be provided with adequate access to inholdings within the Recreation Area. Permits livestock grazing to be allowed to continue in areas in which it is allowed. Designates specified federal lands in Fresno and San Benito Counties, California, to be known as the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness, as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to add the Larious Canyon, San Carlos Creek, Cantua Creek, Picacho Creek, and White Creek and its tributaries as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</summary>
</bill>
