<bill session="112" type="h" number="1026" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Flood Insurance Reform Priorities Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the authorization for the national flood insurance program, to identify priorities essential to reform and ongoing stable functioning of the program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2011-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2011-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1453"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1041"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1284"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2011--Introduced.
Flood Insurance Reform Priorities Act of 2011 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (NFIA) to extend through FY2016 the National Flood Insurance Program and the Pilot Program for Mitigation of Severe Repetitive Loss Properties. Increases maximum coverage limits. Provides a phase-in of actuarial rates for nonresidential properties and non-primary residences. Amends the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (FDPA) to delay for five years the effective date for the mandatory purchase of flood insurance for certain areas not previously designated as having special flood hazards. Amends NFIA to set forth a five-year phase-in of flood insurance rates for newly mapped areas not previously designated as having special flood hazards. Raises the annual limitation on premium increases. Considers any community that has made adequate progress on reconstruction or improvement of a flood protection system eligible for flood insurance premium rates not exceeding those which would be applicable if the flood protection system had been completed. Requires the availability of flood insurance coverage at discounted premiums for areas protected by a flood-protection system that does not provide protection against a 100-year frequency flood. States that, upon completion of certain flood protection projects, a covered area: (1) shall not be considered as having special flood hazards; and (2) shall be eligible for flood insurance. Amends the FDPA to require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to notify tenants: (1) whether property is located in an area having special flood hazards; and (2) that flood insurance for dwelling contents is available, including the maximum amount of such coverage. Prescribes minimum annual deductibles for damage or loss to pre-Flood Insurance Rate Map (pre-FIRM) structures (neither constructed nor substantially improved after the later of December 31, 1974, or the effective date of the initial rate map published under NFIA for the area in which such a structure is located) as well as lower minimum annual deductibles for post-FIRM structures. Requires termination of force-placed insurance after confirmation of a borrower's existing flood insurance coverage. Authorizes the FEMA Administrator to make grants to local governmental agencies in communities that participate in the national flood insurance program to implement outreach activities to encourage the purchase of flood insurance protection. Prohibits the FEMA Administrator from using any insurance company or other insurer to offer flood insurance coverage unless the company or insurer agrees to prohibit excluding wind damage coverage. Authorizes the FEMA Administrator to employ additional staff. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the FEMA Administrator to develop and implement jointly a plan to verify that persons receiving community development funds under the Homeowner Grant Assistance Program of the state of Mississippi or the Road Home Program of the state of Louisiana are maintaining flood insurance on the property for which they receive such funds. Establishes the Office of the Flood Insurance Advocate. Directs the Comptroller General to make several studies, including two on: (1) the impact, effectiveness, feasibility, and constitutional basis for extending mandatory flood insurance coverage purchase requirements to property which is located in any area having special flood hazards and which secures certain loan repayments; and (2) potential methods, practices, and incentives that would increase the extent to which low-income families owning residential properties located within special flood hazards areas would purchase flood insurance coverage under the national program. Requires the FEMA Administrator to make several studies, including three on: (1) inclusion of widely used and nationally recognized building codes as part of floodplain management criteria; (2) the impacts of the national flood insurance program on working waterfronts; and (3) the short- and long-term impacts of significant flooding events and subsequent revisions of hazard modeling and mapping since January 1, 2000, on the financial soundness of the program.</summary>
</bill>
