<bill session="111" type="s" number="2953" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Petersburg National Battlefield Boundary Modification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in the Commonwealth of Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2010-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-645.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3388"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2010--Introduced.
Petersburg National Battlefield Boundary Modification Act - Modifies the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in Virginia to include the properties identified on the map titled "Petersburg National Battlefield Boundary Expansion," and dated June 2007. Authorizes the Secretaries of the Interior and the Army to transfer the administrative jurisdiction for approximately 1.171 acres under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior within the boundary of the Petersburg National Battlefield in exchange for approximately 1.170 acres under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Army within the boundary of the Fort Lee Military Reservation adjacent to the Battlefield. Requires the conveyed land to be included within the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield and administered as part of such Battlefield.</summary>
</bill>
