<bill session="112" type="h" number="3813" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing Annuities for Federal Employees Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Securing Annuities for Federal Employees Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to secure the annuities of Federal civilian employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412411"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 16.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T21:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 112-394, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T21:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on House Administration discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-02-09T21:30:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="274">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 274.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-14T23:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 547 Reported to House. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3408. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Specified amendments printed in part A of the report accompanying this resolution are in order. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3813. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Specified amendments printed in part B of the report accompanying this resolution are in order. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 7.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="547"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="547"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Securing Annuities for Federal Employees Act of 2012 - Increases the employee contribution to the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) and to the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) by .5% of salary in each of calendar years 2013, 2014, and 2015. Reduces the employer contribution to CSRS and FERS by the amount of the increased employee contribution. Establishes new annuity computation rules for federal employees and Members of Congress who begin service after December 31, 2012, and who have less than five years of civilian service creditable under CSRS or any other retirement system for federal employees (secure annuity employees). Increases the employee contribution for secure annuity employees and calculates annuities for such employees based upon the average of their highest five years of salary (for current federal employees, the calculation is based on the highest three years of salary). Eliminates the FERS annuity supplement for employees not subject to mandatory retirement who separate from service after December 31, 2012. Allows federal employees, including employees of the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) and the Postal Regulatory Commission (PRC), and Members of Congress, to contribute payments received for accumulated and accrued annual or vacation leave to the Thrift Savings Fund.</summary>
</bill>
