<bill session="111" type="s" number="1577" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Asthma Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Education with increased authority with respect to asthma programs, and to provide for increased funding for such programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2260"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2009--Introduced.
Asthma Act - Authorizes additional appropriations to the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute to expand the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program. Requires the Program's coordinating committee to report to Congress on: (1) the scope of the asthma problem in the United States; (2) federal programs that carry out asthma-related activities; and (3) recommendations for strengthening and better coordinating such activities. Includes the Secretary of Education or a designee in the committee's membership. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) collaborate with states to expand the scope of asthma-related activities to determine the incidence and prevalence of asthma and prevent related health consequences; (2) conduct local asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma and the quality of asthma management; and (3) compile and annually publish data on the prevalence of asthma in children. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for: (1) information and education on asthma; and (2) referrals to health programs that provide asthma-related services. Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out a program to encourage the states to implement plans for activities to assist children with respect to asthma in accordance with the Institute's guidelines; and (2) make a grant to states under the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) for such activities. Authorizes grants to local educational agencies to carry out asthma-related activities at elementary and secondary schools in communities with a significant number of low-income or underserved individuals.</summary>
</bill>
