<bill session="110" type="s" number="1422" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Farm Risk Management Act for the 21st Century</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program to provide to agricultural operators and producers a reserve to assist in the stabilization of farm income during low-revenue years, to assist operators and producers to invest in value-added farms, to promote higher levels of environmental stewardship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6301-6302"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2242"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy crops"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2007--Introduced.
Farm Risk Management Act for the 21st Century - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to contract with eligible operators and producers (risk management account contracts) to: (1) provide a reserve to assist in the stabilization of farm income during low-revenue years; (2) assist operators and producers to invest in value-added farms; and (3) recognize high levels of environmental stewardship. Sets forth risk management account contract provisions, including: (1) administration; (2) direct payments; (3) stewardship payments; (4) account transfers; and (5) tax treatment. Extends counter-cyclical payments. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to: (1) replace current national dairy market loss payment provisions with dairy payment provisions through FY2012; (2) revise and extend funding authority for the McGovern-Dole international food for education and child nutrition program; (3) extend funding for testing of biobased products for the federal biobased procurement program; (4) revise and extend the biorefinery development program; (5) revise and extend the rural renewable energy development program; and (6) replace current renewable and energy systems and energy improvements provisions with the rural energy for America program (funds through FY2014). Establishes a recourse loan program for each loan commodity through crop year 2014. Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend: (1) the wetlands reserve program and increase maximum program acreage enrollment; (2) the environmental quality incentives program; (3) the conservation innovation grants program; and (4) the ground and surface water conservation program. Increases grassland reserve program maximum acreage enrollment. Extends authority to use Commodity Credit Corporation funds and facilities to carry out specified conservation-related programs. Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 with respect to: (1) combat pay and retirement account exclusions; (2) standard deduction increases; (3) child care deduction limits; (4) state cost-sharing during natural disasters; (5) minimum benefits; (6) program reauthorization; (7) program administration; (8) cash payment pilot projects; (9) block grants for Puerto Rico and American Samoa; (10) the commodity distribution program; (11) outreach grants; (12) the emergency food assistance program; and (13) community food projects. Establishes a community food assistance and food bank infrastructure grant program for eligible emergency feeding organizations. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to extend: (1) the fruit and vegetable program; and (2) the farm to school program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to offer to enter into a contract or grant agreement with a primary nongovernmental organization to establish the National Food for the Hungry Transportation Fund to track, collect, and deliver time-sensitive food products. Extends: (1) the forest land enhancement program; (2) the healthy forests reserve program; (3) the biomass research and development program; (4) the federal crop insurance adjusted gross revenue insurance pilot program; (5) the farmers' market promotion program; and (6) the fruit and vegetable nutrition promotion program.</summary>
</bill>
