<bill session="111" type="h" number="6091" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for further additional emergency unemployment compensation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3706"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/2010--Introduced.
Emergency Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2010 - Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 with respect to the state-established individual emergency unemployment compensation account (EUCA). Requires a further additional Tier-5 period for deposits to an individual's EUCA if, at the time the amount added to such individual's account under the Act is exhausted or at any time thereafter, the individual's state is in an extended benefit period. Prescribes a formula for making such Tier-5 credits. Increases the figures in the basic EUC formula (the lesser of which shall be the amount credited): (1) from 24% to 80% of the total amount of regular compensation (including dependents' allowances) payable to the individual during the benefit year; and (2) from 6 to 20 times the individual's average weekly benefit amount for the benefit year. Prescribes a formula for determining if a state is in an extended benefit period. Allows the Tier-5 period augmentation to be applied to the individual's EUCA only once. Authorizes a state to pay extended compensation to an otherwise eligible individual before any further additional emergency unemployment compensation (EUC), if such individual claimed extended compensation for at least one week of unemployment after the exhaustion of additional EUC.</summary>
</bill>
