<bill session="109" type="h" number="5667" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deficit Reduction and Effective Legislative Line Item Veto Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for the expedited consideration of certain proposed rescissions of discretionary budget authority, promote fiscal responsibility, reinstate Pay-As-You-Go rules, require responsible use of reconciliation procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2006-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1246"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Standards of Official Conduct, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4890"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Item veto"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Presidential messages"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax expenditures"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2006--Introduced.
Deficit Reduction and Effective Legislative Line Item Veto Act of 2006 - Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (CBICA) to authorize the President to propose the cancellation (line item veto) of any dollar amount of discretionary budget authority or targeted tax benefit within 10 days after its enactment. Dedicates any cancellation only to deficit reduction or increase of a surplus. Provides for adjustment of: (1) committee allocations resulting from such rescission; and (2) applicable limits, as appropriate, under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act). Sets forth procedures for expedited congressional consideration of a proposed rescission. Authorizes the President temporarily to: (1) withhold discretionary budget authority (including emergency spending); and (2) suspend implementation of any targeted tax benefit proposed to be repealed. Amends the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act to extend: (1) pay-as-you-go requirements through FY2011; and (2) certain expiring provisions through FY2016. Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the House to prohibit a Member from conditioning the inclusion in any legislation of language to fund a district-oriented earmark, a particular project, or a limited tax benefit on any vote cast by the Member in whose district the project will be carried out. Requires the Joint Committee on Taxation to review any revenue measure, reconciliation bill, or joint resolution for limited tax benefits, and identify them and their beneficiaries, including their sponsors. Amends Rule XIII (Calendars and Committee Reports) to make it generally out of order for the House to consider a bill or joint resolution until 24 hours, or for legislation containing a district-oriented earmark or limited tax benefit until three business days, after copies of such measure (and any accompanying report) are available. Amends Rule XXII (House and Senate Relations) to apply the same requirements to a conference report. Amends Rule XXII to: (1) make a motion to request or agree to a conference on a general appropriation bill in order only if the Senate expresses its disagreements with the House in the form of numbered amendments; (2) require all provisions on which the two Chambers disagree to be open to discussion at any meeting of a conference committee; and (3) make it out of order to consider conference reports not reflecting resolutions of differences between the two Chambers, as approved.</summary>
</bill>
