<bill session="110" type="s" number="1857" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Minority Serving Institutions for Advanced Technology and Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a digital and wireless network technology program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300099"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Paraprofessional school personnel"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2007--Introduced.
Minority Serving Institutions for Advanced Technology and Education Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make competitive grants to eligible institutions for specified activities, including: (1) acquiring equipment, instrumentation, networking capability, hardware and software, digital network technology, wireless technology, and infrastructure; (2) developing and providing educational services, including faculty development, related to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; (3) providing technology-related training for teachers, library and media specialists, early childhood educators, and teacher aides; and (4) forming technology-related consortia or collaborative projects. Defines "eligible institution" as a historically Black college or university, a Hispanic-serving institution, a Tribal College or University, an Alaska Native-serving institution, a Native Hawaiian-serving institution, or an institution with a substantial number of minority, low-income students who received a federal Pell grant for the previous academic year. Requires the Secretary to convene an annual meeting of grant recipients to foster collaboration and capacity-building activities and to disseminate information and ideas generated by the meetings.</summary>
</bill>
