<bill session="112" type="h" number="950" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ticket Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit restrictions on the resale of event tickets sold in interstate commerce as an unfair or deceptive act or practice.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2011-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2011--Introduced.
Ticket Act - Prohibits any ticket issuer from prohibiting or restricting the resale or offering for resale of an event ticket by a lawful possessor. Includes among prohibited activities: (1) purporting to impose license or contractual terms on the initial sale that restrict the terms and conditions under which a ticket may be resold, and (2) requiring the purchaser of a ticket to agree not to resell the ticket or to resell the ticket only through an approved channel. Establishes consumer protection minimum standards applicable to all persons engaging in the trade or business of acting as a ticket issuer, engaging in the resale of more than 25 event tickets in any one year, or providing a physical or electronic market for the sale or resale of event tickets by other persons. Includes within such standards requirements to: (1) maintain a toll-free telephone number for complaints and inquiries, and (2) implement and publicize a standard refund policy that provides for a full refund under specified circumstances. Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce a violation of this Act as an unfair or deceptive act or practice. Authorizes states to file civil actions to enforce this Act. Establishes damages for violations of this Act. Preempts any state or local law that limits the price at which an event ticket may be resold. Exempts from this Act: (1) sponsors or promoters of charitable events for which all tickets are distributed without charge; and (2) not-for-profit educational institutions for athletic events involving their athletes or teams with respect to tickets initially distributed to students, faculty, staff, or alumni without charge or to members of bona fide booster organizations.</summary>
</bill>
