<bill session="113" type="h" number="2211" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accuracy in Reporting Medical Debt Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to provide for a timetable for verification of medical debt and to increase the efficiency of credit markets with more perfect information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2013--Introduced.
Accuracy in Reporting Medical Debt Act of 2013 - Amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to prohibit debt collectors, during a 120-day period, from reporting a medical debt (arising from the receipt of medical services, products, or devices) to any consumer reporting agency if the consumer, within a specified timeframe, disputes the validity of such debt through a written statement that the consumer is: (1) continuing to communicate with an insurance company to determine coverage for the debt, (2) disputing the amount or existence of the debt, or (3) awaiting a determination on an application for financial assistance when the consumer provides evidence of such application. Prohibits this Act from having any effect on when a debt collector may engage in activities to collect or attempt to collect any debt owed or due or asserted to be owed.</summary>
</bill>
