<bill session="109" type="s" number="2261" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Reform Earmarks Process bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transparency and Integrity in Earmarks Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide transparency and integrity in the earmark process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2006-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2265"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2006--Introduced.
Transparency and Integrity in Earmarks Act of 2006 - Amends rule XVI (Appropriations and Amendments to General Appropriations Bills) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to prohibit consideration of an appropriation bill unless: (1) a list of all earmarks in it, the names of the requestors, and a short justification for each earmark are available to all Members, and made available to the general public on the Internet, for at least 72 hours before its consideration; (2) all earmarks are contained in the text of the bill and not incorporated by reference or directed in the committee report; and (3) all earmarks are germane to the bill. Permits waiver of such prohibition only by two-thirds of the Members. Amends rule XXXVII (Conflict of Interest) to prohibit a Member of the Senate from: (1) advocating inclusion of an earmark in any bill or joint resolution (or its accompanying report) or in any conference report on such legislation (including an accompanying joint statement of managers) if the Member has a financial interest in the earmark; or (2) conditioning the inclusion of language to provide funding for an earmark in such legislation (or its accompanying report or joint statement of managers) on any vote cast by the Member in whose state the project will be carried out. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require a recipient of federal funds constituting an award, grant, or loan to file a mandatory disclosure report containing: (1) the name of any registered lobbyist to whom the recipient paid money to lobby on behalf of such federal funding; and (2) the amount of money paid.</summary>
</bill>
