<bill session="109" type="s" number="2792" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Preparedness and Response Security, Accountability, and Flexibility Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to revise and extend certain provisions of the Public Health Security and Bioterrorism Preparedness and Response Act of 2002.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4476"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drug resistance in microorganisms"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poisons"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Syndromes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2006--Introduced.
Emergency Preparedness and Response Security, Accountability, and Flexibility Enhancement Act or the SAFE ACT - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions relating to bioterrorism and other public health emergencies preparedness grants, including to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop measurable critical benchmarks and performance standards. Authorizes the Secretary to develop a real-time surveillance program for collecting and reporting information on notifiable diseases and conditions (infectious diseases, environmental exposures or poisons, and other conditions, the real-time surveillance and control of which in the United States constitute a critical public health need). Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish a national electronic surveillance program for such diseases. Provides for a health alert in the case of a public health emergency or other circumstance requiring active surveillance. Requires the Secretary to award grants to enable states to conduct surveillance and report with respect to notifiable diseases. Makes ineligible for certain funding states or health care providers that do not report notifiable diseases. Allows grantees to use grant funds to develop benchmarks for meeting critical capacity for food or water borne disease detection and response. Requires the Director to provide for the evaluation of the progress made by state and local governments in meeting the benchmarks established under this Act. Requires the Secretary to establish procedures for the inspection, screening, and quarantine of live animals entering the United States for commercial purposes. Requires the federal agency partners of the National Disaster Medical System to conduct a review of the National Disaster Medical System infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
