<bill session="112" type="h" number="4097" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the John F. Kennedy Center Act to authorize appropriations for the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 112-457.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-04-27T11:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="319">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 319.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2296-2297" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4097.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-05-07T16:43:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2296" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-05-23" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3534" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-05-31">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-06-08" type="public" number="112-131">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-131.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2012--Public Law.
John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2012 - Allows the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (the Board) to undertake such activities as may be necessary for the construction of a specified addition to the south end of the building of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (the expansion project). Authorizes the Board to construct the expansion project and makes the Board responsible for the planning, design, engineering, and construction of the project. Requires the costs of those activities to be paid for using nonappropriated funds. Declares that, all activities carried out under this Act shall be within the mission of the John. F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (the Kennedy Center) to serve as the national center for such arts. Instructs the Board: (1) before awarding a contract for the construction of the expansion project, to estimate any additional annual operations and maintenance costs (or savings) associated with the project; and (2) to account for any such additional costs in making a budget request for FY2014 and each fiscal year thereafter. Requires a final determination to proceed with such project to be based on the ability of the Board to accommodate any such identified additional costs within its other budget priorities. Permits the Board to acknowledge private contributions used to carry out the interior portion of the expansion project, but prohibits the acknowledgement of private contributions used on the exterior portion. Requires any acknowledgements of private contributions under this Act to be consistent with requirements under the John. F. Kennedy Center Act regarding the designation or installation of additional memorials or plaques in the nature of memorials in public areas of the Kennedy Center. Authorizes appropriations for FY2013-FY2014 to the Board for: (1) maintenance, repair, and security; and (2) capital projects.</summary>
</bill>
