<bill session="112" type="h" number="3723" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Veteran Healthcare Experience Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into contracts with health care providers to improve access to health care for veterans who have difficulty receiving treatment at a health care facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412423"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2011--Introduced.
Enhanced Veteran Healthcare Experience Act of 2011 - Expresses the sense of Congress that better health care can be provided to veterans at little-to-no increased cost by revising the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) fee-based system for hospital care and medical services in non-VA facilities. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide certain enrolled veterans with health services (authorized hospital care or medical, rehabilitative, or preventative health services) that are provided by a non-VA provider with whom the Secretary enters into a contract pursuant to this Act if the Secretary determines that VA facilities are incapable of furnishing such services because of: (1) geographical inaccessibility; or (2) a lack of required personnel, resources, or ability at VA facilities. Authorizes the Secretary to enter a contract with a non-VA provider that: (1) demonstrates the ability to provide non-VA health care services to veterans; (2) meets or exceeds credentialing standards of the VA and the Utilization Review Accreditation Commission; (3) has coordinators who help veterans make, confirm, and keep medical appointments, a system that allows veterans to file complaints, and a demonstrated ability to respond to potential quality indicators and patient safety events; and (4) has the ability to process claims from other providers in its network, bill third parties, and transmit received amounts to the Secretary. Sets forth requirements concerning the VA's coordination with non-VA providers, performance metrics, and bonus payments for exceeding such metrics.</summary>
</bill>
