<bill session="110" type="h" number="6473" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to modify the conditions for the release of products from the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve Account, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412220"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2008-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3170"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Northeastern States"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2008--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to revise requirements for the sale by the Secretary of Energy of products from the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve. Authorizes the Secretary to sell from the Reserve if the President finds that: (1) there is a severe energy supply interruption (as under existing law); or (2) the price of home heating oil threatens the health and safety of residents of the Northeast. Requires the Secretary to sell specified percentages of the quantity of products in the Reserve as of November 1 of a fiscal year if the President finds that, on successive monthly winter dates of the same fiscal year, the average retail price of No.2 heating oil in the Northeast is equal to or more than $4.00 per gallon. Requires the Secretary to use: (1) half of any revenue derived from such sales to provide assistance to low-income consumers of heating oil under the Weatherization Assistance Program for Low-Income Persons of the Energy Conservation and Production Act; and (2) half to provide any additional home energy assistance needs of one or more state arising from a natural disaster or other emergency.</summary>
</bill>
