<bill session="112" type="s" number="1916" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fishery Science Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to exclude ecosystem component stocks of fish from certain annual catch limits and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7911" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2304"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/28/2011--Introduced.
Fishery Science Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Reauthorization Act of 2006 to prohibit the requirement that a mechanism be established for specifying annual catch limits in fishery management plans prepared by any Regional Fishery Management Council, or by the Secretary of Commerce, implementing regulations, or annual specifications, at a level such that overfishing does not occur in the fishery, from applying to: (1) a stock of fish for which a stock assessment has not been performed during the previous six-year period, if the Secretary has determined that the fishery is not subject to overfishing of that stock and that the stock is not overfished; and (2) an ecosystem component stock. Defines "ecosystem component stock" as a stock of fish determined by the Secretary to be a nontarget stock that is not subject to overfishing or overfished. Requires that ecosystem component species as determined by the Secretary prior to enactment of this Act be determined to be such ecosystem component stocks after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
