<bill session="112" type="h" number="2665" updated="2013-07-20T01:33:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Outsourcing Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To phase out the use of private military contractors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1428"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2011--Introduced.
Stop Outsourcing Security Act - Directs the Secretary of State to ensure that only U.S. government personnel provide diplomatic security services to personnel working on behalf of the United States at U.S. diplomatic or consular missions in areas of: (1) contingency operations; and (2) other significant military operations, other than combat operations, where security personnel may be called upon to use deadly force. Requires the President to report to Congress, by June 1, 2012, on the status of planning for the transition away from the use of private contractors for specified mission critical or emergency essential functions by January 1, 2013, in all areas of such operations. Directs any individual or entity under contract with the federal government to provide mission critical or emergency essential functions after such date to allow Congress to examine their accounting practices. Outlines additional requirements relating to renewals of such contracts. Authorizes specified congressional access to contracts and task orders in excess of $5 million entered into by the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of State, the Department of the Interior, and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) during the period beginning October 1, 2001, and ending on the last day of the month during which this Act is enacted for work to be performed in areas of such operations. Requires certain reports to Congress regarding contracts for the performance of work in areas of such operations.</summary>
</bill>
