<bill session="112" type="s" number="3682" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CAMPUS Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Center to Advance, Monitor, and Preserve University Security Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish and operate a National Center for Campus Public Safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2342"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6691"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2012--Introduced.
Center to Advance, Monitor, and Preserve University Security Safety Act of 2012 or the CAMPUS Safety Act of 2012 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services to establish and operate a National Center for Campus Public Safety. Tasks the Center with strengthening the safety and security of institutions of higher education (IHEs) by: (1) training IHE public safety personnel and their collaborative partners; (2) fostering relevant research; (3) collecting and disseminating information and best practices regarding campus safety; (4) developing protocols and best practices to prevent, protect against, and respond to dangerous and violent situations that threaten the campus community; and (5) promoting cooperation among public safety and emergency management personnel of IHEs and their collaborative partners, including law enforcement, emergency management, and mental health agencies. Authorizes the Director to award grants to IHEs and other nonprofit organizations for activities that will assist the Center in performing its functions.</summary>
</bill>
