<bill session="109" type="h" number="3466" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Meskwaki Code Talkers Recognition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate to make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of gold medals to the Meskwaki Code Talkers in recognition of their contributions to the Nation during World War II, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2006-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="2006-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional gold medals"/>
    <term name="Cryptography"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2005--Introduced.
Meskwaki Code Talkers Recognition Act - Requires the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate to make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of gold medals of appropriate design to each of the named eight Meskwaki Code Talkers who served during World War II. Provides for additional medals to other individuals not named in this Act who also served in such capacity. Allows the medals to be awarded posthumously to a surviving family member of such individuals.</summary>
</bill>
