<bill session="109" type="h" number="4939" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Reservists Pay Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-13T14:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-388, by Mr. Lewis (CA).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-13T14:13:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="210">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 210.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-03-14T21:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 725 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4939 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 725 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 725.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H992-995" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4939 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 725 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul E. Gillmor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4939.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:46:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T12:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4939 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T16:43:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Lewis (CA) asked unanimous consent that, during further consideration of H.R. 4939 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to House Resolution 725, an amendment by Mr. Gilchrest regarding section 3011 and an amendment by Mr. Sabo regarding the Defense Production Act may be offered at any point in the reading, shall be considered as read, shall not be subject to amendment except that the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations each may offer one pro forma amendment for the purpose of debate and shall not be subject to a demand for the division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. Each amendment shall be debatable for 20 minutes, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H999-1008" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1002, H1009, H1011-1013, H1014, H1016, H1017, H1019, H1020-1021, H1022, H1023, H1025, H1027, H1028" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1028-1029" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed general debate on H.R. 4939.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T16:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Gilchrest amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T17:20:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lewis (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T17:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Sabo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T17:31:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of the Gilchrest amendment which was debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T17:59:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T17:59:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4939 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1009-1025" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T18:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T18:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Millender-McDonald amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T18:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Souder amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T18:48:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Engel amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:01:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Shays amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:10:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Burton amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:22:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Lowey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Capuano amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:37:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Capuano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Salazar amendment under the five-minute rule pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:48:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Kirk amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T19:54:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Doggett amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:00:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Doggett demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hinojosa amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:06:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 725, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:11:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4939 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1026-1047" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:21:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:35:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:41:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Foxx demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Melancon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:52:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Melancon demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T20:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jefferson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:08:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jefferson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Jefferson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:11:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jefferson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Jefferson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:13:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:18:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Melancon amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T21:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:01:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Taylor (MS) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:10:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Taylor (MS) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Taylor (MS) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:14:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:18:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:29:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15T22:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4939 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T10:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1067-1074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T10:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T10:29:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of specified amendments which were debated on Wednesday, March 15, 2006, and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehner moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:06:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4939 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1074-1118" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1086-1087, H1116" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:09:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hall amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Paul amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sabo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:50:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sabo amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sabo demanded a recorded vote and made a point of order that a quorum was not present. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T12:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Neugebauer amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:14:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Neugebauer amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Neugebauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:14:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Millender-McDonald amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Millender-McDonald amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Millender-McDonald demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jindal amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jindal amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jindal amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T13:55:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Conaway amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conaway demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kennedy (MN) amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Berry amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T14:18:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeLauro amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T14:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T14:54:00-05:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 193 (Roll no. 55).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T15:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kaptur amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T15:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T15:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Waxman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:09:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Velazquez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:20:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Velazquez amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Velazquez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Velazquez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:29:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Velazquez amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Velazquez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:39:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lee amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T16:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:04:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of specified amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:45:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:45:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4939.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1116" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hinchey moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T17:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hinchey motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained within the motion seek to recommit the bill to the Committee on Appropriations with instructions to report the bill back to the House with an amendment on page 82, line 4, striking "2007" and inserting "2006".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T18:07:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 233 (Roll no. 64).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1116" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1116" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-03-16T18:14:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="65" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 348 - 71 (Roll no. 65).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16T18:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-04">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Cochran with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-230.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="391">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 391.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3400" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3444-3492" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3444-3473" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3532-3568, S3632-3634" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Motion by Senator Ensign to recommit to Senate Committee on Appropriations with instructions that it be reported back with total net spending not exceeding $94.5 billion tabled in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 68 - 28. Record Vote Number: 97.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3639-3692" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Cloture motion on the bill presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3692" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3692" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-01">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3771-3788, S3792-3793, S3847-3848" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3858-3890" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Cloture on the bill invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 92 - 4. Record Vote Number: 103.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3859-3860" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3859" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-03">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3937-3973" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4007-4030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2006-05-04" how="roll" result="pass" roll="112" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 77 - 21. Record Vote Number: 112.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Cochran; Stevens; Specter; Domenici; Bond; McConnell; Burns; Shelby; Gregg; Bennett; Craig; Hutchison; DeWine; Brownback; Allard; Byrd; Inouye; Leahy; Harkin; Mikulski; Reid; Kohl; Murray; Dorgan; Feinstein; Durbin; Johnson; Landrieu.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23T11:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Lewis (CA), Young (FL), Regula, Rogers (KY), Wolf, Kolbe, Walsh, Taylor (NC), Hobson, Bonilla, Knollenberg, Obey, Murtha, Sabo, Mollohan, Olver, Visclosky, Lowey, and Edwards.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 109-494 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3587-3627" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-09T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 857 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 4939. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read when called up for consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 857 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) brought up conference report H. Rept. 109-494 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 857.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3752-3771" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 4939.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T19:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12T19:59:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to the rule, the Yeas and Nays were automatic on the question of adoption of the conference report to accompany H.R. 4939, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until Tuesday, June 13, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13T11:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The House proceeded to consider the conference report H.Rept. 109-494 as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3799-3800" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2006-06-13T12:02:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="257" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 351 - 67 (Roll no. 257).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5750-5757, S5758-5765" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5828-5837" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-06-15" how="roll" result="pass" roll="171" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 98 - 1. Record Vote Number: 171.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5905-5909" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-06-15" type="public" number="109-234">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-234.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="725"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="725"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="857"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="857"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Anthrax"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Bombs"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting Board of Governors"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Famines"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Horticulture"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Marines"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military sealift"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Nonviolence"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuts"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Post exchanges"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Senior centers"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space exploration"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tanks (Combat vehicles)"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="U.S. Institute of Peace"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h701"/>
    <amendment number="h702"/>
    <amendment number="h703"/>
    <amendment number="h704"/>
    <amendment number="h705"/>
    <amendment number="h706"/>
    <amendment number="h707"/>
    <amendment number="h708"/>
    <amendment number="h709"/>
    <amendment number="h710"/>
    <amendment number="h711"/>
    <amendment number="h712"/>
    <amendment number="h713"/>
    <amendment number="h714"/>
    <amendment number="h715"/>
    <amendment number="h716"/>
    <amendment number="h717"/>
    <amendment number="h718"/>
    <amendment number="h719"/>
    <amendment number="h720"/>
    <amendment number="h721"/>
    <amendment number="h722"/>
    <amendment number="h723"/>
    <amendment number="h724"/>
    <amendment number="h725"/>
    <amendment number="h726"/>
    <amendment number="h727"/>
    <amendment number="h728"/>
    <amendment number="h729"/>
    <amendment number="h730"/>
    <amendment number="h731"/>
    <amendment number="h732"/>
    <amendment number="h733"/>
    <amendment number="h734"/>
    <amendment number="h735"/>
    <amendment number="h736"/>
    <amendment number="h737"/>
    <amendment number="h738"/>
    <amendment number="h739"/>
    <amendment number="h740"/>
    <amendment number="h741"/>
    <amendment number="h742"/>
    <amendment number="h743"/>
    <amendment number="h744"/>
    <amendment number="h745"/>
    <amendment number="h746"/>
    <amendment number="h747"/>
    <amendment number="h748"/>
    <amendment number="h749"/>
    <amendment number="h750"/>
    <amendment number="s3588"/>
    <amendment number="s3589"/>
    <amendment number="s3590"/>
    <amendment number="s3591"/>
    <amendment number="s3592"/>
    <amendment number="s3593"/>
    <amendment number="s3594"/>
    <amendment number="s3595"/>
    <amendment number="s3596"/>
    <amendment number="s3597"/>
    <amendment number="s3598"/>
    <amendment number="s3599"/>
    <amendment number="s3600"/>
    <amendment number="s3601"/>
    <amendment number="s3602"/>
    <amendment number="s3603"/>
    <amendment number="s3604"/>
    <amendment number="s3605"/>
    <amendment number="s3606"/>
    <amendment number="s3607"/>
    <amendment number="s3608"/>
    <amendment number="s3609"/>
    <amendment number="s3610"/>
    <amendment number="s3611"/>
    <amendment number="s3612"/>
    <amendment number="s3613"/>
    <amendment number="s3614"/>
    <amendment number="s3615"/>
    <amendment number="s3616"/>
    <amendment number="s3617"/>
    <amendment number="s3618"/>
    <amendment number="s3619"/>
    <amendment number="s3620"/>
    <amendment number="s3621"/>
    <amendment number="s3622"/>
    <amendment number="s3623"/>
    <amendment number="s3624"/>
    <amendment number="s3625"/>
    <amendment number="s3626"/>
    <amendment number="s3627"/>
    <amendment number="s3628"/>
    <amendment number="s3629"/>
    <amendment number="s3630"/>
    <amendment number="s3631"/>
    <amendment number="s3632"/>
    <amendment number="s3633"/>
    <amendment number="s3634"/>
    <amendment number="s3635"/>
    <amendment number="s3636"/>
    <amendment number="s3637"/>
    <amendment number="s3638"/>
    <amendment number="s3639"/>
    <amendment number="s3640"/>
    <amendment number="s3641"/>
    <amendment number="s3642"/>
    <amendment number="s3643"/>
    <amendment number="s3644"/>
    <amendment number="s3645"/>
    <amendment number="s3646"/>
    <amendment number="s3647"/>
    <amendment number="s3648"/>
    <amendment number="s3649"/>
    <amendment number="s3650"/>
    <amendment number="s3651"/>
    <amendment number="s3652"/>
    <amendment number="s3653"/>
    <amendment number="s3654"/>
    <amendment number="s3655"/>
    <amendment number="s3656"/>
    <amendment number="s3657"/>
    <amendment number="s3658"/>
    <amendment number="s3659"/>
    <amendment number="s3660"/>
    <amendment number="s3661"/>
    <amendment number="s3662"/>
    <amendment number="s3663"/>
    <amendment number="s3664"/>
    <amendment number="s3665"/>
    <amendment number="s3666"/>
    <amendment number="s3667"/>
    <amendment number="s3668"/>
    <amendment number="s3669"/>
    <amendment number="s3670"/>
    <amendment number="s3671"/>
    <amendment number="s3672"/>
    <amendment number="s3673"/>
    <amendment number="s3674"/>
    <amendment number="s3675"/>
    <amendment number="s3676"/>
    <amendment number="s3677"/>
    <amendment number="s3678"/>
    <amendment number="s3679"/>
    <amendment number="s3680"/>
    <amendment number="s3681"/>
    <amendment number="s3682"/>
    <amendment number="s3683"/>
    <amendment number="s3684"/>
    <amendment number="s3685"/>
    <amendment number="s3686"/>
    <amendment number="s3687"/>
    <amendment number="s3688"/>
    <amendment number="s3689"/>
    <amendment number="s3690"/>
    <amendment number="s3691"/>
    <amendment number="s3692"/>
    <amendment number="s3693"/>
    <amendment number="s3694"/>
    <amendment number="s3695"/>
    <amendment number="s3696"/>
    <amendment number="s3697"/>
    <amendment number="s3698"/>
    <amendment number="s3699"/>
    <amendment number="s3700"/>
    <amendment number="s3701"/>
    <amendment number="s3702"/>
    <amendment number="s3703"/>
    <amendment number="s3704"/>
    <amendment number="s3705"/>
    <amendment number="s3706"/>
    <amendment number="s3707"/>
    <amendment number="s3708"/>
    <amendment number="s3709"/>
    <amendment number="s3710"/>
    <amendment number="s3711"/>
    <amendment number="s3712"/>
    <amendment number="s3713"/>
    <amendment number="s3714"/>
    <amendment number="s3715"/>
    <amendment number="s3716"/>
    <amendment number="s3717"/>
    <amendment number="s3718"/>
    <amendment number="s3719"/>
    <amendment number="s3720"/>
    <amendment number="s3721"/>
    <amendment number="s3722"/>
    <amendment number="s3723"/>
    <amendment number="s3724"/>
    <amendment number="s3725"/>
    <amendment number="s3726"/>
    <amendment number="s3727"/>
    <amendment number="s3728"/>
    <amendment number="s3729"/>
    <amendment number="s3730"/>
    <amendment number="s3731"/>
    <amendment number="s3732"/>
    <amendment number="s3733"/>
    <amendment number="s3734"/>
    <amendment number="s3735"/>
    <amendment number="s3736"/>
    <amendment number="s3737"/>
    <amendment number="s3738"/>
    <amendment number="s3739"/>
    <amendment number="s3740"/>
    <amendment number="s3741"/>
    <amendment number="s3742"/>
    <amendment number="s3743"/>
    <amendment number="s3744"/>
    <amendment number="s3745"/>
    <amendment number="s3746"/>
    <amendment number="s3747"/>
    <amendment number="s3748"/>
    <amendment number="s3749"/>
    <amendment number="s3750"/>
    <amendment number="s3751"/>
    <amendment number="s3752"/>
    <amendment number="s3753"/>
    <amendment number="s3754"/>
    <amendment number="s3755"/>
    <amendment number="s3756"/>
    <amendment number="s3757"/>
    <amendment number="s3758"/>
    <amendment number="s3759"/>
    <amendment number="s3760"/>
    <amendment number="s3761"/>
    <amendment number="s3762"/>
    <amendment number="s3763"/>
    <amendment number="s3764"/>
    <amendment number="s3765"/>
    <amendment number="s3766"/>
    <amendment number="s3767"/>
    <amendment number="s3768"/>
    <amendment number="s3769"/>
    <amendment number="s3770"/>
    <amendment number="s3771"/>
    <amendment number="s3772"/>
    <amendment number="s3773"/>
    <amendment number="s3774"/>
    <amendment number="s3775"/>
    <amendment number="s3776"/>
    <amendment number="s3777"/>
    <amendment number="s3778"/>
    <amendment number="s3779"/>
    <amendment number="s3780"/>
    <amendment number="s3781"/>
    <amendment number="s3782"/>
    <amendment number="s3783"/>
    <amendment number="s3784"/>
    <amendment number="s3785"/>
    <amendment number="s3786"/>
    <amendment number="s3787"/>
    <amendment number="s3788"/>
    <amendment number="s3789"/>
    <amendment number="s3790"/>
    <amendment number="s3791"/>
    <amendment number="s3792"/>
    <amendment number="s3793"/>
    <amendment number="s3794"/>
    <amendment number="s3795"/>
    <amendment number="s3796"/>
    <amendment number="s3797"/>
    <amendment number="s3798"/>
    <amendment number="s3799"/>
    <amendment number="s3800"/>
    <amendment number="s3801"/>
    <amendment number="s3802"/>
    <amendment number="s3803"/>
    <amendment number="s3804"/>
    <amendment number="s3805"/>
    <amendment number="s3806"/>
    <amendment number="s3807"/>
    <amendment number="s3808"/>
    <amendment number="s3809"/>
    <amendment number="s3810"/>
    <amendment number="s3811"/>
    <amendment number="s3812"/>
    <amendment number="s3813"/>
    <amendment number="s3814"/>
    <amendment number="s3815"/>
    <amendment number="s3816"/>
    <amendment number="s3817"/>
    <amendment number="s3818"/>
    <amendment number="s3819"/>
    <amendment number="s3820"/>
    <amendment number="s3821"/>
    <amendment number="s3822"/>
    <amendment number="s3823"/>
    <amendment number="s3824"/>
    <amendment number="s3825"/>
    <amendment number="s3826"/>
    <amendment number="s3827"/>
    <amendment number="s3828"/>
    <amendment number="s3829"/>
    <amendment number="s3830"/>
    <amendment number="s3831"/>
    <amendment number="s3832"/>
    <amendment number="s3833"/>
    <amendment number="s3834"/>
    <amendment number="s3835"/>
    <amendment number="s3836"/>
    <amendment number="s3837"/>
    <amendment number="s3838"/>
    <amendment number="s3839"/>
    <amendment number="s3840"/>
    <amendment number="s3841"/>
    <amendment number="s3842"/>
    <amendment number="s3843"/>
    <amendment number="s3844"/>
    <amendment number="s3845"/>
    <amendment number="s3846"/>
    <amendment number="s3847"/>
    <amendment number="s3848"/>
    <amendment number="s3849"/>
    <amendment number="s3850"/>
    <amendment number="s3851"/>
    <amendment number="s3852"/>
    <amendment number="s3853"/>
    <amendment number="s3854"/>
    <amendment number="s3855"/>
    <amendment number="s3856"/>
    <amendment number="s3857"/>
    <amendment number="s3860"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/15/2006--Public Law.
Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006 - Title I: Global War on Terror Supplemental Appropriations - Chapter 1: Department of Agriculture - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for FY2006 for the global war on terror to the Department of Agriculture (USDA) for P.L. 480 title II grants (emergency and non-emergency food assistance). Chapter 2: Department of Defense - Military - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military personnel; (2) operation and maintenance (O&amp;M); (3) the Former Soviet Union Threat Reduction Account; (4) the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund; (5) the Iraq Security Forces Fund; (6) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (7) procurement; (8) research, development, test and evaluation (RDT&amp;E); (9) Defense Working Capital Funds; (10) the Defense Health Program; (11) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities related to Afghanistan and Central Asia; (12) the Office of the Inspector General; and (13) the Intelligence Community Management Account. (Sec. 1201) Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (Secretary, for purposes of this Chapter), in the national interest, to transfer between appropriations up to $2 billion of the funds made available to DOD in this Chapter. Requires congressional notification of each transfer. (Sec. 1202) Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2006 to increase from $3.75 billion to $5 billion the amount of DOD working capital funds authorized to be transferred by the Secretary for military functions. (Sec. 1203) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer to DOD appropriations up to $5.85 million from the Defense Cooperation Account. (Sec. 1204) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 to increase the amount authorized for U.S. contributions for the common-funded budgets of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). (Sec. 1205) Authorizes the use of specified DOD funds for support for counter-drug activities of the governments of Afghanistan and Pakistan. (Sec. 1206) Prohibits the total amount of advanced billings rendered or imposed for all DOD working capital funds in FY2006 from exceeding $1.2 billion. (Sec. 1207) Authorizes the use of specified DOD funds to fund the Commander's Emergency Response Program and a similar program to assist the people of Afghanistan. (Sec. 1209) Prohibits funds appropriated in this Chapter from being used to finance programs or activities denied by Congress in FY2005 and FY2006 appropriations to DOD or to initiate a procurement or RDT&amp;E new start program without prior written notification to the congressional defense committees. (Sec. 1210) Changes from May 11, 2005, to August 31, 2005, the eligibility date for retroactive payment of the additional death gratuity for survivors and dependents of certain deceased military personnel as authorized under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006. (Sec. 1211) Rescinds specified Air Force procurement funds under prior Department of Defense appropriations Acts. (Sec. 1212) Expresses the sense of Congress recognizing the importance of ensuring that absent military voters, DOD personnel, and their dependents have the opportunity to exercise the right to vote. Directs that the Interim Voting Assistance System be continued with respect to all such voters, personnel, and dependents covered by the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act. Requires a report from the Secretary to the defense committees on the status of such voting program. Provides funding. (Sec. 1213) Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) any request for funds for a fiscal year after 2007 for ongoing military operations in Afghanistan and Iraq should be included in the annual budget of the President submitted to Congress; (2) such request should include a detailed justification of anticipated uses of the funds; and (3) any funds provided in a fiscal year for ongoing military operations overseas should be provided in appropriations Acts through appropriations to specific accounts. Chapter 3: Bilateral Economic Assistance - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) for: (1) the Child Survival and Health Programs Fund; (2) development assistance; (3) international disaster and famine assistance; and (4) USAID operating expenses. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for: (1) the Economic Support Fund; (2) the Democracy Fund; (3) international narcotics control and law enforcement; (4) migration and refugee assistance; (5) international affairs technical assistance; and (6) peacekeeping operations. (Sec. 1302) Makes funds available for the Iraq Relief and Reconstruction Fund under the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense and for the Reconstruction of Iraq and Afghanistan, 2004 available for one additional year (until September 30, 2007). Revises allocation amounts appropriated under such Fund. (Sec. 1303) Rescinds $7 million of the funds made available for coalition peacekeeping operations under the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Tsunami Relief, 2005. (Sec. 1304) Amends the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2006 to prohibit funds appropriated by such Act or any prior foreign operations, export financing, and related programs appropriations Act from being obligated or expended for assistance for the Palestinian Authority unless the Secretary of State determines, and reports to the appropriations committees, that the Palestinian Authority has complied with a specified 2006 Statement that a future Palestinian government must be committed to nonviolence, recognition of Israel, and acceptance of previous agreements and obligations. Authorizes the President to waive such prohibition after making certain certifications to such committees, including that it is in the U.S. national security interest to provide such assistance, and that Hamas or any other foreign terrorist organization is not influencing the Palestinian Authority. Requires the President to report to such committees whenever such waiver is exercised. Prohibits funds appropriated in the above Act or related prior Acts from being obligated or expended for assistance for the West Bank and Gaza until the Secretary of State consults with the appropriations committees, submits a revised assistance plan to such committees, and determines and reports to such committees that appropriate procedures and safeguards exist to ensure that U.S. assistance is not provided to or through any entity or institution that such Secretary knows or has reason to believe advocates, plans, sponsors, engages in, or has engaged in terrorist activity. (Sec. 1305) Rescinds specified funds available in certain prior Acts for the Export-Import Bank of the United States for tied-aid grants. (Sec. 1306) Establishes the time for the commencement of the obligation of DOD supervision and administrative costs associated with a construction project funded with the Iraq Relief and Reconstruction Fund. Chapter 4: Department of Homeland Security - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for operating expenses of the U.S. Coast Guard. Chapter 5: Department of Defense - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to DOD for military construction. Chapter 6: Department of Justice - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Justice (DOJ) for salaries and expenses of United States Attorneys, the U.S. Marshals Service, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of State and related agencies for: (1) diplomatic and consular programs; (2) the Office of Inspector General; (3) educational and cultural exchange programs; (4) contributions for international peacekeeping activities; (5) international broadcasting operations; and (6) broadcasting capital improvements. (Sec. 1602) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize the Secretary of State (Secretary, for purposes of this section) to waive annuity limitations on foreign service agents reemployed on a temporary basis on a case-by-case basis, or to grant such authority to the head of an executive agency if: (1) and for so long as, such waiver is necessary due to an emergency involving a direct threat to life or property or other unusual circumstances; or (2) the annuitant is employed in a position for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining a qualified employee. Terminates the waiver authority on October 1, 2008. Amends the Department of State Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to provide an identical annuity limitation waiver (with the same termination date) for the Secretary with respect to temporarily reemployed annuitants in a position in the Department of State for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining, or when a temporary emergency hiring need exists. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide the same annuity limitation waiver (with the same termination date) for the USAID Administrator with respect to temporarily reemployed annuitants in a position in USAID for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining, or when a temporary emergency hiring need exists. Requires a report from the Secretary to specified congressional committees on the exercise of the waiver authorities under this section. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize the Secretary to order a member of the Foreign Service to take a leave of absence upon the member's completion of 12 (currently, 18) months of continuous service abroad. Authorizes the Secretary to provide, during any fiscal year, accommodation and subsistence to personnel in Iraq and Afghanistan for whom the Chief of Mission is responsible. (Sec. 1603) Authorizes the head of an agency, during fiscal years 2006, 2007, and 2008, to provide to an individual employed by or assigned to that agency such agency allowances, benefits, and gratuities comparable to those provided by the Secretary to members of the Foreign Service, if such individual is on official duty in Iraq or Afghanistan. Title II: Further Hurricane Disaster Relief and Recovery - Chapter 1: Department of Agriculture - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for FY2006 for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricane Katrina and other hurricanes of the 2005 season for the Department of Agriculture for: (1) executive operations; (2) the Agricultural Research Service; (3) the Natural Resources Conservation Service's (NRCS) Emergency Watershed Protection Program; and (4) rural development. (Sec. 2101) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to provide financial and technical assistance for NRCS's Emergency Watershed Protection Program. (Sec. 2102) Authorizes the Chief of NRCS to enter into agreements to donate up to 20 used vehicles currently on loan to organizations or state or local governments affected by such hurricanes. (Sec. 2103) Authorizes the Secretary to continue to use its emergency rural development authority in hurricane-affected areas for 18 additional months. Authorizes funds made available under the Community Facility Grant to be approved without regard to income limits for purposes related to the consequences of such hurricanes for structures designated by a state or local governmental entity as an emergency shelter. (Sec. 2104) Transfers specified funds under the Farm Service Agency's Emergency Conservation Program to the Department of Commerce's National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) for activities involving oysters. (Sec. 2105) Repeals provisions of the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act to Address Hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico and Pandemic Influenza, 2006 regarding assistance to oyster producers. (Sec. 2106) Directs that funds made available for the Wildlife Habitat Incentive Program remain available until expended to carry out obligations made for FY2001 and not be available for new obligations. Chapter 2: Department of Defense - Military - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military personnel; (2) operations and maintenance; (3) procurement and shipbuilding and conversion; (4) research, development, test, and evaluation; (5) Defense Working Capital Funds and the National Defense Sealift Fund; (6) General Fund Payment, Surcharge Collections, Sales of Commissary Stores, Defense; (7) the Defense Health Program; and (8) the Office of the Inspector General. (Sec. 2201) Authorizes the Secretary of Defense, to ensure the appropriate allocation of DOD funds, to transfer up to $150 million of such funds between appropriations, subject to a reporting requirement. (Sec. 2202) Prohibits the use of such funds to finance programs denied by Congress in FY2005 and FY2006 DOD appropriations or to initiate a procurement or research, development, test, and evaluation new start program without prior written notification to the congressional defense committees. (Sec. 2203) Authorizes the use of funds for Shipbuilding and Conversion, Navy, for infrastructure improvements at Gulf Coast shipyards that have existing Navy shipbuilding contracts and that were damaged by Hurricane Katrina. Chapter 3: Department of Defense - Civil - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of the Army for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for: (1) investigations; (2) construction; (3) operations and maintenance to dredge navigation channels and repair other Corps projects; and (4) flood control and coastal emergencies. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of the Interior for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for water and related resources. (Sec. 2301) Authorizes the use of unexpended funds for general remediation activities being conducted in the vicinity of the Tar Creek Superfund Site in northeastern Oklahoma and in Ottawa County, Oklahoma, to assist individuals and entities in removal from areas at risk of damage caused by land subsidence. (Sec. 2303) Directs the Corps to accelerate completion of any study or any unconstructed portion of the Mississippi River and Tributaries project for the flood and storm damage reduction projects in the south Louisiana area. (Sec. 2305) Amends: (1) the Water Resources Development Act of 1996 to extend the duration of the National Shoreline Erosion Control Development and Demonstration Program and increase the authorization of appropriations; and (2) the Reclamation States Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1991 to extend the Act until September 30, 2010, and reauthorize appropriations through FY2010. (Sec. 2309) Amends the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to provide such sums as necessary to investigate and identify environmentally sound methods for preventing and reducing the dispersal of aquatic nuisance species between the Great Lakes-Saint Lawrence drainage and the Mississippi River drainage through the Chicago River Ship and Sanitary Canal. Chapter 4: Department of Homeland Security - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for: (1) the Office of Inspector General; (2) Customs and Border Protection; (3) the U.S. Coast Guard; and (4) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). Requires: (1) for states in which the President declared a major disaster on September 24, 2005, as a result of Hurricane Rita, each county or parish eligible for individual and public assistance to be treated equally for purposes of cost-share adjustments; and (2) the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit for approval a proposal and an expenditure plan for housing, including the alternative housing pilot programs, to the House and Senate Appropriations Committees, within 45 days of this Act's enactment. Makes appropriations for the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for the cost of direct loans to assist local governments affected by the hurricanes in providing essential services. Provides that the loan amount may be equal to not more than 50% of the annual operating budget of the local government in any case in which that government has suffered a loss of 25% or more in tax revenues due to Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita. Provides that such loans may not be canceled. (Sec. 2401) Permits FEMA to provide funds to a state or local government or assume an existing agreement from such governmental unit to pay for utility costs resulting from the provision of temporary housing units to evacuees from the hurricanes. (Sec. 2402) Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006, to increase appropriations for the National Flood Insurance Fund. (Sec. 2403) Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to consider the costs for alternative housing pilot programs in the areas hardest hit by the hurricanes to be eligible under the FEMA Individual Assistance Program. Chapter 5: Departments of Agriculture and the Interior, Environmental Protection Agency - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of the Interior for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for: (1) the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service; (2) the National Park Service; (3) the U.S. Geological Survey; and (4) the Minerals Management Service. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes to: (1) the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), including for the Leaking Underground Storage Tank ; and (2) the Department of Agriculture for the National Forest System. Chapter 6: Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Labor for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for the Employment and Training Administration. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for: (1) the Human Resources and Services Administration; and (2) the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Education (DOE) for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for hurricane education recovery. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes to the Corporation for National and Community Service, including for the Civilian Community Corps. (Sec. 2601) Authorizes the Secretary of Education to waive or modify statutory or regulatory provisions related to historically Black college and university capital financing under the Higher Education Act of 1965 in connection with a Gulf hurricane disaster to ensure that: (1) the calculation of financing need for an affected institution is modified to reflect any changes in the institution's financial condition as a result of the disaster; and (2) an affected institution that was not receiving assistance under that Act before the disaster is eligible to apply for capital financing to assist in institutional recovery. (Sec. 2602) Authorizes the Secretary to extend the period during which a state or local educational agency may obligate funds made available under the Hurricane Education Recovery Act up to September 30, 2006, provided that such expenditures are for the 2005-2006 school year. (Sec. 2603) Allows funds available to the Mississippi Institutes of Higher Learning to be used to support activities authorized by the Higher Education Act. (Sec. 2604) Transfers specified FEMA disaster relief funds to the Social Security Administration for necessary expenses and losses related to the consequences of the hurricanes. Chapter 7: Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes for: (1) DOD for military construction for the Navy and Marine Corps, Air Force, Army National Guard, Air National Guard, and Navy Reserve; (2) the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA); and (3) planning, design, and construction of a new Armed Forces Retirement Home in Gulfport, Mississippi. (Sec. 2701) Waives the federal contribution limit for an armory or readiness center for projects for which funds are appropriated in this chapter. (Sec. 2702) Rescinds and transfers funds for the VA and Medical Services. (Sec. 2703) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to clean up and transfer all land parcels of the Department's land in Gulfport to the city of Gulfport. (Sec. 2704) Transfers funds to the Armed Forces Retirement Home major construction account for the planning, design, and construction of a new Armed Forces Retirement Home in Gulfport. Chapter 8: Departments of Justice and Commerce - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations for necessary expenses related to the consequences of the hurricanes to: (1) the Department of Justice (DOJ) for salaries and expenses for general legal activities and for U.S. Attorneys; (2) the Department of Commerce for NOAA, for operations, research, and facilities, and for procurement, acquisition, and construction; (3) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for exploration capabilities for necessary expenses related to such consequences, including for the Stennis Space Center and the Michoud Assembly Facility; and (4) the Small Business Administration (SBA) for the Disaster Loans Program. Chapter 9: Departments of Transportation and Housing and Urban Development - Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Transportation (DOT) for the Federal Highway Administration's Emergency Relief Program, including for projects to respond to damage caused by Hurricane Dennis and the 2004-2005 winter storms in California. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) related to the consequences of Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, or Wilma in states for which the President declared a major disaster for the Community Development Fund. Requires, prior to obligating funds: (1) states to submit plans to the Secretary of HUD detailing the proposed use of all funds, including eligibility criteria and how the use of such funds will address long-term recovery and infrastructure restoration; and (2) the Secretary to ensure that such plans give priority to infrastructure development and rehabilitation and the rehabilitation and reconstruction of the affordable rental housing stock including public and other HUD-assisted housing and to establish procedures to prevent recipients from receiving any duplication of benefits. Sets forth reporting requirements, including quarterly reports to the Appropriations Committees regarding steps to prevent fraud and abuse of funds. Makes emergency supplemental appropriations to the General Services Administration (GSA) related to the consequences of the hurricanes for the Federal Buildings Fund. Title III: Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2006 - Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2006 - (Sec. 3002) Defines specified terms. Defines "hurricane-affected county" as a county covered by a natural disaster designation related to Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, Ophelia, or Wilma, or a related condition, and each county contiguous to such county. Subtitle A: Crop and Livestock Assistance - (Sec. 3011) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide: (1) sugarcane and sugar beet disaster assistance for qualifying first processors in Louisiana counties designated as disaster areas due to Hurricanes Katrina or Rita, or related conditions; (2) sugarcane and sugar beet assistance for qualifying producers and first processors in Florida for 2005 losses in hurricane-affected counties due to hurricanes, floods, rain, or storms; and (3) assistance to sugarcane growers in Texas by making a payment to a farmer-owned cooperative sugarcane processor for demurrage, storage, and transportation costs resulting from 2005 hurricanes, wind, rains, flooding, and related conditions. (Sec. 3012) Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) livestock compensation assistance to a qualifying applicant in a hurricane-affected county who produces poultry, swine, sheep, beef, equine, buffalo, beefalo, dairy, goats, or specified other animals; (2) livestock indemnity assistance to a qualifying applicant in a hurricane-affected county who produces poultry, swine, sheep, eggs, beef, equine, buffalo, beefalo, dairy, goats, crawfish, or specified other animals; and (3) assistance (under similar conditions as the livestock indemnity program for contract growers) to poultry and egg producers in hurricane-affected counties that suffered income losses. (Sec. 3013) Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to producers of specialty crops and nursery crops in hurricane-affected counties. (Sec. 3014) Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to dairy producers for production and spoilage losses in hurricane-affected counties. (Sec. 3015) Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to producers and first-handlers of the 2005 cottonseed crop in hurricane-affected counties, which shall be: (1) distributed to producers and first handlers of cottonseed; and (2) based on cottonseed production during the most recent year for which a disaster payment specifically for cottonseed was not authorized. Subtitle B: Forestry - (Sec. 3021) Defines "tree" to include a tree (including a Christmas tree, ornamental tree, nursery tree, and potted tree), bush (including a shrub), and vine. Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to: (1) tree producers in hurricane-affected counties; and (2) fruit and tree nut producers in hurricane-affected counties for site preparation, replacement, rehabilitation, and pruning. (Sec. 3022) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to increase the funding level for the emergency forestry conservation reserve program. Provides that when evaluating an offer to enroll private nonindustrial forest land into such program the Secretary shall accord equal weight to, and not distinguish between, private nonindustrial softwood or hardwood forest lands. Subtitle C: Miscellaneous - (Sec. 3031) Limits funds that may be used to cover Farm Service Agency administrative costs under this title. (Sec. 3032) States that certain aquaculture producer grants shall be provided under the same conditions as specified assistance under the Agricultural Assistance Act of 2003. (Sec. 3033) Designates amounts made available by fund transfer pursuant to this title as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 3034) Authorizes the Secretary to promulgate implementing regulations. Title IV: Pandemic Flu - Appropriates funds to the Department of Health and Human Services for the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund to prepare for and respond to an influenza pandemic, including vaccine development and purchase. Transfers specified funds for planning and response to the avian influenza virus. Designates amounts provided for such purposes as an emergency requirement. Title V: Border Security - Chapter 1: Department of Defense - Appropriates additional amounts, to remain available until September 30, 2007, to DOD for emergency National Guard support to the Department of Homeland Security, including operating surveillance systems, analyzing intelligence, installing fences and vehicle barriers, building patrol roads, and providing training. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to transfer these funds to appropriations for military personnel, operation and maintenance, and procurement to be available for the same purposes as the appropriation or fund to which transferred. Chapter 2: Department of Homeland Security - Appropriates additional amounts for Customs and Border Protection, to remain available until September 30, 2007, for: (1) salaries and expenses; (2) air and marine interdiction, operations, maintenance, and procurement; and (3) construction. Designates such amounts as an emergency requirement. Appropriates an additional amount for Immigration and Customs Enforcement, to remain available until September 30, 2007, for salaries and expenses. Designates such amount as an emergency requirement. Appropriates an additional amount for the Office of Domestic Preparedness for discretionary grants, to remain available until September 30, 2007, for state and local programs. Designates such amount as an emergency requirement. Appropriates an additional amount for the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, to remain available until September 30, 2007, for acquisition, construction, improvements, and related expenses. Designates such amount as an emergency requirement. Chapter 3: Department of Justice - Appropriates additional amounts for the Department of Justice, to remain available until September 30, 2007, for: (1) administrative review and appeals; (2) general legal activities' salaries and expenses; and (3) United States Attorneys' salaries and expenses. Designates such amounts as an emergency requirement. Title VI: Legislative Branch - Appropriates additional funds to the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) for the U.S. Capitol power plant. Designates amounts provided for such purpose as an emergency requirement. Title VII: General Provisions and Technical Corrections - (Sec. 7002) Deems funds appropriated or made available by the transfer of funds in or pursuant to this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress for purposes of the National Security Act of 1947. (Sec. 7004) Rescinds $20 million of unobligated balances remaining available at the end of FY2005 from appropriations for salaries and expenses made available in the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005. Appropriates additional funds to the U.S. Secret Service for salaries and expenses to remain available through FY2007. (Sec. 7005) Rescinds $3.96 million of funds appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for Screening Coordination and Operations. Appropriates the same additional amount for the DHS Office of the Secretary and Executive Management. (Sec. 7006) Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2006 to repeal the requirement that the Secretary of DHS utilize the Transportation Security Clearinghouse as the central identity management system for the deployment and operation of the registered traveler program and the transportation worker identification credential program to collect and aggregate biometric data necessary for background vetting. (Sec. 7007) Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to extend from June 30, 2006, through FY2007 the period for payment of the current reclamation fee by operators of coal mining operations for deposit and transfer to the United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund (after which time, as under current law, the fee is to be established at a new rate to continue to provide for such deposit). (Sec. 7008) Appropriates additional funds through FY2007 under "Department of Labor, Mine Safety and Health Administration, Salaries and Expenses" for the inspection of coal mines and enforcement of mine safety law. Designates amounts provided for such purpose as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 7009) Requires unexpended balances for Health Resources and Services Administration grant number 7C6HF03601-01-00 appropriated in the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2001 to remain available through FY2009. (Sec. 7010) Appropriates additional funds through FY2007 for "Department of Health and Human Services, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Disease Control, Research and Training" to carry out the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 for research to develop mine safety technology, including grants and contracts. Designates amounts provided for such purpose as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 7011) Amends the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006, under "Railroad Retirement Board, Dual Benefits Payments Account," to revise the formula for payment of additional funds to the Dual Benefits Payments Account. (Sec. 7012) Amends the same Act to delay from June 30 until December 30, 2006, the alternative effective date for applicability of certain federal transportation safety regulations requiring height- and weight-appropriate child restraint systems and reverse beepers in school buses or allowable alternate vehicles to any Head Start agency or its designee that provides transportation services for children enrolled in a Head Start or Early Head Start program, if that agency or designee places such children in child restraint systems. (Sec. 7013) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated under such Act or prior Acts for "Employment and Training Administration" to pay the salary and bonuses of an individual, either as direct or indirect costs, at a rate in excess of Executive Level II, except as provided under such Act. Exempts vendors providing goods and services as defined in OMB Circular A-133. Allows any state to establish a lower limit for salaries and bonuses for those receiving salaries and bonuses from subrecipients of such funds, subject to certain conditions. (Sec. 7014) Designates as a Segal AmeriCorps Education Award any national service educational award described in the National and Community Service Act of 1990 that is made with funds appropriated to, transferred to, or interest accumulated in the National Service Trust. (Sec. 7015) Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to repeal the single holder rule for student consolidation loans which limits such loans to a lender which holds an outstanding loan of the borrower. Requires the Secretary of Education to offer an applicant borrower a direct consolidation loan if he or she is unable to obtain a consolidation loan from a lender with an agreement under HEA, or is unable to obtain such loan with income-sensitive repayment terms acceptable to the borrower from such a lender. Makes a conforming amendment to the Higher Education Reconciliation Act of 2005. (Sec. 7016) Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 to increase the authorization of appropriations for National Security Agency installations in Augusta, Georgia, and in Kunia, Hawaii. (Sec. 7018) Amends the same Act to increase the limitation on the total cost of such installations. (Sec. 7019) Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002, as amended by the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2005, to increase the acreage that the Secretary of the Navy is authorized to acquire in a specified land acquisition in Perquimans County, North Carolina. (Sec. 7020) Makes certain funds, otherwise available for Paul Coverdell Forensic Sciences Improvement Grants under the Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2006, available to the Attorney General for a specified study of forensic science. (Sec. 7021) Deems the conference report accompanying the Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 to require certain amounts made available for the Mitchell Institute in Portland, Maine, to be for the science and engineering education endowment. (Sec. 7022) Amends the same Act to require funds earmarked for the Better Business Bureau under the Act: (1) for the Iowa Department of Economic Development for the Entrepreneurial Venture Assistance Project to be used to make subgrants or loans for such project; and (2) for the Clark County Department of Aviation, Las Vegas, Nevada, for the international air trade show to be shifted to the University of Nevada Las Vegas for the same purpose. (Sec. 7023) Amends the Department of Defense, Emergency Supplemental Appropriations to Address Hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico, and Pandemic Influenza Act, 2006, under "Department of Transportation, Federal Highway Administration, Emergency Relief Program," to increase the earmark for funds to repair and reconstruct the I-10 bridge spanning New Orleans and Slidell, Louisiana. (Sec. 7024) Allows funds remaining available under specified Federal Transit Administration (FTA) grant numbers, together with a limited amount in urbanized area formula funds that were allocated by the New York Metropolitan Transportation Council to the New York City Department of Transportation as a designated recipient, to be made available to the New York Metropolitan Transportation Authority for both urbanized area formula funds and eligible capital investment grants. (Sec. 7025) Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) waive the federal matching share requirements for federal transit assistance programs (including the federal matching share requirements contained in existing federal assistance grant agreements) for recipients of such assistance directly affected by Hurricane Katrina; and (2) allow such recipients to use such assistance for operating assistance, notwithstanding the terms and conditions contained in existing federal assistance grant agreements. Terminates such authority two years after the date of enactment of this Act, unless determined otherwise by the Secretary for a compelling need. (Sec. 7026) Amends the Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2006, in the Transportation, Treasury, Housing and Urban Development, the Judiciary, the District of Columbia, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006, under "Department of the Treasury, Departmental Offices, Salaries and Expenses," to exclude from the limitation on appropriations for travel expenses any travel performed by officials in the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence and the Office of International Affairs. (Sec. 7027) Deems funds appropriated for intelligence activities, or made available by the transfer of funds, by this or other specified Acts, to be specifically authorized by Congress for intelligence activities purposes of the National Security Act of 1947, as amended, during FY2006 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006. (Sec. 7028) Amends the Department of Defense, Emergency Supplemental Appropriations to Address Hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico, and Pandemic Influenza Act, 2006 regarding additional appropriations to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) for public and Indian housing tenant-based rental assistance (vouchers) for households within the major 2005 hurricane disaster area that received project-based assistance under specified federal laws before Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Expands such assistance to certain households receiving it under the: (1) McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (currently, the Stewart B. Mckinney Homeless Assistance Act); (2) National Housing Act; and (3) Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965. Exempts such assistance from the leases and tenancy requirements of the Section 8 low-income housing voucher program under the United States Housing Act of 1937. Designates the amount provided under this section as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 7029) Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2006, in the Transportation, Treasury, Housing and Urban Development, the Judiciary, the District of Columbia, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006, to increase the amount earmarked out of funds appropriated for public and Indian Housing section 8 tenant-based rental assistance under the Act for allocation to public housing agencies in need of additional funds to administer their section 8 programs. Decreases funds earmarked to be allocated for the calendar year 2006 funding cycle on a pro rate basis to public agencies based on the amount public housing agencies were eligible to receive in calendar year 2005. (Sec. 7030) Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2006, Division A of the Transportation, Treasury, the Judiciary, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006, as well as the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations to Address Hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico and Pandemic Influenza, 2006, with respect to the terms and conditions for grants for the Economic Development Initiative (EDI) to finance a variety of targeted economic investments. Revises the reference to such terms and conditions to specify the statement of managers correction for H.R. 3058 relating to the Economic Development Initiative submitted to the House of Representatives by the Chairman of the House Committee on Appropriations on November 18, 2005. (Sec. 7031) Deems amended as follows the statement of the conference managers accompanying the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004, Division G of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2004. Substitutes Kansas City Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA) for Kansas City, Missouri, for the location of the building for use as an Incubation Center to be purchased with funds earmarked to the Missouri Soybean Association. Revises certain earmarks to specify for funds: (1) the Boys and Girls Club of Greater Washington in Silver Spring, Maryland, to renovate the Boys and Girls Clubs of Greater Washington Clubhouse #2, Clubhouse #4, Clubhouse #10, Clubhouse #11, and Clubhouse #14 in the District of Columbia in lieu of purchasing the D.C. Metropolitan Police Boys and Girls Club facility; (2) Wesleyan College in Macon, Georgia for facility renovation, build out, and construction in lieu of the City of Macon, Georgia, for construction of the historic Coca-Cola building; (3) Craig County, Virginia to purchase, renovate, build out and upgrade a library in lieu of constructing one; (4) the Minnesota Corn Growers Association in Shakopee, Minnesota, to upgrade an existing facility in lieu of constructing a new one; and (5) Holyoke Community College in Holyoke, Massachusetts for construction and renovation of the Holyoke Community College Enrollment Center in lieu of land acquisition. Replaces funds earmarked for the J. Frank Troy Senior Center in Toledo, Ohio, for renovation and construction with earmarks (whose sum equals the same dollar amount) for: (1) the Northwest Ohio Area Office on Aging for construction of the Jerusalem Township Senior Center and Food Pantry; and (2) the Aurora Gonzales Resource Center, Toledo, Ohio for renovation and build out of a facility. (Sec. 7032) Deems amended as follows the statement of the conference managers accompanying the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2005, Division I of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005. Revises certain earmarks to specify for funds: (1) the Western Five Community Development Corporation in lieu of the City of Canby, Minnesota, to construct the Prairie Farm Preservation Education and Exhibit Center; (2) the City of Buffalo, New York, for demolition and redevelopment of properties in the Broadway-Fillmore Corridor, Buffalo, New York, in lieu of renovations to the Broadway Market; (3) the Trehab Center in Montrose, Pennsylvania, for facilities acquisition in lieu of construction; (4) the Borough of Somerville in New Jersey for the Main Street Revitalization Project in lieu of an economic development planning study; (5) the St. Petersburg College, City of Seminole, Florida, for the development of Science and Nature Park at St. Petersburg College in lieu of the City of St. Petersburg, Florida, for facilities construction and renovation for the Mid-Pinellas Science Center; (6) Crossroads Rhode Island in Providence, Rhode Island, for property renovation at 754 Broad Street for the Family Center emergency shelter for families and children as well as for building renovations; and (7) the City of Brookhaven, Mississippi, for restoration of its historic City Hall in lieu of renovation of its Fire House. (Sec. 7033) Deems amended as follows the statement of the conference managers correction accompanying the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2006, Division A of the Transportation, Treasury, the Judiciary, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006. Revises certain earmarks to specify for funds: (1) the St. Mary Development Corporation, City of Dayton, Ohio, to purchase and demolish blighted property, develop detailed design/construction drawings, and to begin site preparation for new infill housing lots in lieu of street infrastructure and parking facility improvements; (2) the West Virginia University Institute of Technology Community and Technical College in lieu of the West Virginia Technical College for completion of a building for a newspaper publishing program; (3) the Borough of Mahonoy City, Pennsylvania, for improvements to Centre Street in lieu of improvements to West Market Street; (4) the Buffalo Economic Renaissance Corporation for demolition and redevelopment of properties in the Broadway-Fillmore Corridor, Buffalo, New York, in lieu of infrastructure improvements in Central Plaza Park; (5) the Crittenden County Senior Citizens (currently, Day Care) Center, Crittenden County, Kentucky, for expansion of such Center in lieu of the Day Care Center; (6) the Sunnyside Community Services in Queens, New York, for renovation and build out of a multipurpose center in lieu of construction of a senior center; (7) the Boys and Girls Club of Lancaster, Inc. in Pennsylvania (currently, City of Lancaster, Pennsylvania) for construction of the Columbia Clubhouse for the Boys and Girls Club of Lancaster; (8) the City of Greenwood, South Carolina, for the Emerald Triangle Project in lieu of the Greenwood Partnership Alliance, South Carolina, for the renovation of the Old Federal Courthouse; and (9) the UND Center for Innovation Foundation in Grand Forks, North Dakota, for the UND Technology Transfer and Commercialization Center as well as the Ina Mae Rude Entrepreneur Center. (Sec. 7034) Authorizes the Administrator of General Services to convey, without consideration, ownership and jurisdiction (custody, accountability, and control) of specified property in Divide County, North Dakota, to the City of Crosby, North Dakota. (Sec. 7035) Establishes discretionary and mandatory spending limits for the Senate Committee on Appropriations for FY2007 until a concurrent resolution on the budget for FY2007 is agreed to by both chambers.</summary>
</bill>
