<bill session="110" type="s" number="768" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fuel Economy Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase fuel economy standards for automobiles and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2700-2701"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2703-2706" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1506"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="767"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="875"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Automobile engines"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2007--Introduced.
Fuel Economy Reform Act - Amends federal transportation law to: (1) revise the definitions of automobile to require including all automobiles up to 10,000 pounds (currently, not all automobiles up to 10,000 pounds are required to be included in the definition) and passenger automobile to eliminate the exclusion of automobiles capable of off-highway operation; and (2) continue applying the current minimum corporate average fuel economy (CAFE) standards for non-passenger and passenger automobiles to automobiles manufactured through model year 2012, but, for passenger automobiles, adds an increase of four percent per year in such standard for model years 2010 through 2012. Requires an average fuel economy standard of 27.5 miles per gallon for all automobiles manufactured by all manufacturers for model year 2013, with an increase of four percent in the average fuel economy from the level for the prior model year for model year 2014 and beyond. Subjects each manufacturer of passenger automobiles manufactured in a model year, in addition to such CAFE standards, to an average fuel economy standard equal to 92% of the average fuel economy projected by the Secretary for all passenger automobiles manufactured by all manufacturers in that model year. Permits lower fuel economy standards if the minimum standards: (1) are technologically unachievable; (2) materially reduce auto safety and no offsetting safety improvements can be implemented; or (3) are not cost effective. Allows, with specified exceptions, the selling of credits between manufacturers. Allows a person who has been aggrieved by, or suffers a legal wrong because of (currently, adversely affected by), a CAFE standard to apply for judicial review. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) terminate the limitation on the number of new qualified hybrid and advanced lean burn technology vehicles eligible for the alternative motor vehicle credit; (2) extend, through 2011, the alternative vehicle credit for certain new qualified hybrid motor vehicles; and (3) allow an advanced technology motor vehicles manufacturing credit.</summary>
</bill>
