<bill session="109" type="s" number="1033" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Immigration Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secure America and Orderly Immigration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve border security and immigration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5169"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2330"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2330"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor mobility"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Unskilled labor"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2005--Introduced.
Secure America and Orderly Immigration Act - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop and implement a National Strategy for Border Security and other specified border security programs. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a Border Security Advisory Committee. Requires the Secretary of State to provide a framework for security coordination between the governments of North America. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to: (1) authorize appropriations through FY2011 for the State Criminal Alien Assistance Program; and (2) reimburse states for pre-conviction costs. Amends the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 to authorize additional funding through FY2011 to reimburse states for indirect costs of incarcerating undocumented aliens. Establishes: (1) an H-5A essential worker visa program for low-skilled workers; (2) a mechanism for subsequent adjustment of status; and (3) an Essential Worker Visa Program Task Force. Addresses document security. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to create a new Employment Eligibility Confirmation System. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to address the collection of arrival and departure information. Broadens the Department of Labor's investigative authority under INA. Authorizes the Secretary of State to enter into an agreement with foreign governments whose citizens participate in the H-5A program to establish a labor migration facilitation program. Exempts immediate relatives of U.S. citizens from the annual cap on family-sponsored immigrant visas. Increases numerical limits for specified visas. Authorizes H-5B nonimmigrant status for undocumented aliens present in the United States on the date of this Act's introduction who meet specified requirements and pay a fine. Provides a mechanism for subsequent adjustment of status. Defines "authorized representative" for immigration purposes. Makes alien victims of fraud perpetrated by unauthorized representatives eligible for U (victims of certain crimes) nonimmigrant status. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the U.S. Citizenship Foundation. Requires the Secretary to establish a competitive grant program to address civic integration. Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to extend authorization of Federal reimbursement for hospitals that provide emergency care to undocumented immigrants.</summary>
</bill>
