<bill session="113" type="h" number="2270" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose enhanced penalties for certain drug offense that take place on Federal property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2013-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) impose an additional term of up to ten years' imprisonment for cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances on federal property; (2) prohibit a person, while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on federal property, from clear cutting timber or diverting, obstructing, or draining an aquifer, spring, stream, river or body of water; and (3) apply the prohibition against assembling, maintaining, or placing a boobytrap on federal property where a controlled substance is being manufactured to federal property where a controlled substance is being cultivated. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to amend the Federal Sentencing Guidelines to provide an additional penalty increase of two offense levels if the offense of manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing, or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance or a counterfeit substance: (1) includes the use of a poison, chemical, or other hazardous substance to cultivate or manufacture controlled substances on federal property; (2) creates a hazard to humans, wildlife, or domestic animals; (3) degrades or harms the environment or natural resources; (4) pollutes an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water; (5) involves the diversion, redirection, obstruction, or draining of an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water or the clear cut of timber while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on federal property; or (6) involves the possession of a firearm while cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances on federal lands.</summary>
</bill>
