<bill session="111" type="s" number="3748" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Guard and Reserve Soft Landing Reintegration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the retention of members of the reserve components on active duty for a period of 45 days following an extended deployment in contingency operations of homeland defense missions to support their reintegration into civilian life, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412389" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6279"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1426"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
National Guard and Reserve Soft Landing Reintegration Act - Requires that a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who was deployed for more than 269 days for a contingency operation or a homeland defense mission be: (1) retained on active duty in the Armed Forces for 45 days after the end of the member's demobilization from a deployment; (2) allowed to use accrued leave; and (3) paid specified pay and allowances. Requires a member requesting an early release from such active duty to be released within 14 days after such request. Allows such request to be denied only for medical or personal safety reasons. Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide each member so retained (and, as practicable, appropriate family members) reintegration counseling and services. Provides FY2011 funding for costs of such additional active-duty retention.</summary>
</bill>
