<bill session="112" type="s" number="826" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Infrastructure Facilitation and Habitat Conservation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees to enable eligible public entities to acquire interests in real property that are in compliance with habitat conservation plans approved by the Secretary of the Interior under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2516"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2516-2517" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1907"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Infrastructure Facilitation and Habitat Conservation Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) to establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees to enable state political subdivisions&#160; to acquire interests in real property pursuant to habitat conservation plans approved by the Secretary of the Interior under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. Requires the Secretary to: (1) submit loan applications for the Secretary for Interior's review, which shall include a determination that the subdivision has adopted a complementary plan for sustainable infrastructure development that provides for the mitigation of environmental impacts; and (2) give preference to such subdivisions located in biologically rich regions in which rapid growth and development threaten successful implementation of approved habitat conservation plans.</summary>
</bill>
