<bill session="110" type="h" number="1143" updated="2013-07-19T21:13:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-04T18:57:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-03-04T18:57:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to lease certain lands in Virgin Islands National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-02-28T14:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-532.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-02-28T14:37:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="323">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 323.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04T14:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04T14:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1192-1193" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04T14:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04T14:17:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04T18:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1204-1205" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-03-04T18:57:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="88" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 378 - 0 (Roll no. 88).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1192" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04T18:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2008--Passed House amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a lease with CBI Acquisitions, LLC, governing the use of property for the continued management and operation of the Caneel Bay Resort on the island of St. John in Virgin Islands National Park. Requires any lease entered into pursuant to this Act to include the property covered by the retained use estate entered into by the Jackson Hole Preserve and the United States on September 30, 1983, (the RUE) and any associated property owned by CBI donated to the National Park Service (NPS). Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the terms of the lease agreement; (2) appraisals to determine the fair market value of all property covered by the RUE and any property, including the value, if any, of the surrendered term of the RUE, owned by CBI to be donated, or otherwise conveyed, to the NPS; and (3) compensation to the United States of the property's fair market value rent. Makes 80% of such payment available for expenditure within Virgin Islands National Park. Requires CBI, as a condition of the lease, to relinquish to the Secretary all rights under the RUE and to transfer, without compensation, ownership of improvements covered by the RUE to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
