<bill session="112" type="h" number="2186" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Leaders Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance the security of the United States and the readiness of the Armed Forces by increasing diversity within the leadership ranks of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2011--Introduced.
Military Leaders Enhancement Act - Directs Secretary of Defense (DOD) and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) in the case of the Coast Guard to: (1) prepare and implement a plan to achieve, between 2031 and 2041, a dynamic, sustainable level of Armed Forces members (including reserve components) that, among both commissioned officers and senior enlisted personnel of each armed force, reflects the diverse population of the United States eligible to serve in the Armed Forces, including gender specific, racial, or ethnic populations and diversified language and cultural skills; and (2) develop a standard set of metrics and collection procedures, uniform across the Armed Forces, to capture the inclusion and capability aspects of the Armed Forces' broader diversity plans and to verify and systematically link to strategic plans. Requires: (1) the DOD and DHS Secretaries, at least biannually, to meet with the Secretaries of the military departments, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and senior enlisted members of the Armed Forces to discuss progress on the plan; and (2) the DOD Secretary to coordinate with the National Guard Bureau and states in tracking the National Guard's progress on the plan. Directs the DOD Secretary to include in its annual defense manpower requirements report to Congress a discussion of: (1) the progress on implementing the plan while still being able to prevail in any war, prevent and deter any conflict, defeat any adversary, succeed in wide ranges of contingencies, and preserve and enhance the all-volunteer force; (2) the available pool of qualified candidates for the general officer grades of general and lieutenant general and the flag officer grades of admiral and vice admiral, including an assessment of the qualified racial or ethnic minority and female candidates. Directs the DHS Secretary to submit to Congress a related annual report.</summary>
</bill>
