<bill session="111" type="s" number="2729" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Energy Partnerships Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from uncapped domestic sources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="S11202-11203"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2009--Introduced.
Clean Energy Partnerships Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish: (1) a program to govern the creation of credits from emission reductions from uncapped domestic sources and sinks; (2) the Greenhouse Gas Emission Reduction and Sequestration Advisory Committee to provide scientific and technical advice on the establishment and implementation of such offset program; and (3) a carbon conservation program to provide incentives to landowners or grazing contractor holders to implement projects that reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions or sequester or permanently store carbon through conservation easements, sequestration contracts, and timber harvest or grazing contracts with the Department of Agriculture or the Department of the Interior. Requires the Administrator to establish a registry to record approved credits issued under such offset program. Requires each appropriate official to: (1) establish and maintain a list of types of offset projects eligible to generate offset credits under the program; and (2) prescribe regulations to ensure the emission reduction integrity of the offset projects. Authorizes the Administrator to issue offset credits for emissions reduced by specified international projects that reduce deforestation. Provides that a person is not required to hold allowances or credits for emissions resulting from the use of gas as an energy source if the gas is derived from an approved domestic methane offset project. Establishes: (1) the Carbon Conservation Fund for the carbon conservation program; and (2) the Rural Clean Energy Resources Fund to provide assistance for the development of biofuel and bioenergy, including by supporting the Rural Energy for America Program and implementing a research and demonstration program that includes approaches to sequestering carbon through agricultural, grazing, and forestry practices and reducing methane and nitrous oxide emissions associated with agricultural production.</summary>
</bill>
