<bill session="111" type="s" number="386" updated="2013-07-20T00:26:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FERA</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fraud Enforcement and Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">FERA</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Fraud Enforcement and Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">FERA</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Fraud Enforcement and Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">FERA</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Fraud Enforcement and Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">FERA</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Fraud Enforcement and Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve enforcement of mortgage fraud, securities fraud, financial institution fraud, and other frauds related to federal assistance and relief programs, for the recovery of funds lost to these frauds, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">An Act to improve enforcement of mortgage fraud, securities and commodities fraud, financial institution fraud, and other frauds related to Federal assistance and relief programs, for the recovery of funds lost to these frauds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2009-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1681-1682"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1682-1684" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-03-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="28">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 28.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-03-23">
      <text>By Senator Leahy from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 111-10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-03">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 4/02/2009 S4399" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 4/02/2009 S4399" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-20">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4408-4426" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4498" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4531-4561" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4531-4532" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4704-4641, S4657" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Cloture motion on the committee substitute amendment presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4657" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4657" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4735-4738, S4738-4741" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Cloture on the committee substitute amendment invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 84 - 4. Record Vote Number: 170.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4740" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4740" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Point of order raised against pending amendments en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4740" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4774-4781" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2009-04-28" how="roll" result="pass" roll="171" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 92 - 4. Record Vote Number: 171.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4777-4781" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Scott (VA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5260-5270" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 386.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5271-5272" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE" datetime="2009-05-06T15:39:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="235" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 367 - 59, 1 Present (Roll no. 235).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5260-5264" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Senate concurred in House amendment with an amendment (SA 1128) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5494-5495" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2009-05-14" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate concurred in the House amendment to the title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Scott (VA) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5686-5688, S5689" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 386.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Burgess objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5688" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 338 - 52 (Roll no. 268).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5686" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2009-05-20" type="public" number="111-21">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-21.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1748"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1793"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="378"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s982"/>
    <amendment number="s983"/>
    <amendment number="s984"/>
    <amendment number="s985"/>
    <amendment number="s986"/>
    <amendment number="s987"/>
    <amendment number="s988"/>
    <amendment number="s989"/>
    <amendment number="s990"/>
    <amendment number="s991"/>
    <amendment number="s992"/>
    <amendment number="s993"/>
    <amendment number="s994"/>
    <amendment number="s995"/>
    <amendment number="s996"/>
    <amendment number="s997"/>
    <amendment number="s998"/>
    <amendment number="s999"/>
    <amendment number="s1000"/>
    <amendment number="s1001"/>
    <amendment number="s1002"/>
    <amendment number="s1003"/>
    <amendment number="s1004"/>
    <amendment number="s1005"/>
    <amendment number="s1006"/>
    <amendment number="s1007"/>
    <amendment number="s1008"/>
    <amendment number="s1009"/>
    <amendment number="s1010"/>
    <amendment number="s1011"/>
    <amendment number="s1012"/>
    <amendment number="s1013"/>
    <amendment number="s1128"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Public Law.
Fraud Enforcement and Recovery Act of 2009 or FERA - (Sec. 2) Amends the federal criminal code to include within the definition of "financial institution" a mortgage lending business or any person or entity that makes, in whole or in part, a federally related mortgage loan. Defines "mortgage lending business" as an organization that finances or refinances any debt secured by an interest in real estate, including private mortgage companies and their subsidiaries, and whose activities affect interstate or foreign commerce. Extends the prohibition against making false statements in a mortgage application to employees and agents of a mortgage lending business. Applies the prohibition against defrauding the federal government to fraudulent activities involving the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) or a federal economic stimulus, recovery, or rescue plan. Expands securities fraud provisions to cover fraud involving options and futures in commodities. Expands the concept of monetary proceeds, for purposes of enforcing prohibitions against money laundering, to include gross receipts. Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to the prosecution of money laundering crimes in combination with other closely-connected offenses. Requires the Attorney General to report to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees on such prosecutions. (Sec. 3) Authorizes appropriations to the Attorney General for FY2010-FY2011 for investigations, prosecutions, and civil and administrative proceedings involving federal assistance programs and financial institutions. Allocates such funds among various departments of the Department of Justice (DOJ). Requires that an appropriate percentage of such funds be used to investigate mortgage fraud. Authorizes additional appropriations to the U.S. Postal Service, the Inspector General for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), the U.S. Secret Service, and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), including the Office of Inspector General, in FY2010-FY2011 for similar investigations. Requires the Attorney General, in consultation with the U.S. Postal Inspection Service, the Inspector General for HUD, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the SEC Commissioner [sic], to submit a report to Congress identifying: (1) amounts spent for investigations, with a certification of compliance that funds have been spent in accordance with this Act; and (2) amounts recovered from criminal or civil restitution, fines, penalties, and other monetary recoveries. (Sec. 4) Amends the False Claims Act to: (1) expand liability under such Act for making false or fraudulent claims to the federal government; and (2) apply liability under such Act for presenting a false or fraudulent claim for payment or approval (currently limited to such a claim presented to an officer or employee of the federal government). Requires persons who violate such Act to reimburse the federal government for the costs of a civil action to recover penalties or damages. Modifies and expands provisions of the False Claims Act relating to intervention by the federal government in civil actions for false claims, sharing of information by the Attorney General with a claimant, retaliatory relief, and service upon state or local authorities in sealed cases. (Sec. 5) Establishes in the legislative branch the Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission to examine the causes of the current U.S. financial and economic crisis, taking into account fraud and abuse in the financial sector and other specified factors. Requires the Commission to submit a final report on its findings to the President and Congress on December 15, 2010. Requires the Commission chairperson to appear before the House Committee on Financial Services and the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs within 120 days after the submission of such report. Terminates the Commission 60 days after the submission of such report. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
