<bill session="111" type="s" number="3023" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Outsourcing Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to phase out the use of private military contractors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4650"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2010--Introduced.
Stop Outsourcing Security Act - Directs the Secretary of State to ensure that only government personnel provide security services at U.S. diplomatic or consular missions in Iraq or Afghanistan. Requires the President to report to Congress, by June 1, 2010, on the status of planning for the use, by January 1, 2011, of government and military personnel instead of private contractors for mission critical or emergency essential functions in all conflict zones where Congress has authorized the use of force. Directs any individual or entity under contract with the federal government to provide mission critical or emergency essential functions after such date to allow Congress to examine their accounting practices. Outlines additional requirements relating to renewals of such contracts. Authorizes specified congressional access to contracts and task orders in excess of $5 million entered into by the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of State, the Department of the Interior, and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) during the period beginning October 1, 2001, and ending on the last day of the month during which this Act is enacted for work to be performed in Iraq and Afghanistan. Requires certain reports to Congress regarding contracts for the performance of work in Iraq and Afghanistan.</summary>
</bill>
