<bill session="110" type="h" number="3338" updated="2013-07-19T21:33:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southern New Jersey Veterans Comprehensive Health Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to expand the capability of the Department of Veterans Affairs to provide for the medical-care needs of veterans in southern New Jersey.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2007--Introduced.
Southern New Jersey Veterans Comprehensive Health Care Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to determine, and notify Congress, whether the needs of veterans in southern New Jersey (the counties of Ocean, Burlington, Camden, Gloucester, Salem, Cumberland, Atlantic, and Cape May) for full-service medical care shall be met through a project for: (1) inpatient and outpatient services and long-term care to veterans at an existing facility in southern New Jersey; or (2) construction of a new full-service, Department of Veterans Affairs medical center to provide inpatient and outpatient services and long-term care to veterans in southern New Jersey. Directs the Secretary: (1) if the existing facility option is chosen, to enter into an appropriate agreement for the provision of such care and services; or (2) if the new construction option is chosen, to carry out an appropriate major medical facility construction project for such purpose.</summary>
</bill>
