<bill session="112" type="h" number="6403" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MADE Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Manufacturing Assistance Driving Efficiency Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for grants in lieu of expensing under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for energy efficient commercial buildings placed in service by manufacturers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Introduced.
Manufacturing Assistance Driving Efficiency Act of 2012 or MADE Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to provide grants to manufacturers who place energy efficient commercial building property in service: (1) during 2012 or 2013; or (2) after 2013 and before 2016, provided the construction of such property began during 2012 or 2013. Limits such a grant to: (1) the basis of such property, or (2) 50% of any excess of the rate to be paid under a power purchase agreement for renewable energy resources for use in such property over the standard electrical rate, and (3) the allowable income tax deduction for the cost of energy efficient commercial building property placed in service during a taxable year.</summary>
</bill>
