<bill session="111" type="h" number="6539" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reducing American Hunger Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to promote nutrition, to increase access to food, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400426"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="596"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2010--Introduced.
Reducing American Hunger Act - Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (the Food Stamp Act of 1977 as renamed by the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008) to provide that Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits (formerly, food stamp benefits) shall be: (1) redeemable by the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) at face value increased by an amount equal to 100% of benefits used to purchase produce; and (2) used to purchase produce at 50% of the prevailing produce prices in participating retail food stores. States that fingerprinting or other forms of biometric testing of household members shall not be required for SNAP participation. Directs the Secretary to require appropriate states to: (1) submit to the Secretary reports identifying SNAP participation in the 25 largest U.S. cities; and (2) implement practices to increase program participation in cities where eligible household participation is less than 85%. Increases funding for grants to increase program participation. Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to support the use of electronic benefits transfers for federal nutrition programs at farmers' markets.</summary>
</bill>
