<bill session="112" type="h" number="3776" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SKILLS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening Kids' Interest in Learning and Libraries</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding school libraries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/17/2012--Introduced.
Strengthening Kids' Interest in Learning and Libraries Act or SKILLS Act - Amends part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require the inclusion of effective school library programs in school improvement programs. Defines an "effective school library program" as one that: (1) is staffed by a state sanctioned school librarian; (2) has up-to-date materials and technology, including broadband; (3) includes regular collaboration between teachers and school librarians concerning school reform efforts; and (4) supports the development of digital literacy skills. Replaces the existing program under subpart 4 (Improving Literacy Through School Libraries) of part B of title I of the ESEA with a new program (Improving Literacy and College and Career Readiness Through Effective School Library Programs) awarding competitive three-year grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to develop and enhance effective school library programs. Makes LEAs eligible for such grants only if at least 20% of their students are impoverished. Amends part A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund) of title II of the ESEA to rename part A the Teacher, School Librarian, and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund. Requires states and LEAs to use funds under the program to train school librarians, and recruit and retain highly effective school librarians.</summary>
</bill>
