<bill session="109" type="s" number="1891" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the leasing, development, production, and economically feasible and prudent transportation of oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2005-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="39"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2005--Introduced.
Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2005 - Declares that Congress authorizes the leasing, development, production, and economically feasible transportation of oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will result in an environmentally sound program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Coastal Plain, while taking into consideration the interests and concerns of residents of the Coastal Plain, which is the homeland of the Kaktovikmiut Inupiat. Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to repeal the prohibition against production of oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR), including any leasing or development leading to such production. States that, for purposes of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, the Coastal Plain oil and gas leasing program is compatible with the purposes for which ANWR was established, and that no further findings or decisions are required to implement this determination. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) designate a maximum total of Coastal Plain acreage as "Special Areas"; (2) permit oil and gas exploration leasing in such Areas (but prohibit surface occupancy); and (3) permit horizontal drilling technology from lease sites located outside the Special Areas. Prohibits the Secretary from closing land within the Coastal Plain to oil and gas leasing, exploration, development, or production, except in accordance with this Act. Prescribes procedures for: (1) lease sales; (2) grants of leases; (3) lease terms and conditions; (4) Coastal Plain environmental protection; (5) expedited judicial review; and (6) federal and state distribution of revenues. Shields from Title XI of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act the rights-of-way and easements issued by the Secretary for oil and gas transportation across the Coastal Plain. Directs the Secretary to convey: (1) the surface estate of specified lands to the Kaktovik Inupiat Corporation; and (2) the remaining subsurface estate of specified lands to the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation. Establishes the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund to provide financial assistance to specified entities that are directly impacted by oil and gas production and exploration on the Coastal Plain, as determined by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
