<bill session="112" type="h" number="2126" updated="2013-07-20T01:28:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Risk Retention Modernization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modernize the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986 and expand coverage to include commercial property insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2011-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2011--Introduced.
Risk Retention Modernization Act of 2011 - Amends the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986 to require the Director of the Federal Insurance Office to: (1) report periodically to the President and Congress on the extent of state compliance with the Act's prohibition against state regulation of risk retention and purchasing groups that are not domiciliaries of the state; and (2) issue certain corporate governance standards, meeting specified criteria, for risk retention groups. Extends the coverage of the Act to risk retention groups offering commercial property insurance. Applies to commercial property insurance the exemption of purchasing groups from state law. Revises procedures for: (1) submitting financial documents to state insurance commissioners, and (2) mandatory disclosures. Imposes a fiduciary duty upon the board of directors of a risk retention group to operate in the best interests of the group. Redesignates the Act as the Risk Retention Act.</summary>
</bill>
