<bill session="111" type="h" number="4398" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address public safety risks in western States by facilitating insect and disease infestation treatment of National Forest System land and certain adjacent land, to make permanent the good-neighbor authority for Colorado and stewardship contracting authorities available to the Forest Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412298" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2010-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2798"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2009--Introduced.
National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2009 - Designates certain areas of National Forest System land in the states of Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming as insect and disease emergency areas. Allows the designation of an area of System land as an additional insect and disease emergency area if the land: (1) is located in an affected state; and (2) is subject to an insect and disease infestation emergency. Excludes certain lands from inclusion in an insect and disease emergency area. Sets forth requirements for the duration of insect and disease emergency areas designated under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary), in implementing the emergency forest restoration program, to make payments to owners of nonindustrial private forest land to carry out emergency measures in response to an insect and disease infestation emergency under this Act. Authorizes the: (1) Secretary to offer to enter into any contracts or other agreements with the state of Colorado to perform watershed restoration and protection services on System land in the state when similar and complementary restoration and protection services are being carried out on adjacent state or private land; and (2) Secretary of the Interior to carry out such activities on public land located in Colorado. Extends permanently the authority under which the Forest Service may enter into such contracts with private persons and entities to perform services to achieve land management goals for the national forests that meet local and rural communities' needs. Bars the Forest Service from obligating funds to cover the costs of canceling Forest Service multiyear stewardship end result contracts until the date on which they are canceled.</summary>
</bill>
