<bill session="110" type="h" number="802" updated="2013-07-19T21:10:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Act to Prevent Pollution from ships to implement MARPOL Annex VI.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships to implement MARPOL Annex VI.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E257-258"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-54.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-03-20T12:11:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="25">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cummings moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3025-3028" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 802.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3053" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-03-26T18:55:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="187" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 359 - 48 (Roll no. 187).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3025-3026" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-26T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-394.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-06-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="828">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 828.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2008-06-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6303-6304" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6303-6304" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Oberstar moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 802.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-07-08T15:57:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6191-6196" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6191-6192" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-07-08">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-07-21">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-07-21" type="public" number="110-280">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-280.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Antarctic regions"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine engines"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ozone layer depletion"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tankers"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2008--Public Law.
Maritime Pollution Prevention Act of 2008 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (Act) to provide for the adoption of Annex VI (Prevention of Air Pollution From Ships Enforcement) of the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973 (MARPOL Convention, which includes any Protocols or Annexes entered into force for the United States). Makes the Act, with respect to Annex VI, applicable to: (1) ships in a port, shipyard, offshore terminal, or U.S. internal waters; (2) a ship that is bound for, or departing from, a port, shipyard, offshore terminal, or the internal waters of the United States and is in navigable U.S. waters or the U.S. Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ), an emission control, or other specified area; (3) a ship that is entitled to fly the flag of, or operating under the authority of, a party to Annex VI and is in navigable U.S. waters or the EEZ, an emission control, or other specified area; and (4) any other ship to the extent that, and in the same manner as, such ship may be boarded to implement or enforce any other U.S. law or Annex I, II, or V of the Convention, and that is in the EEZ or an emission control or other specified area. Authorizes, but does not require with respect to Annex VI, federal agency heads to determine that some or all Act requirements apply regarding vessel air emissions for public vessels operated under an agency's authority. Prohibits construing provisions relating to ships that are subject to preventive measures to restrict in a manner inconsistent with international law navigational rights and freedoms as defined by U.S. law, treaty, convention, or customary international law. (Sec. 5) Permits only the Administrator (the Administrator) of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and no other person, to issue Engine International Air Pollution Prevention certificates in accordance with Annex VI and the International Maritime Organization's Technical Code on Control of Emissions of Nitrogen Oxides from Marine Diesel Engines, on behalf of the United States for a documented U.S. vessel. (Sec. 6) Gives a certificate issued by a country that is a party to the MARPOL Protocol of 1978 (MARPOL Protocol, which includes the Convention) the same validity as a certificate issued by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard (the Secretary) is operating (currently) or the Administrator. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary and the Administrator, after consulting with appropriate federal agencies, jointly to prescribe regulations setting criteria for determining the adequacy of reception facilities for receiving ozone depleting substances, equipment containing such substances, and exhaust gas cleaning residues at a port or terminal, and stating any additional measures and requirements as are appropriate to ensure such adequacy. Permits denial of entry to a ship to a port without adequate reception facilities to receive such substances and residues. (Sec. 8) Authorizes the Secretary to inspect a ship to which the Act applies to verify whether the ship is in compliance with Annex VI to the Convention and the Act and permits either the Secretary or the Administrator to undertake enforcement actions if an inspection or any other information indicates that there is a violation. (Sec. 9) Authorizes the Secretary of State, after consulting with the Secretary (currently) or the Administrator, to act for the United States on Protocol and related amendments, including proposed amendments to Annex VI to the Protocol. (Sec. 10) Permits the Administrator (currently, only the Secretary) to assess civil penalties. (Sec. 12) Allows any person having an interest which is, or can be, adversely affected to bring an action on his own behalf against the Administrator for a failure to perform any nondiscretionary act or duty.</summary>
</bill>
