<bill session="113" type="s" number="1041" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Crime Victims' Rights Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to afford crime victims' rights to victims of offenses under the Uniform Code of Military Justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3850-3851"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Military Crime Victims' Rights Act of 2013 - Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to provide specific rights for victims of offenses under the UCMJ, including the right to: (1) be protected from the accused; (2) reasonable, accurate, and timely notice of any public proceeding involving the offense; (3) not be excluded from such proceeding (with an exception), and to be heard; (4) confer with trial counsel in the case; (5) full and timely restitution; (6) proceedings free from unreasonable delay; and (7) be treated with fairness and respect for the victim's dignity and privacy. Requires the military judge to ensure such rights in any court-martial proceeding, and requires all others involved in the matter (counsel, investigators, etc.) to make their best efforts to afford such rights. Provides for the enforcement of such rights throughout the process. Provides for the assumption of such rights by a legal guardian, family member, or estate representative in the case of a victim who is under 18 years old, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased. Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to modify the Manual for Courts-Martial to prescribe regulations for the enforcement of such rights.</summary>
</bill>
