<bill session="112" type="h" number="5929" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Next Steps for Credit Availability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Investment Company Act of 1940 to change the asset coverage ratio and treatment of preferred stock for business development companies, to allow business development companies to purchase, otherwise acquire, or hold certain securities, and to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise rules under the Securities Act of 1933 relating to business development companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412420" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2012-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2012--Introduced.
Next Steps for Credit Availability Act - Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to allow a business development company (BDC) to own or acquire securities or other interests in the business of a registered investment adviser or adviser to an investment company. Reduces from 200% to 150% the asset coverage requirements applicable to BDCs. Allows a BDC to issue stock. Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise various rules under the Securities Act of 1933 and to revise forms as necessary to allow a BDC to use security offering rules available to other issuers that are required to file security issuance reports under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</summary>
</bill>
