<bill session="111" type="s" number="4051" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Espionage Statutes Modernization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve, modernize, and clarify the espionage statutes contained in chapter 37 of title 18, United States Code, to promote Federal whistleblower protection statutes and regulations, to deter unauthorized disclosures of classified information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10930-10931"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10931-10932" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Introduced.
Espionage Statutes Modernization Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to five years on a covered individual who intentionally discloses, delivers, communicates, or transmits classified information, without authorization, knowing or having reason to know that such action is a violation of the terms of the classified information nondisclosure agreement entered into by such individual.&#160; Defines "covered individual" as an officer, employee, contractor, or consultant of a federal agency who agrees to be legally bound by the terms of a classified information nondisclosure agreement.&#160; Exempts from such prohibition disclosures made in accordance with a federal whistleblower protection statute&#160;or regulation. Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to review and, if appropriate, amend federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to a person convicted of an offense under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
