<bill session="109" type="h" number="1473" updated="2013-07-19T19:17:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telecommunications Ownership Diversification Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a deferral of tax on gain from the sale of telecommunications businesses in specific circumstances or a tax credit and other incentives to promote diversity of ownership in telecommunications businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Direct broadcast satellites"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2005--Introduced.
Telecommunications Ownership Diversification Act of 2005 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a taxpayer election to exclude from gross income a portion of the gain from the sale of the assets of a telecommunications business to an eligible purchaser. Defines "eligible purchaser" as: (1) any economically and socially disadvantaged business as designated by the Secretary of the Treasury using specified criteria; or (2) a corporation or partnership which, following the sale of a telecommunications business, owns substantially all of the assets of such business and is at least five percent owned by the Telecommunications Development Fund established under the Communications Act of 1934. Allows an investment tax credit of ten percent of the taxable income of any local exchange carrier that is not a Bell operating company and is headquartered in an area designated as an empowerment zone by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development. Allows the exclusion from gross income of 50 percent of the gain from the sale or exchange of stock, held for more than five years, in an eligible purchaser engaged in a telecommunications business. Directs the Comptroller General, not later than January 1, 2007, and two years thereafter, to audit and report on the administration of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
