<bill session="112" type="s" number="1827" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Prosecutor Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Trade Enforcement Division in the Office of the United States Trade Representative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2011--Introduced.
Trade Prosecutor Act of 2011 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to establish within the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) a Trade Enforcement Division. Establishes the position of Deputy United States Trade Representative for Trade Enforcement to head the Trade Enforcement Division. Requires the Deputy to ensure that our trading partners comply with trade agreements to which this country is a party. Establishes within the Trade Enforcement Division an Office of Trade Assistance for Small Business to provide technical and legal assistance and advice to certain small businesses that enables them to prepare and file petitions for a USTR response to violations of trade agreements by foreign governments. Establishes within the Office of the USTR the position of Chief Manufacturing Negotiator. Requires the Chief Manufacturing Negotiator to act as a vigorous advocate on behalf of this country's manufacturing interests.</summary>
</bill>
