<bill session="113" type="h" number="2447" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Committee on Technology under the National Science and Technology Council to develop a national manufacturing competitiveness strategic plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400630"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2013 - Directs the Committee on Technology under the National Science and Technology Council to develop, in lieu of the currently required strategic plan to guide federal programs and activities in support of advanced manufacturing research and development, a national manufacturing competitiveness strategic plan to improve government coordination and provide long-term guidance for federal programs and activities in support of U.S. manufacturing competitiveness, including advanced manufacturing research and development. Requires the Secretary of Commerce, in developing and updating the plan quadrennially, to serve as the chairperson of the Committee. Specifies the goals of the plan to be to: (1) promote growth in the U.S. manufacturing sector, (2) support the development of a skilled manufacturing workforce, (3) enable innovation and investment in domestic manufacturing, and (4) support national security. Requires the Committee, as part of the development of the plan, to conduct an analysis of specified factors that impact the competitiveness and growth of the U.S. manufacturing sector. Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to transmit the plan, and subsequent updates, to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
