<bill session="113" type="s" number="42" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:25-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-04">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide anti-retaliation protections for antitrust whistleblowers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S156"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S156-157" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="233">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 233.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-11-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7799-7800" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7799-7800" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-11-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act of 2013 - Prohibits discharging or in any other manner discriminating against a whistleblower in terms and conditions of employment because: (1) the whistleblower provided information to the employer or the federal government concerning a violation of antitrust law or another criminal law committed in conjunction with a potential violation of antitrust law; or (2) the whistleblower participated in, or otherwise assisted, an investigation relating to such a violation. Allows a whistleblower who alleges discharge or other discrimination to seek relief: (1) by filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor; or (2) if the Secretary has not issued a final decision within 180 days of filing such complaint, to bring an action at law or equity. Entitles a whistleblower who prevails in any such action to all relief necessary to make such whistleblower whole.</summary>
</bill>
