<bill session="112" type="h" number="1819" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Wildlife Management Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to provide for State management of population segments of gray wolves in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400276"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2012-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2011--Introduced.
State Wildlife Management Act of 2011 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) to prohibit any gray wolf from being treated as an endangered species or threatened species or from being subject to such Act if the wolf: (1) is located in any state within the range of the Northern Rocky Mountain distinct population segment or anywhere in Nevada or Colorado and there are at least 450 gray wolves in such segment; (2) is located in any state within the range of the Western Great Lakes distinct population segment and the number of gray wolves within such state's boundaries is at least 1,200 for Minnesota, 150 for Michigan, and 150 for Wisconsin; or (3) is located in Arizona or New Mexico if the combined total number of gray wolves in those states is at least 100. Provides for: (1) state regulation of gray wolves if the population meets or exceeds the applicable number for such state; or (2) treatment as an endangered or threatened species if the number of gray wolves is less than that number until the Secretary determines that the number of gray wolves in such state equals at least that number during two consecutive years. Defines "gray wolf" as any taxonomic group traditionally associated with the gray wolf, including Canus lupus, Canus lupus lycaon, and Canus lupus baileyi, regardless of specific taxonomy of any particular gray wolf variety as a species, subspecies, or other designation.</summary>
</bill>
