<bill session="109" type="s" number="1337" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair and Reliable Medical Justice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restore fairness and reliability to the medical justice system and promote patient safety by fostering alternatives to current medical tort litigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2005-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7635-7637"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7637-7638" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-710.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2005--Introduced.
Fair and Reliable Medical Justice Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award up to ten demonstration grants to states for the development, implementation, and evaluation of alternatives to current tort litigation for resolving disputes over injuries allegedly caused by health care providers or health care organizations. Requires such states to: (1) develop such an alternative to current tort litigation; and (2) promote a reduction of health care errors by allowing for patient safety data related to such disputes to be collected and analyzed by organizations that engage in voluntary efforts to improve patient safety and the quality of health care delivery. Sets forth model alternatives to current tort litigation that states may utilize.</summary>
</bill>
