<bill session="109" type="s" number="3799" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cyanide Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Department of Homeland Security to regulate retail sales of hydrogen cyanide and its salts, and to require the Department of Homeland Security and Department of Justice to conduct a joint study about the risk of use of commercial products including cyanide by terrorists and potential preventative regulations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Poisons"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Cyanide Safety Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to require any person who sells or otherwise transfers, at a retail level, hydrogen cyanide and its salts, to: (1) obtain a license for such sale from the Secretary; and (2) record such sale or transfer, including the identity and address of the recipient and the intended use. Directs the Secretary and the Attorney General to conduct a study of the manufacturing and distribution process of cyanide to determine actions to safeguard the public from its wrongful use, particularly by terrorists, including a determination as to the feasibility and desirability of establishing a central registry of all lot specifications of cyanide to provide quick access to investigative and law enforcement agencies.</summary>
</bill>
