<bill session="112" type="hj" number="6" updated="2013-07-20T02:08:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States waiving the application of the first article of amendment to the political speech of corporations and other business organizations with respect to the disbursement of funds in connection with public elections and granting Congress and the States the power to establish limits on contributions and expenditures in elections for public office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="7"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="8"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Waives application of the First Amendment to the political speech of any corporation, partnership, business trust, association, or other business organization with respect to the making of contributions, expenditures, or other disbursements of funds in connection with public elections. Grants Congress the power to set limits on the amounts of contributions and expenditures with respect to candidates in a federal election. Grants a state the power to set limits on the amounts of contributions and expenditures with respect to candidates in a state or local election.</summary>
</bill>
