<bill session="112" type="s" number="1604" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Port of Entry Personnel and Infrastructure Funding Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide additional resources and funding for construction and infrastructure improvements at United States land ports of entry, to open additional inspection lanes, to hire more inspectors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Emergency Port of Entry Personnel and Infrastructure Funding Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to hire, by the end of FY2016, an additional: (1) 5,000 full-time U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) officers to serve on all inspection lanes and enforcement teams at U.S. land ports of entry on the northern and southern borders of the United States, and (2) 350 full-time support staff for all U.S. ports of entry. Directs the Secretary to: (1) equip each CBP officer with a secure communication and satellite-enabled device that allows communication between ports of entry and inspection stations, and with federal, state, local, and tribal law enforcement entities; and (2) establish a grant program for the purchase of detection equipment at land ports of entry and communication and biometric devices for state and local law enforcement officers serving on the southern border. Authorizes: (1) the Commissioner of CBP to construct land ports of entry, acquire necessary land or land interests, and construct additional ports of entry along the borders; and (2) the Secretary to acquire necessary real property leaseholds. Authorizes appropriations. Rescinds specified funds equal to such appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
