<bill session="113" type="s" number="567" updated="2013-11-05T04:46:38-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Social Security Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the retirement of American families by strengthening Social Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="649"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3118"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="308"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Strengthening Social Security Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe special rules for the determination of taxable wages and self-employment income above the contribution and benefit base after 2013. Amends SSA title II to include surplus average indexed monthly earnings (AIME) in the determination of primary OASDI amounts. Directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) of the Department of Labor to prepare and publish the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI-EC) that indicates changes over time in expenditures for consumption which are typical for individuals in the United States who have attained early retirement age for purposes of an old-age, wife's, or husband's insurance benefit. Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to make the CPI-EC the applicable Consumer Price Index (CPI) for computation of cost-of-living increases in OASDI benefits for such individuals.</summary>
</bill>
