<bill session="111" type="h" number="5560" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quality Cancer Care for Life Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve quality of cancer care and quality of life for patients and survivors by coordinating development and distribution of information about relieving pain, symptoms, side effects, and stress; increasing awareness of treatment and post-treatment health risks for survivors; enhancing research into symptom management and survivorship; increasing health care professional education and training; reducing health disparities in cancer treatment, symptom management, and survivorship care; and expanding and enhancing cancer registries; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412268" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2010-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2010--Introduced.
Quality Cancer Care for Life Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to improve the quality of cancer care and the quality of life for cancer patients and survivors by expanding CDC cancer control programs, including the National Comprehensive Cancer Control Program and the National Program of Cancer Registries. Requires the Director of CDC to award grants to: (1) develop, implement, and evaluate cancer case management and coordination programs to enhance the quality of cancer care and the quality of life for patients and survivors and to improve cancer outcomes; and (2) train individuals to undertake the quality of life needs of cancer patients, survivors, and family caregivers. Requires the Secretary to establish a Quality of Life Advisory Committee to advise, coordinate, and assist the CDC in creating and conducting the cancer quality of life and survivorship activities, program enhancements, and training initiatives under this Act. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to undertake additional cancer quality of life and survivorship research that addresses pain, symptom management, side effects and late effects, and psychosocial factors to improve cancer clinical communication and care planning, treatment and post-treatment, and follow-up care across the life course.</summary>
</bill>
