<bill session="112" type="h" number="1751" updated="2013-07-20T01:25:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CJ's Home Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 to require that weather radios be installed in all manufactured homes manufactured or sold in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-08-01T19:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-191.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-08-01T19:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="124">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 124.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2011--Reported to House without amendment.
CJ's Home Protection Act of 2011 - Requires the consensus committee established under the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974, within 90 days of enactment of this Act, to develop and submit to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) proposed federal manufactured home construction and safety standards. Requires the Secretary to issue a final order promulgating the standard within 90 days after receiving the proposal. Amends the Act to require such standards to require each manufactured home delivered for sale to be supplied with a weather radio: (1) capable of broadcasting emergency information relating to local weather conditions, (2) equipped with a tone alarm and Specific Alert Message Encoding (SAME) technology, and (3) compliant with the Consumer Electronics Association (CEA) Standard 2009-A Performance Specification for Public Alert Receivers (or its current revision). Exempts any aspect of the function, operation, performance, capabilities, or utilization of such weather radio or any related instructions from certain requirements regarding: (1) noncompliance with standards or defective nature of manufactured homes, (2) notification and correction of defects by such manufacturers, or (3) the Secretary's regulations pursuant to the authority under such Act. Requires the Secretary to study whether to condition the applicability of the requirement to supply weather radios in manufactured homes on the geographic location at which a manufactured home is placed, but only to the extent that such requirement applies to new manufactured homes and new site-built homes.</summary>
</bill>
