<bill session="109" type="s" number="3703" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Prescription Drug Lifeline Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a temporary process for individuals entering the Medicare coverage gap to switch to a plan that provides coverage in the gap.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8062-8063"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Introduced.
Medicare Prescription Drug Lifeline Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a process under which an individual may terminate enrollment in the prescription drug plan or the Medicare Advantage Prescription Drug (MA-PD) Plan in which he or she is enrolled and enroll in any prescription drug plan or MA-PD Plan serving the area where the individual resides that provides some coverage of covered part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) drugs after the individual has reached the initial coverage limit but not yet the annual out-of-pocket threshold. Sets forth a special rule permitting applicable individuals to enroll in a prescription drug plan outside the region in which they reside. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on: (1) the costs to the Medicare program of eliminating the initial coverage limit and providing specified standard prescription drug coverage until the individual reaches the annual out-of-pocket threshold; and (2) the adjustment to the applicable coinsurance that would be necessary to eliminate the initial coverage limit under such conditions without increasing the costs to the Medicare program.</summary>
</bill>
