<bill session="111" type="h" number="5997" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anti-Pork Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives and the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to require that public hearings be held on all earmark requests in the district of the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner making the request, and to further increase earmark transparency and accountability.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Anti-Pork Act of 2010 - Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner (Member) requesting a congressional earmark in any bill or joint resolution (or an accompanying report) to provide a written statement to the chair and ranking minority member of the committee of jurisdiction certifying that specified requirements have been met. Requires a governmental entity or nonprofit, earmark recipient within the district of, and designated by, the Member to have held a public hearing on the congressional earmark at least 30 days before its submission to the committee. Requires notice of the public hearing to have been printed in the appropriate local newspaper at least 15 days before the hearing. Requires further that, if such earmark request is for public improvement purposes, the local government entity with jurisdiction over the requested improvement has passed a resolution in support of the earmark request or written a binding official communication in its support. Limits the amount of appropriated funds for the project to 50% of its total cost. Prohibits an earmark from funding any administrative costs. Requires the requesting Member to have posted the earmark request on his or her public website, including the name and address of the intended recipient or, if there is no specifically intended recipient, the intended location of the activity, the earmark's purpose, and the 30-day public hearing notice. Amends Rule X (Organization of Committees) to require any subcommittee of the House Committee on Appropriations to hold a hearing on all requested earmarks to be included in a measure or any accompanying report before it approves such legislation. Requires a 14-day advance public notice of the hearing on the committee website. Requires the Member requesting an earmark to testify in its support at the applicable subcommittee hearing.</summary>
</bill>
