<bill session="112" type="s" number="985" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the definition of a law enforcement officer under subchapter III of chapter 83 and chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, respectively, to ensure the inclusion of certain positions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="327"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act of 2011 - Amends the definition of the term "law enforcement officer" under provisions of the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) and the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) to include: (1) federal employees not otherwise covered by such term whose duties include the investigation or apprehension of suspected or convicted individuals and who are authorized to carry a firearm; and (2) such employees of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) whose duties are primarily the collection of delinquent taxes and the securing of delinquent returns. Requires such service that is performed by an incumbent law enforcement officer: (1) on or after enactment of this Act to be treated for all purposes other than retirement as service performed as a law enforcement officer; and (2) before, on, or after enactment of this Act to be treated for federal retirement purposes as service performed as such an officer if an appropriate written election is submitted to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) not later than the earlier of five years after the date of enactment of this Act and the day before the incumbent separates from government service. Provides that nothing under current law respecting mandatory separation from government service under CSRS or FERS shall cause the involuntary separation of an officer before the end of the three-year period following enactment.</summary>
</bill>
