<bill session="113" type="h" number="2269" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Multi-Hazard School Disaster Planning and Response Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to allow funds provided under the Matching Grant Program for School Security to be used to improve information sharing between law enforcement and schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400274"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2013--Introduced.
Multi-Hazard School Disaster Planning and Response Act of 2013 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to allow funds provided under the Matching Grant Program for School Security to be used for the following law enforcement and school information sharing activities: (1) establishing or improving an electronic data management system for the purpose of sharing specified emergency response plan data with first responders; (2) assisting local law enforcement and local schools with costs associated with collecting information on, evaluating, updating, and digitizing such plan data and making plans electronically available to local dispatch centers and first responders through mobile data terminals and mobile data computers; and (3) enabling law enforcement to consult with schools to develop emergency plans, including such plan data, to ensure that plans are comprehensive, complete, and current. Requires the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services to give preferential consideration to an application for a grant for such an activity from a jurisdiction that demonstrates that: (1) the activity will cover a significant number of schools, (2) such jurisdiction uses (or will use such grant to develop) an electronic record management system that is compatible across multiple jurisdictions, or (3) there is community interest with respect to such activity. Reauthorizes such Program for FY2014-FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
