<bill session="112" type="h" number="1690" updated="2013-07-20T01:24:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MODERN Security Credentials Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Modernizing of Documentation and Elimination of Redundant Identification and Security Credentials Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 49 and 46, United States Code, and the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for certain improvements in surface transportation security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400341"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2011-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM" subcommittee="Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2011--Introduced.
Modernizing of Documentation and Elimination of Redundant Identification and Security Credentials Act or MODERN Security Credentials Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to consolidate and harmonize the DHS security threat assessment process for transportation workers. Revises the criteria for disqualifying an individual for employment with an air carrier, foreign air carrier, airport operator, or government. Prohibits an air carrier, foreign air carrier, airport operator, or government from employing individuals that: (1) have been disqualified from being issued a biometric or other transportation security card, or (2) pose a threat to transportation or national security. Authorizes a disqualified individual to seek a waiver of such requirements. Expands the list of criminal offenses that disqualify an individual temporarily or permanently from being issued a biometric transportation security card if convicted. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary to issue final regulations prohibiting commercial motor vehicle operators and shippers from transporting a security-sensitive material without holding a valid transportation security card. Directs the Secretary to prohibit Mexican or Canadian licensed commercial motor vehicle operators from transporting a security-sensitive material in the United States without being subjected to, and not disqualified as a result of, a security background records check by a federal agency which is similar to the background records check required for U.S. commercial motor vehicle operators transporting security-sensitive materials. Deems individuals who have obtained a hazardous materials endorsement to have met the background check requirements for issuance of a transportation security card. Requires the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to issue biometric transportation security cards to commercial motor vehicle operators transporting security-sensitive material. Requires the Secretary of DHS to establish a task force on disqualifying crimes.</summary>
</bill>
