<bill session="109" type="h" number="5788" updated="2013-07-19T19:55:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Honest Deficit Recognition Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to increase awareness of accrual and long-term budgeting, and to express the sense of Congress that the Presidents' annual budget submissions should consider accrual and long-term budgeting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2006-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2006--Introduced.
Honest Deficit Recognition Act of 2006 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to revise content requirements for the required report from the House and Senate Budget Committees accompanying the concurrent resolution on the budget. Requires inclusion of information discussing the most recent financial report of the federal government, including a summary of the net operating cost, net position, and long-term liabilities of the government (accrual and long-term budgeting). Expresses the sense of Congress that, in the preparation of the annual budget submission, the President should take such information into account and include a discussion of it in each such submission.</summary>
</bill>
