<bill session="113" type="h" number="2135" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cardiac Arrest Survival Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to clarify liability protections regarding emergency use of automated external defibrillators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412577" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Cardiac Arrest Survival Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to expand immunity from civil liability related to automated external defibrillator devices (AEDs), including by giving immunity to: (1) a person who owns, occupies, or manages the premises from which an AED is taken or at which an AED is used or attempted to be used on a victim of a perceived medical emergency; and (2) the owner-acquirer of an AED for any harm resulting from the use or attempted use of such device, unless the harm was proximately caused by the failure of the owner-acquirer to properly maintain the device according to the guidelines of the device manufacturer. Applies immunity regardless of whether: (1) the AED is marked with cautionary signage or registered with any government; or (2) the person who used or attempted to use the AED complied with such signage, had received training on such use, or was assisted or supervised by any other person, including a licensed physician.</summary>
</bill>
