<bill session="111" type="h" number="4908" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to support fire safety education programs on college campuses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2010-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3142"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2010--Introduced.
Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a program to award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education or consortiums of such institutions for: (1) initiating, expanding, or improving fire safety education programs; and (2) increasing fire safety awareness among enrolled students. Directs the Secretary to give priority to institutions that plan to use funds to initiate, expand, or improve fire safety education programs that include educational material specifically prepared for students with physical, sensory, or cognitive disabilities. Sets forth provisions regarding grant periods, limits on awards, and matching and other requirements. Requires an institution to use grant funds to initiate, expand, or improve a fire safety education program that: (1) reaches all enrolled students; (2) ensures maximum exposure to and increased awareness of, and that effectuates change in behavior regarding, fire safety by students through conducting outreach to students a minimum of twice per academic year and through measures that provide fire safety information to any student upon request; (3) includes minimum instruction regarding fire behavior, fire injury and death, ignition scenarios, fire safety systems and equipment, and the importance of means of egress; and (4) includes a mechanism for carrying out evaluations of program effectiveness. Requires the Secretary to publish a report of best practices for initiating, expanding, or improving fire safety education programs.</summary>
</bill>
