<bill session="110" type="h" number="3716" updated="2013-07-19T21:36:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Toys for Kids Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to require independent safety certification of children's products, to increase the Consumer Product Safety Commission's inspection capability for imported products, and to prohibit hazardous imports based on manufacturing site, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400420"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Toys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2007--Introduced.
Safe Toys for Kids Act - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to require every manufacturer (and any related private labeler) of an article for use by a child under 60 months of age which is subject to a consumer product safety standard or a rule under any Act administered by the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) declaring a consumer product a banned hazardous product to certify, based on testing conducted by a nongovernmental independent third party, that the product conforms to such standard or is not a banned hazardous product. Bars importation of such articles lacking independent third party certification. Allows the CPSC, by rule, to designate as a banned manufacturing site any facility in which consumer products are manufactured that has regularly produced consumer products which fail to comply with any applicable consumer product safety standard or engages in acts or practices likely to result in the production of imminently hazardous consumer products. Prohibits imports from banned sites.</summary>
</bill>
