<bill session="111" type="h" number="4854" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Home Inspection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that any home inspection conducted in connection with a purchase of residential real property that involves a federally related mortgage loan be conducted by a State-licensed or State-certified home inspector to determine the existence of structural, mechanical, and electrical safety defects, and to require inclusion in the standard HUD-1 settlement statement of information regarding any home inspection conducted in connection with settlement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400074"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2010--Introduced.
Home Inspection Act of 2010 - Requires the federal banking agencies to prescribe joint regulations to prohibit any lender from making any federally related mortgage loan, under which a home inspection is conducted in connection with settlement of such loan, unless such inspection is conducted by a home inspector who is licensed, certified, approved, or otherwise regulated by the inspector's home state or the state in which the real property is located. Amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 (RESPA) to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to include in the HUD-1 settlement form: (1) an item for identifying any home inspection conducted in connection with the settlement; (2) when such inspection was or is to be completed; (3) the inspection's cost; (4) whether the charge for such inspection is imposed on the borrower or the seller; and (5) whether such charge has been paid before settlement and a copy of such receipt is included with the settlement documents.</summary>
</bill>
