<bill session="112" type="h" number="1455" updated="2013-07-20T01:22:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">9/11 First Responders History Project Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Librarian of Congress to carry out a project to collect video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials of emergency responders and recovery and cleanup workers who responded to the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2011--Introduced.
9/11 First Responders History Project Act of 2011 - Requires, within the limits of available funds, the Librarian of Congress to establish an oral history project to: (1) survey collections of audio and video recordings (as well as ongoing documentary work) of the reminiscences of 9/11 first responders housed in archives, libraries, museums, and other educational institutions; (2) solicit, reproduce, and collect video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials of 9/11 first responders, and visual and written materials (such as letters, diaries, photographs, and ephemera) relevant to the personal histories of individuals; (3) create a collection, with a catalog and index, of the recordings and other materials obtained; and (4) make the collection available for public use through the Library of Congress (LOC) and other appropriate methods. Defines "9/11 first responders" as emergency responders and recovery and cleanup workers who responded to the terrorist attacks that occurred on September 11, 2001, in New York City, in Shanksville, Pennsylvania, and at the Pentagon (including the aftermath of such attacks).</summary>
</bill>
