<bill session="113" type="s" number="716" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the requirements under the STOCK Act regarding online access to certain financial disclosure statements and related forms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-04-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2583-2584" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2584" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2593" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1978-1979" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cantor asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2013-04-12T12:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1979" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-7" type="public" datetime="2013-04-15" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-7.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2013--Public Law.
Nullifies the effectiveness of the Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012 (STOCK Act) with respect to mandatory public, on-line financial disclosure reporting by congressional staff (except Members of Congress and congressional candidates) and executive branch officers and employees (except the President, the Vice President, and officers at levels I and II of the Executive Schedule who require nomination by the President and confirmation by the Senate). Applies the financial disclosure reporting requirements and restrictions of the STOCK Act only to Members of Congress, congressional candidates, the President, the Vice President, and executive branch officers at levels I and II of the Executive Schedule who require nomination by the President and confirmation by the Senate. Extends the deadline until January 1, 2014, for: the Secretary, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Clerk to develop systems to enable the electronic filing of financial disclosure reports as well as their on-line public availability; the Director of the Office of Government Ethics to develop such systems for financial disclosure forms filed by covered executive branch officials. Repeals: (1) the prohibition against requiring a login to search or sort the data contained in the publicly available financial disclosure systems, and (2) the requirement that a login protocol with the name of the user be utilized by a person downloading data contained in the reports.</summary>
</bill>
