<bill session="112" type="hr" number="152" updated="2013-07-20T01:04:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the life-saving role of ostomy care and prosthetics in the daily lives of hundreds of thousands of people in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2011-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="95"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2011--Introduced.
Recognizes: (1) the lifesaving role of ostomy care and prosthetics in the daily lives of hundreds of thousands of people in the United States, (2) the necessity of a specialized ostomy nurse to recommend and customize ostomy prostheses, and (3) that a patient undergoing a surgical procedure that results in the patient needing a prosthetic that manages or restores intestinal or urinary system function should have access to individually prescribed, customized prosthetics that will best meet the patient's needs. Urges: (1) that ostomy products be recognized, categorized, covered, and adequately reimbursed by Medicare in a new payment category of "prosthetic supplies"; and (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to ensure that HHS programs, policies, and payment practices facilitate innovation of and access to medical devices that restore or improve intestinal or urinary system function of individuals with an ostomy.</summary>
</bill>
