<bill session="113" type="s" number="262" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Equity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide equity for tuition and fees for individuals entitled to educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are pursuing programs of education at institutions of higher learning, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S526"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S526" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="595"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2013--Introduced.
Veterans Education Equity Act of 2013 - Revises the formula for the payment by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) of tuition and fees for individuals entitled to educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program and pursuing programs of education at public institutions of higher learning to include, as an additional payment formula, the greater of: (1) the actual net costs for in-state tuition after applying the receipt of any tuition waivers, reductions, scholarships, or other assistance; or (2) $17,500 for the academic year beginning on August 1, 2011 (such amount to be increased each subsequent year by the average percentage increase in undergraduate tuition costs).</summary>
</bill>
