<bill session="109" type="sr" number="209" updated="2013-07-19T20:08:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to strengthen fiscal responsibility by improving Senate consideration of conference reports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8832-8833"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8833" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2005--Introduced.
Makes it out of order to consider a conference report: (1) if it is not filed and made available 48 hours before presentation; (2) unless the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) cost estimate or table is available at the time of consideration; (3) if the preponderance of matter in the conference report is not in the jurisdiction of the committee (or Appropriations subcommittee for one of the regular appropriation bills) that had jurisdiction of the Senate passed bill submitted to conference; (4) if it contains extraneous material outside the scope of conference; or (5) if it contains extraneous material in the jurisdiction of a committee other than a committee from whom conferees were appointed. Allows a Senator to raise a single point of order that several provisions of a bill, resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report violate this Act. Sets forth procedures for consideration of certain points of order. Requires: (1) this Act to be waived or suspended in the Senate only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Members, duly chosen and sworn; and (2) the same three-fifths affirmative vote to sustain an appeal of the ruling of the Chair on a point of order raised under this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
