<bill session="110" type="h" number="4932" updated="2013-07-19T21:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to make certain additional plans eligible to participate in the health benefits program under chapter 89 of such title.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2008--Introduced.
Adds as health benefits plans that the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) may contract for or approve under the federal employee health benefits program one or more plans (other than a government-wide plan or an employee organization plan) that may be underwritten by carriers licensed in any number of states, offering one or more levels of benefits, under which payment is made: (1) by a carrier under contracts with physicians, hospitals, or other health services providers for benefits (of the types provided under a service or indemnity benefit plan) given to employees, annuitants, family members, former spouses, or persons having continued coverage; or (2) by a carrier to the employee, annuitant, family member, former spouse, or person having continued coverage.</summary>
</bill>
