<bill session="110" type="h" number="7057" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a liaison with the Federal Bureau of Investigation in United States Citizenship and Immigration Services to expedite naturalization applications filed by members of the Armed Forces and to establish a deadline for processing such applications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400339"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2840"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Office of the FBI Liaison in United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), which shall monitor and assist with Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) functions related to expeditiously processing naturalization applications filed by members and former members of the Armed Forces.Amends the the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that USCIS, within six months of receipt of a naturalization application filed by a member of the Armed Forces: (1) process and adjudicate the application; or (2) provide the applicant with an explanation for the inability to meet such deadline and an estimate of the adjudication date.Repeals the provisions of this Act five years after the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
