<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1263" updated="2013-07-19T21:01:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-11T18:08:00-04:00">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-11T18:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Chief Administrative Officer and the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives to take timely action to ensure that all Members, committees, and offices of the House are alerted of the dangers of electronic attacks on the computers and information systems used in carrying out their official duties and are fully briefed on how to protect themselves, their official records, and their communications from electronic security breaches.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5280-5287" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1263.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Lofgren, Zoe moved to refer the resolution.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5287" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to refer the resolution was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5287" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to refer the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5280" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-11T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The resolution was referred to the Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer hackers"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2008--Introduced.
Urges the Chief Administrative Officer and the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives to take timely action to ensure that all Members, committees, and offices of the House are: (1) alerted to the dangers of electronic attacks on the computers and information systems used in carrying out their official duties; and (2) fully briefed on how to protect themselves and their official records and communications from electronic security breaches.</summary>
</bill>
