<bill session="110" type="h" number="2372" updated="2013-07-19T21:24:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">WEAN Off of Oil Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Windfall Energy Alternatives for the Nation (WEAN) Off of Oil Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a temporary windfall profit tax on crude oil, to make the revenues from such tax available for investments in renewable energy and energy efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Excess profits tax"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2007--Introduced.
Windfall Energy Alternatives for the Nation (WEAN) Off of Oil Act of 2007 or the WEAN Off of Oil Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose upon major integrated oil companies an excise tax of 50 percent of their net windfall profits from the production of taxable crude oil in a taxable year. Defines "windfall profit" as the excess of the removal price (sales price) of a barrel of taxable crude oil over the adjusted base price of such barrel (i.e., $50 per barrel, adjusted for inflation). Terminates such tax three years after the enactment of this Act. Allows a tax deduction for the payment of any windfall profit tax.Establishes a separate account to be funded by windfall profit tax receipts (to be known as the Strategic Energy Efficiency and Renewables Reserve) for the purpose of financing legislation to: (1) accelerate the use of clean domestic renewable energy resources and alternative fuels; (2) promote the utilization of energy-efficient products, practices, and conservation; and (3) increase research, development, and deployment of clean renewable energy and efficiency technologies.</summary>
</bill>
