<bill session="112" type="h" number="4285" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to give members of the United States Capitol Police the option to delay mandatory retirement until age 60.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2012-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2012--Introduced.
Revises mandatory retirement requirements for members of the U.S. Capitol Police under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) and the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS). Requires the Capitol Police Board, at a member's request, to exempt the individual from automatic separation requirements until he or she becomes age 60, if the member: (1) undergoes a physical examination during the six-month period ending on the day the member turns age 57; and (2) on the basis of the examination, meets appropriate physical fitness criteria. (Currently, the Board, when in its judgement the public interest so requires, may exempt such a member from automatic separation until that member becomes 60 years of age.)</summary>
</bill>
