<bill session="110" type="s" number="1419" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Fuels, Consumer Protection, and Energy Efficiency Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Biofuels for Energy Security and Transportation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Energy Diplomacy and Security Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Petroleum Consumer Price Gouging Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Public Buildings Cost Reduction Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Ten-in-Ten Fuel Economy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to move the United States toward greater energy independence and security, to increase the production of clean renewable fuels, to protect consumers from price gouging, to increase the energy efficiency of products, buildings and vehicles, to promote research on and deploy greenhouse gas capture and storage options, and to improve the energy performance of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="156">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read twice. Ordered Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 156.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6272-6301" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3238"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1636"/>
    <amendment number="s1753"/>
    <amendment number="s1836"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/17/2007--Introduced.
Renewable Fuels, Consumer Protection, and Energy Efficiency Act of 2007 - Biofuels for Energy Security and Transportation Act of 2007 - Sets forth a schedule for motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel to contain specified volumes of renewable fuel by calendar year 2022. Prescribes a pilot program to establish refueling infrastructure corridors for gasoline blends containing renewable fuel.Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) increase funding for bioenergy research and development; (2) establish bioresearch centers that target biofuels; and (3) authorize loan guarantees for renewable fuel facilities.Establishes a grants program for: (1) renewable fuel production in states with low rates of ethanol production; and (2) transportation of biomass to local biorefineries.Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a biorefinery information center.Directs the Federal Trade Commission to impose a fuel tank cap labeling requirement for alternative fueled vehicles. Requires studies on specified renewable fuels and biofuels. Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act regarding advanced lighting technologies.Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prescribe new energy efficiency standards.Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 with respect to high efficiency vehicles, advanced batteries, and energy storage.United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) implement a research and development program for energy storage systems for motor transportation and electricity transmission and distribution; and (2) establish an Energy Storage Advisory Council.Sets forth national goals for: (1) energy savings in transportation; and (2) national energy efficiency improvement.Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act regarding federal fleet conservation requirements.Prescribes implementation of energy efficiency and renewable energy initiatives with respect to federal facilities.Extends programs assisting state and local governments with energy efficiency programs.Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 regarding utility energy efficiency programs.Provides: (1) technical assistance to governmental entities for energy efficiency and demand response programs, including an energy and environmental block grant; and (2) energy efficiency grants to institutions of higher education.Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to establish a carbon capture and storage research and demonstration program.Public Buildings Cost Reduction Act of 2007 - Provides a framework for: (1) the Administrator of General Services to establish a program to accelerate the use of more cost-effective technologies and practices at GSA facilities; and (2) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Program to provide competitive grants that target local government buildings.Ten-in-Ten Fuel Economy Act - Amends federal transportation law to increase average fuel economy standards for automobiles, medium-duty trucks, and heavy duty trucks.Petroleum Consumer Price Gouging Protection Act - Prohibits price gouging regarding oil, gasoline, or petroleum distillates during any period declared an energy emergency by the President. Energy Diplomacy and Security Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress on energy diplomacy and security. Urges the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, to take certain actions with respect to: (1) strategic energy partnerships; (2) international energy response mechanisms; and (3) a hemisphere energy cooperation forum.</summary>
</bill>
