<bill session="111" type="s" number="652" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Coalitions for Access and Quality Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to community health coalitions to assist in the development of integrated health care delivery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1614"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
Community Coalitions for Access and Quality Improvement Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to assist in developing integrated health care delivery systems to serve defined communities of individuals to: (1) improve efficiency and coordination among providers; (2) assist local communities in developing programs targeted toward preventing and managing chronic diseases; and (3) expand and enhance services provided. Authorizes the Secretary, in awarding grants, to accord priority to: (1) applicants that demonstrate the greatest unmet need for a more coordinated system of care; and (2) applicants that best promote the objectives of this Act. Authorizes a grantee to use amounts provided only for: (1) direct expenses associated with achieving greater integration of a health care delivery system to directly provide or ensure the provision of a broad range of culturally competent services; and (2) direct patient care and service expansions to fill identified or documented gaps within an integrated delivery system.</summary>
</bill>
