<bill session="111" type="sr" number="400" updated="2013-07-20T00:19:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution urging the implementation of a comprehensive strategy to address instability in Yemen.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S347-348" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="313">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 313.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to: (1) helping prevent state collapse in Yemen, denying terrorists a safe-haven, and supporting the people and government of Yemen in dealing with Yemen's challenges; and (2) defeating al-Qaeda and affiliated movements worldwide. Urges the government of Yemen to strengthen efforts against al-Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula. Calls upon: (1) the government of Yemen to address corruption, respect human rights, and work with its citizens and the international community to address the factors driving instability in Yemen; and (2) the international community to strengthen assistance programs in Yemen. Recognizes the critical role of Saudi Arabia and other members of the Gulf Cooperation Council in such programs. Applauds the February 2010 ceasefire that ended the latest round of fighting between the government of Yemen and the Houthi rebellion, and urges both parties as well as Yemen's neighbors and the international community to support the ceasefire through the provision of humanitarian and reconstruction assistance in areas affected by the fighting. Requests that the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense (DOD), and the Director of National Intelligence submit a comprehensive strategy for Yemen and urges the President to work with Yemen, the international community, and international organizations to implement such strategy.</summary>
</bill>
