<bill session="111" type="h" number="5322" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patent and Trademark Office Funding Stabilization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide authority to the Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office to set or adjust patent and trademark fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2010-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E867-868"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2010--Introduced.
Patent and Trademark Office Funding Stabilization Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (Director) to set or adjust patent and trademark fees in order to recover costs, including administrative costs, for patent and trademark processing, activities, services, and materials. Reduces such fees for micro and small entities. Terminates the Director's authority to establish and adjust fees upon the expiration of the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act. Makes, as of October 1, 2011, funds for the United States Patent and Trademark Office available until expended. Establishes in the Treasury the United States Patent and Trademark Office Public Enterprise Fund. Revises patent service fees. Establishes a 15% patent fee surcharge through September 30, 2011.</summary>
</bill>
