<bill session="109" type="s" number="2482" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Open for Business Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize funding for State-administered bridge loan programs, to increase the access of small businesses to export assistance center services in areas in which the President declared a major disaster as a result of Hurricane Katrina of 2005, Hurricane Rita of 2005, or Hurricane Wilma of 2005, to authorize additional disaster loans, to require reporting regarding the administration of the disaster loan programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2604-2605"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Horticulture"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2006--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Open for Business Act of 2006 - Authorizes appropriations for grants to appropriate state agencies in Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi, Texas, and Florida for state bridge loan programs in response to economic disruption caused by Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, or Wilma (hurricanes) in 2005. Requires the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to hire a full-time international finance specialist for the SBA's Office of International Trade to help carry out export promotion efforts in Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Arkansas. Amends the Small Business Act to waive grant limits in the case of grants made to small business development centers for assisting small businesses affected by the hurricanes. Authorizes the SBA to: (1) allow qualified lenders to process disaster loans and to verify loan losses; (2) make loans to nonprofit organizations that were negatively impacted by the hurricanes or are providing services to persons negatively impacted; and (3) make loans to any small business in the United States negatively impacted by the hurricanes. Provides for the deferred payment of disaster loans. Requires the Administrator to provide daily updates to Congress on the operation of SBA disaster loans in presidentially declared disaster areas. Requires the Administrator and the head of each federal agency making procurements related to relief, recovery, and reconstruction in areas affected by the hurricanes to set a goal for small business subcontracts with respect to such procurements. Requires the use of local firms and individuals in the use of federal funds for debris clearance, distribution of supplies, reconstruction, and other emergency assistance activities in hurricane-affected areas. Directs the Administrator to submit to the congressional small business committees a 2006 Atlantic hurricane season disaster response plan.</summary>
</bill>
