<bill session="110" type="s" number="2320" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Immunosuppressive Drug Coverage for Kidney Transplant Patients Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide continued entitlement to coverage for immunosuppressive drugs furnished to beneficiaries under the Medicare Program that have received a kidney transplant and whose entitlement to coverage would otherwise expire, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14066-14067"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14067" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3282"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Immunosuppressive drugs"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2007--Introduced.
Comprehensive Immunosuppressive Drug Coverage for Kidney Transplant Patients Act of 2007 - Amends SSA title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) to: (1) continue entitlement to prescription drugs used in immunosuppressive therapy furnished to an individual who receives a kidney transplant for which payment is made under Medicare; and (2) extend Medicare secondary payer requirements for end stage renal disease (ESRD) beneficiaries. Amends title XVIII (Medicare ) of SSA to apply special rules to kidney transplant recipients receiving additional coverage for immunosuppressive drugs. Deems such individual to be enrolled under Medicare part B. Makes him or her responsible for the full amount of the applicable premiums. Applies deductible and coinsurance requirements to the provision of such drugs. Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to set forth requirements for group health plans to provide coverage of immunosuppressive drugs for kidney transplant patients.</summary>
</bill>
