<bill session="113" type="h" number="3127" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cutting Red Tape, Green-Lighting Small Businesses Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit to small employers for certain newly hired employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412297"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2013--Introduced.
Cutting Red Tape, Green-Lighting Small Businesses Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an employer with not less than 2 or more than 150 employees in a calendar year a business-related tax credit for the cost of up to 5 newly-hired employees who are employed, on average, at least 30 hours per week. Makes such credit available to tax-exempt eligible small employers. Terminates such credit for wages paid after December 31, 2015. Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to: (1) determine, for a new small business concern, what SBA applications, submissions, or other paperwork are not essential to file during the first year of operation of such small business concern; and (2) make rules for the waiver of such filings.</summary>
</bill>
