<bill session="109" type="s" number="474" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mark O. Hatfield-Elizabeth Furse Scholarship and Excellence in Tribal Governance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Mark O. Hatfield-Elizabeth Furse Scholarship and Excellence in Tribal Governance Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2006-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2788"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2005--Introduced.
Mark O. Hatfield-Elizabeth Furse Scholarship and Excellence in Tribal Governance Act of 2005 - Establishes as an independent entity of the executive branch the Mark O. Hatfield-Elizabeth Furse Scholarship and Excellence in Tribal Governance Foundation, to be located in Portland, Oregon. Requires the Foundation to: (1) develop resources to train Native American and Alaska Native tribal council members properly in self-government and related fields; (2) foster greater recognition and understanding of the role of tribal self-government in the development of the United States; (3) identify critical issues facing tribal governments in the Nation; (4) establish a program for tribal governance research at the Institute for Tribal Government at Portland State University; and (5) provide educational outreach regarding tribal self-government. Authorizes the Foundation to award scholarships, fellowships, internships, and grants to eligible individuals who meet the minimum criteria established by the Foundation for study in fields relating to tribal governance. Authorizes the Foundation to award scholarships to outstanding undergraduate students who intend to pursue careers relating to tribal goverance, and Native Americans and Alaska Natives intending to pursue careers in tribal public policy. Authorizes the Foundation to award fellowships to: (1) outstanding graduate students who intend to pursue advanced degrees in fields relating to tribal governance, and Native Americans and Alaska Natives intending to pursue advanced degrees in tribal public policy, law, or medicine; and (2) faculty from a variety of disciplines to bring their expertise to the Foundation. Authorizes the Foundation to award internships to deserving and qualified: (1) individuals to work in Federal, State, and local agencies or in offices of major tribal governance organizations; and (2) Native American and Alaska Native individuals to work in Federal, State, and local agencies or in offices of major public health or public policy organizations. Directs the Foundation to award grants to the Institute to: (1) provide for an annual panel of experts to discuss contemporary tribal governance issues; (2) conduct research in tribal governance policy and on Native American and Alaska Native tribal public policy issues; and (3) invite visiting policymakers to share practical experiences with the Foundation. Establishes in the Treasury the Mark O. Hatfield- Elizabeth Furse Scholarship and Excellence in Tribal Governance Trust Fund to be administered by the Foundation.</summary>
</bill>
