<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1473" updated="2013-07-19T21:03:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-23T15:07:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-23T15:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the 150th anniversary year of the founding of Macy's, Inc., as an American entrepreneurial success story and the role Macy's, Inc., plays in supporting America's small businesses and vendors, including those that are minority and women owned; celebrating the vision, innovativeness, and ingenuity of all of our Nation's small businesses that aspire to grow and prosper as Macy's, Inc., has over its 150-year history; and congratulating Macy's, Inc., as an American entrepreneurial success story.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2008-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Velazquez moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8625-8626" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1473.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-23T15:07:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8625" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Recognizes the 150th anniversary of the founding of Macy's, Inc., and the role Macy's plays in supporting America's small businesses and vendors, including those that are minority and women owned. Celebrates the vision, innovativeness, and ingenuity of all U.S. small businesses that aspire to grow and prosper as Macy's has. Congratulates Macy's as an American entrepreneurial success story.</summary>
</bill>
