<bill session="111" type="s" number="1640" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Take Back Your Health Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide coverage of intensive lifestyle treatment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9043-9044"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Take Back Your Health Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to cover intensive lifestyle treatment, which is a physician-supervised program furnishing to eligible beneficiaries certain exercise, medication, nutritional, and other specified items and services intended to affect beneficially the progression of chronic coronary heart disease, Type 2 diabetes, metabolic syndrome, prostate cancer, or breast cancer. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Lifestyle Rewards Program for eligible beneficiaries who have successfully completed an intensive lifestyle program and meet certain other requirements. Expresses the sense of Congress that the services provided under an intensive lifestyle treatment program: (1) would benefit individuals with chronic diseases who are not enrolled in the Medicare program; and (2) should be covered by all public and private payers.</summary>
</bill>
