<bill session="113" type="hr" number="368" updated="2013-11-02T06:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-01T01:11:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-01T01:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Relating to consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 59) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-240, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule makes in order for the House to take H.J.Res. 59 from the Speaker's table, with the House amendment to the senate amendment thereto, insist on its amendment, and request a conference with the Senate thereon. Section 2 makes it in order for any motion pursuant to clause 4 of rule XXII relating to H.J.Res. 59 be offered only by the Majority Leader or his designee.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-30T23:37:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="63">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6041-6049" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 368.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30T23:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H. Res. 368.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T00:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6048" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="505" datetime="2013-10-01T01:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 199 (Roll no. 505).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6041" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T01:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hj" number="59"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Takes from the Speaker's table H.J. Res. 59, making continuing appropriations for FY2014, and for other purposes, with the House amendment to the Senate amendment thereto, insists on the House amendment, and requests a conference with the Senate. Limits to the Majority Leader or the designee of the Majority Leader the offering of a motion pursuant to clause 4 of Rule XXII (House and Senate Relations) of the Rules of the House of Representatives relating to H.J. Res. 59. (Clause 4 makes privileged a motion to dispose of any amendment when the stage of disagreement has been reached on a bill or resolution with House or Senate amendments.)</summary>
</bill>
