<bill session="112" type="h" number="102" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Photo Identification Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that only certain forms of identification of individuals may be accepted by the Federal Government and by financial institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Photo Identification Security Act - Restricts the forms of individual identification that may be accepted by the federal government or by financial institutions to the following: (1) a Social Security card accompanied by a photo identification card issued by the federal or a state government; (2) a driver's license or identification card issued by a state that is in compliance with the REAL ID Act of 2005; (3) a passport issued by the United States or a foreign government; and (4) a photo identification card issued by the Secretary of Homeland Security (acting through the Director of the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services).</summary>
</bill>
