<bill session="110" type="h" number="1423" updated="2013-07-19T21:16:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-08T19:08:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-08T19:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Lease Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Lease Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to lease a portion of a visitor center to be constructed outside the boundary of the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore in Porter County, Indiana, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a partnership with the Porter County Convention, Recreation and Visitor Commission regarding the use of the Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center as a visitor center for the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400417"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-737.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-08T14:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="468">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 468.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6187-6189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1423.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6200" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-07-08T19:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="472" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 376 - 11 (Roll no. 472).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6187" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2008--Passed House amended.
Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Partnership Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a memorandum of understanding to establish a joint partnership with the Porter County Convention, Recreation and Visitor Commission with regard to the use of the Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center as a visitor center for the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore. Allows the Secretary to: (1) plan, design, construct, and install exhibits in the Center related to the use and management of the resources at the Lakeshore, at a cost under $1.5 million; and (2) use park staff from the Lakeshore in the Center to provide visitor information and education. States that, for the purposes of the acquisition of lands or interests in lands outside the present boundaries of the Lakeshore, lands may be considered contiguous to other lands if the lands touch them, or are separated from them by only a public or private right-of-way, such as a road, railroad, or utility corridor.</summary>
</bill>
