<bill session="109" type="h" number="5502" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the academic competitiveness of students in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4845"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Chinese language"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economic security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Japanese language"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Life sciences"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Russian language"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Innovation and Competitiveness Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states and to partnerships of institutions of higher education and high need local educational agencies (LEAs) to implement strategies to increase the number of teachers qualified to teach advanced placement and pre-advanced placement courses in mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages. Replaces the Robert C. Byrd Honors Scholarship program with the Robert C. Byrd Mathematics and Science Honors Scholarship program. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award funds to a private nonprofit organization to administer, through a public-private partnership, a Mathematics and Science Honors Scholarships program for postsecondary and graduate students who commit to five consecutive years of service in a science, engineering, or mathematics field. Authorizes the Secretary to cover the student loan interest obligations of mathematics, science, or engineering professionals and elementary and secondary school teachers who make such an obligation. Authorizes grants to states for: (1) activities promoting the professional development of elementary and secondary school teachers; and (2) state mathematics and science education coordinating councils where education, business, and community leaders collaborate to improve teacher recruitment and training and student performance in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Authorizes grants to LEAs and public or private educational organizations to recruit and train individuals outside of the elementary and secondary education system who have expertise in mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages to teach such subjects at secondary schools on an adjunct basis. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to partnerships of institutions of higher education and LEAs to: (1) establish elementary and secondary school critical foreign language teacher recruitment and preparation programs; and (2) provide innovative critical language learning opportunities for students.</summary>
</bill>
