<bill session="109" type="h" number="1363" updated="2013-07-19T19:16:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Workplace Goods Job Growth and Competitiveness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a statute of repose for durable goods used in a trade or business.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2005-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3509"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2005--Introduced.
Workplace Goods Job Growth and Competitiveness Act of 2005 - Prohibits the filing of a civil action against a manufacturer or seller of a durable good (except a motor vehicle, vessel, aircraft, or train that is used primarily to transport passengers for hire) more than 18 years after it was delivered to its first purchaser or lessee for: (1) damage to property arising out of an accident involving such good; or (2) damages for death or personal injury arising out of an accident involving such good if the claimant has received or is eligible to receive worker compensation and the injury does not involve a toxic harm (including, but not limited to, any asbestos-related harm). Declares that this Act: (1) shall not bar an action against a defendant who made an express warranty in writing as to the safety or life expectancy of a specific product for a period of more than 18 years (except that this Act shall apply at the expiration of such warranty); (2) does not affect the limitations period established by the General Aviation Revitalization Act of 1994; and (3) does not supersede or modify any statute or common law that authorizes an action for civil damages, cost recovery, or any other form of relief for remediation of the environment.</summary>
</bill>
