<bill session="109" type="s" number="1444" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance for Industries Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to provide for alternative means of certifying workers for adjustment assistance on an industry-wide basis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8669-8670"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8670-8672" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12404"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2005--Introduced.
Trade Adjustment Assistance for Industries Act of 2005 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the Secretary of Labor, upon the request of the President, the U.S. Trade Representative, or of a congressional resolution, to initiate an investigation promptly to determine a petition for eligibility for trade adjustment assistance (TAA) by: (1) a group of workers (which may include workers from more than one facility or employer); or (2) all workers in an occupation. Prescribes duties of the governor of such state in which the workers' firm or subdivision is located, and of the Secretary with respect to the petition and its investigation. Repeals the requirement that the Secretary study a domestic industry whenever the International Trade Commission (ITC) begins investigations with respect to such industry. Requires, before certain actions are taken, notification to appropriate individuals by: (1) the ITC regarding certain investigations, determinations, and bilateral safeguards; (2) the Commissioner of Customs regarding agricultural safeguards; (3) the President regarding textile safeguards; and (4) the ITC regarding antidumping and countervailing duties. Requires the Secretary, upon receiving a request or a resolution on behalf of workers in a domestic industry or occupation, or upon receiving three or more of such TAA petitions within six months on behalf of such workers, to make an industry-wide determination with respect to the domestic industry or occupation in which the workers are or were employed. Requires the Secretary also, if TAA eligibility is not certified under such a determination, to make a determination of TAA eligibility regarding each group of workers in that domestic industry or occupation from which a petition was received. Requires industry-wide certification, as appropriate, including industry-wide certification for agricultural commodity producers, to be based on specified global safeguards, bilateral safeguard provisions, or antidumping or countervailing duty orders. Increases from $220 million to $440 million the total amount of fiscal year payments that may be made for training of adversely affected workers under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
