<bill session="109" type="s" number="525" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Caring for Children Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Caring for Children Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to reauthorize the Act, to improve early learning opportunities and promote school preparedness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2005-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2031-2032"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2032-2037" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-08-31">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Enzi under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/29/2005 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-130.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-08-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="199">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 199.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/31/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Caring for Children Act of 2005 - Title I: Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 - (Sec. 101) Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (CCDBGA) to include among CCDBGA goals early learning, school preparedness, and parental involvement in the education of young children in child care settings. (Sec. 102) Authorizes appropriations to carry out CCDBGA for FY2006-FY2010. (Sec. 103) Revises CCDBGA requirements for: (1) state plans, with respect to lead agencies, consumer and child care provider education information, use of block grant funds for child care resource and referral systems, direct services, and payment rates; (2) activities to improve the quality of child care, to include early learning and school preparedness standards; (3) optional priority use of additional funds; (4) reports and audits; (5) national activities; and (6) a child's eligibility based on a state-determined income level, with priority based on state-defined need. (Sec. 109) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to reserve specified amounts for: (1) annual grants to improve child care quality and access; and (2) a toll-free hotline. (Sec. 111) Declares that nothing in CCDBGA shall be construed to require a state to impose state child care licensing requirements on any type of early child care provider. Title II: Enhancing Security at Child Care Centers in Federal Facilities - (Sec. 202) Directs the following federal officials to issue regulations concerning matters relating to occupant emergency plans, evacuations, and relocation sites for their respective child care facilities: (1) the Administrator of General Services, for executive facilities; (2) specified officers of the House and Senate, and the Librarian of Congress, for legislative facilities; and (3) the Director of the Office of the U.S. Courts, for judicial facilities. Title III: Removal of Barriers to Increasing the Supply of Quality Child Care - (Sec. 301) Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish a demonstration program of competitive three-year grants to states, and to Indian tribes and tribal organizations, to help them provide funds to encourage the establishment and operation of small business employer-operated child care programs. Requires a state to give priority for such assistance to applicants that desire to form a consortium to provide child care in a geographic area within the state where such care is not generally available or accessible. Requires such a consortium to include at least one small business, and allows it to include other small businesses, nonprofit agencies or organizations, local governments, or other appropriate entities. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY2006-FY2010. Terminates the program at the end of FY2010.</summary>
</bill>
