<bill session="109" type="s" number="3810" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PACT Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevent All Cigarette Trafficking Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent tobacco smuggling, to ensure the collection of all tobacco taxes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2006-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8820-8821"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S8821-8827" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Prevent All Cigarette Trafficking Act of 2006 or the PACT Act - Amends the Jenkins Act to: (1) include smokeless tobacco as a regulated substance; (2) impose shipping and recordkeeping requirements on delivery sellers (sellers using the telephone, mails, or the Internet) of cigarettes and smokeless tobacco; (3) require common carriers of cigarette products to obtain age and identity verification upon delivery of such products; (4) require the Attorney General to compile and publish a list of delivery sellers of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco who have not complied with the registration or other requirements of such Act; (5) increase criminal penalties and impose new civil penalties for violations of such Act; (6) grant jurisdiction to U.S. district courts to restrain violations of such Act and direct the Attorney General to administer and enforce such Act; and (7) treat cigarettes and smokeless tobacco as nonmailable and prohibit such items from being deposited in or carried through the U.S. mails. Prohibits a tobacco product manufacturer or importer from selling or delivering in states cigarettes not in compliance with model or qualifying state statutes. Provides funding for undercover criminal investigative operations of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF). Authorizes ATF officers to enter the premises of certain cigarette shippers to inspect records and inventories.</summary>
</bill>
