<bill session="111" type="s" number="817" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pacific Salmon Stronghold Conservation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Pacific Salmon Stronghold Conservation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Salmon Stronghold Partnership program to conserve wild Pacific salmon and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4370"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4370-4373" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Subcommittee on Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and Coast Guard. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-833.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. With written report No. 111-348.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="642">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 642.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM22" subcommittee="Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and Coast Guard" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2055"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Pacific Salmon Stronghold Conservation Act of 2009 - (Sec. 3) Defines "salmon stronghold" as all or part of a watershed or that meets biological criteria for abundance, productivity, diversity (life history and run timing), habitat quality, or other biological attributes important to sustaining viable populations of salmon throughout their range. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary of Commerce (the Secretary) to establish the Salmon Stronghold Partnership as a cooperative, incentive-based, public-private partnership working across political boundaries and land ownerships to identify and conserve salmon strongholds. Requires that its board, to the extent possible, include: (1) representatives of Alaska, California, Idaho, Oregon, and Washington state; (2) specified federal entities; (3) nongovernmental organizations; (4) representatives from Indian tribes; and (5) a national or regional representative from associated counties. Directs such board to define criteria and develop a process for identifying salmon strongholds. (Sec. 5) Requires the Assistant Administrator for the National Marine Fisheries Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to carry out information and assessment functions associated with salmon strongholds and conservation planning, including trend analysis, geographic mapping, and climate change projections. (Sec. 6) Establishes a salmon stronghold watershed grants and technical assistance program to fund program administration, assist locally with a network of local authorities and private entities, provide financial assistance, accelerate recovery plans for threatened or endangered salmon populations, conduct public and education outreach, and other stronghold protection and restoration activities. Sets forth guidelines for program selection, prioritization, and funding to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (NFWF) or qualified states with a competitive grant process. Limits the federal share of the cost of a project on nonfederal land to 50%. (Sec. 7) Directs federal agencies responsible for managing federal land within a stronghold to cooperate with the Assistant Administrator and the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. (Sec. 8) Authorizes the sharing of status and trends data, innovative conservation strategies, conservation planning methodologies, and other information with North Pacific countries, including Canada, Japan, Russia, and South Korea, and appropriate international entities to promote salmon conservation and habitat. (Sec. 9) Prohibits acquiring private property without the owner's consent. Requires the deed of any real property that the Secretary of the Interior transfers for a conservation project to contain a reversion of title to the United States if the owner fails to manage the property in accordance with this Act. (Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter cooperative agreements, contracts, and grants; (2) accept donations; (3) participate in interagency financing; and (4) provide funds and donated property to federal agencies. (Sec. 12) Requires the Assistant Administrator to submit a report to Congress at least once every three years. (Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013.</summary>
</bill>
