<bill session="110" type="h" number="6800" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Drugs for Seniors (MEDS) Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to replace the Medicare prescription drug benefit adopted by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 with a revised and simplified prescription benefit program for all Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Medicare Drugs for Seniors (MEDS) Act of 2008 -Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to replace the current part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) program, adopted by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement and Modernization Act of 2003, with a revised prescription drug benefit program under a new part D (Prescription Medicine Benefit for the Aged and Disabled) for all Medicare beneficiaries. Provides for reductions in the price of prescription drugs for Medicare beneficiaries. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to: (1) revise requirements with respect to the commercial and personal importation of prescription drugs and the disposition of certain drugs denied admission; and (2) prescribe requirements with respect to Internet sales of prescription drugs. Provides that if any federal agency or any non-profit entity undertakes federally funded health care research and development, and is to convey or provide a patent or other exclusive right to use such research and development for a drug or other health care technology, such agency or entity shall not make such conveyance or provide such patent or other right until the recipient first agrees to a reasonable pricing agreement with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary determines that the public interest is served by a waiver of the reasonable pricing agreement. Sets forth Medigap transition requirements.</summary>
</bill>
