<bill session="110" type="s" number="128" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area Technical Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Cache La Poudre River National Heritage Area Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Cache La Poudre River Corridor Act to designate a new management entity, make certain technical and conforming amendments, enhance private property protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S126"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-266.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-01-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-285.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="637">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 637.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="591"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area Technical Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Cache La Poudre River Corridor Act to redesignate the Cache La Poudre Corridor as the "Cache la Poudre River National Heritage Area." Designates the Poudre Heritage Alliance as the management entity for the Area. Provides for the removal of private property included within the boundary of the Area upon request from the owner. Prohibits the Alliance from using federal funds received under this Act to acquire real property. Bars the acquisition of any land or interest in land by the Secretary of the Interior or the Alliance under this Act without the owner's consent. Requires the Alliance to prepare and submit a management plan for the Area. Allows the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the Alliance for the purpose of carrying out the plan. Prohibits any private property from being preserved, conserved, or promoted under the plan until: (1) the Alliance notifies the owner; and (2) the owner provides to the Alliance consent for the preservation, conservation, or promotion. Specifies private property protections. Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance to the Alliance (excluding technical assistance and administrative oversight) under the Act 10 years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
