<bill session="113" type="h" number="3037" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Litigation Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 5 and 28, United States Code, with respect to the award of fees and other expenses in cases brought against agencies of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412406" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Government Litigation Savings Act - Revises provisions of the Equal Access to Justice Act (EAJA) and the federal judicial code relating to the fees and other expenses of parties in agency proceedings and court cases against the federal government. Restricts awards of fees and other expenses under EAJA to prevailing parties with a direct and personal interest in an adjudication, including because of medical costs, property damage, determination of benefits, an unpaid disbursement, and other expenses of adjudication, or because of a policy interest. Requires (currently, authorizes) the reduction or denial of an award if the party during the course of the proceedings engaged in conduct which unduly or unreasonably (currently, unduly and unreasonably) protracted the final resolution of the matter in controversy. Increases to $200 per hour the cap on attorney fees awarded under EAJA and eliminates the cost-of-living and special factor considerations for allowing an increase in the hourly rate for such fees. Eliminates the net worth exemption for determining eligibility for fees and expenses under EAJA for tax-exempt organizations and cooperative associations under the Agricultural Marketing Act.</summary>
</bill>
