<bill session="112" type="s" number="137" updated="2013-07-20T02:17:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Insurance Rate Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide protections for consumers against excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory increases in premium rates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S204-206"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S206" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="416"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Health Insurance Rate Review Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to declare that federal provisions requiring the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to review unreasonable premium increases in health care coverage shall not be construed to prohibit a state from imposing additional rate requirements on health insurance issuers that are more protective of consumers. Expands such review to include all rate increases, not only premium increases. Directs the Secretary or the relevant state insurance commissioner (or state regulator) to take corrective actions to ensure that any excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates are corrected prior to, or as soon as possible after, implementation, including through mechanisms such as denying rates, modifying rates, or requiring rebates to consumers. Requires the Secretary to determine whether the state insurance commissioner or regulator or the Secretary will undertake such corrective actions based on whether the state can adequately undertake such actions. Applies these provisions to grandfathered health plans under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</summary>
</bill>
