<bill session="112" type="s" number="1324" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Captive Primate Safety Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Captive Primate Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to prohibit the importation, exportation, transportation, and sale, receipt, acquisition, or purchase in interstate or foreign commerce, of any live animal of any prohibited wildlife species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-09-20" withdrawn="2011-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-17">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 112-188.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="456">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 456.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4306"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Captive Primate Safety Act - Amends the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to add nonhuman primates to the definition of "prohibited wildlife species" for purposes of the prohibition against the sale or purchase of such species in interstate or foreign commerce. Makes it unlawful for a person to import, export, transport, sell, receive, acquire, or purchase a live animal of any prohibited wildlife species in interstate or foreign commerce (i.e., for pet trade purposes). Sets forth exceptions to such prohibition, including, under certain conditions, for: (1) transporting a nonhuman primate to or from a veterinarian, (2) transporting a nonhuman primate to a legally designated caregiver as a result of the death of the preceding owner, and (3) transporting a single primate of the genus Cebus that was obtained from and trained by a charitable organization to assist a permanently disabled individual with a severe mobility impairment. Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violations of the requirements of this Act. Extends the authorization of appropriations to carry out such prohibition for FY2011-FY2015.</summary>
</bill>
