<bill session="112" type="hr" number="349" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prevent duplicative and overlapping government programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2011-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="623"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="427"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2011--Introduced.
Amends Rule III (Calendars and Committee Reports) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the report accompanying each public bill or joint resolution reported by any committee to contain: (1) an analysis by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) to determine if the bill or joint resolution creates any new federal program, office, or initiative that would duplicate or overlap any existing federal entity with similar mission, purpose, goals, or activities, along with a listing of all such overlapping or duplication; and (2) an explanation provided by the committee as to why the creation of each new program, office, or initiative is necessary if a similar program, office, or initiative exists. Makes it out of order to consider such a measure unless the committee of jurisdiction has prepared and posted on its website an overlapping and duplicative program analysis and explanation for the legislation that contains the same CRS analysis and committee explanation. Provides for a waiver of this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
