<bill session="111" type="h" number="5405" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a visitor center for visitors to Yosemite National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E947"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2010--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire not more than 18 acres of lands and interests from willing sellers outside of the boundaries of Yosemite National Park near the junction of highways CA-49 and CA-140 in Mariposa, California, to provide a site or sites for visitor services and administrative purposes. Permits the use of federal and other available funds for the construction, management, and maintenance of permanent improvements to provide visitor services and administrative facilities on acquired lands and interests. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) partner with Mariposa County on land use planning related to the acquired lands and interests; and (2) consider the feasibility of allowing the state of California to locate the California State Mining and Mineral Museum on such lands and interests.</summary>
</bill>
