<bill session="111" type="h" number="2389" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care for Members of the Armed Forces Exposed to Chemical Hazards Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Defense to establish registries of members and former members of the Armed Forces exposed in the line of duty to occupational and environmental health chemical hazards, to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide health care to veterans exposed to such hazards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="642"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1779"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
Health Care for Members of the Armed Forces Exposed to Chemical Hazards Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Defense, for each occupational and environmental health chemical hazard of particular concern, to establish and administer a registry of members and former members of the Armed Forces who were exposed to such hazard in the line of duty on or after September 11, 2001. Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify a member or former member who may have been exposed to such a hazard; and (2) provide a complete physical and medical examination of such individual. Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies for the Institute of Medicine under which the Institute, for each incident of exposure reported in a registry, shall review and summarize the scientific evidence, and assess the strength thereof, concerning the association between the exposure to such hazard and acute and long-term health consequences of such exposure. Requires the Institute to: (1) make recommendations for necessary additional scientific studies; and (2) conduct periodic subsequent reviews of such evidence. Requires members and former members listed in registries to be notified of any conclusive determinations with respect to such exposure, as well as any other significant related developments. Makes any veteran who was exposed in the line of duty to an occupational and environmental health chemical hazard of particular concern eligible for hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for any disability, notwithstanding insufficient medical evidence to conclude that the disability may be associated with such exposure.</summary>
</bill>
