<bill session="109" type="h" number="1244" updated="2013-07-19T19:15:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide health care coverage for spouses and children of members of the uniformed services on active duty through the Federal Employees Health Benefits program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2005--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense to enter into an agreement with the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) under which eligible beneficiaries may enroll in health benefits plans offered through the Federal Employees Health Benefits program (FEHBP). Defines as eligible beneficiaries members of the uniformed services on active duty for more than 30 days with either a wife or a dependent child or children. Allows FEHBP enrollment under either self or self and family coverage. Prohibits dependents covered under such enrollment from receiving care at a military medical treatment facility or enrolling in a health care plan under the TRICARE program (a Department of Defense managed health care program).</summary>
</bill>
