<bill session="112" type="s" number="1890" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pirate Fishing Vessel Disposal Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent forfeited fishing vessels from being transferred to private parties and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3472"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Pirate Fishing Vessel Disposal Act of 2011 - Directs the head of a U.S. agency with administrative control over a forfeited vessel to transfer such vessel to the Commandant of the Coast Guard for use in live-fire sinking exercises if the Commandant determines that the vessel would be useful for such exercises. Requires, if a forfeited vessel is not transferred to or utilized by the Commandant for such exercises, that the forfeited vessel be transferred to or otherwise under the control of the Commandant, the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, or the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere of the Department of Commerce, and be: (1) scrapped or recycled; (2) sold or donated to a developing nation for fisheries enforcement; or (3) donated to a not-for-profit institution or governmental agency for education, research, or other public interest purposes with an agreement that the vessel will never be utilized for illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing or related activities. Defines a "forfeited vessel" as a foreign or stateless vessel forfeited to the United States for engaging in specified illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing under any of the living marine resource statutes implemented by the Secretary of Commerce. Applies this Act to all forfeited vessels surrendered or seized and forfeited after September 1, 2011.</summary>
</bill>
