<bill session="113" type="s" number="271" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Health in the Arctic Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Arctic health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2013--Introduced.
Better Health in the Arctic Act - Directs the Arctic Research Commission to examine the science base, gaps in knowledge, and strategies for the prevention and treatment of mental, behavioral, and physical health problems, including alcohol abuse, faced by populations in the Arctic, with a focus on Alaska. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to develop a national Arctic health science policy, reviewing and taking into consideration the National Arctic Health Science Policy developed by the American Public Health Association Task Force in 1984. Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a Desk for Arctic Health to: (1) work with the Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee to ensure adequate health representation from federal agencies, (2) collaborate and consult with governmental entities and U.S. nongovernmental organizations involved in Arctic health issues, and (3) collaborate with the Canadian Institutes of Health Research on indigenous Arctic people health issues. Directs the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish a program at the National Center of Environmental Health to foster advances and help provide technical support in the field of Arctic health impact assessments.</summary>
</bill>
