<bill session="113" type="hj" number="80" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-14T19:04:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-14T19:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">American Indian and Alaska Native health, education, and safety bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Indian Education, and Indian Health Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Indian Education, and Indian Health Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Bureau of Indian Education, and the Indian Health Service for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400376"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-12T09:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 371.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6548-6556" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-12T09:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 80.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-12T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of Rule 19, the Chair announced that further proceedings on H.J.Res. 80 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6574-6576, H6576-6579" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, the House resumed debate on H.J. Res. 80.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6576" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, the Chair announced that further proceedings on H.J.Res. 80 were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kirkpatrick moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6576-6578" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="H6576" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kirkpatrick motion to recommit with instructions, pending the reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J. Res. 59, Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Simpson stated that the proposed amendment contained in the motion to recommit with instructions was not germane to the underlying bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kirkpatrick appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6577-6578" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 180 (Roll no. 547).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="548" datetime="2013-10-14T19:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 233 - 160 (Roll no. 548).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/12/2013 H6548-6549" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-14T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the rule, the Chair announced the amendment was not debatable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="221">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 221.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="371"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h480"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/3/2013--Introduced.
Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Indian Education, and Indian Health Service Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations for FY2014 for continuing projects or activities not otherwise specifically provided for that were conducted in FY2013 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by Full Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (division F of P.L. 113-6) under the headings "Department of the Interior--Bureau of Indian Affairs and Bureau of Indian Education" and "Department of Health and Human Services--Indian Health Service." Requires the rate of operations to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-6), and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2). Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities. Authorizes amounts made available for civilian personnel compensation and benefits to be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for FY2013, except that such authority shall not be used until after the agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the American Indian and Alaska Native, Health, Education, and Safety Act.</summary>
</bill>
