<bill session="112" type="h" number="6204" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Investment Adviser Examination Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to require certain investment advisers to pay fees to help cover the costs of inspecting and examining investment advisers under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2012-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2012-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2012--Introduced.
Investment Adviser Examination Improvement Act of 2012 - Declares the sense of Congress that the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) should increase the number and frequency of examinations of investment advisers. Amends the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to direct the SEC to collect an annual fee from investment advisers subject to SEC inspection or examination to defray the cost of such inspections and examinations. Exempts certain state-regulated investment advisers from the requirement to pay an annual fee. Prescribes a fee calculation formula. Requires the SEC to make the formula publicly available on its website along with the factors used to reach the fee determination. Requires the Comptroller General to audit biennially the use of such fees, SEC reviews of the fee formula, and any adjustments to it. Makes such fees available to the SEC, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, to pay costs associated with inspecting and examining investment advisers.</summary>
</bill>
