<bill session="110" type="h" number="6804" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Families and Small Business Energy Tax Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals a temporary refundable credit for the cost of natural gas, home heating oil, and propane, to allow small businesses, farmers, and fishermen a credit for motor and other fuel costs, and to increase the credit for nonbusiness energy property and make it permanent, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2008-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6321"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6784"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3561"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Families and Small Business Energy Tax Relief Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual taxpayer an income-based refundable tax credit for the lesser of 50% of such taxpayer's residential energy costs for a taxable year or $750 ($1,500 for married taxpayers filing jointly). Defines "residential energy costs" as amounts paid in 2008 or 2009: (1) to any utility for natural gas used in the taxpayer's principal residence during the heating season (September through March); and (2) for heating oil or propane.Allows a certain small farming or commercial fishing businesses (gross receipts of not more than $20 million) a tax credit for up to 15% of amounts paid in 2008 or 2009 for gasoline, diesel fuel, heating oil, propane, and natural gas.Increases and makes permanent the tax credit for nonbusiness energy property expenditures.Amends the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 to authorize additional appropriations for outreach activities to inform eligible households of available energy-related assistance and for residential weatherization and repair activities for low-income households.</summary>
</bill>
