<bill session="111" type="h" number="6349" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for greater transparency in the conversion of Department of Defense functions previously performed by contractors to performance by Department of Defense employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to submit to Congress and make publicly available on an Internet website the total number of: (1) jobs, performed by both DOD civilian employees and contractors, in each state and at each military installation; and (2) DOD functions converted from performance by contractors to performance by DOD civilian employees in each state and at each military installation, as well as the task area of each function. Requires the Secretary to make publicly available the comparison of the cost of performance of each DOD function so converted. Allows any small business that performs a DOD function that is converted to performance by DOD civilian employees and, by reason of that conversion, loses 33% or more of its revenue generated through contracts or 33% or more of its employees, to appeal such conversion to the inspector general of the military department concerned or to the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
