<bill session="109" type="s" number="2113" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Digital Age Communications Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the widespread availability of communications services and the integrity of communication facilities, and to encourage investment in communication networks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2005-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2005--Introduced.
Digital Age Communications Act of 2005 - Makes it unlawful for any provider of electronic communications service to participate in unfair methods of competition, or unfair or deceptive practices, in or affecting electronic communications networks and services. Prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from denying an application to assign or transfer control of a communications license, permit, or certificate unless it is in violation of the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) or a specific FCC rule or regulation. Repeals the Act's application to universal service three years after the enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Federal-State Joint Board on universal service to periodically recommend to the FCC modifications as to which basic electronic communications services are to be supported by federal universal service support mechanisms. Directs the FCC to: (1) promulgate rules to reform the universal services contribution mechanism and adopt a new mechanism; and (2) revise its current universal service fund system to establish a single universal service fund which shall be the exclusive federal universal service support mechanism. States that it shall be U.S. policy: (1) to integrate federal, state, and local regulation of electronic communications networks; (2) that such networks and their services be governed by a single, minimally pervasive regulatory regime; (3) to eliminate rate regulation and rate-setting when feasible; and (4) to create incentives to invest in new technologies and to encourage the deployment of advanced electronic communications services. Authorizes continued state regulation of rates for basic stand-alone local service.</summary>
</bill>
