<bill session="112" type="h" number="4036" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pass a Budget Now Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to impose a daily reduction in the rates of pay for Members of Congress if Congress fails to agree to a concurrent resolution on the budget.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2012-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2012--Introduced.
Pass a Budget Now Act - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to reduce the rate of pay for a Member of Congress for failure to agree to a concurrent resolution on the budget. Reduces the rate of pay during each pay period of any year, if there is no agreement by April 15 on a budget resolution for the following fiscal year, by an amount equal to the product of the average daily rate of pay involved and the number of days during the pay period which occur after April 15 and before Congress does reach agreement on a budget resolution. Requires all unpaid compensation to be used for deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
