<bill session="113" type="h" number="2857" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Loan Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to provide the interest rate for certain disaster related loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2013--Introduced.
Disaster Loan Fairness Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act to provide the interest rate to be charged by the Small Business Administration (SBA) for loans made to small businesses 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act or later in major disaster areas. Requires such rate to be the lesser of 4% or one-half the prevailing rate for similar loans in the area for those unable to attain credit elsewhere, or three-fourths the prevailing rate for those able to attain credit elsewhere. Directs the Administrator to report to Congress on whether the reduced rate has resulted in: (1) a greater number of applications for disaster-related loans, (2) a greater number of approvals for such loans, or (3) a decreased default rate. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury, with respect to any presidential election held after 2012, from making any payments from the Presidential Election Campaign Fund (Fund) to any national committee of a political party for political nominating conventions.</summary>
</bill>
