<bill session="113" type="h" number="2417" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure High-voltage Infrastructure for Electricity from Lethal Damage Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Power Act to protect the bulk-power system and electric infrastructure critical to the defense and well-being of the United States against natural and manmade electromagnetic pulse ("EMP") threats and vulnerabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2013--Introduced.
Secure High-voltage Infrastructure for Electricity from Lethal Damage Act or SHIELD Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), with or without notice, hearing, or report, to order emergency measures to protect the reliability of either the bulk-power system or the defense critical electric infrastructure whenever the President issues a written directive or determination identifying an imminent grid security threat. Directs FERC to consult with governmental authorities in Canada, Mexico, and the Electric Reliability Organization (ERO) regarding implementation of emergency measures. Prescribes: (1) implementation procedures; and (2) related cost recovery measures affecting owners, operators, and users of either the bulk-power system or the defense critical electric infrastructure. Directs FERC to require any owner, user, or operator of the domestic bulk-power system to implement measures to protect the system against specified vulnerabilities. Requires FERC to issue an order directing ERO to submit for approval, within 30 days, a reliability standard requiring implementation, by any owner, operator, or user of the bulk-power system in the United States, of measures to protect the bulk-power system against an identified grid security vulnerability (including a protection plan with automated hardware-based solutions). Directs FERC also to order the ERO to submit reliability standards to: (1) protect the bulk-power system from a reasonably foreseeable geomagnetic storm event or electromagnetic pulse event (EMP); and (2) require entities that own or operate large transformers to ensure their adequate availability to restore promptly the reliable operation of the bulk-power system in the event of destruction or disability as a result of attack or a geomagnetic storm or EMP. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to: (1) develop technical expertise in the protection of electric energy systems against either geomagnetic storms or malicious acts using electronic communications or electromagnetic weapons; and (2) share it with owners, operators, or users of systems for the generation, transmission, or distribution of electric energy located in the United States and with state commissions.</summary>
</bill>
