<bill session="109" type="s" number="2248" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mathematics and Science Teaching Corps Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Math and Science Teaching Corps.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="4705"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5871"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2006--Introduced.
Mathematics and Science Teaching Corps Act of 2006 - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to create a Math and Science Teaching Corps to significantly improve mathematics and science achievement among secondary school students in the United States. Requires the Director of the Corps to carry out a program that awards: (1) Math and Science Teaching Corps Fellowships for Prospective Teachers (MSTC Fellowships) who possess comprehensive subject area knowledge; (2) grants to partner institutions to pay the tuition, fees, and overhead costs of the fellows; and (3) grants to participating local educational agencies to pay the expenses associated with facilitating the induction and professional development services for the fellows. Requires MSTC Fellowship recipients to: (1) receive specified pedagogical training; and (2) teach mathematics or science in a secondary school, for which they shall receive a stipend, and participate in induction programs of participating local educational agencies, for four years. Requires the Director to carry out a program that awards Math and Science Teaching Corps Fellowships for Experienced Teachers (MSTC Master Fellowships). Requires an MSTC Master Fellowship recipient to: (1) continue to teach mathematics or science in a secondary school of a participating agency for at least five of the seven years after receiving such fellowship, for which he or she shall receive a stipend; (2) serve as a leader within the individual's department and school; (3) mentor other recipients; and (4) attend subject or pedagogy workshops offered by the participating local educational agency.</summary>
</bill>
