<bill session="113" type="h" number="2844" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-09T19:26:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-09T19:26:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to consolidate the reporting obligations of the Federal Communications Commission in order to improve congressional oversight and reduce reporting burdens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2013-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-189.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-09T14:38:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="136">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 136.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Scalise moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5414-5416" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2844.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5417-5418" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="449" datetime="2013-09-09T19:26:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 449).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5414-5415" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1379"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2013--Passed House amended.
Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to publish on its website and submit to Congress a biennial report on the state of the communications marketplace assessing: (1) competition, including intermodal, facilities-based, and new and emergent services competition and addressing the provision of content, as well as communications using the Internet; (2) deployment of communications capabilities, including whether advanced telecommunications capability is being deployed to all Americans in a reasonable and timely fashion; and (3) whether laws, regulations, or regulatory practices pose a barrier to competitive entry or expansion of existing providers of communications services. Requires the FCC to: (1) compile a list of geographic areas that are not served by any provider of advanced telecommunications capability; and (2) consider market entry barriers for entrepreneurs and other small businesses in the communications marketplace in accordance with existing national policy favoring diversity of media voices, vigorous economic competition, technological advancement, and promotion of the public interest, convenience, and necessity. (Sec. 3) Repeals and consolidates various FCC reports including reports on satellite competition, international broadband, video programming, cable industry prices, small business entry barriers, commercial mobile radio, waivers from requirements prohibiting FCC employees from being financially interested in companies subject to FCC regulation, and several other existing reports under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
