<bill session="112" type="h" number="3273" updated="2013-07-20T01:38:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Port Security Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 46, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security or of any other department in which the Coast Guard is operating to enter into agreements with foreign governments or international organizations for the performance of port security assessments on behalf of the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412483"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-27">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2011--Introduced.
Port Security Efficiency Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) or of any other department in which the Coast Guard is operating, in assessing the effectiveness of antiterrorism measures maintained at foreign ports and notifying foreign governments of any steps necessary to improve such antiterrorism measures, to treat an assessment conducted by a foreign government or international organization as an assessment by the Secretary, provided that the Secretary certifies that such assessment was conducted in accordance with procedures specified in existing port security laws. Allows the appropriate Secretary to enter into agreements with a foreign government or international organization under which: (1) such governments or organizations may conduct such assessments on behalf of the Secretary or share related information, and (2) the Secretary may conduct such assessments on behalf of such governments or organizations or share related information. Prohibits this Act from: (1) requiring the approprite Secretary to recognize an assessment conducted by a foreign government or international organization, or (2) limiting the discretion or ability of the Secretary to conduct such an assessment.</summary>
</bill>
