<bill session="112" type="s" number="372" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cybersecurity and Internet Safety Standards Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce the ability of terrorists, spies, criminals, and other malicious actors to compromise, disrupt, damage, and destroy computer networks, critical infrastructure, and key resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S796"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S796-797" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2011--Introduced.
Internet and Cybersecurity Safety Standards Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct an analysis to determine the costs and benefits of requiring Internet service providers, communications service providers, electronic messaging providers, electronic mail providers, and other persons who provide a service or capability to enable computers to connect to the Internet to develop and enforce voluntary or mandatory minimum cybersecurity and Internet safety standards for users of computers to prevent terrorists, criminals, spies, and other malicious actors from compromising, disrupting, damaging, or destroying computer networks, critical infrastructure, and key resources. Directs the Secretary to consider: (1) the effect that such standards may have on homeland security, the global economy, innovation, individual liberty, and privacy; and (2) any legal impediments that may exist to the implementation of such standards.</summary>
</bill>
