<bill session="111" type="h" number="5759" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Rural Landscapes Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to require an operator to compensate a surface owner for damages resulting from the oil and gas operations of the operator on land affected by the operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2010--Introduced.
Protecting Rural Landscapes Act of 2010 - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act, with respect to the lease of oil and gas lands, to require a person with the legal right to conduct oil and gas operations on covered land (operator) to compensate the surface owner for damages resulting from: (1) loss of agricultural production and income; (2) lost land value; (3) lost use of and lost access to the land; and (4) the lost value of improvements. Requires the operator to reclaim the affected surface. Requires the operator to give notice prior to: (1) initial entry for activities that do not disturb the surface; and (2) commencing oil and gas operations. Requires the operator, at the time of providing notice of commencement of oil and gas operations, to provide the surface owner with a proposed surface use agreement that includes an offer of compensation for damages to the surface affected by oil and gas operations. Requires an operator to provide the surface owner with appropriate financial assurance of reclamation in lieu of executing a surface use agreement. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to provide notice of upcoming lease sales and drilling permits to each: (1) surface owner of affected covered land; and (2) permittee or right-of-way holder with the right to use the surface of affected federal land.</summary>
</bill>
