<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1432" updated="2013-07-19T21:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18T17:51:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-18T17:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Adoption Day and National Adoption Month by promoting national awareness of adoption and the children in foster care awaiting families, celebrating children and families involved in adoption, recognizing current programs and efforts designed to promote adoption, and encouraging people in the United States to seek improved safety, permanency, and well-being for all children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McDermott moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8319-8324" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Weller objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8454" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-18T17:51:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/17/2008 H8319" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18T17:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Supports the goals and ideals of National Adoption Day (November 15, 2008) and National Adoption Month (November 2008). Recognizes that every child in foster care deserves a permanent and loving family and the significant commitment of taxpayers to support adoption.</summary>
</bill>
