<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1466" updated="2013-07-19T23:08:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Energy to provide certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Energy's application to foreclose use of Yucca Mountain as a high level nuclear waste repository.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported Without Recommendation by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-19T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 111-550.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-19T19:23:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="220">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 220.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2010--Reported to House without amendment.
Requests the President and directs the Secretary of Energy to furnish to the House of Representatives all documents relating to: (1) the Department of Energy's (DOE) Motion to Withdraw its pending licensing application with prejudice for a permanent geologic repository at Yucca Mountain, Nevada; (2) the President's elimination of future funding for Yucca Mountain; (3) DOE's reprogramming of FY2010 funds to bring to the Yucca Mountain Project to an orderly close; (4) DOE's discontinuation of standard monitoring and data collection of the site; and (5) DOE's efforts to preserve documents supporting its Yucca Mountain Repository License Application.</summary>
</bill>
