<bill session="109" type="hr" number="921" updated="2013-07-19T19:02:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20T12:10:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-20T12:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the recent attacks against the State of Israel, holding terrorists and their state-sponsors accountable for such attacks, supporting Israel's right to defend itself, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2006-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hyde moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5451-5480" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the House proceeded with 2 hours of debate on H. Res. 921.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19T20:30:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Ms. Ros-Lehtinen asked unanimous consent that debate time on H. Res. 921 be extended by 40 minutes equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19T21:50:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Ms. Ros-Lehtinen asked unanimous consent that debate time on H. Res. 921 be extended by 40 minutes equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19T22:40:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until July 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5505-5506" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-07-20T12:10:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="391" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 8, 4 Present (Roll no. 391).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/19/2006 H5451-5452" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="922"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="923"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="926"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="1044"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sr" number="534"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bombardment"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Passed House without amendment.
Reaffirms steadfast support for Israel. Condemns Hamas and Hezbollah for: (1) engaging in unprovoked and reprehensible attacks against Israel on undisputed Israeli territory, for taking hostages, for killing Israeli soldiers, and for indiscriminately targeting Israeli civilian populations with rockets and missiles; and (2) exploiting civilian populations as shields, locating their equipment and bases of operation, including rockets and other armaments, amidst civilian populations, including in homes and mosques. Recognizes Israel's commitment to minimizing civilian loss and welcomes Israel's efforts to prevent civilian casualties. Demands that Iran and Syria direct Hamas and Hezbollah to immediately and unconditionally release the captive Israeli soldiers. Affirms that all governments that have provided continued support to Hamas or Hezbollah share responsibility for the hostage-taking and attacks against Israel and should be held accountable for their actions. Condemns the governments of Iran and Syria for their continued support for Hezbollah and Hamas in their attacks against Israelis and other terrorist activities. Supports Israel's right to defend itself, including to conduct operations both in Israel and in the territory of threatening nations in accordance with international law, including Article 51 of the United Nations Charter. Commends the President of the United States for fully supporting Israel as it responds to attacks by terrorist organizations and their state sponsors. Urges the President to bring the full force of U.S. political, diplomatic, and economic sanctions against the governments Syria and Iran. Demands that the government of Lebanon do everything in its power to free the kidnapped Israeli soldiers held in Lebanon. Calls on the U.N. Security Council to: (1) condemn these unprovoked acts; and (2) ensure full implementation of Security Council 1559, which requires that Hezbollah be dismantled and all Syrian personnel and Iranian Revolutionary Guards leave Lebanon. Expresses condolences to all families of innocent victims of recent violence. Declares a continued commitment to working with Israel and other U.S. allies to fight terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
