<bill session="109" type="h" number="5064" updated="2013-07-19T19:49:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to eliminate the MA Regional Plan Stabilization Fund and to extend health status adjustment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="18"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2260"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Preferred provider organizations (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2006--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to eliminate the Medicare Advantage Regional Plan Stabilization Fund. Amends SSA title XVIII, as amended by the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005, to repeal the phase-out, and instead extend indefinitely application, of the budget neutrality factor in the health status adjustment in determining the amount of payments to Medicare Advantage Organizations. (The budget neutrality factor reflects changes in treatment and coding practices in the fee-for-service sector, as well as differences in coding patterns between Medicare Advantage plans and providers under part A and B, to the extent that the Secretary has identified such differences.)</summary>
</bill>
