<bill session="111" type="h" number="3274" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Voters' Equal Access to Voter Registration Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to provide members of the Armed Forces and their family members equal access to voter registration assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412190" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1265"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2009--Introduced.
Military Voters' Equal Access to Voter Registration Act of 2009 - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require designating direct each Secretary of a military department to designate an office on each Armed Forces installation to ensure that certain individuals are provided the opportunity to register to vote in federal elections, update voter registrations, and request absentee ballots under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act. Designates as those individuals those who are: (1) members of the Armed Forces and are undergoing a permanent change of duty station, deploying overseas for at least 6 months, returning from an overseas deployment of at least 6 months, or requests assistance related to voter registration; and (2) are dependents of members of the Armed Forces, request assistance, and are at least 18 years old. Considers an office so designated to be a voter registration agency for all purposes of the Act. Requires informing Armed Forces members and their dependents of the assistance available under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
