<bill session="113" type="h" number="1986" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SANE Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the assignment of Sexual Assault Nurse Examiners-Adult/Adolescent to brigades and equivalent units of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400630"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2013--Introduced.
Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Deployment Act or SANE Deployment Act - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to direct the Secretary of each military department to assign at least one Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner-Adult/Adolescent (Examiner) to each brigade or equivalent unit level under that Secretary's jurisdiction, unless assignment to other units is determined to be more practicable and effective by the Secretary of Defense (DOD). Allows the assignment of more than one Examiner as necessary based on the demographics or needs of a unit. Allows for the waiver of such assignment for a specific unit level if a department Secretary determines that compliance will impose an undue burden, but requires congressional notification and justification therefor. Requires that, on and after October 1, 2015, only members of the Armed Forces and civilian DOD employees may be assigned as Examiners. Requires appropriate Examiner training and certification.</summary>
</bill>
