<bill session="112" type="h" number="6492" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sustainable, Livable And Green (S.L.A.G.) Highway Construction Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment, in the Office of Pavement Technology of the Federal Highway Administration, of the position of Recovered Mineral Component Ombudsman.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Sustainable, Livable And Green (S.L.A.G.) Highway Construction Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish in the Office of Pavement Technology of the Federal Highway Administration the position of Recovered Mineral Component Ombudsman to: (1) act as a liaison between the states and the DOT on federally funded highway projects; (2) encourage states to use recovered mineral component (RMC) to drive down costs and be more environmentally sensitive; and (3) provide information on projects that use RMC, its safety, and training and educational seminars on RMC environmental benefits. Urges the Secretary to amend comprehensive procurement guidelines for federally-funded asphalt and concrete highway projects to include specifications that encourage the use of such RMCs as ground granulated blast furnace slag, blast furnace slag aggregate, and steel furnace slag aggregate. Requires the Director of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish standards to ensure that the use of RMCs does not violate the Federal Water Pollution Control Act or any other environmental law.</summary>
</bill>
