<bill session="110" type="s" number="2177" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Get in Line Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the payment of individuals to reserve a place in line for a seat for a lobbyist at a congressional committee hearing or business meeting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2007--Introduced.
Get in Line Act - Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to prohibit any lobbyist or lobbyist-employing organization, either registered or required to register, or any employee listed or required to be listed as a lobbyist by a registrant, from making a payment to an individual to reserve a place in line for a seat for such lobbyist, employee, or organization at a congressional committee hearing or business meeting. Requires the lobbyist, employee, or organization to certify in their semiannual reports on certain contributions that they have read and are familiar with this Act and have not violated it. Requires a Senate committee that is unable to accommodate all persons wishing to sit in the hearing room for a committee hearing or business meeting to: (1) make all reasonable accommodations for such overflow, including opening up an overflow room with a video monitor showing the hearing or meeting if possible; and (2) stream the hearing or meeting on the committee website to the extent practicable.</summary>
</bill>
