<bill session="111" type="h" number="6060" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Textile Technology Innovation and Research for Exportation (ATTIRE) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support innovation and research in the United States textile and fiber products industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2010-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
American Textile Technology Innovation and Research for Exportation (ATTIRE) Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a grant program to fund textile research and innovation in the U.S. textile and fiber products industry and to promote increased U.S. textile exports. Limits eligibility under such grant program to institutions of higher education and not-for-profit research institutions, including not-for-profit industry associations whose mission is to support textile research and innovation. Gives preference in the award of such grants to collaborative research organizations that emphasize peer-reviewed research by leading academic and industry experts. Requires grant funds to be used for research and development activities that achieve at least one of the goals described in this Act, including to: (1) build and sustain innovation and competitiveness in the U.S. textile industry; (2) contribute to transforming the U.S. textile and apparel industry into a highly flexible supply chain; and (3) facilitate the creation of domestic jobs in the textile industry.</summary>
</bill>
