<bill session="110" type="s" number="2686" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Complete Streets Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that all users of the transportation system, including pedestrians, bicyclists, and transit users as well as children, older individuals, and individuals with disabilities, are able to travel safely and conveniently on streets and highways.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5951"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the aged"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2008--Introduced.
Complete Streets Act of 2008 - Amends the surface transportation program to require state and metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs) to: (1) adopt a policy statement that ensures that all users of the transportation system, including pedestrians, bicyclists, and transit users as well as children, older individuals, and individuals with disabilities, are able to travel safely and conveniently on streets and highways within the public right-of-way; and (2) apply such policy to Transportation Improvement Program projects as well as to all aspects of the transportation project development process. Requires states and MPOs to certify that each road project has been reviewed for compliance with the policy statement and enhances the safety, convenience, and accessibility for all users of the transportation system to the extent reasonably possible. Requires the U.S. Access Board to issue final standards for accessibility of new construction and alterations of pedestrian facilities in the public right-of-way. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to require the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) to conduct complete streets research to assist states and MPOs in developing and implementing plans, projects, procedures, policies, and training that comply with the policy statement.</summary>
</bill>
