<bill session="109" type="s" number="2061" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security and Interior Enforcement Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act and other Act to provide for true enforcement and border security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drone aircraft"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teleconferencing"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Border Security and Interior Enforcement Improvement Act of 2005 - Provides for construction of fencing and security improvements in the border area from the Pacific Ocean to the Gulf of Mexico. Provides for increases in: (1) border patrol agents; (2) Department of Defense (DOD) surveillance equipment along the southern border; (3) Customs and Border Patrol officers; and (4) Department of Homeland Security (DHS) immigration and worksite enforcement personnel and Department of Justice immigration attorneys and judges. Revises and extends implementation deadlines for the integrated entry and exit data system. Requires state and local law enforcement agencies to provide DHS with specified information about apprehended illegal aliens. Provides for: (1) increased federal detention space and utilization of DOD installations identified for closure; (2) transfer of illegal aliens from state or local custody to federal custody; (3) listing of immigration violators in the National Crime Information Center database; (4) federal reimbursement of state and local detention and transportation costs; (5) continuation of the institutional removal program (IRP), its expansion to all states, and a private right of action to remedy a violation of its enforcement by state or local authorities; and (6) immigration-related training for state and local personnel. States that state and local law enforcement personnel are fully authorized to investigate, apprehend, or transfer to federal custody aliens in the United States (including interstate transportation of such aliens to detention centers) in order to assist in the enforcement of U.S. immigration laws. Increase and enhances penalties for alien smuggling, document fraud, and certain crimes committed by illegal aliens. Provides for asset forfeiture and additional criminal fines and/or imprisonment for an alien who is illegally in the United States. (Provides an affirmative defense for an overstay due to unusual hardship or illness.) Makes criminal street gang members inadmissible and deportable. Requires mandatory detention of aliens subject to removal based upon criminal street gang membership. Makes such aliens ineligible for asylum and protection from removal to certain countries. Revises specified voluntary departure, detention, and removal provisions. Provides for: (1) expedited removal of criminal aliens; and (2) detention alternative pilot programs. Provides: (1) for public listing of every alien who is subject to a final order of removal and with respect to whom there is no likelihood of foreseeable future removal due to the refusal, or unreasonable delay, of all countries designated by the alien to receive such alien; (2) that such listing shall indicate whether the alien has been released from federal custody and the city and state of such alien's residence; and (3) for discontinuance of visas for a country having 24 or more of its citizens or nationals per month on such list.</summary>
</bill>
