<bill session="113" type="s" number="962" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRS Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit amounts made available by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 from being transferred to the Internal Revenue Service for implementation of such Acts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2013--Introduced.
IRS Accountability Act of 2013 - Amends the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 to prohibit any amounts made available in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) or the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 from being appropriated to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) for purposes of carrying out such Acts. Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) none of the amounts made available in PPACA or the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 should be appropriated to the IRS to carry out any provisions of such Acts in FY2014 or thereafter; and (2) no amounts appropriated to the IRS, from whatever source, for FY2014 or thereafter should be used to implement, enforce, or carry out the provisions of such Acts.</summary>
</bill>
