<bill session="110" type="h" number="4036" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cents and Sensibility Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to save the American taxpayers money by immediately altering the metallic composition of the 1-cent coin, to require a prompt review and report, with recommendations, for cost-saving changes in the metallic content of other circulating United States coins, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Alloys"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copper"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Weights and measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2007--Introduced.
Cents and Sensibility Act - Revises the discretionary authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe the weight and the composition of the alloy of the one-cent coin. Requires that the one-cent coin be: (1) produced primarily of steel; and (2) treated to impart a copper color to its appearance so that the appearance is similar to one-cent coins produced of a copper-zinc alloy. Exempts from such requirement certain Lincoln Bicentennial numismatic pennies. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report to certain congressional committees on a unified plan to change the metallic content of the five-cent, ten-cent, quarter-dollar and half-dollar circulating coins so as to return the ratios between the unit cost to produce such coins and their face value to a point where it is as close as possible to the historic production-cost-to-face-value ratios achieved in the 1980s.</summary>
</bill>
