<bill session="112" type="s" number="1620" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">POLAR-C Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserve Our Large Arctic Response Capability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure the icebreaking capabilities of the United States and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3113"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Preserve Our Large Arctic Response Capability Act or POLAR-C Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should maintain domestic heavy and medium duty icebreaker assets to meet U.S. Coast Guard (CG) statutory requirements and priorities for maritime transportation; and (2) maintaining less than a sufficient number of such assets jeopardizes national security, law enforcement, maritime safety, environmental protection, disaster response, scientific research, and natural resource protection in the polar regions and Alaska. Directs the CG Commandant to submit to Congress its polar icebreaker business case analysis for replacing or performing service life extensions on the CG's 2 heavy polar icebreakers: (1) Cutter POLAR SEA (WAGB 11), and (2) Cutter POLAR STAR (WAGB 10). Prohibits the CG Commandant and the Administrator of the Maritime Administration from disposing or taking any other specified action with respect to such icebreakers until 2 years after such submission.</summary>
</bill>
