<bill session="109" type="sr" number="387" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the need to replace the United Nations Human Rights Commission with a new Human Rights Council.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2006-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1657" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="714"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations delegations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2006--Introduced.
States that the United States remains committed to the creation of a new Human Rights Council to replace the discredited United Nations Human Rights Commission (UNHRC). Urges the President and the governments of other U.N. member countries to continue with negotiations for the creation of a Human Rights Council. Expresses the sense of the Senate that a credible Human Rights Council would: (1) establish membership criteria that would exclude the worst human rights abusers, including exclusion of member countries subject to U.N. Security Council sanctions; (2) include Israel's full participation; (3) set a size limit consistent with ensuring that only countries that respect human rights are members of the primary U.N. human rights body; (4) exclude any provision that prevents the consecutive election of member countries to the Council; and (5) utilize a formula for the distribution of membership among U.N. member countries that gives priority to countries that respect human rights, while also giving consideration to geographical distribution, the representation of different forms of civilization, and the principal legal systems.</summary>
</bill>
