<bill session="112" type="h" number="6406" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Federal Employee Whistleblower Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand whistleblower protections to non-Federal employees whose disclosures involve misuse of Federal funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2012-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="241"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Introduced.
Non-Federal Employee Whistleblower Protection Act of 2012 - Repeals and replaces provisions prohibiting reprisals against employees of civilian and defense contractors for disclosing to a federal official information relating to a substantial violation of law related to a public contract. Prohibits an employee of any non-federal employer receiving covered funds (i.e., a contract, grant, or other payment any portion of which is provided by the federal government) from being discharged, demoted, or discriminated against as a reprisal for initiating or participating in any proceeding related to the misuse of federal funds, reasonably opposing the misuse of federal funds, or disclosing to specified federal agencies or officials information that the employee reasonably believes is evidence of: (1) gross mismanagement of an agency contract or grant relating to covered funds; (2) a gross waste of covered funds; (3) a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety, or an abuse of authority, related to the implementation or use of covered funds; or (4) a violation of a law, rule, or regulation related to an agency contract, subcontract, or grant relating to covered funds. Sets forth provisions on: (1) time limitations for determinations by inspector generals on whether to conduct or continue an investigation of a reprisal complaint, (2) access by a complainant to the inspector general's investigative file, (3) the standard of proof for showing the occurrence of a reprisal, (4) agency actions to deny relief or remedy a reprisal, (5) the exhaustion of administrative remedies authorizing civil action by a complainant, and (6) nonenforceability of waivers and arbitration of disputes.</summary>
</bill>
