<bill session="109" type="h" number="4369" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To withhold amounts available for contributions to the regular assessed budget of the United Nations unless certain requirements relating to the transfer and public availability of the complete archive of files of the Independent Inquiry Committee into the Oil-for-Food Program are met.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dictators"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2005--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of State to withhold $100 million from each of the FY2007-FY2009 contributions to the regular assessed budget of the United Nations until the Secretary certifies to Congress that the following requirements have been met: (1) the complete archive of the Independent Inquiry Committee into the Oil-for-Food Program has been transferred by the Committee or the United Nations to an entity other than the Committee or the United Nations; (2) such archive is made available for public inspection for at least five years as a research resource into the history of the Oil-for-Food Program and the practices of the Saddam Hussein regime; and (3) the United Nations has foregone any censorial control over such archive.</summary>
</bill>
