<bill session="112" type="s" number="354" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Classified Information Procedures Reform and Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Classified Information Procedures Act to improve the protection of classified information and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S753"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S753-754" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2011--Introduced.
Classified Information Procedures Reform and Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the Classified Information Procedures Act, with respect to the use and disclosure of classified information in legal proceedings, to: (1) allow ex parte pretrial conferences where the presence of both parties reasonably could be expected to cause damage to national security or the defendant's ability to make a defense; (2) expand protective orders to limit the use of or access to classified information; (3) expand discovery rules to restrict access&#160;to classified information, other than documents; (4) expand a defendant's notice requirement to include intent to use classified information; (5) establish additional standards for the admissibility, use, and disclosure of classified information at trial; (6) expand the interlocutory appeal rights of the United States; and (7) allow a court to fashion alternative procedures to prevent unnecessary disclosures of classified information at trial.</summary>
</bill>
