<bill session="109" type="s" number="1571" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Comprehensive Hepatitis C Health Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish a comprehensive program for testing and treatment of veterans for the Hepatitis C virus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9493"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9493-9494" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="90"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Hepatitis"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Psychiatrists"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Veterans Comprehensive Hepatitis C Health Care Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, during the first year after the enactment of this Act, to provide a blood test for the Hepatitis C virus to: (1) each veteran who served on active military duty during the Vietnam era, or who is considered to be "at risk," and who is enrolled to receive veterans' medical care and requests such test or is otherwise receiving a physical examination or any other care or treatment from the Secretary; and (2) any other veteran who requests such test. Requires the Secretary, after such period, to provide such test to any veteran who requests it. Requires the Secretary to provide followup tests and appropriate treatment for any veteran who tests positive. Prohibits a copayment from being charged for such treatment. Provides funding for the Department of Veterans Affairs for Hepatitis C detection and treatment programs, beginning with FY2006. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop and implement a standardized Department policy with respect to such virus; and (2) annually take appropriate outreach actions to notify untested veterans. Directs the Secretary to establish at least one, and no more than three, additional Hepatitis C centers of excellence within the Department health care network. Provides funding.</summary>
</bill>
