<bill session="111" type="h" number="1247" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Tenants at Foreclosure Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the interests of bona fide tenants in the case of any foreclosure on any dwelling or residential real property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2009-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2009-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2009-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2009--Introduced.
Protecting Tenants at Foreclosure Act of 2009 - States that any immediate successor in interest to residential property in foreclosure assumes such interest subject to: (1) giving an existing tenant at least 90-day notice to vacate; and (2) specified rights of such tenant to occupy the premises until the end of the lease. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require a housing assistance payment contract to provide that in the case of an owner who is an immediate successor in interest pursuant to foreclosure: (1) during the initial term of the lease vacating the property prior to sale shall not constitute other good cause for termination of the lease; but (2) in subsequent lease terms vacating the property prior to sale may constitute good cause if the property is unmarketable while occupied, or if such owner will occupy the unit as a primary residence. Authorizes: (1) a housing assistance payment contract entered into by the public housing agency and the owner of a dwelling unit to provide that the immediate successor in interest to property in foreclosure in which a housing assistance recipient resides assumes such interest subject to the lease between the prior owner and the tenant, and subject to the housing assistance payments contract between the prior owner and the public housing agency for the occupied unit; and (2) the public housing agency, where the successor owner cannot be identified, to use rental funds to pay for the property's utilities if owed by the owner or for reasonable moving costs, including security deposits.</summary>
</bill>
