<bill session="112" type="s" number="982" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Detaining Terrorists to Secure America Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reaffirm the authority of the Department of Defense to maintain United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, as a location for the detention of unprivileged enemy belligerents held by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412493"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2011-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2948" label="text of measure as introduced in Senate"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="944"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Detaining Terrorists to Secure America Act of 2011 - Reaffirms that the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo), is and shall be a location for the detention of individuals in the custody or control of the Department of Defense (DOD) who have engaged in or supported hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners on behalf of al Qaeda, the Taliban, or an affiliated group to which the Authorization for Use of Military Force (P.L. 107-40) applies. Directs the Secretary of Defense to maintain Guantanamo as an open and operating facility for the current and future detention of such individuals. Amends the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 to make permanent (under current law, terminates on January 7, 2012) a prohibition on the use of any federal funds (under current law, only DOD funds) to transfer any individual detained at Guantanamo on or after October 1, 2009, to the individual's country of origin or any other foreign country or entity unless the Secretary makes a specified certification to Congress relating to such transfer. Prohibits any federal funds (under current law, only DOD funds) from being used to construct or modify any facility in the United States or its territories or possessions to house any individual in the custody or control of DOD or under detention at Guantanamo on or after the above date for the purpose of detention or imprisonment.</summary>
</bill>
