<bill session="112" type="h" number="2847" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Specialty Agriculture Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a nonimmigrant H-2C work visa program for agricultural workers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2011-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2011--Introduced.
American Specialty Agriculture Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish an H-2C nonimmigrant visa for an alien having a residence in a foreign country which he or she has no intention of abandoning and who is coming temporarily (10-month maximum per contract period) to the United States to perform agricultural labor or services, including the pressing of apples for cider on a farm. Requires an employer or employer association to file an H-2C petition with the Department of Agriculture (USDA) which shall include specified employment-related attestations. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) penalties; (2) working conditions, wages, and transportation reimbursement; (3) admissions and extensions of stay; (4) abandonment of employment and worker replacement; (5) legal assistance; and (6) arbitration and mediation. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct investigations and random audits of employer work sites. Requires an employer to guarantee to offer the worker employment for the hourly equivalent of at least 50% of the work hours during the total anticipated period of employment. Limits the number of annual fiscal year H-2C admissions. Prohibits the admission of spouses and children of H-2C workers. Extends coverage under the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act to H-2C workers. Makes the provisions of this Act effective two years after its enactment. Terminates authority to petition for H-2A temporary agricultural workers two years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
