<bill session="110" type="s" number="3651" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10069-10070, S10074"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10070-10073" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3560"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2008--Introduced.
Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization Act - Authorizes Sealaska Corporation, the Regional Corporation for Southeast Alaska, to select and receive conveyance of its remaining land entitlement under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) from specified: (1) economic development land; (2) sites with sacred, cultural, traditional, or historical significance (with certain restrictions on sites located within a unit of the National Park System); and (3) Alaska Native futures sites with traditional and recreational use value.Authorizes the Director of the National Park Service to enter into a cooperative management agreement with Sealaska, other village corporations and urban corporations, and federally recognized Indian tribes with cultural and historical ties to Glacier Bay National Park to recognize and perpetuate values associated with the Tlingit homeland and culture, wilderness, and ecological preservation. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to complete the conveyance of lands to Sealaska within one year of selection.Prohibits Sealaska from selecting or receiving any conveyance of lands from within any conservation system unit, federally designated wilderness area, or certain land use designation areas.Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) covenants and conditions on land conveyances to Sealaska, including covenants prohibiting commercial timber harvesting or mineral development; (2) authorized uses for the sacred, cultural, traditional, and historic sites; and (3) nonexclusive access and use rights that are required to be included in conveyances to Sealaska of native enterprise sites.</summary>
</bill>
