<bill session="112" type="s" number="744" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Passport Identity Verification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize certain Department of State personnel, who are responsible for examining and processing United States passport applications, to access relevant information in Federal, State, and other records and databases, for the purpose of verifying the identity of a passport applicant and detecting passport fraud, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2201-2202"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2011--Introduced.
Passport Identity Verification Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to consider, for data sharing purposes only, that when Department of State personnel authorized by the Secretary of State to grant, refuse, revoke, deny, or adjudicate U.S. passports are lawfully engaged in authorized data sharing activities regarding such passport activities, those activities shall be considered law enforcement activities involving the administration of criminal justice. Considers such Department personnel to be engaged in authorized data sharing activities when lawfully seeking to: (1) verify the identity of a passport applicant, (2) detect passport fraud, or (3) deny or revoke a passport. Directs the Secretary to promulgate implementing regulations regarding data sharing regulations, procedures, and policies. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study, and report to Congress, to determine: (1) if U.S. passport applicants or renewals should provide biometric identification information, and (2) if technology should be employed to verify identity documents.</summary>
</bill>
