<bill session="109" type="h" number="5071" updated="2013-07-19T19:49:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Animas River Good Samaritan Mined Land Remediation Pilot Project Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a pilot project for the remediation of abandoned and inactive hardrock mines in the Upper Animas River basin in southwestern Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400620"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2006--Introduced.
Animas River Good Samaritan Mined Land Remediation Pilot Project Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a 10-year pilot project under which the Administrator, with the State of Colorado's concurrence, may issue or modify, enforce, or terminate a permit to a remediating party for discharges associated with remediation activity at an abandoned or inactive mined land in the Animas River watershed above Elk Creek in San Juan County, Colorado, that modifies otherwise applicable discharge requirements, effluent limitations, and permit certification requirements. Defines a "remediating party" as: (1) the United States, except with respect to abandoned or inactive mined land on federal land; (2) the State of Colorado or its political subdivisions; or (3) persons that are neither responsible for site activities that contributed to pollution discharges nor owners of the site. Sets forth procedural guidelines for a applying for, reviewing, issuing, enforcing, and terminating such permits for remediation activities at an abandoned or inactive mined land from which there is, or may be, a discharge of pollutants into U.S. waters. Requires: (1) an applicant to submit a remediation plan describing pollutants present, persons responsible, remediation goals, practices to meet maximum daily load allocations, the monitoring method, and the remediation schedule and budget; and (2) the Administrator to issue regulations establishing generally applicable requirements for such plans.</summary>
</bill>
