<bill session="109" type="s" number="1868" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GAS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gasoline Affordability and Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure gasoline affordability and security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11324-11325"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11325-11326" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2005--Introduced.
Gasoline Affordability and Security Act or the GAS Act - States it is unlawful to sell gasoline or diesel fuel at a price which constitutes price gouging (as defined by Federal Trade Commission (FTC)) during the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the President determines the existence of conditions warranting the drawdown and sale of petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve. Requires the FTC to establish a Competitive Pricing Task Force to provide assistance upon request of a state attorney general. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary of Energy to: (1) ensure that specified funds are allocated to coal-based gasification technologies, including a Fischer-Tropsch technology project to produce ultra-low sulfur liquid transportation fuel; (2) establish as an energy policy priority the expedited, large-scale commercialization of such technology; and (3) provide funds for a subsequent Fischer-Tropsch technology project. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow as a credit against the income tax the qualified teleworking expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer during such year. Prescribes guidelines for the treatment of employer-provided computer equipment as a fringe benefit. Expresses the sense of Congress that Congress and the employees of the legislative branch of the federal government should: (1) conserve gasoline, aviation, and diesel fuel by whatever means practicable; and (2) as a part of such conservation efforts, promote teleworking.</summary>
</bill>
