<bill session="109" type="h" number="1190" updated="2013-07-19T19:14:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-08T10:33:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-08T10:33:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a feasibility study to design and construct a four reservoir intertie system for the purposes of improving the water storage opportunities, water supply reliability, and water yield of San Vicente, El Capitan, Murray, and Loveland Reservoirs in San Diego County, California in consultation and cooperation with the City of San Diego and the Sweetwater Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="2005-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2005-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T15:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-321.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-06T15:48:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="175">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 175.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-03-08T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gohmert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-08T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H651-652" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-08T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1190.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-03-08T10:33:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H652" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-03-08T10:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydraulic engineering"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2006--Passed House amended.
San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the City of San Diego and the Sweetwater Authority, to undertake a study to determine the feasibility of constructing a four reservoir intertie system to improve water storage opportunities, water supply reliability, and water yield of the existing non-federal water storage system. Directs that the feasibility study: (1) document the Secretary's engineering, environmental, and economic investigation of the proposed reservoir and intertie project, taking into consideration the needs of and potential benefits to the area; and (2) indicate whether the proposed project is recommended. Limits the federal cost share and total federal costs. Directs the Secretary to: (1) consult and cooperate with appropriate state, regional, and local authorities; and (2) submit to Congress a feasibility report and seek specific authority to develop and construct any recommended project. Requires such report to include: (1) good faith letters of intent by the City, the Authority, and its nonfederal partners to indicate that they have committed to share allocated costs; and (2) a schedule identifying the annual operation, maintenance, and replacement costs that should be allocated to the City and the Authority, as well as the current and expected financial capability to pay operation, maintenance, and replacement costs. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
