<bill session="111" type="hj" number="38" updated="2013-07-20T00:12:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T10:25:00-05:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Hastings (FL) asked unanimous consent that at any time without intervention of any point of order to consider in the House the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 38) making further continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2009, and for other purposes; such joint resolution shall be considered as read; such joint resolution shall be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations; and the previous question shall be considered as ordered on such joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T10:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 219 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 38 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived except those arising under clause 10 or rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T10:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated by previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by previous special order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3060-3066" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J.Res. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T11:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3064" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T11:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3064-3066" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T11:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lewis(CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be repored back to the House with sundry amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3065" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3065" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 160 - 218 (Roll no. 108).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3065-3066" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-03-06T12:08:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="109" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 328 - 50 (Roll no. 109).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3060" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2009-03-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2871" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2009-03-06" type="public" number="111-6">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-6.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="219"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2009--Public Law.
Amends the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2009 (division A of Public Law 110-329) to extend until March 11, 2009, specified continuing appropriations for FY2009.</summary>
</bill>
