<bill session="111" type="sr" number="570" updated="2013-07-20T00:21:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-28">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling for continued support for and an increased effort by the Governments of Pakistan, Afghanistan, and other Central Asian countries to effectively monitor and regulate the manufacture, sale, transport, and use of ammonium nitrate fertilizer in order to prevent the transport of ammonium nitrate into Afghanistan where the ammonium nitrate is used in improvised explosive devices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2010-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2010-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-06-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5497" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5497" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5493" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Urges the governments of Pakistan, Afghanistan, and other Central Asian countries to commit to regulating the sale, transport, and use of ammonium nitrate in the region. Calls on the Secretary of State to: (1) address with the governments of Pakistan, Afghanistan, and other Central Asian countries the proliferation and transportation of ammonium nitrate and other improvised explosive device (IED) precursors in the region; and (2) work with the World Customs Organization and other international bodies on initiatives to improve global controls on IED components. Urges the Secretary to work with the governments of Pakistan, Afghanistan, and other Central Asian countries to support improvements in infrastructure and procedures at border crossings to prevent the flow of ammonium nitrate and other IED precursors or components into the region.</summary>
</bill>
