<bill session="112" type="s" number="845" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Return Due Date Simplification and Modernization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the logical flow of return information between partnerships, corporations, trusts, estates, and individuals to better enable each party to submit timely, accurate returns and reduce the need for extended and amended returns, to provide for modified due dates by regulation, and to conform the automatic corporate extension period to longstanding regulatory rule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2012-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2012-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2012-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2012-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2382"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Tax Return Due Date Simplification and Modernization Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to change tax return due dates for partnerships (from April 15 to March 15, with extensions until September 15), S corporations (from March 15 to March 31, with extensions until September 30), and C corporations (from March 15 to April 15, with extensions until October 15). Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2011, to modify by regulation the due dates for extensions of tax returns for partnerships, estates, employee benefit plans, and tax-exempt organizations. Sets a due date of April 15 for the annual information return of a foreign trust with a U.S. owner and for the report of foreign bank and financial accounts (with extensions until October 15). Extends the automatic extension for corporation income tax returns from three to six months.</summary>
</bill>
