<bill session="109" type="s" number="182" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-26">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Uintah Research and Curatorial Center Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Uintah Research and Curatorial Center Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Uintah Research and Curatorial Center Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Uintah Research and Curatorial Center for Dinosaur National Monument in the States of Colorado and Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300007"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S592"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment. With written report No. 109-42.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="58">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 58.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9018-9052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9043" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2005--Passed Senate amended.
Uintah Research and Curatorial Center Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to establish the Uintah Research and Curatorial Center on land located outside the boundary of the Dinosaur National Monument in Colorado and Utah. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire such land by donation in the vicinity of Vernal, Utah. Makes the map depicting such land available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service. Requires the Center to be used for the curation of, storage of, and research on items in: (1) the museum collection of the Monument; and (2) any collection maintained by an entity specified in this Act that enters into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary for the curation of, and research on, the museum collection and the development, use, management, and operation of the Center. Provides that land acquired for the Center shall not be part of the Monument or subject to laws and regulations applicable to the Monument. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
